<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Encoding: Computers as a Global Medium at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drawing from the Libraries&amp;rsquo; extensive collections, &lt;i&gt;Encoding&lt;/i&gt; illustrates two fundamental shifts in the history of computing: recasting computers as a communications medium rather than solely as a means for calculation by &amp;ldquo;number crunching&amp;rdquo; and developing encoding systems that encompassed more of the world&amp;rsquo;s text and language systems. The result was global computing: a technology that today encompasses virtually all the world&amp;rsquo;s cultural, financial, educational and entertainment media. Notable collections include &lt;i&gt;the Unicode Collection&lt;/i&gt;, t&lt;i&gt;he Louis Rosenblum Papers&lt;/i&gt;, &amp;amp; &lt;i&gt;the Thomas S. Mullaney East Asian Information Technology History Collection&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Encodingexhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43777083471902/huge/fe5b6405c13574f4b206a4a8d6c3fb17509313a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3098" width="4000" isDefault="true" fileSize="1126422"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science Before Silicon Valley  at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition to show August 11, 2023 &amp;mdash; March 24, 2024, in Cecil H. Green Library&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the reception.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;An extension of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition entitled:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; Early Stanford Women in STEM &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;will show from September 25 &amp;mdash; December 15, 2023, in the Hohbach Hall Entrance Case, Silicon Valley Archives, Green Library.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. It showcases Stanford&amp;rsquo;s considerable holdings for this subject, including the role of our own university in this history. Our exhibition displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East. We invite viewers to see them as building blocks in a global history of gender and knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Many women participated in making knowledge. Long before the rise of the institutional laboratory, the body and the home were domestic laboratories. Largely denied access to institutions of research and learning, women improvised their own opportunities. We have looked for patterns rather than exceptions, documenting women&amp;rsquo;s scientific labor and the practical realities of earning a living. The variety of scientific and medical publications written by, for, and about women reminds us that this is a history of the many rather than the few. Every author has a reading public&amp;mdash;the most successful ones reached large international audiences. Individual histories reveal larger networks and often exist in relationship to institutions. We explore the evolution of women&amp;rsquo;s scientific education, research, publications, and careers with these questions in mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Hypatia of Alexandria (355&amp;ndash;415 CE) provides a symbolic point of departure for our exhibition. She was renowned for her lectures in Greek philosophy, mathematics, and astronomy in Alexandria and was brutally murdered by Christians; none of her writings survive, but her reputation endured. Our opening case also includes Maria Sibylla Merian&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous and insightful Metamorphosis of Surinamese Insects (1705). Merian (1647&amp;ndash;1717) was a trained artist and self-educated naturalist who left her husband, collaborated with her daughters, and traveled all the way to Dutch Surinam to observe insects. There she learned about the medicinal uses of Caribbean plants from indigenous and enslaved women. Her life and career were their own metamorphosis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Bringing a long global story home, we end our exhibition by reflecting on women and science &amp;quot;before Silicon Valley.&amp;quot; From its inception in 1891, Stanford educated and encouraged women of science. Focusing on the early decades, we have extracted interesting Stanford women scientists, engineers, and physicians&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;from the archives, exploring their intellectual passions and pursuits. Louise Brown Nash&amp;rsquo;s portfolio of scientific illustrations in the opening case illuminates the kind of opportunity talented women unexpectedly discovered at Stanford, where Nash was the first &amp;quot;Artist of the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory.&amp;quot; This pioneering generation of Stanford women found possibilities even as they confronted their limits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The next generations of Stanford women bridge the gap between the growth of women&amp;rsquo;s higher education in the late nineteenth century, the era of women&amp;rsquo;s suffrage, and the postwar boom in American universities, scientific research, and technological innovation. A 1957 memo of one of the earliest meetings of Stanford women faculty records three women in science and engineering&amp;mdash;Myra Keen (paleontology), Mary Sunseri (mathematics), and Irmgard Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz (aeronautical engineering). Keen and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz also open this exhibition. Keen&amp;rsquo;s career as a curator and professor illuminates the end of an era when natural history was an important part of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s mission. Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz&amp;rsquo;s arrival at Stanford marks the growth of aeronautical engineering. Her work brought her great acclaim in Germany, where she headed a research institute, and led to a spousal lectureship at postwar Stanford. In 1957, Keen was in her third year as an assistant professor and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz was still a lecturer&amp;mdash;until 1960 when the conspicuous gap between her reputation and status became too uncomfortable. Both women help us to understand the importance of second careers, a subject explored with selections from two major Stanford archives in the exhibit case downstairs in the Silicon Valley Archive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The renowned physicist and chemist Marie Curie would have surely enjoyed meeting the Stanford women we have encountered, had she been able to come as a visiting professor in the early 1930s. Every episode in this exhibition deserves further study, as do others we could not include. We invite you to explore these histories and their artifacts and get to know some very interesting scientific women.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. M-F, 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Sat, and 12 p.m. to 5 p.m. Sun. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Library Hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; page to confirm hours and access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Libraries&amp;#39; entry requirements and available services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge_women_and_science_before_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43725646356122/huge/283f182485005a2848d9ad5d0707f7c7355c1020.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="730683"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons of History: The Rise and Fall of Technology in Chinese History at Green Library, 5th floor, Bender Room</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://sccei.fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stanford Center on China&amp;#39;s Economy and Institutions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;are pleased to present the&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;2023 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;featuring&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Professor Yasheng Huang &lt;/b&gt;who will be speaking on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Lessons of History: The Rise and Fall of Technology in Chinese History.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;To attend in person, please register&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSesl2FGLEZYTnv1oQ7B_B56nkL3ZVYPBCgnoZkvfwL2PhrEsQ/viewform"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;To attend online, please register&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ixqW297LTj2lThgZEXz18Q#/registration"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China was once the most technologically advanced civilization in the world.&amp;nbsp;Ancient Chinese achievements in technology are simply staggering. China led Europe in metallurgy, ship construction, navigation techniques, and many other fields, often by several centuries. The Chinese also invented gunpowder, paper, the water clock, the moveable printing press, and other consequential technologies way ahead of the West. For example, the Chinese invented the seismograph 1,700 years before the French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But China&amp;rsquo;s technological development stalled, stagnated, and eventually collapsed and its early technological leadership did not set the country on a modernization path. This lecture examines the factors behind the rise and the fall of Chinese historical technology and draws lessons for today&amp;rsquo;s China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor &lt;a href="https://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/directory/yasheng-huang"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yasheng Huang&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the International Program Professor in Chinese Economy and Business and a professor of global economics and management at the MIT Sloan School of Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huang founded and runs China Lab and India Lab, which aim to help entrepreneurs in these countries improve their management skills. He is an expert source on international business, political economy, and international management. In collaboration with other scholars, Dr. Huang is conducting research on human capital formation in China and India, entrepreneurship, and ethnic and labor-intensive foreign direct investment (FDI). Prior to MIT Sloan, he held faculty positions at the University of Michigan and at Harvard Business School. Huang also served as a consultant to the World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family of&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;donated his personal archive to the Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world&amp;#39;s largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://hsiehlecture.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2023hsiehlecture</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44039748929265/huge/738a220a659bb477427c7332e1e6c18f97105076.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="411" width="565" isDefault="true" fileSize="294163"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArcGIS Online 101 (DRMC Sept 29) at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overview of the ArcGIS Online platform, Esri Interactive Web Mapping app. Learn how to use ArcGIS Online to upload, analyze and share geospatial data and create interactive web maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Adding yourself to the Stanford enterprise AGO organization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exploring the ArcGIS Online interface (Contents and Groups)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;U﻿ploading, organizing, and sharing spatial data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating and using Groups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Intro to Map Viewer (adding data and basic setting styles)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;If you plan to follow along with the hands-on portion of the workshop, please be sure to bring your own laptop. There are no computers provided in the DRMC.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directions to the David Rumsey Map Center and a URL to the event landing page will be emailed to attendees separately.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;N﻿ote&lt;/b&gt;: workshop is open to current Stanford affiliates only. You must have a valid Stanford SUnetID.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/arcgis_online_101_drmc_sept_29</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323329744936/huge/20dcd97b8db5776946ac8f15096c466d1d145c31.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="132914"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrate Tag der Deutschen Einheit (Day of German Unity)  by Gaming in German at Green Library! at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:left"&gt;Celebrate this German national holiday with a variety of German-language games such as &lt;i&gt;Catan, Mensch &amp;auml;rgere Dich nicht, Schafkopf&lt;/i&gt;, and many more. We&amp;rsquo;ll also have lists of terms for those who wish to learn or practice their German skills in preparation for a &lt;i&gt;Spieleabend&lt;/i&gt; (game night).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fest zum Tag der Deutschen Einheit:&lt;br /&gt;
Brettspielen auf Deutsch in der Green Library!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Am Tag der Wiedervereinigung feiern wir mit deutschsprachigen Brettspielen, wie z.B., &lt;i&gt;Catan, Mensch &amp;auml;rgere Dich nicht, Schafkopf&lt;/i&gt;, usw. Zur F&amp;ouml;rderung der deutschen Spieleabend-Sprachkenntnisse werden auch Wortschatzlisten dabei sein.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Oct 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrate_tag_der_deutschen_einheit_day_of_german_unity_by_gaming_in_german_at_green_library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44375996438613/huge/b008a496ec968bf9ac609d394adbe840c06d5903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="225" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="43122"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reception for Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley Exhibition at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us in the&amp;nbsp;Green Library Rotunda&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;4:30 - 6:30 PM&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;Thursday, October 5th,&amp;nbsp;for a reception to celebrate Professor Paula Findlen&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Embodied Knowledge&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. The exhibition showcases&amp;nbsp;Stanford&amp;rsquo;s considerable holdings for this subject, including the university&amp;#39;s role in this history, and displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Embodied Knowledge&lt;/i&gt; was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43979943702075/huge/4b99fe6cf60d8e2605435b9d2e7a7795a16ab6e3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="730683"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArcGIS Pro Quick Start (October 6th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Introduction to ArcGIS Pro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using ArcGIS Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloading and licensing through Stanford&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new Map Project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArcGIS Pro user interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loading and styling spatial data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis Tools (Spatial Joins, Overlay Analysis)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Map Layout and Exports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required:&lt;/b&gt; No installations required but all attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises. ArcGIS Pro is a Windows only application, but can be run from any laptop through the Stanford Virtual Computer Cluster (Apporto):&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.apporto.com"&gt;https://stanford.apporto.com&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/db92da69bdee4cae834ab36bc59ec358" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;ArcGIS Pro Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Open to current Stanford affiliates ONLY. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/arcgispro_autumn2023</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44316352230055/huge/73373f2c7b913f8ca602c83a539b4ed4652602f8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="355446"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VOICES TO BE HEARD, STORIES TO BE TOLD: Exploring the Dijkstra Black Music Collection at Stanford’s Archive of Recorded Sound</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tamar Barzel&lt;/b&gt;, head of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Music Library and Archive of Recorded Sound&lt;/i&gt;, will present an illustrated webinar on a recently acquired, transformative collection of historic vinyl records of African-American and Afro-diasporic music, especially jazz and reggae. The webinar will focus on the origins of the Dijkstra Collection, explore its gems, and consider the role sound archives play in preserving diverse sonic legacies for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tamar Barzel (PhD in Ethnomusicology, University of Michigan, 2004) came to Stanford in 2021 from New York University Libraries. She has taught at NYU, Harvard, and Wellesley College.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This event is sponsored by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/friends-of-music"&gt;Friends of Music at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/voices_to_be_heard_lecture</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43200823850481/huge/46c4f7d1845d1055899b5c6ad0e8328726fafcee.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="312" width="468" isDefault="true" fileSize="258253"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advantages of Reusable Data: Utilizing Social Science Datasets in Redivis at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data reuse, or secondary data analysis, is the analysis of existing data collected by other individuals or institutions for a new research purpose (&lt;a href="https://www.nnlm.gov/guides/data-glossary/data-reuse" target="_blank"&gt;National Library of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;). Data reuse is a resource-effective way to conduct novel research, discover new collaborators, and contribute to your academic field. In this workshop, we will learn about the advantages of reusable data and how to evaluate data for reuse. Then, we will apply these principles to Stanford Libraries&amp;rsquo; growing data collections, which are sourced from vendors like Gallup, Washington Post and CoreLogic. Finally, we will practice using basic SQL commands to query reusable data on the Redivis platform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/11219416" target="_blank"&gt;REGISTER NOW!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None. Please bring your own computer. It would be helpful before the class to &lt;a href="https://redivis.com/SUL" target="_blank"&gt;create a free Redivis account&lt;/a&gt; if you don&amp;rsquo;t already have one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Audience&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advanced undergraduate students, graduate students and postdocs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;Learning Objectives&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the end of the workshop, attendees will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply data quality criteria when considering a dataset for reuse&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Define &amp;ldquo;relational database&amp;rdquo; and explain their applications in research&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Recognize basic SQL keywords, such as SELECT, FROM, WHERE and JOIN&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/reusable_data</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44137673741924/huge/56112b67e6cddfdf69a69b483ae2097104e81553.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="52840"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bob Stein on The Tapestry Project at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Bob Stein as he leads a discussion on The Tapestry Project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s call it . . . the print era is officially over. We now live in a networked digital world. As a result everything is breaking and everything is being born anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New forms of expression are emerging. We may not know the specifics, but two aspects are coming into focus &amp;mdash; a) expository text is being dislodged as the principal medium of intellectual discourse and b) the creation and consumption of media are increasingly social activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, people need tools that foster collaboration &amp;mdash; finally realizing the vision of the internet&amp;rsquo;s founders who understood that the problems facing humanity are too complex for individuals to solve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tapestry Project answers this challenge with a paradigm-breaking new tool that anyone can use to construct a non-linear landscape of ideas and the connections between them &amp;mdash; a new form of writing which allows readers to interact directly with the author&amp;rsquo;s ideas and the sources they are based on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Stein was the founder of The Criterion Collection, The Voyager Company and The Institute for the Future of the Book. Currently, he heads up The Tapestry Project at the Internet Archive. In 2018 Bob donated his extensive analog and digital archives to Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bob_stein_on_the_tapestry_project</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42669238566991/huge/a8d42572f76f6496f6d7d59ac24e1d5e8f575f5b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="881" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="1139204"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abby Smith Rumsey: Memory, Edited at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a book talk with Abby Smith Rumsey who will discuss her recent publication, &lt;a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262048477/memory-edited/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Memory, Edited: Taking Liberties with History&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The book is an exploration of historical memory and networks of meaning in the context of today&amp;#39;s crises of extremism and polarization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Kg3VULC7jgs7wBxSA" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As authoritarianism continues to rise around the world, the stories we tell ourselves about what has happened and what is happening become ever more relevant. In &lt;i&gt;Memory, Edited&lt;/i&gt;, Abby Smith Rumsey examines collective memory, how it binds us, and how it can be used by bad actors to manipulate us. Bringing forward the voices of a rich cast of Eastern European artists from the past two hundred years&amp;mdash;from Fyodor Dostoevsky to Gerhard Richter&amp;mdash;Rumsey shows how their work and lives illustrate the devastation wrought by regimes dependent on entrenched lies to survive. This hijacking of the narrative polarizes communities even as it commandeers our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through an interdisciplinary lens that includes the best thinking from history, the arts, cognitive science, psychology, and political philosophy, Rumsey lays bare our narratives, showing how they are constructed and how they have changed over time. Ever-aware of resisting the false promise of utopia, Rumsey argues that only by confronting the past and reckoning with the crimes that were committed can we ever hope to heal and gain self-knowledge. &lt;i&gt;Memory, Edited&lt;/i&gt; is an indispensable text for anyone who cares about democracy, equality, and freedom in our current age of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://rumseywrites.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abby Smith Rumsey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an intellectual and cultural historian. She chairs the board of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University and is the author of &lt;i&gt;When We Are No More: How Digital Memory Is Shaping Our Future&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/memory_edited</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44033532455425/huge/c7989b913454674fda703c02e63b95a68e3a059f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1719" width="2357" isDefault="true" fileSize="1515469"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to QGIS (October 13th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Introduction to QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis and Map Construction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required: &lt;/b&gt;Attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises. We will cover QGIS installation during the workshop set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/stanford.edu/gis-online-workshops/intro-to-qgis?authuser=1" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Intro to QGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/QGIS-intro_oct13</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322833706183/huge/ebb814cb3fa3cd33ed0b0b16d49bd8705048b45e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1839312"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for October&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;. Theme and featured games will be announced closer to the event date!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_5542</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43466372701087/huge/dda6cb7978d1fd19b4659fc91fd2679563f31feb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="font-size:13.125px; font-style:normal; text-align:start"&gt;The conference, hosted by the David Rumsey Map Center and Barry Lawrence Ruderman Antique Maps, will focus on maps &amp;amp; data visualization.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Maps can communicate all kinds of information. While geographic features and toponyms are frequently highlighted, arraying information in a spatial layout has proven useful for centuries. Maps and data visualization go hand-in-hand, but in ways that are complex and deserve critical examination; this is why they are the focus of the fourth biennial Ruderman Conference on Cartography, held October 18-20, 2023 at the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford University. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Speakers from a variety of disciplinary backgrounds and specializations will share their expertise about historical, design, and digital applications of data visualization. Attendees will examine examples of maps that share information in a variety of ways and discuss the potential and limitations of the medium in the past, present, and for the future. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Keynote speakers include Michael Friendly (York University, Canada), who will discuss the history of data visualization, and Karen Lewis (the Ohio State University), who will share the mapping methodology and design behind the recovery of Underground Railway routes and stories.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/barry_lawrence_ruderman_conference_on_cartography</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43890725953540/huge/4219ec240fa19856c53741ec4c2b1bdc27215702.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1754" width="2357" isDefault="true" fileSize="1839021"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Raja Adal  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Raja Adal on October 19 in Hohbach Hall.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rethinking the Role of the Printing Press and Typewriter Outside of the World of Latin Characters: A Large-Scale Analysis of Writing and Reproduction Technologies in the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine Archive, 1889-1941&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few decades, the history of the book, of bureaucratic cultures, and of information societies has introduced us to the centrality of printing presses and typewriters in European and North American offices. This presentation explores the material history of writing outside of the world of Latin characters through the indexing of one of the largest business archives in modern Japan, the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine archive. Over several years, this indexing project ordered the 38,096 pages in this archive into 20,713 individual documents, categorized according to criteria that reveal the practice of document production, circulation, storage, and consumption in the offices of a large Japanese firm over the course of a half century from 1889 to 1941. Although the printing press and typewriter have a role in the offices of the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine, when we look not at discourses but at practices, it turns out that in a society in which most texts are composed of thousands of logographic and phonographic symbols, writing and reproduction technologies other than the printing press and typewriter are much more prominent. Through the large-scale analysis of the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine archive, this presentation begins to chart a theory of the practice of writing and reproduction, from the brush to Unicode, in the context of global scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_raja_adal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44031837526865/huge/74fc815b8e2c310c2c82bb8eff41501358945268.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1440" width="2560" isDefault="true" fileSize="1993381"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chip War: Book Talk with Chris Miller at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Chris Miller&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Tufts University) and &lt;b&gt;Stephen Kotkin&lt;/b&gt; on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chip War: The Fight for the World&amp;#39;s Most Critical Technology&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, military, economic, and geopolitical power are built on a foundation of computer chips. Virtually everything&amp;mdash;from missiles to microwaves, smartphones to the stock market&amp;mdash;runs on chips. Until recently, America designed and built the most advanced chips and used its control over computing power to maintain its lead as the world&amp;#39;s leading superpower. The Soviet Union--which designed and manufactured many of its most advanced semiconductors in the Baltic States--could never keep up. Now, America&amp;#39;s edge is slipping, undermined by competitors in Taiwan, Korea, Europe, and, above all, China. Today, China, which spends more money each year importing chips than it spends importing oil, is pouring billions into a chip-building initiative to catch up to the US, and using this to build a military that threatens Taiwan, the beating heart of the digital world. At stake is America&amp;#39;s military superiority and economic prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPEAKER:&amp;nbsp;Chris&amp;nbsp;Miller&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the author&amp;nbsp;of &amp;quot;Chip&amp;nbsp;War: The Fight for the World&amp;#39;s Most Critical Technology,&amp;quot; a geopolitical history&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;the computer&amp;nbsp;chip. He previously wrote three other books on Russia, including &amp;quot;Putinomics: Power and Money in Resurgent Russia;&amp;quot; &amp;quot;We Shall Be Masters: Russia&amp;#39;s Pivots to East Asia from Peter the Great to Putin;&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;The Struggle to Save the Soviet Economy: Mikhail Gorbachev and the Collapse&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;the USSR.&amp;quot; He also serves as Associate Professor&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;International History at Tufts University, where his research focuses on technology, geopolitics, economics, international affairs, and Russia. He has previously served as the Associate Director&amp;nbsp;of&amp;nbsp;the Brady-Johnson Program in Grand Strategy at Yale, a lecturer at the New Economic School in Moscow, a visiting researcher at the Carnegie Moscow Center, a research associate at the Brookings Institution, and as a fellow at the German Marshall Fund&amp;#39;s Transatlantic Academy. He received his PhD and MA from Yale University and his BA in history from Harvard University. For more information, see&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="http://www.christophermiller.net/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;www.christophermiller.net&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DISCUSSANT: Stephen Kotkin&lt;/b&gt; is&amp;nbsp;Kleinheinz Senior Fellow at Hoover Institution and&amp;nbsp;senior fellow at the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies (Stanford University).&amp;nbsp;He is also the Birkelund Professor in History and International Affairs emeritus at the Princeton School of Public and International Affairs (formerly the Woodrow Wilson School), where he taught for 33 years.&amp;nbsp;He earned his PhD at the University of California&amp;ndash;Berkeley and has been conducting research in the Hoover Library &amp;amp; Archives for more than three decades. Kotkin&amp;rsquo;s research encompasses geopolitics and authoritarian regimes in history and in the present.&amp;nbsp;His publications include&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Stalin: Waiting for Hitler, 1929&amp;ndash;1941&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Penguin, 2017) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Stalin: Paradoxes of Power, 1878&amp;ndash;1928&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(Penguin, 2014), two parts of a planned three-volume history of Russian power in the world and of Stalin&amp;rsquo;s power in Russia.&amp;nbsp;He has also written a history of the Stalin system&amp;rsquo;s rise from a street-level perspective,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Magnetic Mountain: Stalinism as a Civilization&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(University of California 1995); and a trilogy analyzing Communism&amp;rsquo;s demise, of which two volumes have appeared thus far:&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Armageddon Averted: The Soviet Collapse 1970&amp;ndash;2000&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(Oxford, 2001; rev. ed. 2008) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Uncivil Society: 1989 and the Implosion of the Communist&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Establishment&lt;/i&gt;, with a contribution by Jan T. Gross (Modern Library, 2009).&amp;nbsp;The third volume will be on the Soviet Union in the third world and Afghanistan.&amp;nbsp;Kotkin&amp;rsquo;s publications and public lectures also often focus on Communist China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/1JNr5XsjVEZqUEvD9"&gt;RSVP is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/chris-miller-chip-war</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322613413478/huge/0d35e5acdeeca128593c911368c1b4f78897c749.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="563" width="460" isDefault="true" fileSize="298430"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Coalition Alumni Panel at Green Library, East Wing, 1st floor Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join Stanford Libraries as we host what is sure to be an insightful discussion. Professor David Palumbo-Liu will moderate a panel of former activist alumni who were a part of the original Rainbow Coalition at Stanford. &amp;nbsp;Listen to their experience and learn how their activism changed Stanford as we know it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScBuILP5ZaIW5xbnImlrlvbHrDfsM7-PPy6-BktVK0XwRPu5Q/viewform" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;if you would like to attend the event &lt;b&gt;in person&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_a5d5LeyPSKCPhZdA4SNZrw" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;if you would like to attend the event &lt;b&gt;online&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is being held in conjunction with Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; 3rd annual &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/jedi2023" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and find out how you can get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following the fair in the same location from 3:30 to 5:30 pm, celebrate with us as we listen to selections from the recently acquired &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/stanford-libraries-receives-major-black-music-collection-supporting-new-department-and" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dijkstra Black Music Collection&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a vast collection of Black music on vinyl spanning a wide range of genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rainbow_coalition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44032895838931/huge/fc52b7b997689ee0d1c901c1ac1afb1768bc9700.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1276" width="2294" isDefault="true" fileSize="1434109"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Chris Clay, "Unstoppable" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Chris Clay as he discusses his father&amp;#39;s book, Unstoppable: The Unlikely Story of A Silicon Valley Godfather, on October 25, 2023. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Unstoppable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;explores the life of Roy L. Clay Sr. from his time as a teenager using his uncanny math skills to run back-room craps game in segregated, rural Missouri, to his rise as a Silicon Valley technology pioneer.&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;Unstoppable&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;has been featured by Stephen Curry&amp;#39;s Underrated Book Club, &lt;a href="https://www.usatoday.com/story/money/2023/06/07/silicon-valley-tech-black-history-roy-clay/70262081007/"&gt;USA Today&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.nbcbayarea.com/discover-black-heritage/roy-clay-the-story-of-the-black-godfather-of-silicon-valley/3150014/"&gt;NBC Bay Area&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.ktvu.com/video/1184381"&gt;Fox Bay Area&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chris Clay holds a B.S. in Electrical Engineering from University of California, Berkeley and an M.B.A. in Finance from UCLA&amp;rsquo;s Anderson Graduate School of Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After graduating from UCLA, Chris worked for 10 years as an Engineering leader at Rod-L Electronics, a company founded by his father, Roy Clay Sr. After Rod-L Electronics, Chris worked in Product Management, Marketing and Business Development at several other technology companies. Chris currently works as a business development leader for German based software company SAP. Chris is also the Managing Editor for Roy Clay Sr&amp;rsquo;s memoir, Unstoppable: The Unlikely Story of a Silicon Valley Godfather.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When not working, Chris enjoys a multitude of hobbies including music creation, cycling, tennis and golf.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_chris_clay_unstoppable</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44349981956243/huge/f95c078b438ce691cad58ad8b3d95d6fb5b6e4d8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="400" width="267" isDefault="true" fileSize="15506"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair at Centennial Green</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting its 3rd annual &lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and find out how you can get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following the fair in the same location from 3:30 to 5:30 pm, celebrate with us as we listen to selections from the recently acquired &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/stanford-libraries-receives-major-black-music-collection-supporting-new-department-and" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dijkstra Black Music Collection&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a vast collection of Black music on vinyl spanning a wide range of genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The day before, on &lt;b&gt;October 24 &lt;/b&gt;from 3:00 to 4:00 pm, join us for the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rainbow_coalition" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rainbow Coalition Alumni Panel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Professor David Palumbo-Liu will moderate a panel of former activist alumni who were a part of the original Rainbow Coalition at Stanford. Listen to their experience and learn how their activism changed Stanford as we know it today. Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/DUrvKkPURY3eEh5a9" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;register&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Check back for updates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jedi2023</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427136</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.168622</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40621750570646/huge/4fac2a857cffbbe07b7fa5dd9c09ed4ffc7c1db1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="181353"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (October 27th) at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required:&lt;/b&gt; Attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises. You will need to have a current version of QGIS installed and must have at least some experience using QGIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/e8d1d13ca8894643970f315d16010ee9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing_in_qgis_october_27th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322911531026/huge/cf7b6de46af2ee9ff10d458e77b6dcc52427c1df.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="101109"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Engine 101 (Nov 3,2023) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine 101: Introduction to Earth Engine for beginners&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Earth Engine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine &lt;/a&gt;is a geospatial processing service. With Earth Engine, you can perform geospatial processing at scale, powered by Google Cloud Platform. The purpose of Earth Engine is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive platform for geospatial algorithm development at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable high-impact, data-driven science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make substantive progress on global challenges that involve large geospatial datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine&lt;/a&gt; combines a multi-petabyte catalog of satellite imagery and geospatial datasets with planetary-scale analysis capabilities and makes it available for scientists, researchers, and developers to detect changes, map trends, and quantify differences on the Earth&amp;#39;s surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presenter: &lt;/b&gt;Stace Maples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that this workshop is for Stanford University affiliates, only.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description&lt;/b&gt;: The Earth Engine API (application programming interface) provides the ability to create your own algorithms to process raster and vector imagery. This session is geared toward people who would like to analyze satellite and vector data. The session will be hands-on, using the Earth Engine Javascript code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of the class will be an introduction to Remote Sensing, in general. The second half will&amp;nbsp;focus on introducing the Google Earth Engine Platform, and accessing imagery, creating composites, and running analyses over stacks of images, computing statistics on imagery, creating charts and exporting the results of your analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;No previous experience with Earth Engine or JavaScript is necessary for the beginner workshop, but programming experience, basic knowledge of remote sensing and/or GIS are highly desirable. Willingness to learn programming is required. Participants with no programming experience will require additional attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Access to Google Earth Engine Immediately!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are registering with a @Stanford.edu email address, it is possible that you already have access to Google Earth Engine, through the Stanford Geospatial Center&amp;#39;s collaboration with The Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability. You can test this by going to &lt;a href="https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb&lt;/a&gt; and logging in with your Stanford.edu credentials. The link should load a script that will produce a &amp;quot;Tanaka Hillshade&amp;quot; map of the terrain in the Yosemite Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you do not currently have access to Google Earth Engine, through your Stanford.edu credentials, please email &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:maples@stanford.edu"&gt;maples@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/b&gt;to request to be added to the Stanford Geospatial Center&amp;#39;s organizational GEE account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that we are only able to provide access to users with valid Stanford.edu credentials, and a fully sponsored SUNetID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides below are the same as those covered in the webinar video. You can open these slides in a separate widow in order to follow along and have access to the linked URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sample Scripts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have signed up for and received confirmation of your Google Earth Engine account, you can copy the script repository for this webinar by clicking on the following link, which will redirect you to the Google Earth Engine Code Editor and import a series of scripts designed to introduce you to the basic mechanics of working in Google Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/9f9NgB" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://goo.gl/9f9NgB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/google_earth_engine_101_nov_32023</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323412923648/huge/57a46e2861a7a56bdf31331bc5da314632a5300e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1307" width="1722" isDefault="true" fileSize="2541518"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GDAL/OGR, the Geospatial Data Abstraction Library at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL/OGR) is an open-source translator library for working with geospatial data. GDAL/OGR contains a variety of useful command line utilities that can be easier or more efficient to use than standalone GIS software or rolling your own code. In this workshop you will learn how to use GDAL to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect and query datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert data between different formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update and transform spatial reference systems (projections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clip and subset data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create tile indexes and mosaics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop website: &lt;a href="https://slides.com/staceymaples/handsonwithgdal"&gt;https://slides.com/staceymaples/handsonwithgdal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_gdalogr_the_geospatial_data_abstraction_library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323552354930/huge/4d7ee59211d8181e64884476addfe4a8764d22c4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1311252"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recoding America: Book Talk With Jennifer Pahlka at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Jennifer Pahlka &lt;/b&gt;(Code for America&lt;b&gt;)&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Ingrid Pappel&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(Tallinn University of Technology), and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Stanford University) on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recoding America: Why Government is Failing in the Digital Age and How We Can Do Better&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when we most need our government to work &amp;ndash; to decarbonize our infrastructure and economy, to help the vulnerable through a pandemic, to defend ourselves against global threats &amp;ndash; it is faltering. Government at all levels has limped into the digital age, offering online services that can feel even more cumbersome than the paperwork that preceded them and widening the gap between the policy outcomes we intend and what we get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not more money or more tech we need. Government is hamstrung by a rigid, industrial-era culture, in which elites dictate policy from on high, disconnected from and too often disdainful of the details of implementation. Lofty goals morph unrecognizably as they cascade through a complex hierarchy. But there is an approach taking hold that keeps pace with today&amp;rsquo;s world and reclaims government for the people it is supposed to serve. Jennifer Pahlka shows why we must stop trying to move the government we have today onto new technology and instead consider what it would mean to truly recode American government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPEAKER: Jennifer Pahlka&lt;/b&gt; is the author of &lt;a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250266774/recodingamerica"&gt;Recoding America: Why Government is Failing in the Digital Age and How We Can Do Better&lt;/a&gt;. She founded Code for America in 2010 and led the organization for ten years. In 2013, she took a leave of absence to serve as U.S. Deputy Chief Technology Officer under President Obama and helped found the United States Digital Service. She served on the Defense Innovation Board under Presidents Obama and Trump. At the start of the pandemic, she also co-founded United States Digital Response, which helps government meet the needs of the public with volunteer tech support. She received the Skoll Award for Social Entrepreneurship, and was named by Wired as one of the 25 people who has most shaped the past 25 years. Jennifer is a graduate of Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DISCUSSANT: Ingrid Pappel &lt;/b&gt;is the 2023 Global Digital Governance Fellow at Stanford University,&amp;nbsp;Associate Professor at the Department of Software Science and Vice-Dean for Master&amp;#39;s studies at the School of IT, Tallinn University of Technology. She has more than 20 years of experience in different development projects related to e-governance solutions in Estonia and abroad. She is the head of the Digi-State Technologies and Architecture research group, which addresses the complexity related to how governments can satisfy the demands of their citizens in times of need. Her research focuses on digital government ecosystems by investigating technologies that support digital transformation. Her research topics are related to the development activities in launching paperless management by creating interoperability with state registries and external and internal systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MODERATOR: Andrew J. Grotto&lt;/b&gt; is a William J. Perry International Security Fellow at the Cyber Policy Center and&amp;nbsp;a Research Fellow at the Hoover Institution, both at Stanford University. He is also Director of the&amp;nbsp;Program on Geopolitics, Technology, and Governance (FSI).&amp;nbsp;Grotto&amp;rsquo;s research interests center on the national security and international economic dimensions of America&amp;rsquo;s global leadership in information technology innovation, and its growing reliance on this innovation for its economic and social life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/CVscSgY3mbaawRrm9"&gt;RSVP is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jennifer-pahlka-recoding-america</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322743688727/huge/cecb82b54388a97cd4391b95fad7079f8978c9aa.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1899" width="1542" isDefault="true" fileSize="562453"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Henry Lowood, Replayed at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archies in welcoming Henry Lowood, the Harold C. Hohbach Curator for History of Science &amp;amp; Technology Collections, as he discusses his most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Replayed&lt;/i&gt;, on November 14, 2023.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the early 2000s, Henry Lowood has had a key role in initiatives devoted to the preservation and documentation of virtual worlds, digital games, and interactive simulations, establishing himself as a major scholar of game studies. Replayed offers Lowood&amp;rsquo;s far-flung and significant publications on these subjects in a single volume.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_henry_lowood_replayed</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44031985006928/huge/119a5a308f4be1b23e01bd2782fd90f3eb11c802.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="219" width="290" isDefault="true" fileSize="120474"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s New North?  Enduring stereotypes in the Nordic and Baltic regions at Encina Commons</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Daunis Auers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(University of Latvia) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Amir Weiner&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(Stanford University) on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Europe&amp;rsquo;s New North? &amp;nbsp;Enduring stereotypes in the Nordic and Baltic regions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stereotypes (deeply ingrained beliefs or assumptions) about nations are central to country images which in turn impact domestic economic developments and relations with other states. Stereotypes are also resistant to change and can become outdated and themselves stymie change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contemporary images of the three Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania and the five Nordic states of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway and Sweden present an interesting case study of the durability of stereotypes despite a radically changed reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three decades ago, the three Baltic states regained their sovereign independence following the collapse of the Soviet Union and started out on a path of democratic and economic development that would eventually lead them to accession to the European Union and NATO in 2004. Baltic-Nordic cooperation in the 1990s was quite intense and the initial expectation (and hope) on both sides of the Baltic Sea was that the Baltic states would gradually converge with the Nordic states, passively adopting &amp;ldquo;Nordic models&amp;rdquo; of democracy, economy and the welfare state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty years later, both Baltic and Nordic regions have changed drastically, although national stereotypes have barely shifted. This talk examines the radical transformations in politics, economics and culture in the Northern Europe and discusses why, despite these changes, stereotypes of the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; Nordics and the &amp;ldquo;shifty&amp;rdquo; Baltics persist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPEAKER: Daunis Auers&lt;/b&gt; is Professor of European Studies and Jean Monnet Chair at the University of Latvia, and serves as Director-at-large of the Association for the Advancement of Baltic Studies (AABS). He studied at the London School of Economics and defended his PhD at University College London. He has been a Fulbright Scholar at the University of California-Berkeley (2005-2006) and a Baltic-American Freedom Foundation Scholar at Wayne State University in Detroit (2014) and published widely on political parties, elections, referendums, populism and the radical right and economic competitiveness in the Baltic states. His book on The Comparative Government and Politics of the Baltic States: Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania in the 21st Century &amp;ndash; was published by Palgrave Macmillan in 2015. He is currently working on a monograph analyzing Nordic-Baltic integration and is a Fulbright program Visiting Professor at the University of Washington in Seattle during the fall and winter of 2023/2024.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DISCUSSANT: Amir Weiner&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;is Director of Stanford&amp;#39;s Center for Russian, East European, and Eurasian Studies and Associate Professor of Soviet History. Professor Weiner teaches and writes on totalitarian movements and regimes with a focus on the Soviet polity; population politics; the Second World War; and modern mass violence. His current research is on the KGB and the Soviet surveillance state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Nq94qHjW6cqh6Dna8"&gt;RSVP is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/europes-new-north-daunis-auers</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426792</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.164842</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44341897853465/huge/0ba80a797f361c8bb369a5c8b513232c7b883e7f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="532" width="800" isDefault="true" fileSize="58818"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for November&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;. Theme and featured games will be announced closer to the event date!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_625</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43466372701087/huge/dda6cb7978d1fd19b4659fc91fd2679563f31feb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
