<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>To Trust or Not to Trust: Authenticity by Design at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is at an inflection point. With the growth of mis/disinformation, artificial intelligence and synthetic media, trust in information faces unprecedented threats. Authenticity is not guaranteed. At the same time, new technologies–referred to as “Web 3”–present opportunities to protect the integrity of data. These solutions can be applied to critical practices including investigative journalism, historical archiving, and the admissibility of legal evidence. This exhibit, curated by the &lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/"&gt;Starling Lab for Data Integrity&lt;/a&gt;, asks: How might we design information systems for authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Joshua Roberts/Reuters, “Day 69" (&lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/78daysarchive/"&gt;78 Days Archive&lt;/a&gt;), January 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-authenticity-by-design</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47436587901093/huge/641630e9442e946525a91d66b21735740fa8d98c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="475" width="718" isDefault="true" fileSize="492778"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;黛文洵美：山水記憶&lt;br&gt;
Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford Libraries, the East Asia Library, and the Center for East Asian Studies. Organized and guest curated by Beryl Zhou, graduate student, Center for East Asian Studies, and Ellen Huang, Ph.D, distinguished practitioner at the Center for East Asian Studies and associate professor of art history and material culture at ArtCenter College of Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanghai-born artist Victoria Yau (1939–2023) created around 300 works of abstract ink paintings, watercolors, multimedia collages, prints, and textiles after she moved to the United States from Taipei. These artworks, spanning nearly half a century of art-making in Chicago, New York and the Southwest, testify to her commitment to abstraction and investment in material experimentation. Featuring a selection of works in a range of media—and complemented by the artist’s own writings, collections, and poetry—this exhibition asks viewers to consider the transformation of East Asian landscape painting from compositional structure into abbreviated form emphasizing texture and line. Gathered together here for the first time since her passing, the works and texts on display explore how Yau negotiated disparate experiences of geopolitical flux, immigration, and physical struggle throughout her seventy-year career. Modern in their simplicity but complex in their historical and international references, Victoria Yau’s mountain clouds, her own poetic reworking of the historical term for landscape painting, “mountain-water 山水,” signal the intricacies of international contemporary art through the vantage of an Asian diasporic woman artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/victoria-yau-i-slept-in-the-mountain-cloud</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46252014368895/huge/6eb4274218d52cea507377e8acbd22c97908c505.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="839" width="838" isDefault="true" fileSize="552389"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whodunnit? Mystery and Detective Fiction at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whodunnit? Come find out in Green Library, with the Mystery and Detective Fiction book display in October.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/whodunnit-mystery-and-detective-fiction</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47668685945615/huge/9c8ec6a1f640e0bc26d59ebd0a675804ac2e37e8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1344" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="121285"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCRABrraaNNG! The Explosion of Futurist Poetry at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Bowes Library’s Autumn 2024 exhibition, &lt;i&gt;SCRABrrRrraaNNG! The Explosion of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Futurist Poetry&lt;/i&gt;, explores the unique history of Italian Futurist poetry during its first period (1909-1918). Futurism, founded by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti in 1909, was a leading avant-garde movement in Europe that rejected history and tradition in the name of technology, dynamism, and violence. In 1912, Marinetti declared war on his Symbolist predecessors, inventing a new form of poetics that tested the limits of typography and aimed to shock readers with obliterated syntax, onomatopoeias, and word-images. On display are featured items from Bowes and Green Libraries' Special Collections, as well as the Futurist Archive's private collection, including Marinetti's seminal work of "words-in-freedom,"&lt;i&gt;Zang&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tumb Tuuum&lt;/i&gt; (1914), and several first editions by other Futurist poets. Curated by Ty Davidian, PhD Candidate in Italian. Sponsored by the Department of French and Italian and the Division of Literatures, Cultures, and Languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Library hours: M-Th 9-7pm, Friday 9-5pm, Sunday 12-6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/scrabrraanng-the-explosion-of-futurist-poetry</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47634195743312/huge/d56ba229f75b9d12e064fe23910675ed8db55420.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1200" width="1800" isDefault="true" fileSize="1492270"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Deal &amp; The Federal Writers' Project at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-UT_h28D9ylo9I3qEOfJJXmbaL_Ol8wq4VIw_k6PEU4/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New Deal &amp;amp; The Federal Writers' Project | Selections from the Bruce and Rachel Jeffer Collection&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view May 6, 2024, through January 26, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by childhood automobile trips across the U.S. with his father and a lifelong love of American history and literature, Los Angeles attorney Bruce Jeffer assembled a magnificent collection—totaling nearly two thousand titles—of the Federal Writers’ Project and related WPA and New Deal publications. He and his wife Rachel gifted it to the Stanford Libraries Department of Special Collections in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created as a New Deal program within the Works Progress Administration in 1935, the Federal Writers’ Project (Federal Writers’ Program 1939–1943) employed as many as six thousand writers, researchers, and editors in fifty-two state and territorial offices and produced a prodigious number of publications—including the American Guide Series, oral histories, ethnographies, collections of folklore and books for children—well over one thousand, but likely many more: the exact number is unknowable, and new discoveries have surfaced in the wake of each successive bibliography. Over sixty years, Jeffer’s passion for collecting the output of the Federal Writers’ Project and its offshoots brought him into contact with the foremost antiquarian book dealers of the day, former Writers’ Project employees, and leading collectors across the United States. With his wife Rachel, he made great use of auctions, eBay, and trades with other notable collectors and dealers. Through the decades, he searched for these publications by visiting bookstores in towns and cities around the country, directly contacting booksellers, and later maintaining a private network of like-minded collectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two core influences in Jeffer’s collecting activities were his close relationship with collector Fred Board of Connecticut and collector/book dealer Arthur Scharf of Pennsylvania. Board’s own collection of the State Guides (apart from his larger FWP collection) later served as an inspiration to his great-nephew Scott Borchert, which led Borchert to write his recent excellent history of the Project, &lt;i&gt;Republic of Detours: How the New Deal Paid Broke Writers to Rediscover America&lt;/i&gt; (New York, 2021). Besides selling and trading, Arthur Scharf was a source of bibliographic information on the FWP publications. Like most serious collectors of the FWP, when Evanell Powell self-published her ambitious (if amateur) WPA Writers’ Publication: &lt;i&gt;A complete bibliographic checklist… of items, major and minor, of the Federal Writers' Project and Program&lt;/i&gt; (Palm Beach, 1974), Jeffer took advantage of the information there to hunt for more titles—and to find many titles unknown to Powell, historians, and scholars. Of the over twelve hundred published FWP titles in the Jeffer collection, approximately one hundred and fifty FWP items were unknown to Powell and historians, thus representing an excellent opportunity for further research. The presence of sixteen original, unpublished FWP works adds significantly to the prospects for research in the collection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collecting the often ephemeral publications that characterized the richness and diversity, as well as controversy, of the project’s output, Jeffer has been guided by a desire to document this seminal period in American history, preserve it for posterity, and make it broadly available to students and researchers. In addition to rare published items, Jeffer sought out unpublished material as well—always with an eye for unique material that, in the words of one FWP catalog, embodied the project’s mission of “presenting America to all Americans.”  His collection contains copies of a number of exceedingly scarce titles, typescripts of unpublished works, and presentation copies gifted to New Deal luminaries such as Harry L. Hopkins, as well as publications from allied agencies such as the Federal Art Project, the Museum Extension Project, the Federal Theatre Project, and the Federal Music Project.  &lt;br&gt;
As demonstrated throughout the exhibit, The FWP’s lasting influence on literary and ethnographic work since the 1930s is strong, and the cultural resonance of the project continues unabated—including serving as the inspiration for a proposed twenty-first-century FWP, congressional legislation (Bill # HR 3054) introduced during the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2021 by Reps. Ted Lieu (D-CA and Stanford, B.A., B.S., '91) and Teresa Leger Fernandez (D-NM).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Benjamin Stone, Associate Director of Special Collections and Curator for American and British History; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their expert cataloging of books and manuscripts: Nancy Lorimer, Kay Teel, and their staff in the Metadata Department; For their assessment of materials Kristen St. John and Kimberly Kwan in Conservation Services; For his photography services Wayne Vanderkuil in the Digital Production Group; Glynn Edwards, Ann Myers, Brian Bethel, Gurudarshan Khalsa and especially Esther Wan in the Collection Services division of the Department of Special Collections, and Ben Albritton and Ever Rodriguez in Rare Books, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-deal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46210554145667/huge/5835b820fcd4b2c26aeb7ed65aab8559a0126e81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="71541"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Oct. 2 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-6521</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Naturally Hazardous: Volcanoes at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection presents an exhibit series: Naturally Hazardous&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the cosmically unavoidable to the anthropogenically-induced, Earth can be naturally hazardous to humans. In the 2024-25 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature the science and impact of volcanoes, wildfires, drought, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
September 16 - October 31: Explore the science of volcanism and volcanic hazard mitigation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  The exhibit is available for viewing throughout the month during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Oct 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-volcanoes</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47509450814326/huge/22c3f6833f80dba80122474944e7643d1342d5ea.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="540" width="540" isDefault="true" fileSize="114797"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Python at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop provides an introduction to the Python programming language, covering basic syntax, variables, functions, and control flow. You will learn enough Python to write basic scripts, and to allow you to explore the rich environment of Python packages available. Prior experience with programming in another language is helpful, but not required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-python</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47562910339286/huge/f3120492016397d771ae86963ab625f9647930b4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="59174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: The Supernatural at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Special, Unique, and Rare returns to Green Library on &lt;b&gt;Tuesday, October 8th&lt;/b&gt;, with &lt;b&gt;THE SUPERNATURAL&lt;/b&gt;.  Drop by &lt;b&gt;Hohbach 123 (Silicon Valley Archive classroom)&lt;/b&gt; any time between&lt;b&gt; 2-4 PM&lt;/b&gt; to see a curated popup exhibit of items that celebrate the start of spooky season: magic spells, first editions of classic horror tales, vintage film lobby cards, stunningly illustrated fairytales from all over the world, and more -- all from Stanford Libraries' collections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-supernatural</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47667608753249/huge/9e20b6edc8b815ff1aa8a9bd2e95eacbf1f95cee.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2043" width="2345" isDefault="true" fileSize="2091565"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Supernatural: A Spooky Popup at Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;On Wednesday, October 9th, from 1-4 pm stop by Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library to see a selection of magical, paranormal, and psychic works, including a collaged novel by Max Ernst from 1934. The featured works are from our Locked Stacks collection.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/supernatural-a-spooky-popup-at-bowes-art-architecture-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47633999060061/huge/154d276f940aaeb1c9e33a366890bbc5befe1f81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="1545" isDefault="true" fileSize="5845944"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing without labels: Applied AI at the National Library of Sweden at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While the digital archives of memory institutions have expanded exponentially in recent years, much of this material remains inaccessible. With the advent of mass digitization programs and the ever-increasing flow of incoming born digital material, the range and extent of digital heritage collections has grown enormously over the past two decades. However, due to a constellation of factors – from copyright restrictions and data protection regulation to outdated technical systems – it can often prove surprisingly difficult for researchers and the wider public to access and make use of these collections. Digitally collected does not simply equate to digitally available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can AI be used to improve this accessibility? This talk presents the work of KBLab, data lab at the &lt;a href="https://www.kb.se/in-english.html"&gt;National Library of Sweden&lt;/a&gt; (KB), in applying AI models trained at the library as a means of enhancing accessibility to the library’s digital collections. In the first part, we explain how and why KBLab has established itself as a key actor in the training of new Swedish AI models based on the library’s collections. In the second part, we offer a case study showing how these models can be applied to making parts of the collections currently lacking metadata searchable for researchers and users at large. More precisely, we present an example of how multimodal AI can be applied as the basis for an image search system to search and analyze large image collections, based upon the following demo: &lt;a href="https://lab.kb.se/bildsok/"&gt;https://lab.kb.se/bildsok/&lt;/a&gt;. We conclude with some broader reflections on the possibilities and challenges of establishing an AI-based infrastructure, including the potential for new organizational configurations to aid further exploration about the role of AI at the library.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;KBLab&lt;/b&gt; is a national infrastructure for digital research at the National Library of Sweden. Read more about our development projects within AI and data science on our &lt;a href="https://kb-labb.github.io/"&gt;blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Love Börjeson&lt;/b&gt; is director at KBLab and responsible for R&amp;amp;D at KB, as well as an affiliated researcher in applied language technology at The Stockholm School of Economics Institute for Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chris Haffenden&lt;/b&gt; is research coordinator at KBLab and affiliated researcher at the Department of the History of Science and Ideas, Uppsala University.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/seeing-without-labels-applied-ai-at-the-national-library-of-sweden</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47596315802867/huge/1d3dcf3b5ae9032c8d54a4476fc4c20fe1fb0536.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1094" width="1129" isDefault="true" fileSize="322902"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (Oct 10th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required:&lt;/b&gt; Attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises. You will need to have a current version of QGIS installed and must have at least some experience using QGIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/e8d1d13ca8894643970f315d16010ee9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing-in-qgis-oct-1th</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45863702407160/huge/964cf05ac7de6cba8ae54b7686bd7cc804625eb5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="101089"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to R at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This introductory workshop is geared towards those who would like to get started with R or need to brush up on their skills. You will learn how to use R, RStudio, how to create objects in R, how to work with different data types, how to read tabular data into R and how to subset tables.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-intro/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Workshop materials avaialble at this link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-r</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47562682430835/huge/68620308a78ef167eb0bca6bd5e52aa5f143fe40.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="59174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Jason Schreier, "Play Nice: The Rise, Fall, and Future of Blizzard Entertainment" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jason Schreier as he discusses &lt;i&gt;Play Nice: The Rise, Fall, and Future of Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/i&gt; on October 14, 2024. &lt;a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/jason-schreier/play-nice/9781538725429/?lens=grand-central-publishing"&gt;A copy of &lt;i&gt;Play Nice &lt;/i&gt;can be purchased using this link&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For video game fans, the name Blizzard Entertainment was once synonymous with perfection. The renowned company celebrated the joy of gaming over all else, and every product it released was an instant classic: StarCraft, Diablo, Overwatch, Hearthstone, and World of Warcraft, which forever changed the video game landscape. What was once two UCLA students' simple mission — to make games they wanted to play — launched an empire with thousands of employees, millions of fans, and billions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when Blizzard cancelled a buzzy project in 2013, it gave Bobby Kotick, the infamous CEO of corporate parent Activision, the excuse he needed to start cracking down on Blizzard's proud autonomy. Led by executives from McKinsey and Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, Activision began invading Blizzard from the inside, driving away throngs of key employees in a push for predictability over creativity. Glitchy products, PR disasters, and mass layoffs followed, marring the company’s once pristine image. In 2021, the state of California filed a staggering lawsuit against the company for sexual misconduct and discrimination, leading to a widespread reckoning and a $69 billion acquisition that sent shockwaves through the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on firsthand interviews with more than 300 current and former employees, PLAY NICE chronicles the creativity, frustration, beauty, and betrayal across the epic 33-year saga of Blizzard Entertainment — and explores the delight and despair of what it really means to "bleed Blizzard blue." Full of colorful personalities and dramatic twists, PLAY NICE is The Social Network for the video game industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABOUT THE AUTHOR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Schreier is the New York Times bestselling author of Press Reset and Blood, Sweat, and Pixels and a reporter at Bloomberg News, where he covers the video game industry. He lives in Westchester, New York with his wife and two children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jason-schreier-press-play-the-rise-fall-and-future-of-blizzard-entertainment</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46676503105277/huge/817c4038d6199c955ba7aa5bb39f440cd4faca45.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2201" width="2400" isDefault="true" fileSize="498418"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Zotero at Building 200, History Corner</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is a basic introduction to the free reference management software, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.zotero.org/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zotero&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;. Attendees will learn how to use Zotero to organize their research, create citations, separate their research into different projects or chapters, and connect Zotero to their web browsers for citations. Zotero can help create an environment where your research is organized into one place.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is suitable for beginners to Zotero, including undergraduates, graduate students, and faculty.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-zotero</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427405</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.1697</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47562783006238/huge/d83e214ca1a1b8844d86f2e8c3031b3b28da55c2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="59174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: October 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-october-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Weyodi Oldbear, "As Many Ships as Stars"  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;You are invited to join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming game designer and author Weyodi Old Bear as she discuss her latest book, &lt;i&gt;As Many Ships as Stars&lt;/i&gt;, on October 16, 2024. This event is virtual and requires an RSVP. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weyodi OldBear’s book,&lt;i&gt; As Many Ships As Stars&lt;/i&gt;, is a science fiction retelling of the oral tradition of Comanche horse acquisition. Set in the future the story details how modern characters Indigenize space, essentially transforming themselves to be more traditionally Comanche the more futuristic their lives become. She will discuss the story and the impetus behind its writing and give a short reading from the book, followed by a question and answer period. &lt;a href="https://pt.android-press.com/product-page/as-many-ships-as-stars-paperback"&gt;A copy of the book may be purchased here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weyodi OldBear is a voting citizen of the Comanche Nation who has been writing on a daily basis since she was 7 years old. She is disabled in a seizures and can't see much out of one eye sort of way. She writes from a Numunu (Comanche) perspective because that is her original factory setting. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-weyodi-old-bear-as-many-ships-as-stars</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47383754676224/huge/2988106e6e09cd001cc5e1ec900020b09f29ce1f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3264" width="2448" isDefault="true" fileSize="1115552"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Data Visualization in R</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to working with the ggplot2 visualization library in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! For a more foundational introduction to R, consider attending &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-r"&gt;Introduction to R&lt;/a&gt; (an in-person event) on October 10, 2024. By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate 1D and 2D plots, and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/9oEYHisKrnMCoiMHA"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. This workshop is open exclusively to current Stanford affiliates, and registration will be on a first-come, first-served basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your SUNet ID to access the registration form.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location: Virtual (A zoom link will be sent to registrants one week before the event.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date and Time: 1:00 PM to 4:00 PM, Wednesday, October 16, 2024&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Earth Sciences Library&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries-stanford-data-visualization-in-r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47634091972272/huge/8d6743108f368e35283ea99944b2a747222649f1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="486443"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Engine 101 (Wednesday, October 16th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine 101: Introduction to Earth Engine for beginners&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Earth Engine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine &lt;/a&gt;is a geospatial processing service. With Earth Engine, you can perform geospatial processing at scale, powered by Google Cloud Platform. The purpose of Earth Engine is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive platform for geospatial algorithm development at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable high-impact, data-driven science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make substantive progress on global challenges that involve large geospatial datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine&lt;/a&gt; combines a multi-petabyte catalog of satellite imagery and geospatial datasets with planetary-scale analysis capabilities and makes it available for scientists, researchers, and developers to detect changes, map trends, and quantify differences on the Earth's surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presenter: &lt;/b&gt;Stace Maples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that this workshop is for Stanford University affiliates, only. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description&lt;/b&gt;: The Earth Engine API (application programming interface) provides the ability to create your own algorithms to process raster and vector imagery. This session is geared toward people who would like to analyze satellite and vector data. The session will be hands-on, using the Earth Engine Javascript code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of the class will be an introduction to Remote Sensing, in general. The second half will focus on introducing the Google Earth Engine Platform, and accessing imagery, creating composites, and running analyses over stacks of images, computing statistics on imagery, creating charts and exporting the results of your analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;No previous experience with Earth Engine or JavaScript is necessary for the beginner workshop, but programming experience, basic knowledge of remote sensing and/or GIS are highly desirable. Willingness to learn programming is required. Participants with no programming experience will require additional attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Access to Google Earth Engine Immediately!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are registering with a @Stanford.edu email address, it is possible that you already have access to Google Earth Engine, through the Stanford Geospatial Center's collaboration with The Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability. You can test this by going to &lt;a href="https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb&lt;/a&gt; and logging in with your Stanford.edu credentials. The link should load a script that will produce a "Tanaka Hillshade" map of the terrain in the Yosemite Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you do not currently have access to Google Earth Engine, through your Stanford.edu credentials, please email &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:maples@stanford.edu"&gt;maples@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/b&gt;to request to be added to the Stanford Geospatial Center's organizational GEE account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that we are only able to provide access to users with valid Stanford.edu credentials, and a fully sponsored SUNetID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides below are the same as those covered in the webinar video. You can open these slides in a separate widow in order to follow along and have access to the linked URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sample Scripts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have signed up for and received confirmation of your Google Earth Engine account, you can copy the script repository for this webinar by clicking on the following link, which will redirect you to the Google Earth Engine Code Editor and import a series of scripts designed to introduce you to the basic mechanics of working in Google Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/9f9NgB" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://goo.gl/9f9NgB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/google_earth_engine_101_feb_16_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323412923648/huge/57a46e2861a7a56bdf31331bc5da314632a5300e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1307" width="1722" isDefault="true" fileSize="2541518"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to QGIS (Oct 17th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Introduction to QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis and Map Construction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required: Attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises&lt;/b&gt;. We will cover QGIS installation during the workshop set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/stanford.edu/gis-online-workshops/intro-to-qgis?authuser=1" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Intro to QGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 09:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/QGIS-intro</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322833706183/huge/ebb814cb3fa3cd33ed0b0b16d49bd8705048b45e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1839312"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Manipulation with Pandas at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;DataFrame&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;You should be familiar with basic Python syntax and fundamental programming concepts such as variables, functions, and control flow. If you need a refresher, check out A Byte of Python (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://python.swaroopch.com/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-manipulation-with-pandas</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47562833510445/huge/2a2fc6ca19f13e87d375a74279e2c9482c1e12d3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="59174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Whatever Victory Takes: The Lithuanian Perspective on Russia’s War against Ukraine and Transatlantic Security at Encina Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Ambassador of Lithuania to the United States Audra Plepytė and Director of the Freeman-Spogli Institute Michael McFaul on Russia’s war against Ukraine, its global implications, and transatlantic support to Ukraine:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Whatever Victory Takes: The Lithuanian Perspective on Russia’s War against Ukraine and Transatlantic Security&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As we are nearing 1,000 days of Russia’s full-scale war against Ukraine, the debate in Washington, D.C., and European capitals remains on what Ukraine can and cannot do to defend itself, its territory, and the whole democratic world. Lithuania has been among the most vocal supporters of Ukraine advocating that instead of Western commitments to stand with Ukraine as long as it takes, commitment to Ukraine’s victory is needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will feature a discussion on what is at stake in Russia’s war on Ukraine and why it matters beyond Ukraine and Europe. Ambassador Plepytė and Professor McFaul will discuss security on NATO’s Eastern flank, Western strategy for Ukraine, and the U.S. role in standing up to the new ‘axis of evil’ in defense of democracy and the free world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Ambassador &lt;b&gt;Audra Plepytė&lt;/b&gt; was appointed as Lithuania’s Ambassador to the United States of America and to the United Mexican States in 2021. Before this she was a Lithuanian Permanent Representative to the United Nations where she facilitated several negotiations, led the Group of Friends, and was elected to executive bodies of UN instruments and institutions, including being elected as the President of the Executive Board of the United Nations Children’s Fund (UNICEF) in 2021. As a career diplomat for over 30 years, she has held numerous positions within the Lithuanian Ministry of Foreign Affairs, dealing with bilateral and multilateral issues, heading the European Union Department (2014–2017), the Personnel Department, and International Missions and Conflict Prevention Division. She was also &lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lithuania’s ambassador to Spain, World Tourism Organization from 2010 till 2014.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael McFaul&lt;/b&gt; is Director at the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies, the Ken Olivier and Angela Nomellini Professor of International Studies in the Department of Political Science, and the Peter and Helen Bing Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1995. He served for five years in the Obama administration, first as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Russian and Eurasian Affairs at the National Security Council at the White House (2009-2012), and then as U.S. Ambassador to the Russian Federation (2012-2014).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Opening remarks will be delivered by &lt;b&gt;Michael Keller&lt;/b&gt;, Vice Provost and University Librarian.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This in-person event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://info-fsi.stanford.edu/acton/fs/blocks/showLandingPage/a/19053/p/p-004f/t/page/fm/0"&gt;Registration is required.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/whatever-victory-takes</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427319</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.164625</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47545305782291/huge/acd08f40e98073fd1f96e06cf79212b5348576f3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1155" width="1233" isDefault="true" fileSize="485919"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planetscope Satellite Imagery 101 at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real-Time Satellite Monitoring with Planet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With roughly 200 Dove satellites in orbit, &lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/products/monitoring/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;PlanetScope Monitoring&lt;/a&gt; provides a high-resolution, continuous, and complete view of the world from above, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planet Monitoring provides 3.7 meter resolution images of the entire Earth daily. Access to these ready-to-use images is made simple with Planet’s APIs, web application, and GIS integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for an Introduction to Planetscope Daily Imagery. This event is designed for those keen on advancing their understanding of leveraging Planetscope Imagery, at scale, for research and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll begin with an overview of Planetscope, and how to get access. Then we'll shift to a hands on demonstration of the Planetscope Explorer, for searching and ordering Planet.com imagery. Finally, we'll introduce the Data &amp;amp; Orders APIs from Planet.com, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Attendees should arrive with their own laptops if they wish to participate. Compters will not be provided. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/plnetscope_satellite_imagery_101</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45571105672451/huge/29be13abdea7542ef11faa86d069bcc5bdb0f976.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="79561"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Justice &amp; Equity in Food &amp; Agriculture</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Please join Stanford University Libraries for a webinar on &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justice &amp;amp; Equity in Food &amp;amp; Agriculture&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;b&gt;Karli A. Moore (Lumbee)&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Jocelyn Breeland&lt;/b&gt; will discuss the issues around food/agricultural security and equity that Indigenous communities and Black farmers are facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Karli A. Moore (Lumbee), PhD Candidate Environment and Resources, Knight-Hennessy Scholar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Moving Towards Indigenous Food Sovereignty&lt;/i&gt; – Indigenous communities and Tribal nations sharing borders with the United States are working hard to create healthy, thriving food systems. Unfortunately, structural, economic, and societal barriers make it difficult to exercise food sovereignty. We'll talk about a number of pressing issues and folks working for solutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Karli grew up on a family farm near Prospect, NC, and aspires to advance food sovereignty and economic development for Native peoples through sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jocelyn Breeland, Chief Communications and Marketing Officer for Residential &amp;amp; Dining Enterprise&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Black Farmers: Together Toward Justice and Equity&lt;/i&gt; – The Black Farmers Initiative, led by R&amp;amp;DE’s Stanford Food Institute and Oakland-based partner Farms to Grow, Inc., works with farmers and distributors to reverse the effects of generations of racism by helping Black Farmers enjoy the same support and market access as other farmers. In this session, Jocelyn will outline the Black Farmers Initiative, discuss the discrimination Black farmers still face today, and the ways the initiative is successfully advancing toward equity and justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Jocelyn is a member of the 2023 and 2024 Stanford IDEAL Honor Rolls. She is also an alumna of Stanford University, with a Bachelor of Arts in International Relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive a Zoom link for the webinar, please&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_jUk9ETtjQ-ejGXYHNBcb6A"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is being held in conjunction with Stanford Libraries' 4th annual &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice-equity-diversity-and-inclusion-jedi-fair" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and learn how to get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-insecurities</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47618809504827/huge/7de0e1e6966b43bd4abc7b647da038c28a1da346.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="349868"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Circling the Square: How Geometrical and Administrative Mapping Intersected in Seventeenth-Century Eurasia at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the historiography of East Asian cartography, maps produced by Jesuit missionaries to China have played a prominent role. It is often assumed that Jesuits successfully transmitted ‘scientific cartography’ from Europe to China, so that the question of the impact of their maps on cartography in East Asia has stood central in the literature. This talk problematizes this approach by reconstructing the intellectual, social, and material landscapes that informed the meeting of two vastly different modes of mapping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecture will be given by distinguished map scholar Mario Cams, an Associate Professor of Chinese Studies at KU Leuven in the Netherlands. Professor Cams is a historian of science who specializes in cartographic exchange between Europe and China in the 16th-17th centuries. He conducts research in multiple languages, including Chinese, Latin, French, German, and English, and he stresses the importance of social networks and physical objects in map history. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please register in advance to attend.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/circling-the-square-how-geometrical-and-administrative-mapping-intersected-in-seventeenth-century-eurasia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47607062999103/huge/cd1ef302cbdf3bf482c366947bb631c4bcad052f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2475" width="2465" isDefault="true" fileSize="2681684"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair at Green Library, East wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting its 4th annual &lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and find out how you can get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Check back for updates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The day before, on &lt;b&gt;October 29 &lt;/b&gt;from 12:00 to 1:00 pm, join us for a webinar on &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-insecurities"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justice &amp;amp; Equity in Food &amp;amp; Agriculture&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;b&gt;Karli A. Moore (Lumbee)&lt;/b&gt;, PhD Candidate in Environment and Resources, and &lt;b&gt;Jocelyn Breeland, &lt;/b&gt;Chief Communications and Marketing Officer for&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Residential &amp;amp; Dining Enterprises (R&amp;amp;DE) will discuss the issues around food/agricultural security and equity that the communities they are working with are facing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Karli A. Moore (Lumbee), PhD&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Moving Towards Indigenous Food Sovereignty&lt;/i&gt; – Indigenous communities and Tribal nations sharing borders with the United States are working hard to create healthy, thriving food systems. Unfortunately, structural, economic, and societal barriers make it difficult to exercise food sovereignty. We'll talk about a number of pressing issues and folks working for solutions. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Karli A. Moore grew up on a family farm near Prospect, NC, and aspires to advance food sovereignty and economic development for Native peoples through sustainable agriculture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jocelyn Breeland&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;Black Farmers: Together Toward Justice and Equity&lt;/i&gt; – In this session, Jocelyn Breeland will outline the Black Farmers Initiative, the discrimination Black farmers still face today, and the ways the initiative is successfully advancing toward equity and justice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jocelyn is a member of the 2023 and 2024 Stanford IDEAL Honor Rolls. She is also an alumna of Stanford University, with a Bachelor of Arts in International Relations. She and her full-service, in-house team support R&amp;amp;DE by developing and implementing strategic plans to engage campus audiences, promote the many services R&amp;amp;DE provides for the campus, and share the results of groundbreaking R&amp;amp;DE research and innovation, such as the Black Farmers Initiative.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To receive a Zoom link for the webinar, please&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_jUk9ETtjQ-ejGXYHNBcb6A"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice-equity-diversity-and-inclusion-jedi-fair</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47554531974933/huge/10a9eafb77d5e6c193ef6d1ecdd7239aa5cae093.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="170443"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GDAL/OGR, the Geospatial Data Abstraction Library at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL/OGR) is an open-source translator library for working with geospatial data. GDAL/OGR contains a variety of useful command line utilities that can be easier or more efficient to use than standalone GIS software or rolling your own code. In this workshop you will learn how to use GDAL to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect and query datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert data between different formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update and transform spatial reference systems (projections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clip and subset data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create tile indexes and mosaics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop website: &lt;a href="https://slides.com/staceymaples/handsonwithgdal"&gt;https://slides.com/staceymaples/handsonwithgdal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_gdalogr_the_geospatial_data_abstraction_library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323552354930/huge/4d7ee59211d8181e64884476addfe4a8764d22c4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1311252"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>She Rises Up: Documentary Film Screening at Traitel Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Stanford University Libraries are pleased to host a special in-person screening of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;She Rises Up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;a new documentary feature film from Maureen Castle Tusty and James Tusty&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;She Rises Up&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; chronicles the remarkable journeys of three women who are helping to lift their communities out of poverty through the local businesses they fight the odds to maintain. This documentary reveals the explosive implications of women's economic participation as we follow radically different women from Sri Lanka, Peru, and Senegal who are fighting to build businesses that create job opportunities for women, while also contributing to the reduction of poverty in their communities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EOidW9NJmhA" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;View the trailer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;She Rises Up &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sherisesupfilm.com/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;learn more about the film&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The event will take place on Friday, November 1st, 2024 at the Hauck Auditorium in the Hoover Traitel Building. A panel discussion and reception to follow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Schedule&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;3 - 5 pm: Film Screening &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;5 - 6 pm: Panel Discussion&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;6 - 8 pm: Reception with appetizers and non-alcoholic beverages&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The event is free and open to the public, but registration is required to attend. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please use the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/95Wd8LrgHiuZu9MC7" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;RSVP Form&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; to register.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;--------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:20pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;About the Filmmakers &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Maureen Castle Tusty and James Tusty founded Sky Films Inc. in 2008 in order to produce documentary films that inform, uplift and inspire. Their first feature film, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Singing Revolution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, was released theatrically in over 100 North American markets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The New York Times&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; declared the film a coveted “Critic’s Choice” and wrote “Imagine the scene in Casablanca in which the French patrons sing La Marseillaise in defiance of the Germans, then multiply its power by a factor of thousands, and you’ve only begun to imagine the force of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Singing Revolution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.” &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Singing Revolution&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; told the little-known story of how the country of Estonia played a critical role in the collapse of the Soviet Union by using singing as a weapon of resistance. Subsequent documentaries such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;India Awakes&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;To Breathe As One&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Sweden: Lessons for America?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Trailblazers: The New Zealand Story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Corporate Welfare: Where’s the Outrage?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; have all aired nationally on U.S. Public Television.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;For many years prior, the Tustys specialized in international productions for some of the largest corporations in the world such as Coca-Cola, IBM, and GE. Recognized with scores of awards, that work took them to over 60 countries around the world. It is that experience that allows them to produce compelling films that take place in many remote corners of the world; sharing stories and voices that might not otherwise be heard.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2024 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/she-rises-up-documentary-film-screening-7699</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427563</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167691</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47597985346455/huge/e0584b187bff36748e95e812303969433468a53b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5902332"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Nov. 6 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-9912</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Chaim Gingold, "Building SimCity: How to Put the World in a Machine"  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming authour Chaim Gingold as he discusses his book, "Building SimCity: How to Put the World in a Machine," on November 13, 2024, in Hohbach Hall. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Building SimCity: How to Put the World in a Machine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As play is intrinsic to humanity, it should come as no surprise that the history of computing is veined with playful simulations and games of all kinds. From the Balinese cockfight to Los Alamos’s Monte Carlo simulations, play and games, in all their kaleidoscopic glory, reflect the diverse cultures and communities of those who make and play them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk focuses upon &lt;i&gt;SimCity&lt;/i&gt;, the genre-defying urban planning hit from 1989, and the people who made it. We’ll examine how &lt;i&gt;SimCity&lt;/i&gt;’s design counts urban planning, videogames, graphical user interfaces, and complexity science among its many influences. This set the stage for &lt;i&gt;SimCity&lt;/i&gt;’s reception and enabled Maxis, &lt;i&gt;SimCity&lt;/i&gt;’s developer, to establish relationships with wide-ranging communities: Nintendo, the Santa Fe Institute, Wall Street venture capitalists, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Focusing on people such as developers, managers, and investors sheds light on the messy process of software development—a negotiation between individuals, their aspirations and worldviews, and shape-shifting technologies. Springing forth from this mess came &lt;i&gt;The Sims&lt;/i&gt;, which required an extraordinary amount of research and development. But this same mess also thwarted Maxis’s solvency and its attempts to bring &lt;i&gt;The Sims&lt;/i&gt; to market. Ultimately, we’ll see how &lt;i&gt;SimCity&lt;/i&gt;, Maxis, and &lt;i&gt;The Sims&lt;/i&gt;—like games, play, and software more generally—reflect their time and place, and the people who make them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Chaim Gingold &lt;/b&gt;is the author of &lt;i&gt;Building SimCity: How to Put the World in a Machine&lt;/i&gt; (MIT Press), which Stewart Brand called "one of the best origin stories ever told and the best account I've seen of how innovation actually occurs in computerdom.”&lt;i&gt; &lt;/i&gt;Gingold began his design career apprenticed to Will Wright on &lt;i&gt;Spore&lt;/i&gt;, where his chief accomplishment was designing the critically acclaimed&lt;i&gt; Spore Creature Creator. &lt;/i&gt;His projects, like &lt;i&gt;Earth: A Primer&lt;/i&gt;, a science book made of interactive toys, have been featured by &lt;i&gt;Wired&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;CNN&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;New York Times.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-chaim-gingold-building-simcity-how-to-put-the-world-in-a-machine</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47419498282629/huge/6f344f28e70440c7d8e37d487b2d6367a69a6b3b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1280" width="960" isDefault="true" fileSize="217756"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: November 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-november-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-293</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: December 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-december-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
