<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Up for Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders exhibit</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the precipitous increase in Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) hate crimes throughout the United States, the staff of Stanford Libraries created the Rise Up against AAPI exhibit which focuses on the history of systemic racism against the AAPI community. The aim of this exhibit is to help educate our community and provide support and resources so that we can start the process of healing and prevent future incidents. In this exhibit, we discuss past events that have led to these reprehensible acts, including institutionalized policies that have pitted minority groups in our country against each other to weaken the other&amp;#8217;s influence.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We hope that through education, our community at large can rise to action against racism at all levels of our society. From the nuanced exclusions on the playground and in the workplace, to the blatant disregard for human life demonstrated in the murders of Asian American women in Atlanta and the brutal attacks on elderly AAPI community members in California and New York&amp;#8212;we must all take an active stand against the scourge that racism is to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibit has both an online and physical presence. You can access the online exhibit at &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup&lt;/a&gt;. The physical exhibit is in the East Asia Library and is a companion to the online exhibit. The physical exhibit highlights material from the Stanford Libraries collection and other sources that illustrate the racial struggle of the Asian American and Pacific Islander community throughout US history. Please note the physical exhibit is only open during the East Asia Library's open hours. Visit &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;library.stanford.edu/hours&lt;/a&gt; to see current hours.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibit is a work in progress and just the beginning of our efforts to combat racism in this country. Look for expanded content covering more ethnic groups and a broader range of issues as this exhibit continues to grow over the fall 2021 quarter.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries stands with the AAPI community and denounces all hate crimes, including the recent surge in hate crimes specifically targeted at the AAPI community. We hope you will join our efforts to learn about the history of violence against the AAPI community so that we can prevent history from repeating itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rise_up_for_asian_americans_and_pacific_islanders_exhibit_6719</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574964232972/huge/51d7df4d3a242c95b72cfc6a541c16b99c5ff99b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="89766"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Say Their Names - No More Names</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Say Their Names &amp;ndash; No More Names&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is an online and in-person exhibit that highlights Black Americans who have been killed or impacted by police brutality and systemic racism. The exhibit originated in direct response to the global Black Lives Matter movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical exhibition in Green Library includes names affixed to glass panels in the Bing Wing as well as banners throughout the first floor that contain the names and faces of the featured victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/saytheirnames" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;online exhibit&lt;/a&gt; displays the images and individual stories of victims, including Emmett Till, Kalief Browder, Salecia Johnson and Bettie Jones; it also calls attention to events like the Tulsa riots, the Tuskegee syphilis experiment and the Chicago Police Department Midnight Crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who visit Stanford can also see a large banner featuring the words &amp;#39;Know Justice Know Peace,&amp;#39; which was hung on the front entrance of Green Library commemorating the opening of the exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note the physical exhibit in Green Library is currently limited to authorized Stanford ID cardholders due to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp; However, the online exhibit, which also includes photos of the physical exhibit is available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit is sponsored by the Stanford Libraries and is a follow up to a &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/171904" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;statement of solidarity and support&lt;/a&gt; against systemic racism published by Stanford Libraries over the summer. It offers opportunities for learning, reflection and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/say_their_names_-_no_more_names_5200</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574945719380/huge/1338d497cd2a334e576defd1efcaa1e0d3740ede.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="108932"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view February 24, 2022, through August 28, 2022, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Robert Trujillo; produced, designed, and installed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/materialia_lumina_contemporary_artist_books_from_the_codex_international_book_fair</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118485903850/huge/23c7599baa91e1cd67c67e00d6c403ed88b088a4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="151056"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-stress &amp; refresh fest- celebrate π at the Science Library at Li &amp; Ma Science Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pi week scavenger hunt begins Wednesday, March 9, and ends Monday, March 14.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hello Stanford! Is it just us, or is everyone feeling stressed lately?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come join the De-stress and refresh fest at the Science Library and participate in fun &amp;pi; -themed activities such as a scavenger hunt, puzzles,&amp;nbsp; games, crafts, Pi&amp;nbsp;trivia, and an Albert Einstein birthday photo booth.&amp;nbsp; Win one of&amp;nbsp;ten gift cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All giveaways are limited to current Stanford students, faculty, and staff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress_refresh_fest-_celebrate_at_the_science_library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39317127776616/huge/3f3fd8da708127f3663f64e10b6f2ea68959928d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="250" width="250" isDefault="true" fileSize="13616"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Thursday, March 10 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that masks will be required and we will be asking that hands be sanitized before and after petting. Hand sanitizer will be provided. Please join us!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_3702</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39145118553259/huge/4415fe2208df0b5e88f1834b4aef1dd155be28ad.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canceled: Andres Sutt, Minister of Entrepreneurship and IT of Estonia at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;THIS EVENT HAS BEEN CANCELED DUE TO THE CANCELLATION OF THE MINISTER'S VISIT.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Andres Sutt, Minister of Entrepreneurship and Information Technology of the Republic of Estonia, &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;who will discuss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Future of AI Society&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Estonia has long been at the forefront of digital innovation in government. In 2020, Estonia joined the UN Security Council for the first time. As an elected member, it has been at the center of crisis diplomacy, keeping the focus on violations of international law and supporting international justice. Estonia was the first one to bring the topic of cybersecurity to the Security Council and has kept the security issues of its region in the global focus.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Artificial intelligence (AI), government e-solutions, and (cyber)security are immediate and pressing challenges a modern state has to tackle, especially during the current security crisis in Europe, caused by Russia's war against Ukraine and Putin's escalating rhetoric. Our goal has been, and continues to be, to raise awareness on the international level of emerging threats, including in cyberspace. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The conversation will be facilitated by &lt;a href="https://fsi.stanford.edu/people/andrew-j-grotto" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Andrew Grotto,&lt;/a&gt; Director of Program on Geopolitics, Technology, and Governance, Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.valitsus.ee/en/prime-minister-ministers/minister-entrepreneurship-and-information-technology-andres-sutt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Mr. Andres Sutt&lt;/a&gt;, Minister of Entrepreneurship and Information Technology of the Republic of Estonia since 26 January 2021, is a member of the liberal Reform Party. He has over 25 years of international experience in central banking, bank restructuring, and crisis management. Mr. Sutt was the Deputy Governor of the Bank of Estonia, worked for the European Financial Stability Facility, and represented Estonia at the Executive Board of the IMF. Mr.  Sutt has a Master's Degree in Economics and Finance (cum laude) from Tartu University and has studied management at INSEAD, France. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;He serves as the Board Member of SOS Children's Village Estonia, Estonian Maternity Hospitals Foundation, and the University of Tartu Foundation.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admission Info&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. Seating is extremely limited.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;All attendees must be vaccinated and adhere to Stanford's &lt;a href="https://healthalerts.stanford.edu/covid-19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;health policies&lt;/a&gt;. Non-Stanford guests must complete the &lt;a href="https://redcap.stanford.edu/surveys/?s=TMJAC9X3JM" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;health attestation form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/andres_sutt_minister_of_entrepreneurship_and_it_of_estonia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39304104453918/huge/36c2a1249c61b54d66918fc25b6bb29d469351e7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="450" isDefault="true" fileSize="67994"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Radically Inclusive Solutions Exhibition at Green Library, Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intersectional design drives innovation while supporting social justice and environmetnal sustainability. It's about getting the design right for people across all of soceity -- from the very beginning. This exhibit takes visitors through the &lt;em&gt;Intersectional Design Cards&lt;/em&gt;, a design activity to create radically inclusive products, processes, and paradigms that was developed by an interdisciplinary team from Stanford University's Hasso Plattner Instiute of Design (the d.school). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibition is free and open to active Stanford ID cardholders during Green Library's operating hours. Face coverings are strongly recommended. For the most up-to-date information regarding library access, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;library.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/designing_radically_inclusive_solutions_exhibition</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39330967402362/huge/e59d353aaacb05b45bf3619ea04781ce2fbfd838.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="196230"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Radically Inclusive Solutions</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for the next in a series of conversations hosted by the Silicon Valley Archives. &lt;em&gt;Intersectional design &lt;/em&gt;offers concepts and methods for inclusive design and considers intersecting social environmental factors in designing new technologies. It drives innovation while supporting social justice and environmental sustainability. It's about getting the design right for people across all of society -- from the very beginning. Please join us for the next in a series of conversations hosted by the Silicon Valley Archives. Londa Schiebinger, Hannah Jones, Ann Grimes, and Andrea Small, the co-authors of &lt;em&gt;Intersectional Design Cards&lt;/em&gt;, recently available from Stanford University Press, will speak to us about this approach to design and show us how it works. This event also celebrates the opening of a new exhibit from the Silicon Valley Archives in Hohbach Hall devoted to the Intersectional Design project and its development out of the Gendered Innovations in Science, Health &amp; Medicine, Engineering, and Environment project at Stanford. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Signed copies of &lt;em&gt;Intersectional Design Cards &lt;/em&gt;will be available for purchase at the event. To purchase a copy today, please visit &lt;a href="https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=35687" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Stanford University Press&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/londa-schiebinger" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Londa Schiebinger&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is the John L. Hinds Professor of History of Science at Stanford University, and Director of Gendered Innovations in Science. Health &amp; Medicine, Engineering, and Environment. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.academia.edu/HannahJones" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Hannah Jones&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is a design researcher and a teaching instructor at Stanford University's d.school. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/ann-grimes-50778312" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Ann Grimes&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;is the Director of Journalism Fellowships for the Starling Lab for Data Integrity, a research center at Stanford and the University of Southern California. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.andreasmall.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Andrea Small&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;leads advanced technology explorations for Samsung Research America's R&amp;D innovation Strategy Team. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Limited seating is available for in-person attendance at this event, which will also be live-streamed. To attend in-person or via livestream, you must RSVP beforehand. &lt;strong&gt;Stanford Libraries are open to currently active Stanford ID cardholders only. To attend this event in-person, y&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ou must have an active Stanford ID. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/designing_radically_inclusive_solutions</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39330972352484/huge/f2cc0faeb1566e559bf7a9dc0be05f5c061b4c5f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="117512"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
