<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Translating Three Japanese Masters, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura, and Kazuko Shiraishi: Selections from the Yumiko Tsumura Collection at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On display at the East Asia Library from 3/6/25-5/13/25, selections from a recent donation from Yumiko Tsumura, a local poet and translator, related to three major modern Japanese authors, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura and Kazuko Shiraishi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yumiko Kurahashi’s meteoric career began with &lt;i&gt;Parutai&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;The Party&lt;/i&gt;), a brilliant satire of the Japanese leftist students movement that she wrote while still a student. As part of a first generation of women writers who had benefited from equal opportunity for education in the post-war period, her innovative writing style, influenced by Satre, Kafka, and Camus, rocked the literary world of the 1960s, exposing structural inequities in Japanese society. Perhaps the most renowned post-WWII Japanese poet, Ryuichi Tamura’s poetry searingly reveals the agony of war and the disorientation induced by rapid modernization. Kazuko Shiraishi, known for performing her provocative poetry to jazz accompaniment, has been called the “Allen Ginsberg of Japan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to introduce this donation in an exhibit in our main exhibit space. Please visit the East Asia Library to learn more about these three authors, who each left a powerful critique of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/east-asia-library-exhibits-selections-yumiko-tsumura-collection-japanese-poetry"&gt;Read an interview with the donor, Yumiko Tsumura, to learn more about her and each of these authors.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/translating-three-japanese-masters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49021026270886/huge/0a889191391152cee3133e7261ae17eb90597460.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="469" width="512" isDefault="true" fileSize="80335"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit runs from April 2 to August &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, 2025, in Green Library’s Hohbach Hall. This exhibit is free and open to the public.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks exploring e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48784006670593/huge/fcc0e4782c3b22ef835cd5a2bc04a6752a27d369.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="858" width="862" isDefault="true" fileSize="1286480"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art of the Ad: Fashion for a New Century  at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pochoir fashion plates and advertisements are part of the allure of early 20th-century Parisian fashion magazines. Art history major, Sita Antel, '26 investigates the role of fashion in her Spring exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On view in Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 1 - June 20th. M-Th 9-7, Fri 9-5, Sun. 12-6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/art-of-the-ad-fashion-for-a-new-century</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49092294783840/huge/f89ef044fd107f813a0005d6667e49c04115261e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="626799"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ART/WORK at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;ART/WORK | Creative Pursuits of Stanford Libraries Staff&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; on view February 20, 2024, through April 27, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this exhibition, we sought to create a space where staff could share their artistic, creative side that may not otherwise be a part of their work at Stanford. In the Summer of 2024, Special Collections invited current Stanford Libraries staff to enter creative work in any medium to be considered for a Winter 2025 exhibit in Green Library’s Peterson Gallery and Rotunda. Response to the call for entries was hearty. In addition to traditional fine art techniques of drawing, painting, printmaking, and photography, submissions included mixed media sculpture, ceramics, collage, textiles, and poetry. An anonymous selection committee of library staff blind-reviewed over a hundred entries and chose the fifty works displayed in the galleries. We asked the people whose pieces were selected to write a brief statement to accompany their work in the exhibit and posed several questions for their consideration: Why do creative work? What medium do you work in and why? How did you get started? What does it mean to you to be an artist (if you define yourself as one)? Does art need an audience? Who is your audience? What influences your work, and whose work do you admire? As you will see, Stanford library staff are talented and thoughtful, pursuing many forms of creative work after hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo, Associate University Librarian, Director of Special Collections and Frances and Charles Field Curator of Special Collections; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their careful consideration of all staff art submissions, we thank the staff members who served on the jury; For their assessment of materials, Aisha Wahab and Beth Ryan in Conservation Services; For their assistance with logistics Ranelle Sharma and Jacob Cohn in Library Facilities, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/artwork</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48687359684680/huge/603b1fb303d73747de62963ba10e4c95a4135903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="78990"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bo Ruberg, "How to Queer the World: Radical Worldbuilding through Video Games" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Bo Ruberg as they discuss their book, &lt;i&gt;How To Queer the World: Radical Worldbuilding through Video Games," &lt;/i&gt;on April 17, 2025. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today more than ever, we need the power to build new worlds. Video games are exceptional tools for worldbuilding because every video game itself is a world. Yet, in video games and other media forms, worldbuilding is still commonly understood as an expression of storytelling. A queer reading of video games shows us that worldbuilding means something much deeper and more radical than narrative elements that sit on the surface of the world. In video games, worlds are built on the foundation of interaction design, software simulations, graphical dimensions, and other elements often overlooked as too technical to hold cultural meaning. By analyzing these elements of game development as acts of worldbuilding, we can reimagine worldbuilding itself: as a process of challenging firmly held beliefs about the fundamental structures, conventions, and irreducible truths that give shape to the world around us. Video games also powerfully model the concept of queer worldbuilding--a practice of building worlds that destabilizes the fundamental logics of our universe and builds new worlds founded on alternate expressions of gender, sexuality, embodiment, intimacy, and desire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bo Ruberg&lt;/b&gt;, Ph.D. is a Professor in the Department of Film and Media Studies at the University of California, Irvine and the co-editor-in-chief of the &lt;i&gt;Journal of Cinema and Media Studies&lt;/i&gt;. Their research explores gender and sexuality in digital media with a focus on LGBTQ topics in video games. They are the author of four books: &lt;i&gt;Video Games Have Always Been Queer&lt;/i&gt; (NYU Press, 2019), &lt;i&gt;The Queer Games Avant-Garde: How LGBTQ Game Makers Are Reimagining the Medium of Video Games&lt;/i&gt; (Duke University Press, 2020), &lt;i&gt;Sex Dolls at Sea: Imagined Histories of Sexual Technologies&lt;/i&gt; (MIT Press, 2022), and &lt;i&gt;How to Queer the World: Radical Worldbuilding through Video Games&lt;/i&gt; (NYU Press, 2025). They have also co-edited two volumes,&lt;i&gt; Queer Game Studies&lt;/i&gt; (University of Minnesota Press, 2017) and &lt;i&gt;Real Life in Real Time: Live Streaming Culture&lt;/i&gt; (MIT Press, 2023).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bo-ruberg-how-to-queer-the-world-radical-worldbuilding-through-video-games</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49296002965432/huge/a2ce4b33156b4d1dd37d10376bd469750b851329.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3334" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2706442"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/83a42ebc28b44fe7b355532da798b938"&gt;view digitally&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Naturally Hazardous: Wildfires at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Naturally Hazardous&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the cosmically unavoidable to the anthropogenically-induced, Earth can be naturally hazardous to humans. In the 2024-25 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature the science and impact of volcanoes, wildfires, drought, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
April 1 - April 24:  Extreme wildfires have become more frequent. Learn more about their effects on the environment, public health, infrastructure, and efforts to monitor and remediate those effects through books, maps, and data in our monthly exhibit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-naturally-hazardous-wildfires</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49243078500398/huge/2e04d7f86b57cf45a111ede44d125340be99d063.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="317898"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling with R at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: IC Classroom, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 10AM–Noon, Friday, April 18, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Claudia Engel, Academic Technology Specialist for Anthropology&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is for those who know the basics of R and would like to get started working with their research data. Here you will learn ways to wrangle and reshape tabular data, specifically using the dplyr and tidyr packages. CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or equivalent knowledge).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Workshop materials available at this link.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-wrangling-with-r-2025-04-18</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412377827077/huge/4aa1072b6179da2f20ee9687ae39677a5f748a51.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (April 18th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the More Info link for registration and workshop landing page URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing-in-qgis-april-18th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39519065549929/huge/36ecf7eef696ef2fc4be5cd1cafb4c93c8ea2a25.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive a Robot Apocalypse </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming filmmaker Andrea Gatopoulos for a talk on their latest film, "The Eggregores Theory," on April 22, 2025, for an online presentation. Please register for the event ahead of time for the Zoom information. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconstructing the culture, philosophies, and economic structures that gave rise to artificial intelligences, Andrea will try to deconstruct the apocalyptic fear that is associated with this technology.  The goal is a better understanding of AI’s limits as well as the potential it has to power up our creative energy and upscale the output of our world-building imagination. After the introduction, we will watch and delve into the making of my film, "The Eggregores' Theory", the first AI film to be screened at Venice Film Festival. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Andrea Gatopoulos&lt;/b&gt; is an Italian and Greek director, producer and distributor. Member of EFA, Berlinale Talents, Locarno Spring Academy and TFL, he founded his company Il Varco, the short film distribution Gargantua and the avant-garde cinema residency Nouvelle Bug. He graduated in Literature and studied in workshops with W. Herzog, Radu Jude and A. Weerasethakul. His films deal with virtual realities, uncanny valleys, disillusion, anti-capitalism and critiques of progressivism. "Happy New Year, Jim" (2022) was the first machinima in Cannes, at the 54. Quinzaine des Réalisateurs. In 2023 he presented in Locarno "Eschaton Ad", a film about the apocalyptic advent of AI. Later that year he presented "A stranger quest" (2023), his first documentary feature about the map collector David Rumsey at Torino Film Festival. In 2024 his short film "The Eggregores' Theory" opened the 39. Venice Film Critics' Week as the first AI film in Venice and was nominated for EFA by ZINEBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/how-to-survive-a-robot-apocalypse</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49287680748846/huge/fac3ed2042b3def43b0d1bb7fbf3d703434decdc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1489" width="2560" isDefault="true" fileSize="709524"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Science and Health Policy: Forward Progress or Complete Chaos? (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month, the Bay Area Open Science Group will feature Kathryn Phillips, PhD, Professor of Health Economics and Health Services Research at UCSF, in a conversation on open science and health policy. Although the move towards open science – including data sharing and open access publication – continues, these efforts must now consider the changing policy environment. Kathryn will lead a discussion on open science and health policy with topics to include evolving trends in open science, particularly open access publication, and how these trends might be impacted by the changing policy environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathryn will bring her perspectives as both a researcher and Editor-in-Chief of an open access journal. Her thoughts will be informed by her 2024 publication on open access, her upcoming participation in the National Academy of Sciences Journal Summit, and an upcoming one-month residency at the Brocher Foundation (Geneva) to focus on open access publication globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/open-science-and-health-policy</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49268398667096/huge/a924a2d39baf14fe7ae607d131d5dc425b6b551c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to API Authentication at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 2PM–3PM, Wednesday, April 23, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Instructor: Katie Frey, Data Curator for Programmatic Access&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to methods of API authentication, with a focus on different approaches for securely storing API credentials and how to avoid publishing them online by accident.  We will cover common types of authentication systems that someone may encounter when using APIs for research purposes, such as API keys, Bearer tokens, and Basic Authentication. Basic boilerplate scripts will be provided in Python and R that can be used to authenticate with these kinds of APIs. The workshop will also discuss general pointers on how to obtain API keys and tokens. Attendees to this workshop should have familiarity with Python or R. There may be portions of the workshop that you will want to follow along with on your own computer if you have Python or R installed, but this is not required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro-to-api-authentication</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412423436590/huge/5f7bbbaa75f12e343bba50d18688119b9bda9905.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conservation in Special Collections Pop-up Exhibit at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Conservation Services at Stanford University Libraries celebrates Preservation Week with a pop-up exhibition in collaboration with Special Collections. In addition to a live papyrus treatment demonstration, a variety of materials from medieval manuscripts to bespoke protective enclosures will be on display.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Each year, libraries across the U.S. participate in the American Libraries Association’s Preservation Week to highlight what we can do to care for personal and community collections and raise awareness of the role of libraries and cultural institutions in ongoing preservation education.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Drop by &lt;b&gt;Barchas Room&lt;/b&gt; (Green Library West 200 - entrance through the Lane Reading Room) anytime between &lt;b&gt;10:00am - 11:30am on Monday, April 28th&lt;/b&gt; to chat with conservation staff and see how conservation work impacts Special Collections materials.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/conservation-in-special-collections-pop-up-exhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49409629533379/huge/fd4979cd9b1e1adf9c3d5279806b4da31576695a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3384" width="3384" isDefault="true" fileSize="3703737"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Wrangling with Python at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Hohbach Hall Presentation Room 122, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM–3PM, Tuesday, April 29, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Instructor: Simon Wiles, Digital Scholarship Research Developer&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;You should be familiar with basic Python syntax and fundamental programming concepts such as variables, functions, and control flow. If you need a refresher, check out &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A Byte of Python&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-wrangling-with-python-2025-04-29</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412429914576/huge/fcf6883343ef12c4c5b373d4a5b5466a1147f390.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39152"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in R</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1:00PM - 4:00PM, Wednesday, April 30, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to working with data visualization in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate common plots, and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. A Zoom link will be provided upon registration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-visualization-in-r-2025-04-30</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412433102168/huge/dfb1ad268fa5691e59b5bf77645fea980557012c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis with Python at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM–3PM, Thursday, May 1, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm, Head of Data Science Training and Consultation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Curious about how to work with text data using Python? Join us for a practical introduction to text analysis, tailored for those new to programming. This workshop will cover key techniques, including text pre-processing, named entity recognition, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis. No prior Python experience is necessary. We’ll guide you through foundational Python concepts, introduce essential libraries and modules for text analysis, and provide hands-on examples to support your learning. This event is a great starting point for discovering the potential of Python in working with text data, and will inspire you to learn Python to gain even greater insights and capabilities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/text-analysis-with-python</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412436572648/huge/b35be88519f337fb2d641325390a30a274ae0bd1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39152"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Time, Space and Habitat: a talk by Dr. Ben Gitai at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have always shaped and been shaped by the landscapes they inhabit. "Chronomapping" is an innovative methodology developed by Dr. Gitai that investigates landscape transformations through time by integrating data and insights from disciplines such as architecture, landscape architecture, hydrology, urban planning, climatology, ecology, sociology, anthropology, political geography, history, and even the psychology of aesthetics. The methodology is a means to produce visual representations and new conceptual frameworks of territories and habitats across time. It can also cast power dynamics and territorial transformations in new lights by examining the interplay between terrain, territory, and cartography across historical periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is designed to serve as a counterbalance to the short-sightedness that has characterized much development in the Western world. The methodology is explicitly designed to account for the palimpsestic nature of development. It has both scholarly and practical applications with potential utility in fields of governance, urban and spatial planning, and industrial development. Dr. Gitai's lecture will reference two of his forthcoming publications: &lt;i&gt;Mapping Power: History of Landscape in the Jordan Valley&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Landscapes Atlas of Paris&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the speaker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ben Gitai integrates geography, architecture, and related disciplines in his research and practice. He has taught at various institutions in Switzerland (ETHZ, EPFL) and France. His cross-disciplinary approach combines tools and perspectives from landscape architecture, urban planning, political geography, and history, exploring the evolution of geo-spatial configurations over historical periods and how these transformations reflect broader socio-political and economic processes. His work recontextualizes mapping practices as instruments for understanding the complex relationships between human and natural systems, offering innovative perspectives on the forces that shape our environments. Today, he is the head coordinator of the Habitat Research Center and the Paris Atlas of Landscapes at EPFL. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScZfdPIJvqU2suflntJ37WPy2l5DzHRt2LS9IeCbNB-MDnfhw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register to attend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is an in-person-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mapping-time-space-and-habitat-a-talk-by-dr-ben-gitai</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48986076260218/huge/574da834c9fe7204b040f8ea7caab42d6ca0da0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="302" width="454" isDefault="true" fileSize="144870"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R for Reproducible Scientific Analysis</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1:00PM - 4:00PM, Wednesday, May 7, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to reproducible data analysis in R for those who have basic programming experience in R. This class will focus on project management , task automation, and general best practices. By the end of this workshop, you will have learned how to write functions and scripts to use between projects and that can be shared with others through reports created in R Markdown.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. A Zoom link will be provided upon registration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/r-for-reproducible-scientific-analysis</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412438712559/huge/cddedefe758530dcf876537ff2fb4b02dd6a8c7e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, May 7 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-4083</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book talk with Ala Ebtekar – Thirty-Six Views of the Moon at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join us for a talk and reading with &lt;b&gt;Ala Ebtekar&lt;/b&gt; on &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.alaebtekar.com/works/project-three-t5mw3" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Thirty-Six Views of the Moon&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, his new monograph comprised of a collection of photographs, night exposures — left from dusk till dawn and exposed by moonlight on book pages from texts referencing the moon and night sky spanning the last ten centuries.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Following the talk will be a panel discussion with the artist &lt;b&gt;Ala Ebtekar&lt;/b&gt;; &lt;b&gt;Alexander Nemerov&lt;/b&gt;, the Carl and Marilynn Thoma Provostial Professor in the Arts and Humanities at Stanford; and &lt;b&gt;Ladan Akbarnia&lt;/b&gt;, Curator of South Asian and Islamic Art at The San Diego Museum of Art; moderated by &lt;b&gt;Kim Beil&lt;/b&gt;, associate director of the ITALIC interdisciplinary arts program at Stanford.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/ceYM3mYNkaULZCwGA" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;register&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to attend.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please be advised that this event may be filmed, and official photographs may be taken for posting on Stanford websites and/or may be used in other university publications. By registering for this event and/or entering this event venue, you consent to Stanford University using your image and likeness.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://postimg.cc/BPQNDnsS" target="_self"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.postimg.cc/5y8rhXRC/Ala.jpg" style="height:130px;width:100px;"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.alaebtekar.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ala Ebtekar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (b. 1978, Berkeley, CA) has situated his practice as a leveling and collapsing of time and space. His work frequently orchestrates various orbits and cadences of time, bringing forth sculptural and photographic possibilities of the universe and time observing humanity. Exploring time, exposure, and light as both medium and metaphor, he uses sunlight, moonlight, and starlight to create durational works—sometimes taking an entire night to expose—which he views as collaborations with the sun, moon, and stars.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Ebtekar, throughout his practice, has employed the tactile traditions and properties of bookmaking, page and illumination in bound manuscripts, and classical training in Iranian coffeehouse painting. His alchemy of combining these legacies weaves into his commitment and work alongside enduring centuries of reclaimed text &amp;amp; image archives, poetry, and translation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;His work has been widely exhibited across the globe at institutions such as the British Museum, Xinjiang Biennale, California Biennial, Maraya Art Centre in Sharjah, Honolulu Museum of Art, and the Brooklyn Museum. His works are held in leading public and private collections, including the Whitney Museum of American Art, British Museum, de Young Fine Arts Museum, Microsoft Art Collection, Devi Art Foundation in India, and Berkeley Art Museum, among others.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.postimg.cc/RZzzPBq8/Ladan.jpg" style="height:130px;width:100px;"&gt;​​Ladan Akbarnia&lt;/b&gt; (PhD, Harvard University) is Curator of South Asian and Islamic Art at The San Diego Museum of Art (SDMA) and curator of &lt;i&gt;Wonders of Creation: Art, Science, and Innovation in the Islamic World&lt;/i&gt; (2024–25), which addresses intersections of art and science through the lens of a 13th-century Islamic cosmography. A specialist in Islamic visual culture, she studies cross-cultural transmissions; Sufism; contemporary art; and museum display methodologies. Previously, she curated the Islamic collections at the Brooklyn and British Museums, including a major reinstallation of the latter’s Albukhary Foundation Gallery of the Islamic World. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/kim-beil" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.postimg.cc/tgNRdg52/Beil.jpg" style="height:130px;width:100px;"&gt;Kim Beil&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the associate director of the ITALIC interdisciplinary arts program at Stanford. In addition to two books on photography, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://bookshop.org/p/books/good-pictures-a-history-of-popular-photography-kim-beil/11832647" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Good Pictures: A History of Popular Photography&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.mackbooks.us/products/anonymous-objects-inscrutable-photographs-and-the-unknown-kim-beil-spbh-editions?srsltid=AfmBOoq4aJznNIQMIo5PZ8Mn4wJVKclXtGS-Z62EmWvMrirzS0FWepFN" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Anonymous Objects: Inscrutable Photographs and the Unknown&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, she also writes for the general public about the intersections of art and the natural world. Her writing has appeared in &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;, the &lt;i&gt;Believer&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Cabinet&lt;/i&gt; magazine, &lt;i&gt;The New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Paris Review&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Smithsonian&lt;/i&gt; magazine.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://art.stanford.edu/people/alexander-nemerov" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://i.postimg.cc/Sstn8sSH/Nemerov.jpg" style="height:130px;width:100px;"&gt;Alexander &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Nemerov&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, a professor at Stanford, is the author of many books, including most recently &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Forest: A Fable of America in the 1830s&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (2023), called by the novelist Annie Proulx “deeply beautiful, achingly painful and astonishingly tender," and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Fierce Poise: Helen Frankenthaler and 1950s New York&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, short-listed for the National Book Critics Circle Award in Biography.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book-talk-with-ala-ebtekar-thirty-six-views-of-the-moon</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49341589353950/huge/7a582e4285ff9eb6e8f8cf82343233406c2894e8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="771027"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management and Open Science Workshop</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 2:00PM - 3:00PM, Thursday, May 15, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Maricela Abarca, Data Curator for Interdisciplinary Sustainability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Wherever you are in the research data lifecycle, this workshop will help you assess your data hygiene and adopt data management strategies that enhance the integrity, quality, reproducibility, compliance, accessibility and preservation of your data. We will discuss FAIR (Findable, Reproducible, Interoperable, Reusable) and CARE (Collective Benefit, Authority to Control, Responsibility, Ethics) principles, as well as how to implement them in your work. Those interested in open science and open scholarship will also benefit from this session. Register via Zoom to attend live and/or receive a recording. Submit any questions you’d like answered during the workshop through the Zoom registration form. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. A Zoom link will be provided upon registration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/research-data-management-and-open-science-workshop</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412444113232/huge/1c6091cf89d74a3f912a2fc153e363490794dd0f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Using Open-Source Software Tools: From Neuroinformatics to Biomechanics (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month, the Bay Area Open Science Group will be joined by Sydney Covitz, a Bioengineering PhD Student at Stanford. Sydney graduated from Swarthmore College in 2020 with a double major in Computer Science and English Literature. She is currently working in the Neuromuscular Biomechanics Lab (NMBL), led by PI Scott Delp, using an open-source video-based application the lab developed to analyze upper extremity function in neuromuscular clinic patients. Between college and graduate school, Sydney spent three years as a Senior Software Developer in the University of Pennsylvania's Lifespan Brain Institute where she collaborated with informatics teams around the world to develop software packages and workflows for reproducibly analyzing large neuroimaging datasets. Her talk will touch on her experience in neuroinformatics software development and data management as well as her current work using open-source biomechanics tools for clinical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/open-source-software-tools-from-neuroinformatics-to-biomechanics</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49338953433312/huge/5fc19a6050ad3f71a4a5fc186f99243db157979f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: May 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-may-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM as RA: Leveraging AI for Academic Research at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1:00PM - 3:00PM, Thursday, May 22, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm, Head of Data Science Training and Consultation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Are you looking to harness the potential of AI to streamline your research workflow? This workshop will introduce you to the architecture and applications of Large Language Models (LLMs), empowering you to effectively and responsibly leverage them in your academic research. We will explore the use cases, possibilities, and limitations of LLMs, as well as essential considerations for their ethical use. Key topics will include: pre-processing techniques for data preparation, strategies for working with tabular data, and evaluation measures for LLM-driven research tasks. You will also gain practical experience utilizing both Stanford’s AI Playground API and local language models. By the end of the workshop, you will be equipped with the knowledge, skills, and sample code to integrate AI into your research workflow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/llm-as-ra-leveraging-ai-for-academic-research</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412447565594/huge/d2ce585febbbcd6af243f661235824ed1929c20f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGulf: Creating Open Historical Data about the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;How can we critically examine, interpret, and repurpose colonial knowledge through creating structured data? Can colonial texts serve as meaningful data sources to explore the histories of understudied regions like the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf? How can historical sources be transformed into datasets, and what insights can such data offer? This symposium addresses these questions and marks the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://opengulf.github.io" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; research collective’s completion and publication of a comprehensive dataset of geocoded place names derived from a seminal early-twentieth-century British colonial Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabian Peninsula, and Oman. This open-access, historical-geographical dataset is the culmination of seven years of collaborative annotation, geolocation, and disambiguation carried out by faculty, students, and OpenGulf community members across several institutions. During the sessions, we will discuss OpenGulf’s collaborative workflows and methods, introduce potential uses among scholars and practitioners, and emphasize the pedagogical potential of historical dataset creation by celebrating the work of student researchers. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;In addition to morning sessions at the David Rumsey Map Center, the event will feature an exhibition of historical materials related to the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at Branner Library and a student-led poster session including lightning talks on undergraduate research.  The afternoon event will include cartographic visualizations created using the OpenGulf dataset such as the one pictured here, a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/camels/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; of mentions of over 66,000 camels in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Oman and Central Arabia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Scholars, students, and members of the public with an interest in advancing and broadening their knowledge of both the history of the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf and digital humanities debates and methodologies will especially benefit from this event. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Detailed program coming soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdlExG8oCxQA7mwF9gL3IdeWS6QRquumozO-DMWwEcHxA4GSA/viewform?usp=sharing" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;register to attend&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/opengulf-creating-open-historical-data-about-the-arabian-peninsula-and-the-persian-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49172453653870/huge/7764bcaf3c34e491522165c573f8173fa768a589.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3146" width="4058" isDefault="true" fileSize="1438579"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> From Ecotopia to NIMBYland:  Environment, Ideology, and the Antigrowth Style in California Politics at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jacob Anbinder and Michael Kahan on May 29, 2025, as they discuss Jacbob Anbinder's upcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation: The War on Growth That Created Our Housing Crisis and Remade American Politics&lt;/i&gt;. This event is co-sponsored by &lt;a href="https://west.stanford.edu"&gt;The Bill Lane Center for the American West&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu/"&gt;The Stanford University Department of History&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1975, a tiny Berkeley press published &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt;. Set in 1999, the novel told the story of a fledgling nation which had declared its independence from the U.S. out of disdain for America’s obsession with growth. &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt; ended up selling more than four hundred thousand copies and won author Ernest Callenbach praise in progressive circles for his visionary environmentalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Callenbach and others, California was ground zero for the disasters wrought by unfettered urbanization. Yet it was also the place where an alternative politics focused on ecological protection and quality of life seemed most likely to emerge. In the seventies and eighties, California liberals embarked on an intensive effort to remake their political agenda in the Ecotopian mold. Whether expressing dismay about freeway traffic, forest fires, water use, overcrowded parks and beaches, the loss of scenic views, or the unsightliness of high-rises, environmental protection became the shared language through which they voiced their objection to growth. This “mood of revulsion,” as one journalist called it, permeated every level of politics and ultimately reshaped the state’s patterns of urban development and land use. Soon, however, the imbalance between people’s demand to live in California and California’s new inability to accommodate them produced one of the most severe housing shortages in American history. No longer the poster child of unchecked sprawl, the state instead found itself at the center of a new epidemic: NIMBYism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on his forthcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation&lt;/i&gt;, Anbinder tells a new history of California’s cost-of-living crisis that moves beyond simplistic caricatures of NIMBYs and their motives. Instead, he instead traces the origins of the housing shortage to a more fundamental shift in liberals’ ideas about whether urban growth could help effect social progress at all. This influential but largely overlooked political movement ultimately dismantled much of the “growth machine” that had built modern California. In doing so, however, antigrowth liberals created the conditions for the paradoxical problem that defines the Golden State today: namely, that America’s most ostensibly progressive place is too expensive for most Americans to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jacob Anbinder&lt;/b&gt; is a historian of the modern United States with a particular focus on the politics of cities and suburbs in the twentieth century. His research interests include the political economy of major infrastructure projects, movements for and against change to the built environment, and the ways in which sprawl and spatial segregation create social inequities. His writing has been published in &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Business History Review&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Week&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Democracy: A Journal of Ideas&lt;/i&gt;, and other outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael Kahan &lt;/b&gt;is the Co-Director of the Program on Urban Studies at Stanford University and a senior lecturer in Sociology at Stanford University. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jacob-anbinder-nimby-nation-the-war-on-growth-that-created-our-housing-crisis-and-remade-american-politics</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48914944947267/huge/6006580a3a1941c248b79331b8954649e74a4a0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="515" width="450" isDefault="true" fileSize="29742"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7053</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: June 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-june-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: July 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-july-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
