<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Religion in Manga and Anime: A Poster Exhibition by IntroSems RELIGST 6N at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Introductory Seminar RELIGST 6N “Religion in Anime and Manga,” taught by Professor Michaela Mross, students explored religious themes and imagery in manga (Japanese comics) and anime (animated films or TV series). The exhibit on display in the East Asia Library features academic posters on manga and anime, such as &lt;i&gt;My Neighbor Totoro&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Kamisama Kiss&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Deathnote&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Jujutsu Kaisen&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;The Tale of the Princess Kaguya&lt;/i&gt;, that the students created as their final projects. The posters aim to contribute to a deeper understanding of the cultural and religious background of these modern works, produced for mainly entertainment purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is located in the 3rd floor exhibit cases at the East Asia Library. An opening reception will be held on Wednesday, March 13, from 1:30 - 2:45 PM in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is sponsored by Stanford Libraries, the East Asia Library, the Introductory Seminars Program, and the Department of Religious Studies&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/religion_in_manga_and_anime_a_poster_exhibition_by_introsems_religst_6n</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45819348362183/huge/11f1619bda59edc32f082749030e0c86f539da8d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3409" width="2206" isDefault="true" fileSize="5320448"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acclaimed photographer &lt;a href="https://www.marybethmeehan.com/"&gt;Mary Beth Meehan&lt;/a&gt; collaborated with Stanford professor &lt;a href="https://fredturner.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fred Turner&lt;/a&gt; to highlight an often overlooked side of Silicon Valley: the people who are struggling to make ends meet in a region known as the center of technological innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A selection of portraits and text from their award-winning book &lt;a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/S/bo90479007.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Seeing Silicon Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on display throughout Hohbach Hall's study spaces. This long-term exhibition will be up through 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/seeing_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44632871153947/huge/9bdd0a6a9240812158b5f139c218c34bb9b226f2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="384" width="576" isDefault="true" fileSize="293286"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford's Rainbow Coalition at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; In 1987, the Asian American Student Association, Black Student Union, Movimiento Estudiantil Chicano de Aztlán (MEChA), and the Stanford American Indian Association united to form the Rainbow Coalition and drafted a “Rainbow Agenda,” a set of demands that highlighting the shared needs of these communities, including increased recruitment of students and faculty of color, improved curriculum and ethnic studies, a permanent ban on grapes, and a renewed commitment to discourage Indian mascot fanatics. Rainbow Coalition actions included protests against the ethnocentric Western Culture requirement in 1988, and the takeover of the President’s Office in 1989.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/stanfords-rainbow-coalition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46215331638972/huge/f1029cf6f6575d27ae291c91e7e5b5d3f722a619.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="237" width="480" isDefault="true" fileSize="137347"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apes &amp; Us: A Century of Representations of Our Closest Relatives at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Centering upon a set of paintings by the Austrian artist and evolutionist Gabriel von Max (1840-1915), &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Apes &amp;amp; Us&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; explores a century of of representations of primates in relation to humans. Come tour the cultural fascination with apes that began in the decades after Darwin published &lt;i&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/i&gt; (1859) as it spread into art, literature, and film, science and pseudoscience, the scholarly and the sensational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Gabriel von Max, &lt;i&gt;Abelard and Heloise&lt;/i&gt;, c. 1900, oil on canvas. The Jack Daulton Collection. Photography by Don Tuttle/Marty Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_apes_and_us</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45093763636988/huge/1d58a0f9333c80310003fd0cd4499fbca4a6c367.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1600" width="1248" isDefault="true" fileSize="430715"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;黛文洵美：山水記憶&lt;br&gt;
Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford Libraries, the East Asia Library, and the Center for East Asian Studies. Organized and guest curated by Beryl Zhou, graduate student, Center for East Asian Studies, and Ellen Huang, Ph.D, distinguished practitioner at the Center for East Asian Studies and associate professor of art history and material culture at ArtCenter College of Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanghai-born artist Victoria Yau (1939–2023) created around 300 works of abstract ink paintings, watercolors, multimedia collages, prints, and textiles after she moved to the United States from Taipei. These artworks, spanning nearly half a century of art-making in Chicago, New York and the Southwest, testify to her commitment to abstraction and investment in material experimentation. Featuring a selection of works in a range of media—and complemented by the artist’s own writings, collections, and poetry—this exhibition asks viewers to consider the transformation of East Asian landscape painting from compositional structure into abbreviated form emphasizing texture and line. Gathered together here for the first time since her passing, the works and texts on display explore how Yau negotiated disparate experiences of geopolitical flux, immigration, and physical struggle throughout her seventy-year career. Modern in their simplicity but complex in their historical and international references, Victoria Yau’s mountain clouds, her own poetic reworking of the historical term for landscape painting, “mountain-water 山水,” signal the intricacies of international contemporary art through the vantage of an Asian diasporic woman artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/victoria-yau-i-slept-in-the-mountain-cloud</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46252014368895/huge/6eb4274218d52cea507377e8acbd22c97908c505.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="839" width="838" isDefault="true" fileSize="552389"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Display: Pride Month at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come to Green Library and check out our book display celebrating Pride Month. Find a title you like? Check it out at the Circulation Desk!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 08:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book-display-pride-month</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46604369015416/huge/1828fb9b3eba1b969911ff24cc436a89ca1e9313.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2832" width="2124" isDefault="true" fileSize="329387"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Color Deceives: Le Corbusier &amp; Josef Albers at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bowes Library’s Spring 2024 exhibition, &lt;i&gt;Color Deceives&lt;/i&gt;, explores the color theories of modern artist Josef Albers (German-American, 1888-1976) and modern architect Le Corbusier (Swiss-French, 1887-1965). Albers famously wrote, “color deceives continually,” a statement that becomes increasingly true through observing the complex interactions of color he documents in &lt;i&gt;Interaction of Color &lt;/i&gt;(1963). Likewise, Le Corbusier believed color to be “a means as powerful as the ground plan and the section itself.” His designs turn to polychromatic color schemes to create cohesive interiors and generate specific spatial and mood effects. The featured items from Bowes Library’s special collections highlight color as a powerful tool in every kind of art making. Curated by Abigail Schweizer '24. Library hours: M-Th 9-7pm, Friday 9-5pm, Sunday 12-6pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/color-deceives-le-corbusier-josef-albers</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46128272658826/huge/0a824c66a76284724dc3c8f13d7406ff301a51ea.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3264" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="1003108"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keep calm and create at Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Feeling stressed? Take a break in Bowes with origami, puzzles, and coloring books. Available until 6/15. M-Th 9-7, F 9-5, Sun 12-6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/keep-calm-and-create-at-bowes-art-architecture-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46605147291287/huge/a3c87eacf639d6891ac809d613f31fc4c2b5940b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1024" width="768" isDefault="true" fileSize="67262"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Deal &amp; The Federal Writers' Project at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-UT_h28D9ylo9I3qEOfJJXmbaL_Ol8wq4VIw_k6PEU4/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New Deal &amp;amp; The Federal Writers' Project | Selections from the Bruce and Rachel Jeffer Collection&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view May 6, 2024, through January 26, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by childhood automobile trips across the U.S. with his father and a lifelong love of American history and literature, Los Angeles attorney Bruce Jeffer assembled a magnificent collection—totaling nearly two thousand titles—of the Federal Writers’ Project and related WPA and New Deal publications. He and his wife Rachel gifted it to the Stanford Libraries Department of Special Collections in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created as a New Deal program within the Works Progress Administration in 1935, the Federal Writers’ Project (Federal Writers’ Program 1939–1943) employed as many as six thousand writers, researchers, and editors in fifty-two state and territorial offices and produced a prodigious number of publications—including the American Guide Series, oral histories, ethnographies, collections of folklore and books for children—well over one thousand, but likely many more: the exact number is unknowable, and new discoveries have surfaced in the wake of each successive bibliography. Over sixty years, Jeffer’s passion for collecting the output of the Federal Writers’ Project and its offshoots brought him into contact with the foremost antiquarian book dealers of the day, former Writers’ Project employees, and leading collectors across the United States. With his wife Rachel, he made great use of auctions, eBay, and trades with other notable collectors and dealers. Through the decades, he searched for these publications by visiting bookstores in towns and cities around the country, directly contacting booksellers, and later maintaining a private network of like-minded collectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two core influences in Jeffer’s collecting activities were his close relationship with collector Fred Board of Connecticut and collector/book dealer Arthur Scharf of Pennsylvania. Board’s own collection of the State Guides (apart from his larger FWP collection) later served as an inspiration to his great-nephew Scott Borchert, which led Borchert to write his recent excellent history of the Project, &lt;i&gt;Republic of Detours: How the New Deal Paid Broke Writers to Rediscover America&lt;/i&gt; (New York, 2021). Besides selling and trading, Arthur Scharf was a source of bibliographic information on the FWP publications. Like most serious collectors of the FWP, when Evanell Powell self-published her ambitious (if amateur) WPA Writers’ Publication: &lt;i&gt;A complete bibliographic checklist… of items, major and minor, of the Federal Writers' Project and Program&lt;/i&gt; (Palm Beach, 1974), Jeffer took advantage of the information there to hunt for more titles—and to find many titles unknown to Powell, historians, and scholars. Of the over twelve hundred published FWP titles in the Jeffer collection, approximately one hundred and fifty FWP items were unknown to Powell and historians, thus representing an excellent opportunity for further research. The presence of sixteen original, unpublished FWP works adds significantly to the prospects for research in the collection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collecting the often ephemeral publications that characterized the richness and diversity, as well as controversy, of the project’s output, Jeffer has been guided by a desire to document this seminal period in American history, preserve it for posterity, and make it broadly available to students and researchers. In addition to rare published items, Jeffer sought out unpublished material as well—always with an eye for unique material that, in the words of one FWP catalog, embodied the project’s mission of “presenting America to all Americans.”  His collection contains copies of a number of exceedingly scarce titles, typescripts of unpublished works, and presentation copies gifted to New Deal luminaries such as Harry L. Hopkins, as well as publications from allied agencies such as the Federal Art Project, the Museum Extension Project, the Federal Theatre Project, and the Federal Music Project.  &lt;br&gt;
As demonstrated throughout the exhibit, The FWP’s lasting influence on literary and ethnographic work since the 1930s is strong, and the cultural resonance of the project continues unabated—including serving as the inspiration for a proposed twenty-first-century FWP, congressional legislation (Bill # HR 3054) introduced during the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2021 by Reps. Ted Lieu (D-CA and Stanford, B.A., B.S., '91) and Teresa Leger Fernandez (D-NM).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Benjamin Stone, Associate Director of Special Collections and Curator for American and British History; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their expert cataloging of books and manuscripts: Nancy Lorimer, Kay Teel, and their staff in the Metadata Department; For their assessment of materials Kristen St. John and Kimberly Kwan in Conservation Services; For his photography services Wayne Vanderkuil in the Digital Production Group; Glynn Edwards, Ann Myers, Brian Bethel, Gurudarshan Khalsa and especially Esther Wan in the Collection Services division of the Department of Special Collections, and Ben Albritton and Ever Rodriguez in Rare Books, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-deal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46210554145667/huge/5835b820fcd4b2c26aeb7ed65aab8559a0126e81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="71541"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Stress at the Science Library at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:18.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Hello Stanford! Is it just us, or is everyone feeling stressed lately? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:18.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Take a break from studies to lift your inner artist and join the Li &amp;amp; Ma Science Library staff for fun-filled activities to alleviate stress. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress-at-the-science-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46457138488074/huge/e64f1b5ab722e3775240c9d6e39fb6b434cf6c8c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3000" width="4000" isDefault="true" fileSize="3782128"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Stress at Stanford Libraries 2024 at Green Library, east patio</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;DIY calming jars • Ice cream • Dog petting • Succulents • And more! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stop by the Stanford Libraries for some self-care during finals week. De-stress with fun activities, yummy snacks, and more.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library | Thursday, May 30th | 10:00 AM - 2:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/take-a-break-paint-a-rock-grab-a-coffee-spring-2024"&gt;Take a break, paint a rock, grab a coffee!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Take a moment to relax while painting a rock or just stop by the Branner Earth Sciences Library for free coffee, tea, and snacks. We'll have origami and Lego stations too!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Robin Li and Melissa Ma Science Library | Wednesday, June 5th | 11:00 AM - 3:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress-at-the-science-library"&gt;The Science Library will be hosting fun activities&lt;/a&gt; such as making clay figurines, coloring, games, origami, rock painting, and more on the SAPP Center 3rd Floor, Room 315. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Green Library |&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Wednesday, June 5th | 12:00 - 2:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
De-stressing activities at Green will include DIY calming jars, succulents, dog petting, specialty ice cream, as well as pizza and swag compliments of the Stanford Federal Credit Union. A variety of table activities including games, puzzles, and more will be available outside of Green Library, on the patio nearest Coupa Café throughout the event. Puzzles and coloring books will be available inside Green Library throughout finals week as well! See &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/?week=2024W23"&gt;Green Library's open hours during finals week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Terman Engineering Library|&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Wednesday, June 5th | 3:00 - 4:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Stop by the SEQ quad (Y2E2 Courtyard) to &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-6814"&gt;take a break, and pet a dog &lt;/a&gt; Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;More events to come!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/"&gt;library.stanford.edu/hours &lt;/a&gt;to see hours for all libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress-at-stanford-libraries-2024</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43106545934909/huge/9e88278d8a8151d44e293e0361f6ed635b15820c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="677136"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-6814</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center (DRMC) at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the DRMC, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the DRMC, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the DRMC to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Open Gaming at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the program and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_june_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45446035612546/huge/adcdbfb0f6f09ab7ea8fc4c739372bdeddb022a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="192066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: July 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more information on the featured game for July! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Jul 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_july_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45446035612546/huge/adcdbfb0f6f09ab7ea8fc4c739372bdeddb022a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="192066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
