<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>To Trust or Not to Trust: Authenticity by Design at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is at an inflection point. With the growth of mis/disinformation, artificial intelligence and synthetic media, trust in information faces unprecedented threats. Authenticity is not guaranteed. At the same time, new technologies–referred to as “Web 3”–present opportunities to protect the integrity of data. These solutions can be applied to critical practices including investigative journalism, historical archiving, and the admissibility of legal evidence. This exhibit, curated by the &lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/"&gt;Starling Lab for Data Integrity&lt;/a&gt;, asks: How might we design information systems for authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Joshua Roberts/Reuters, “Day 69" (&lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/78daysarchive/"&gt;78 Days Archive&lt;/a&gt;), January 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-authenticity-by-design</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47436587901093/huge/641630e9442e946525a91d66b21735740fa8d98c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="475" width="718" isDefault="true" fileSize="492778"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Native American Heritage Book Display at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come to Green Library and check out a book display that celebrates the indigenous peoples of the United States, in honor of Native American Heritage Month.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 08:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/native-american-heritage-book-display</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47967828152086/huge/390fe47eca248695ba42b1b0bff30f8f73bfa183.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2832" width="2124" isDefault="true" fileSize="1166452"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SCRABrraaNNG! The Explosion of Futurist Poetry at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Bowes Library’s Autumn 2024 exhibition, &lt;i&gt;SCRABrrRrraaNNG! The Explosion of&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Futurist Poetry&lt;/i&gt;, explores the unique history of Italian Futurist poetry during its first period (1909-1918). Futurism, founded by Filippo Tommaso Marinetti in 1909, was a leading avant-garde movement in Europe that rejected history and tradition in the name of technology, dynamism, and violence. In 1912, Marinetti declared war on his Symbolist predecessors, inventing a new form of poetics that tested the limits of typography and aimed to shock readers with obliterated syntax, onomatopoeias, and word-images. On display are featured items from Bowes and Green Libraries' Special Collections, as well as the Futurist Archive's private collection, including Marinetti's seminal work of "words-in-freedom,"&lt;i&gt;Zang&lt;/i&gt; &lt;i&gt;Tumb Tuuum&lt;/i&gt; (1914), and several first editions by other Futurist poets. Curated by Ty Davidian, PhD Candidate in Italian. Sponsored by the Department of French and Italian and the Division of Literatures, Cultures, and Languages. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Library hours: M-Th 9-7pm, Friday 9-5pm, Sunday 12-6pm. Opening reception Oct. 10, 4-6pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/scrabrraanng-the-explosion-of-futurist-poetry</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47634195743312/huge/d56ba229f75b9d12e064fe23910675ed8db55420.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1200" width="1800" isDefault="true" fileSize="1492270"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Deal &amp; The Federal Writers' Project at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-UT_h28D9ylo9I3qEOfJJXmbaL_Ol8wq4VIw_k6PEU4/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New Deal &amp;amp; The Federal Writers' Project | Selections from the Bruce and Rachel Jeffer Collection&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view May 6, 2024, through January 26, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by childhood automobile trips across the U.S. with his father and a lifelong love of American history and literature, Los Angeles attorney Bruce Jeffer assembled a magnificent collection—totaling nearly two thousand titles—of the Federal Writers’ Project and related WPA and New Deal publications. He and his wife Rachel gifted it to the Stanford Libraries Department of Special Collections in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created as a New Deal program within the Works Progress Administration in 1935, the Federal Writers’ Project (Federal Writers’ Program 1939–1943) employed as many as six thousand writers, researchers, and editors in fifty-two state and territorial offices and produced a prodigious number of publications—including the American Guide Series, oral histories, ethnographies, collections of folklore and books for children—well over one thousand, but likely many more: the exact number is unknowable, and new discoveries have surfaced in the wake of each successive bibliography. Over sixty years, Jeffer’s passion for collecting the output of the Federal Writers’ Project and its offshoots brought him into contact with the foremost antiquarian book dealers of the day, former Writers’ Project employees, and leading collectors across the United States. With his wife Rachel, he made great use of auctions, eBay, and trades with other notable collectors and dealers. Through the decades, he searched for these publications by visiting bookstores in towns and cities around the country, directly contacting booksellers, and later maintaining a private network of like-minded collectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two core influences in Jeffer’s collecting activities were his close relationship with collector Fred Board of Connecticut and collector/book dealer Arthur Scharf of Pennsylvania. Board’s own collection of the State Guides (apart from his larger FWP collection) later served as an inspiration to his great-nephew Scott Borchert, which led Borchert to write his recent excellent history of the Project, &lt;i&gt;Republic of Detours: How the New Deal Paid Broke Writers to Rediscover America&lt;/i&gt; (New York, 2021). Besides selling and trading, Arthur Scharf was a source of bibliographic information on the FWP publications. Like most serious collectors of the FWP, when Evanell Powell self-published her ambitious (if amateur) WPA Writers’ Publication: &lt;i&gt;A complete bibliographic checklist… of items, major and minor, of the Federal Writers' Project and Program&lt;/i&gt; (Palm Beach, 1974), Jeffer took advantage of the information there to hunt for more titles—and to find many titles unknown to Powell, historians, and scholars. Of the over twelve hundred published FWP titles in the Jeffer collection, approximately one hundred and fifty FWP items were unknown to Powell and historians, thus representing an excellent opportunity for further research. The presence of sixteen original, unpublished FWP works adds significantly to the prospects for research in the collection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collecting the often ephemeral publications that characterized the richness and diversity, as well as controversy, of the project’s output, Jeffer has been guided by a desire to document this seminal period in American history, preserve it for posterity, and make it broadly available to students and researchers. In addition to rare published items, Jeffer sought out unpublished material as well—always with an eye for unique material that, in the words of one FWP catalog, embodied the project’s mission of “presenting America to all Americans.”  His collection contains copies of a number of exceedingly scarce titles, typescripts of unpublished works, and presentation copies gifted to New Deal luminaries such as Harry L. Hopkins, as well as publications from allied agencies such as the Federal Art Project, the Museum Extension Project, the Federal Theatre Project, and the Federal Music Project.  &lt;br&gt;
As demonstrated throughout the exhibit, The FWP’s lasting influence on literary and ethnographic work since the 1930s is strong, and the cultural resonance of the project continues unabated—including serving as the inspiration for a proposed twenty-first-century FWP, congressional legislation (Bill # HR 3054) introduced during the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2021 by Reps. Ted Lieu (D-CA and Stanford, B.A., B.S., '91) and Teresa Leger Fernandez (D-NM).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Benjamin Stone, Associate Director of Special Collections and Curator for American and British History; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their expert cataloging of books and manuscripts: Nancy Lorimer, Kay Teel, and their staff in the Metadata Department; For their assessment of materials Kristen St. John and Kimberly Kwan in Conservation Services; For his photography services Wayne Vanderkuil in the Digital Production Group; Glynn Edwards, Ann Myers, Brian Bethel, Gurudarshan Khalsa and especially Esther Wan in the Collection Services division of the Department of Special Collections, and Ben Albritton and Ever Rodriguez in Rare Books, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-deal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46210554145667/huge/5835b820fcd4b2c26aeb7ed65aab8559a0126e81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="71541"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Naturally Hazardous: Impacts at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Naturally Hazardous&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the cosmically unavoidable to the anthropogenically-induced, Earth can be naturally hazardous to humans. In the 2024-25 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature the science and impact of volcanoes, wildfires, drought, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
November 4 - November 30: From asteroid collisions to the formation of the Earth’s most dramatic landscapes, discover the science and spectacle of impact cratering in our November exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  The exhibit is available for viewing throughout the month during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-naturally-hazardous-impacts</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47968374647782/huge/2b2bc4291c09a568cf0d638fbdca6a1901453df8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="540" width="540" isDefault="true" fileSize="102915"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheonggea Ilsu Cha: Grasp the essence, and the form fades away at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;청계 차일수: 득의망상 (得意忘象)&lt;br&gt;
Cheonggea Ilsu Cha: Grasp the Essence, and the Form Fades Away&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stanford East Asia Library presents an exhibition by the South Korean artist Cheonggea Ilsu Cha from November 18, 2024 to February 20, 2025. Artist Cha has dedicated his 40-year career to the mastery of ‘literati’ painting.  The literati genre combines written word with a painterly interpretation of text, a form of art that has been practiced by the scholarly elite in Korea for over 400 years. His work has been featured at the prestigious Grand Art Exhibition of Korea, and he has held eight solo exhibitions.&lt;br&gt;
A significant number of Korean scholars practiced literati painting during the Joseon Dynasty, which extended from 1392 to 1897. Literati painting reflects the scholar’s observation, understanding and interpretation of a poetic topic. The artist strives for aesthetic discipline; the text must be no longer than what the topic minimally requires. So too must the artist seek simplicity in his visual vocabulary.  The exhibition is inspired by the philosophy of Tŭgŭi mangsang (得意忘象), which emphasizes abandoning artifice in order to seek the true nature of things.  The works at the exhibition employ the use of ink and a constrained palette of color using materials such as traditional Korean paper, scrolls, and fans. The paintings touch on a wide variety of topics, from nature to philosophical reflections to expressions of human emotion. Cha’s work is inspired by the artistic sensibility of his predecessors. Visitors to the museum will find paintings imbued with a classic aesthetic, timeless charm, and a lively wit.&lt;br&gt;
This exhibition of Cha’s Korean literati paintings was curated by Jee-Young Park, Korean Studies Librarian at Stanford East Asia Library; Ji Soo Kim, M.A. in  Museum Studies from San Francisco State University; and Wooju Chong, M. A. in Center for East Asian Studies from Stanford University, in consultation with the East Asia Library Exhibits Committee.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cheonggea-ilsu-cha-grasp-the-essence-and-the-form-fades-away</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48041771240023/huge/261eed6631f369912267440e775bf36888eaba1c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3391" width="3342" isDefault="true" fileSize="1588901"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Text Analysis in Python</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Curious about how to work with text data using Python? Join us for a practical introduction to text analysis, tailored for those new to programming. This workshop will cover key techniques, including text pre-processing, named entity recognition, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis. No prior Python experience is necessary. We’ll guide you through foundational Python concepts, introduce essential libraries and modules for text analysis, and provide hands-on examples to support your learning. This event is a great starting point for discovering the potential of Python in working with text data, and will inspire you to learn Python to gain even greater insights and capabilities. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScsE5dLHdRNpRUS9dtzex3fYkCfecOwjVi9q5veEUaznhm5KA/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. This workshop is open exclusively to current Stanford affiliates, and registration will be on a first-come, first-served basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your SUNet ID to access the registration form.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Location: Virtual (A zoom link will be sent to registrants one week before the event.)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Date and Time: 11:00 AM to 1:00 PM, Tuesday, November 19, 2024&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm, Head of Data Science Training and Consultation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro-to-text-analysis-in-python</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47924603342857/huge/5e5d37e6e6d847914848120c3c0c8c5768c4298a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="31801"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Webinar workshop for My China Roots: A database for researching the Chinese diaspora available at Stanford</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;On November 19, please join the webinar about &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14742404" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;My China Roots&lt;/a&gt;, a family history database available to the Stanford community and featuring historical records of Chinese immigrant communities from North America to Southeast Asia and the Caribbean. This session will be relevant to individuals exploring their Chinese family history, as well as any students of Asian American Studies, Ethnic Studies, Chinese/East Asian Studies, Chinese American history, migration and diaspora, and anthropology. Clotilde Yap, representative of the database producer, will provide a live demo of the database and tips on how to search the collections. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/webinar-workshop-for-my-china-roots</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47996896002803/huge/b118b81a21b998bea639183936761e2ab492d690.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="1545" isDefault="true" fileSize="2944772"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A checklist to guide sensitivity analyses and replications of impact evaluations (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This month the Bay Area Open Science Group will be joined by Sridevi Prasad. Sridevi is a second-year PhD student in Global Health and Development at the Emory Rollins School of Public Health, specializing in water, sanitation and hygiene. Prior to Emory, she was a Senior Research Associate at the International Initiative for Impact Evaluation (3ie), where she was involved in their Transparency, Reproducibility and Ethical Evaluation Initiative. Sridevi will discuss a checklist to guide sensitivity analyses and replications of impact evaluations.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/checklist-to-guide-sensitivity-analyses</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48040710051931/huge/1546f1557552634548bdf4f329d63a4101a3b07a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Medium Management: the multimedia world of Mind MGMT at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;For November, we'll be diving into the multimedia world of &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/in00000204673"&gt;Mind MGMT&lt;/a&gt;, a hidden movement game about psychic espionage based on the comic book series of the same name by Matt Kindt, and the question: what does it mean to adapt a visual story into a board game? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Image: Matt Kindt, &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/in00000192817"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mind MGMT&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2019). &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-november-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48038688210963/huge/afd0abce45855a0a0e089de45967eb03d5a610c7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="327" width="465" isDefault="true" fileSize="406983"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epicenters: Navigating Recovery and Renewal from Disasters at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;In the wake of disaster, maps play many roles, shaping understanding of the event in the immediate aftermath, serving as visceral portrayals for those who were not there, and communicating both scale and extent of the tragedy. They gavanize support for rebuilding by showing new possible futures and can be used to memorialize the event, inscribing the memory over the landscape. Drawing upon sources from historical representations to contemporary satellite imagery, the maps in this exhibition explore various ways communities use maps to make sense of calamity and move forward from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford student Muhammad Dhafer, winner of the 2024 California Map Society student exhibition competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This exhibition is ongoing and will be available until February 28th, 2024. To view the exhibit, visit the David Rumsey Map Center during its public drop-in hours.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/epicenters-navigating-recovery-and-renewal-from-disasters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426635</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167076</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47684547090877/huge/3760917787646284b7c17d5db40811eb358972fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1229" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="562133"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISDay@Stanford 2024 at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;GISDay@Stanford 2024&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GISDay@Stanford 2024 will spotlight the theme "GeoAI: The intersection of spatial data science and AI/ML methods and technology." The event, held at The David Rumsey Map Center, will feature talks that delve into how AI and machine learning are transforming the ways we approach geospatial challenges. Attendees will gain insights into cutting-edge technologies and their applications, from the analysis of remote sensing data to enhancing urban planning and sustainability efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year’s agenda includes a keynote by Steve Citron-Pousty, who will discuss AI/ML vector data workflows, followed by a presentation from Stace Maples, outlining geospatial resources and their impact on AI research. The day will also feature lightning talks, showcasing innovative projects from various sectors, including AI applications in Stanford’s vast map collections, presented by Evan Thornberry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cameron Kruse of Earth Genome will close the event with a talk on foundational models and their role in geospatial data science. GISDay@Stanford 2024 will conclude with a "Mappy Hour" at The Treehouse, offering attendees an opportunity to connect with peers and discuss future directions for GeoAI. With this agenda, the event promises to inspire and foster collaboration in the fast-evolving field of GeoAI.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;GISDay@Stanford 2024&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Tentative) Agenda &amp;amp; Schedule&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:30 PM – 1:35 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Opening Remarks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Welcome and introduction to the event.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:35 PM – 2:30 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Learning Keynote: Steve Citron-Pousty - Founder, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.techravenconsulting.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tech Raven Consulting&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Quick Intro to AI/ML Vector Data for Geospatial Folks"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869804739%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-191602?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=96e2eff03571ad2f2fd776b0a24d9272"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the last two years, AI machine learning has exploded in prominence. One of the key concepts used in the modeling and storage of AI is vectors. There is no doubt vector data management will be a key concern of most people concerned with the lifecycle of data management. Feeling like you should learn more and how you would use them in your data work? Then have I got a talk for you!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will start by explaining the concept of (embedding) vectors and how they are used in the AI life cycle. From there we will go into putting them into a database.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that those vectors are in a database we can talk about the use cases where the technology makes sense. As opposed to an RDBMS, vector databases are more tightly focused and optimized for particular use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ground this discussion in something more concrete, we will show live demos of the technology throughout the talks. By the time you leave you will have a strong base to go home and explore more (and impress friends at dinner parties).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869724069%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-180306?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=023f865faedb737110916598deeed29e"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2:30 PM – 2:50 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stace Maples, Head of The Stanford Geospatial Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Food for Thought: Stanford Geospatial Center resources for your ML/AI research and projects"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869804909%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-191610?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=15b38cb90fa709af7c148cba2e79d102"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Food for Thought: Stanford Geospatial Center resources for your ML/AI research and projects"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Updates on support and services provided by the Stanford Geospatial Center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Planet.com Planetscope &amp;amp; SkySat access.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;AIS Data access from SPIRE - Global Shipping Trajectories and Metadata&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Using Google Earth Engine with your own Google Cloud Project for access to the Earth Engine Python API and more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;High throughput Geocoding Services with &lt;a href="https://locator.stanford.edu/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;locator.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869725319%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-180405?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=0b065a5a02bf33bee371c70d88524b99"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;2:50 PM – 3:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Break&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10-minute restroom break and networking opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:00 PM – 3:30 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lightning Talks (5-minutes each)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;TBA Lightning Talk 1&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;TBA Lightning Talk 2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;TBA Lightning Talk 3&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;TBA Lightning Talk 4&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;TBA Lightning Talk 5&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:30 PM – 3:50 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Evan Thornberry, Head &amp;amp; Curator of the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Looking ahead with legacy collections: How computer vision and AI are helping unlock the hidden knowledge within Stanford’s map collections."&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869805019%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-191616?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=c5dc3bda3a699400790e668e6893cfeb"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An overview of two AI projects: &lt;a href="https://machines-reading-maps.github.io/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Machines Reading Maps&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href="https://github.com/maps-as-data/MapReader" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Map Reader&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A description of the current state of using them on &lt;a href="https://davidrumsey.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;davidrumsey.com&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How to stay in the loop and involved.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869727999%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-180615?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=25c3c5de334787e95af075fdd48c64e1"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:50 PM – 4:30 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Applied Keynote: Cameron Kruse, Creative Technologist, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.earthgenome.org/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Earth Genome&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Harnessing the power of geospatial foundation models to empower end users"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869805159%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-191622?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=d970a29c0889c9150e3d7ec1046cc943"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cameron is a Creative Technologist with Earth Genome and a National Geographic Explorer. At Earth Genome Cameron leads the Plotline, an initiative exploring the intersection of food systems and climate change, and supports product and development of Earth Index. In his work with National Geographic, Cameron has led several expeditions where he has produced films, photo essays, and interactive map based stories focused on rural communities and climate change. In his free time, you may find him trail running or struggling to climb large rocks in Yosemite. Learn more about Cameron’s work at cameronwkruse.com or reach out on social media @camkruse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F869728799%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20241008-180655?h=740&amp;amp;w=1200&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=cf1fb0c7ee0e42251ff5efbc31491b70"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;4:30 PM – 4:45 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Closing Remarks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wrap-up, final thoughts and grab some swag.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;4:45 PM – ??? PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us at The Treehouse at Tressider for Mappy Hour!!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2024 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/gisdaystanford-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47728203852493/huge/dc3fb440c8a7c2638329b9e5420a5fe34804a4d4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="4749944"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the Winners of the 2024 Saroyan Prize at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us as we celebrate the winners of the &lt;b&gt;2024 William Saroyan International Prize for Writing&lt;/b&gt;!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Mirinae Lee&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
fiction winner and author of&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;8 Lives of a Century-Old Trickster&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&amp;amp;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Fae Myenne Ng&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
nonfiction winner and author of&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Orphan Bachelors&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, December 3, 2024&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
4:30 to 6:30 pm&lt;br&gt;
Green Library, 5th floor, Bender Room&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
At the event, the authors will read from their books and copies will be available for purchase and signing.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf2xD2IvQ_tQRjY_hfvsAVmQLDz8uYhEkusdy8bOfFUrVi7yw/viewform"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register if you would like to attend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/8-lives-of-a-century-old-trickster-mirinae-lee?variant=40901179047970"&gt;&lt;i&gt;8 Lives of a Century-Old Trickster&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Harper, 2023), a novel by Mirinae Lee, and &lt;a href="https://groveatlantic.com/book/orphan-bachelors/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Orphan Bachelors&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Grove Press, 2023), a memoir by Fae Myenne Ng, are the recipients of the 2024 William Saroyan International Prize for Writing administered by Stanford University Libraries and the William Saroyan Foundation. The biennial prize honors the life and legacy of novelist, playwright, and short-story author William Saroyan by encouraging and recognizing new and emerging writers.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/mirinae-lee-and-fae-myenne-ng-awarded-2024-william-saroyan-international-prize-writing"&gt;Learn more about the winners and their books&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2024-saroyan-prize</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47757666747832/huge/a516912eb83458ea3018c09ffd0e042b69de13e4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="163774"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A World Made By Travel: The Digital Grand Tour at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;A World Made By Travel: The Digital Grand Tour&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exploring the Challenges and Opportunities of Digital History and Publishing&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Event:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Travel back to eighteenth-century Italy as we explore &lt;i&gt;A World Made by Travel&lt;/i&gt;, a pioneering digital history publication in open access by esteemed Stanford scholar &lt;b&gt;Giovanna Ceserani&lt;/b&gt;. Through this interactive work combining data and humanistic approaches, Ceserani and her team illuminate the journeys of more than 6,000 travelers who embarked on the Grand Tour, a popular rite of passage for young Europeans that helped shape cultural and political perspectives across the continent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Giovanna Ceserani&lt;/b&gt; will be joined by panelists &lt;b&gt;Paula Findlen &lt;/b&gt;(world-renowned scholar of early modern Europe and Ubaldo Pierotti Professor of History at Stanford), &lt;b&gt;Mae Velloso-Lyons &lt;/b&gt;(Associate Director of the Fox Center for Humanistic Inquiry and Digital Publishing in the Humanities at Emory University),&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Rochelle Lundy &lt;/b&gt;(Director of the Stanford Libraries Office of Scholarly Communications and expert of Open Access policies).&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Together they will&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;examine how digital technology using data and dynamic tools in open access brings new insights into historical research, enabling us to rediscover the Grand Tour’s impact on Enlightenment ideas about art, politics, leisure, and education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Event Highlights&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:30 - 3 PM: Presentation and Panel Discussion&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event will open with &lt;b&gt;Giovanna Ceserani’s&lt;/b&gt; introduction of her digital publication &lt;i&gt;A World Made by Travel&lt;/i&gt;. Following this, respondents &lt;b&gt;Paula Findlen&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Mae Velloso-Lyons&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Rochelle Lundy&lt;/b&gt; will speak about the unique challenges and exciting possibilities of digital history and open-access publishing. The discussion will cover how digital formats in open access can reveal hidden histories, democratize access to academic work, and reshape our understanding of complex historical narratives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3 - 4 PM: Interactive Digital Display&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Attendees will have the opportunity to engage directly with &lt;i&gt;A World Made by Travel&lt;/i&gt; on interactive screens, exploring data visualizations and stories of diverse Grand Tour travelers. This immersive experience allows users to delve into the digital maps and timelines that trace the lives and paths of travelers from all backgrounds who contributed to this transformative period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eighteenth-Century Primary Sources&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a richer historical context, a curated set of original eighteenth-century sources will be on display, providing attendees with a tangible connection to the narratives highlighted in Ceserani’s digital work. This viewing will offer a hands-on experience of the artifacts that document these historical journeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeZXn2VcB9pwQjntyM_1hFtq1Se6g7YnNjK92gRpI_z9mF9AA/viewform"&gt;Please register in advance to attend&lt;/a&gt;. This event is in-person only. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/a-world-made-by-travel-the-digital-grand-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48029885381094/huge/8e8aebb22da5338ca888901fcf5f206a37c04ec2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="450930"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-293</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: December 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2024 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-december-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: January 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-january-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
