<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Accessible/Assistive: Addressing Barriers to Information with Technology at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Accessible technology is designed to be inclusive of the needs of all users; assistive technology is created to enhance the daily lives of people with specific disabilities. Both types of technology are vital to a library&amp;rsquo;s ability to address barriers to information for its patrons. This exhibit provides an overview of past and present forms of accessible and assistive technology used on Stanford&amp;rsquo;s campus.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curated through a collaborative effort of Stanford University Libraries (Natalie Jean Marine-Street, Oral History Program Manager, Stanford Historical Society; Rebecca Pernell, Associate Director &amp;amp; Head, Access Services; Josh Schneider, University Archivist; Hilary Thorsen, Resource Sharing Librarian; Kristen Valenti, Exhibits Coordinator, Silicon Valley Archives), the Office of Digital Accessibility (Auston Stamm, Digital Accessibility Instructional Specialist), the Office of Accessible Education (Robin Cole, Alternate Format &amp;amp; Assistive Technology Manager), as well as former Telesensory Inc. employees &amp;amp; the Optacon community (Judy Adams; Joan Bliss; Steve Brugler; Richard Oehm; Noel Runyan).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/access_assist</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42880951248689/huge/24ffc9e94de7600a974652eaf126cef4cb375203.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="452" width="482" isDefault="true" fileSize="439247"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected Technology at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drawing from archival collections across Stanford, this exhibit explores the unexpected, overlooked, and surprising results of the multi-dimensional relationships between technology and culture. Two simple concepts inform this exploration. First, technology is everywhere. Second, &amp;ldquo;technology is neither good nor bad, nor is it neutral&amp;rdquo; (Mel Kranzberg&amp;rsquo;s famous &amp;ldquo;first law&amp;rdquo;).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Curated by a cross-departmental team: Hanna Ahn, Assistant University Archivist; Tamar Barzel, Head Librarian, Music Library &amp;amp; Archive of Recorded Sound; Chris Doan, Hohbach Archivist; Spencer Gondorf, Curatorial Assistant, History of Science &amp;amp; Technology Collections; Eitan Lev Kensky, Reinhard Family Curator of Judaica &amp;amp; Hebraica Collections; Kevin Kishimoto, Head of Music Metadata Services; C. Ryan Perkins, Curator for South Asian Studies, Islamic Studies, &amp;amp; the Baha&amp;rsquo;i Collection; Chloe Pfendler, Hohbach Archivist; Margarita Nafpaktitis, Curator for Slavic &amp;amp; East European Collections; Kathleen Smith, Curator for Germanic Collections &amp;amp; Medieval Studies; and Sarah Sussman, Curator for French &amp;amp; Italian Collections; Head, Humanities &amp;amp; Area Studies Resource Group. Organized by Kristen Valenti, Exhibits Coordinator, Silicon Valley Archives, with consultation and introduction by Henry Lowood, Harold C. Hohbach Curator for History of Science &amp;amp; Technology Collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/unexpected_tech</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42880922249072/huge/9e5b4f3bb1773b19cdd5bd25c519e69ddda5be82.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1164" width="1394" isDefault="true" fileSize="2848188"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to ArcGIS Pro (April 21st) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Introduction to ArcGIS Pro&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using ArcGIS Pro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Topics covered:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Downloading and licensing through Stanford&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up a new Map Project&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ArcGIS Pro user interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Loading and styling spatial data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis Tools (Spatial Joins, Overlay Analysis)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Map Layout and Exports&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required: &lt;/b&gt;The Branner Library teaching space only has 3 workstations so all workshop attendees will be required to bring in their own laptops. ArcGIS Pro is a Windows only application, but it can be run from a Windows or Mac laptop through the Stanford Virtual Computer Cluster (Apporto): &lt;a href="https://stanford.apporto.com"&gt;https://stanford.apporto.com&lt;/a&gt;/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_arcgis_pro_april_21st</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42084995207236/huge/34851c63f22d9677ca6a7c553f49105fe9fbb397.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="217754"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Photographs of Rod Dresser at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Photographs of Rod Dresser&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view March 3, 2023, through May 7, 2023, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_photographs_of_rod_dresser</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42399897509627/huge/20e948668a25dcc3861d6d013c6c3f452068bb5d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="211604"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Machines Reading Maps Summit Workshop @ CESTA: Search Within Maps! at CESTA, 4th floor of Wallenberg Hall, 450 Jane Stanford Way </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This hands-on workshop hosted by &lt;a href="https://cesta.stanford.edu" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;CESTA &lt;/a&gt;(Center for Spatial and Textual Analysis) presents the new, experimental features developed by the &lt;a href="https://machines-reading-maps.github.io/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Machines Reading Maps (MRM)&lt;/a&gt; project for the &lt;a href="https://davidrumsey.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;David Rumsey Map Collection (DRMC)&lt;/a&gt; and introduces new ways to explore and analyze digitized map collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This is an in-person only event. Please, bring your own laptop.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the first part of the workshop, participants will experience search and visualization driven by the application of the &lt;i&gt;mapKurator&lt;/i&gt; machine-learning pipeline. Through the discussion of guided paths through the large and diverse Rumsey collection, participants will become familiar with the different kinds of queries that can be run when it is possible to search the maps not just by their title and metadata but their full text.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the second half of the workshop, participants will learn to navigate the corpus of map text, select a relevant sample, and then interrogate, visualize and compare within an open dataset that has been created by processing circa 60,000 georeferenced maps in the DRMC. The MRM team will guide attendees through a computational workflow using simple Jupyter and Observable notebooks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop does not require any previous computational knowledge, but some familiarity with Jupyter notebooks is welcome. To prepare, check out this tutorial on Jupyter notebooks: &lt;a href="https://programminghistorian.org/en/lessons/jupyter-notebooks" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://programminghistorian.org/en/lessons/jupyter-notebooks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop will take place at CESTA on the 4th floor of Wallenberg Hall, 450 Jane Stanford Way at Stanford University. Registration is required to attend as space is limited.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We strongly recommend COVID-19 testing prior and masks during the event. Do attend if you are experiencing symptoms of illness.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/machines_reading_maps_summit_workshop_cesta_search_within_maps</link>
      <geo:lat>37.42766</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.17006</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42960516114724/huge/3946e40e48016a2e0e78def4fbfcc7a8cabbc8a5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="2160" isDefault="true" fileSize="1555459"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 3 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385314" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/6_Core_concepts_vocabularies.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_3_3486</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403929043465/huge/7852e90c3de8b3b45eb2a7e927e8234714d6dfe7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How the Estonian Model Can Expand Economic Opportunity in America: Fireside Chat with Avik Roy at Cecil H. Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for a fireside chat with Avik Roy, President of the Foundation for Research on Equal Opportunity, and Karen Jagodin, Director of Vabamu, who will discuss:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;How the Estonian Model Can Expand Economic Opportunity in America&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its best, the United States is a dynamic society in which people can rise from humble origins to achieve amazing things. But many Americans still struggle to rise, due to the increasing cost of living, inflexible public services, and barriers to economic and political competition. In many of these areas, tiny Estonia has leapfrogged the U.S. with its remarkable digital infrastructure. How can the Estonian model help Americans do better?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Panelists:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Avik Roy&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the President of the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://freopp.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Foundation for Research on Equal Opportunity&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(FREOPP.org), a non-partisan, non-profit think tank that conducts original research on expanding opportunity to those who least have it. Roy&amp;rsquo;s work has been praised widely on both the right and the left.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;National Review&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;has called him one of the nation&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;sharpest policy minds,&amp;rdquo; while the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo; Paul Krugman described him as a man of &amp;ldquo;personal and moral courage.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roy serves as the Policy Editor at&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Forbes&lt;/i&gt;, where he writes on politics and policy. His writing has also appeared in The&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Wall&lt;/i&gt;&lt;i&gt; Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;, The&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, The&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Washington Post&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;USA Today&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;National Review&lt;/i&gt;, and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;National Affairs&lt;/i&gt;, among other publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roy is an Aspen Institute Health Innovators Fellow. He serves on the advisory boards of the National Institute for Health Care Management, the Milken Center for Advancing the American Dream, the Cicero Institute, and the Bitcoin Policy Institute; is a Senior Advisor to the Bipartisan Policy Center; co-chaired the Fixing Veterans Health Care Policy Taskforce; and serves on the Boards of Directors of CrowdHealth and the Texas Bitcoin Foundation. From 2011 to 2016, Roy served as a Senior Fellow at the Manhattan Institute for Policy Research. Previously, he served as an analyst and portfolio manager at Bain Capital, J.P. Morgan, and other firms, where he invested in biotechnology and healthcare companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Karen Jagodin&lt;/b&gt; serves as the CEO of &lt;a href="https://www.vabamu.ee/"&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/a&gt; (Tallinn, Estonia). Karen graduated from the Estonian Academy of Art in art theory and University College London, Bartlett School of Architecture with MA in architectural history. Before joining Vabamu, Karen worked at the Museum of Estonian Architecture and the Estonian Maritime Museum and has led a number of major projects on the museum scene. She is a member of the Estonian Museum Association and the Estonian Society of Art Historians and Curators.&lt;br /&gt;
At Vabamu, Karen has been the primary driver behind the &amp;#39;Why Estonia?&amp;#39; exhibition on digital society, overseeing its development and successful opening in November 2021. Vabamu is the largest active non-profit museum in Estonia with a mission to educate the people of Estonia and its visitors about the recent past and the fragility of freedom and to advocate for justice and the rule of law. It operates in three areas: Vabamu Museums, Youth Engagement, and Global Conversations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Admission Info&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is free and open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to attend the event in person,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/vqLDyMjAW1TqEBng8" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;RSVP is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event can also be followed via &lt;a href="https://livestream.com/accounts/1973198/opportunity-2023"&gt;live stream&lt;/a&gt;. No registration is needed to watch the live stream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is part of the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2022/04/stanford-libraries-and-vabamu-launch-global-conversations"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and seminars focusing on the benefits and fragility of freedom, and is hosted by Stanford University Libraries and co-sponsored by The Europe Center and Center for Russian, East European, and Eurasian Studies.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Avik-Roy-Karen-Jagodin-Estonian-Model</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42616993019154/huge/0b6efdf890ee2ebf629e13a303ee88b2efcc7982.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="935" width="1400" isDefault="true" fileSize="69201"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performing Intermedia in Japan – Day 1 at Levinthal Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many examples in traditional Japanese cultural forms that involve intermedia performance, including&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh, Bunraku,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Kabuki&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;These&amp;nbsp;theatrical genres bring together spoken or sung text, acting, visual staging, costume, movement, and music into true intermedia performances.&amp;nbsp;The international symposium&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;focuses on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a prime example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, these rich intermedia forms were studied almost exclusively through the narrow lens of particular disciplinary specializations &amp;mdash; for example, it is still common for theater to be discussed as literature, with print as its dominant publication format. This approach has inadvertently limited what could be shown of these works&amp;rsquo; intermedia character. The website &amp;ldquo;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://noh.stanford.edu/"&gt;Noh as Intermedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;rdquo; is a digital humanities project that aims to address this limitation. It illustrates&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo;s intermedia character by presenting its unique form as an extraordinarily sophisticated and thorough interplay of media beyond mere printed texts. This highly interactive project is intended to help advance a new approach to&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;that is integrative of all its interacting media, both in perspective and delivery.&amp;nbsp;The international symposium &amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo; was inspired by the enthusiastic reactions of colleagues across the disciplines as they have engaged with this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The symposium&amp;rsquo;s combined focus on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;, intermediality, and digital humanities is a natural follow-up, offering a space for scholars interested in these topics to share their views and ideas. The two-day symposium will engage a variety of formats including papers, audio-visual presentations, panel discussions, exhibits, and an evening performance. The symposium schedule and all individual sessions can be explored &lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/events/symposium-performing-intermedia"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the evening concert is open to the public,&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;registration is&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;required&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;for all symposium sessions. Please register in advance for &amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo;&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/performing-intermedia-in-japan-tickets-596218083337"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Day 1 presentation abstracts can be viewed &lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/events/symposium-performing-intermedia/day-1"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/performing_intermedia_in_japan_day_1</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42775936857314/huge/af0fb9e3f0b4a07fca8b59a8202d8b37c67126c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="800" width="1193" isDefault="true" fileSize="658754"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performing Intermedia in Japan – Lecture &amp; Demonstration: Noh as Intermedia at Dinkelspiel Auditorium</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many examples in traditional Japanese cultural forms that involve intermedia performance, including&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh, Bunraku,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Kabuki&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;These&amp;nbsp;theatrical genres bring together spoken or sung text, acting, visual staging, costume, movement, and music into true intermedia performances.&amp;nbsp;The international symposium&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;focuses on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a prime example.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two-day symposium will include an evening lecture and demonstration, &lt;i&gt;Noh as Intermedia&lt;/i&gt;, presented by &lt;b&gt;Professor&amp;nbsp;Takanori Fujita&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;along with artists from Japan using excerpts from&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;theater works to demonstrate stylistic characteristics of the genre. This&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;event in &lt;/span&gt;Dinkelspiel Auditorium&amp;nbsp;is &lt;span&gt;free and open to the public&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;. The program&amp;#39;s details can be viewed&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/events/symposium-performing-intermedia/concert"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
This event will be livestreamed &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/noh_as_intermedia_live"&gt;here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2023 19:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/performing_intermedia_in_japan_lecture_demonstration</link>
      <geo:lat>37.424086</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.16997</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42776108165100/huge/9ff4403decb658eb2500fc5b65fe98154d8c03b8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="944" width="1800" isDefault="true" fileSize="1110956"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Performing Intermedia in Japan – Day 2 at Levinthal Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many examples in traditional Japanese cultural forms that involve intermedia performance, including&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh, Bunraku,&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Kabuki&lt;/i&gt;.&amp;nbsp;These&amp;nbsp;theatrical genres bring together spoken or sung text, acting, visual staging, costume, movement, and music into true intermedia performances.&amp;nbsp;The international symposium&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;&amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;focuses on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;as a prime example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, these rich intermedia forms were studied almost exclusively through the narrow lens of particular disciplinary specializations &amp;mdash; for example, it is still common for theater to be discussed as literature, with print as its dominant publication format. This approach has inadvertently limited what could be shown of these works&amp;rsquo; intermedia character. The website &amp;ldquo;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://noh.stanford.edu/"&gt;Noh as Intermedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;rdquo; is a digital humanities project that aims to address this limitation. It illustrates&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;rsquo;s intermedia character by presenting its unique form as an extraordinarily sophisticated and thorough interplay of media beyond mere printed texts. This highly interactive project is intended to help advance a new approach to&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;that is integrative of all its interacting media, both in perspective and delivery.&amp;nbsp;The international symposium &amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo; was inspired by the enthusiastic reactions of colleagues across the disciplines as they have engaged with this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The symposium&amp;rsquo;s combined focus on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Noh&lt;/i&gt;, intermediality, and digital humanities is a natural follow-up, offering a space for scholars interested in these topics to share their views and ideas. The two-day symposium will engage a variety of formats including papers, audio-visual presentations, panel discussions, exhibits, and an evening performance. The symposium schedule and all individual sessions can be explored &lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/events/symposium-performing-intermedia"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the evening concert is open to the public,&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;registration is&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;required&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;for all symposium sessions. Please register in advance for &amp;ldquo;Performing Intermedia in Japan&amp;rdquo;&lt;b&gt; &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/performing-intermedia-in-japan-tickets-596218083337"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Day 2 presentation abstracts can be viewed &lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/events/symposium-performing-intermedia/day-2"&gt;&lt;b&gt;here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/performing_intermedia_in_japan_day_2</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42775936857314/huge/af0fb9e3f0b4a07fca8b59a8202d8b37c67126c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="800" width="1193" isDefault="true" fileSize="658754"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bob Stein on The Tapestry Project at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives on April 26 in welcoming Bob Stein as he leads a discussion on The Tapestry Project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s call it . . . the print era is officially over. We now live in a networked digital world. As a result everything is breaking and everything is being born anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New forms of expression are emerging. We may not know the specifics, but two aspects are coming into focus &amp;mdash; a) expository text is being dislodged as the principal medium of intellectual discourse and b) the creation and consumption of media are increasingly social activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, people need tools that foster collaboration &amp;mdash; finally realizing the vision of the internet&amp;rsquo;s founders who understood that the problems facing humanity are too complex for individuals to solve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tapestry Project answers this challenge with a paradigm-breaking new tool that anyone can use to construct a non-linear landscape of ideas and the connections between them &amp;mdash; a new form of writing which allows readers to interact directly with the author&amp;rsquo;s ideas and the sources they are based on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Stein was the founder of The Criterion Collection, The Voyager Company and The Institute for the Future of the Book. Currently, he heads up The Tapestry Project at the Internet Archive. In 2018 Bob donated his extensive analog and digital archives to Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bob_stein_on_the_tapestry_project</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42669238566991/huge/a8d42572f76f6496f6d7d59ac24e1d5e8f575f5b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="881" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="1139204"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the Provenance of a Medieval Manuscript: A Step-by-Step Demonstration with Peter Kidd at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wondered how a medieval European manuscript, written many hundreds of years ago, could make its way into the collections of a relatively young university in California? The Department of Special Collections, Stanford Libraries, holds hundreds of medieval manuscript fragments and dozens of manuscript codices. What paths did these items take to get here, whose hands did they pass through, what information can we glean from them about previous owners, collectors, and book dealers, and how can that in turn inform our understanding of these objects?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next Stanford Manuscript Sciences gathering focuses on the discipline of provenance in a workshop with world-renowned expert Peter Kidd. Through his work describing and investigating manuscripts for Christie&amp;#39;s and Sotheby&amp;#39;s auction houses, and his role as Curator of Illuminated Manuscripts at the British Library, he has developed a rich and encyclopedic understanding of the ways medieval manuscripts move through our modern world. Since 2006, as a freelance researcher, he has contributed to our knowledge of provenance through his research and teaching, especially his annual courses on provenance research, codicology, and cataloging for the International Palaeography Summer School, and his scholarly blog where he shares the fruits of his research labors, &lt;a href="https://mssprovenance.blogspot.com/"&gt;Medieval Manuscripts Provenance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same workshop will be given on two different days so that we can accommodate as many campus attendees as possible in the Special Collections teaching room in Hohbach Hall (HH123). Space is limited, so please register either for the morning workshop on Thursday, April 27, or the afternoon workshop on Friday, April 28.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event sponsored by Stanford Libraries, Stanford Global Studies, and Stanford Manuscript Studies&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Apr 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_provenance_of_medieval_manuscripts_a_workshop_with_peter_kidd</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42845788025688/huge/6b405180ea2ea950c5af642395aa154823a56f09.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1183" width="1344" isDefault="true" fileSize="305566"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing 101 at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing_101_6466</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42094555601095/huge/9b1fdae1c13deb81d532fdc7addfb630933ffcfb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 4 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385321" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/8_spaCy_textaCy.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_4_4169</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403927605041/huge/bd37cdff710bef443b051c0911b46fa4b094bb3f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ato Quayson: Suffering and Tragedy from the Greeks to Toni Morrison at Green Library, Bing Wing, 5th floor, Bender Room </title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please join us for a hybrid event featuring Professor Ato Quayson.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;In this lecture Professor Quayson will proffer working definitions of suffering and tragedy drawing first on the violent disagreements in the history of tragedy from the Greeks through Shakespeare to more modern tragedies and on the relationship of these violent disagreements to different forms of historical transition.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Quayson will also explore the fraught individual processes of self-production in different historical epochs and the ambiguation of attitudes to individual and collective pasts that are the outcomes of these transitions. The lecture will draw on examples from a wide range of traditions and cultures but will settle on the works of Chinua Achebe and Toni Morrison to anchor the main terms of the argument.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To attend in person, please register &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Fqmev6sdKAg6SBmz8" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;To attend online, please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_WTqBFKzpRPe0ozXaYIAeQQ" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Ato Quayson&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Chair of the Department of English and the Jean G. and Morris M. Doyle Professor in Interdisciplinary Studies and Professor of English at Stanford.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descbigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.0pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;He studied for his undergraduate degree at the University of Ghana and took his Ph.D. from the University of Cambridge after which he held a Junior Research Fellowship at Wolfson College, Oxford before returning to Cambridge to become Reader in Commonwealth and Postcolonial Literature in the Faculty of English from 1995-2005. He was also Director of the Centre for&amp;nbsp;African Studies&amp;nbsp;and a Fellow of Pembroke College while at Cambridge.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Prior to&amp;nbsp; Stanford he was Professor of African and Postcolonial Literature at New York University (2017-2019) and Professor of English and inaugural Director of the Centre for Diaspora and Transnational Studies at the University of Toronto (2005-2017). In 2016 he was appointed University Professor at the University of Toronto, the highest distinction that the university can bestow. &lt;a href="https://english.stanford.edu/people/ato-quayson" target="_blank"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt; about Professor Quayson.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2023 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ato_quayson_suffering_and_tragedy_from_the_greeks_to_toni_morrison</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42916248692380/huge/3ced0b50cfdf0a87cbcc09078e3a94dc58ace7b0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="724" width="1086" isDefault="true" fileSize="173533"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Atari Design at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;author Raiford Guins as he and&amp;nbsp;the Harold C. Hohbach Curator for the History of Science and Technology Collections, Henry Lowood, discuss his latest book,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Atari Design: Impressions on Coin-Operated Video Game Machines.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from deep archival research and extensive interviews,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Atari Design&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a rich, historical study of how Atari&amp;#39;s industrial and graphic designers contributed to the development of the video game machine. &lt;a href="https://www.bloomsbury.com/us/atari-design-9781474284523/"&gt;You may purchase a copy of the book here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raiford Guins is Chair and Professor of Cinema and Media Studies in the Media School at Indiana University, Bloomington. He is the author of&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Game After: A Cultural Study of Video Game Afterlife&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(MIT Press, 2014) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Atari Design: Impressions on Coin-Operated Video Game Machines&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Bloomsbury, 2020). Guins is currently writing a book on the popularity of the English Premier League in the US. He co-edits MIT Press&amp;#39;s Game Histories Book Series with Henry Lowood.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 May 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_raiford_guins</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42669427114517/huge/56f9a5332775ba368ee37f22c2431723b4ac8ea1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="751" width="568" isDefault="true" fileSize="61508"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, May 3 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 May 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_446</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42833284686117/huge/0b44169f294c84afc035cc0538ab672a9297fa6e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Intro to Qualtrics at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Attend this workshop and learn the Qualtrics survey software, why you should use it, and how to access it. We will teach you how to create a survey, write different question types and understand their behaviors, organize questions into blocks, explore response data, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649655" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_intro_to_qualtrics</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944082270075/huge/7917167d26dc76add09950c2043d1e1af93d9a05.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS R Bootcamp at Tierney Room (Green Library 121A)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Need to get up to speed with R in a hurry? Join SSDS as we spend the day learning R! This fast-paced bootcamp will introduce you to many aspects of R, including the basics of research design, navigating R and RStudio, data types and structures, wrangling and reshaping, visualization, exploratory data analysis, statistical tests, presentation of your research, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649348" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;9:15 - 9:30AM PST: Installations (optional).&lt;/b&gt; Show up early if you need installation help&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to download R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to download RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;9:30 - 9:45: The modern academic research workflow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Researcher responsibilities&lt;br /&gt;
R and RStudio, navigating RStudio&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;9:45 - 10:45: R basics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Variable assignment; functions, parameters, and arguments&lt;br /&gt;
Data types: numeric, character, logical, integer, factor&lt;br /&gt;
Data structures: lists and matrices, vectors and data frames&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;10:45 - 11:00: Break&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;11:00-12:00PM: Data wrangling and reshaping&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
The dollar sign operator and backet notation&lt;br /&gt;
The dplyr and tidyr R packages&lt;br /&gt;
Working with text data&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;12:00 - 1:15: Data visualizaiton with ggplot2&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
ggplot2 requirements: layers, the plus symbol, data, aes, geom_, and theme_&lt;br /&gt;
Histogram: hist and geom_histogram&lt;br /&gt;
Boxplot: boxplot and geom_boxplot&lt;br /&gt;
Barchart: geom_col&lt;br /&gt;
Scatterplot: plot, geom_point, and geom_jitter&lt;br /&gt;
Line plot: geom_line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;1:15 - 2:15: Exploratory data analysis&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Summary statistics: mean, standard deviation, median, skew, and kurtosis&lt;br /&gt;
Principal component analysis&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;2:15 - 3:15: Hypotheses, p-values, and confidence intervals&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sums of squares tests: t.test, aov, cor.test, lm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:15 - 3:30: Break&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:30 - 4:30: Presenting your research&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
R Markdown, knit, html, ioslides&lt;br /&gt;
Dashboards with the flexdashboard package&lt;br /&gt;
Reproducible research and the targets package&lt;br /&gt;
Tips for writing&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4:30 - 4:45: Wrap-up&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Green Library, SSDS, tutorials, and other resources&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 May 2023 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_r_bootcamp</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944157195645/huge/944724d1eae718392764776fe44b0762e6598432.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Intro to Python at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides an introduction to the Python programming language: basic syntax, variable assignment, functions, .txt and .csv data import, and how to understand error messages and find help. You will learn enough Python to perform common tasks and explore the rich environment of Python packages available.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649349" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_intro_to_python_9385</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42943932423562/huge/7775c9d55256496fa8e86847b7e63390250f2e3b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for May&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_6593</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228738162/huge/3f8b100c63ed496606ccee46a8c4b5897cde4123.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Wrangling at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649351" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python (or similar knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_wrangling_3345</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944264665011/huge/57bde645816477766462736f858e868acdf24604.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The War in Ukraine and the Baltic States at Encina Commons, Room 119</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;The impact of Russia&amp;rsquo;s invasion of Ukraine on the Baltic states&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The three Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania, which share an 850 mile long border with Russia and Belarus, have been profoundly impacted by Russia&amp;rsquo;s war on Ukraine. This talk adresses both the international effects &amp;ndash; particularly shifts in regional coalitions and the balance of power in northern Europe &amp;ndash; and the long-term domestic impact of militarization, Ukrainian refugees, and sweeping de-russification.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Daunis Auers&lt;/b&gt; is Professor of European Studies and Jean Monnet Chair at the University of Latvia, and serves as Director-at-large of the Association for the Advancement of Baltic Studies (AABS). He studied at the London School of Economics and defended his PhD at University College London. He has been a Fulbright Scholar at the University of California-Berkeley (2005-2006) and a Baltic-American Freedom Foundation Scholar at Wayne State University in Detroit (2014) and published widely on political parties, elections, referendums, populism and the radical right and economic competitiveness in the Baltic states. His book on &lt;i&gt;The Comparative Government and Politics of the Baltic States: Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania in the 21&lt;sup&gt;st&lt;/sup&gt; Century&lt;/i&gt; &amp;ndash; was published by Palgrave Macmillan in 2015. He is currently working on a monograph analyzing Nordic-Baltic integration and will be a Fulbright program Visiting Professor at the University of Washington-Seattle in fall 2023. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;a href="https://bit.ly/40NmiaS"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span&gt;RSVP Required&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_war_in_ukraine_and_the_baltic_states</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42783640147096/huge/68e78d678bc08233294ed0eb2fcd48dcfedf8d00.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2424" width="3636" isDefault="true" fileSize="2717769"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Bash Bootcamp at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Have you ever wanted to build a basic data science toolkit but can&amp;rsquo;t get started? No need for Python and R to hog all the credit, kickstart Winter Quarter with SSDS&amp;rsquo;s Bash Bootcamp!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This 4-hour data science project will boost your confidence through transferrable skills essential for the modern, data-driven job market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here you will learn the basics of: 1) the Bash programming language, 2) Git for version control, 3) SQLite database engine, and 4) free static GitHub Pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649350" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Part 1 - 10:00-11:00 AM -&lt;/b&gt; Learn basic Bash code to navigate your computer&amp;rsquo;s file system and create directories and files using pwd, ls, cd, mkdir, and touch commands.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Part 2 - 11:00-12:00 PM -&lt;/b&gt; Build a Git repository to control version tracking with git clone, add, commit, push, and pull.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;12:00-1:00 PM - Lunch on your own&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Part 3 - 1:00-2:00 PM -&lt;/b&gt; Launch SQLite3 and learn to wrangle data with SELECT, FROM, WHERE, GROUP BY, and ORDER BY.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Part 4 - 2:00-3:00 PM -&lt;/b&gt; Use the GitHub repository you build in parts 1-3 and turn it into a simple static webpage with GitHub Pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Links to materials: &lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/BashGitHub" target="_blank"&gt;BashGitHub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/IntroSQLite" target="_blank"&gt;IntroSQLite&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/GitHubPages" target="_blank"&gt;GitHubPages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: basic familiarity with computers. &lt;a href="https://github.com" target="_blank"&gt;Sign up for free GitHub account.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Before the workshop - Mac users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you have the Xcode developer toolset installed. Open a Terminal and type:&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; xcode-select --install&lt;br /&gt;
When asked if you want to install the command line developer tools, click &amp;quot;yes/install&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Before the workshop - Windows users&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Install GitBash here: &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/downloads"&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt;. Download the file and double-click it to run the installer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_bash_bootcamp_7711</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944281313427/huge/ca8cff869bc321dded937c717adabd232747fb22.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Visualization at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will introduce you to three basic visualizations using the Python matplotlib and seaborn libraries: histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649707" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 May 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_visualization_6820</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944310288117/huge/536d27dd9d932dbf1bb95e66aff0994f066b035a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Text Analysis at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to working with text data using the spaCy and textacy Python libraries. You will learn to effectively streamline text preprocessing, understand word tokenization, sentence segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, and named entity recognition using a single document (a short excerpt from H.G. Wells&amp;#39;s A Short History of the World) and across a corpus of legal documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649353" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_text_analysis_5149</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944325108896/huge/65c388daee5119249df2cf63f9511c8cca06b49b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Machine Learning at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for classifying text and images using the scikit-learn, lime, and tensorflow Python libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649354" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_machine_learning_3127</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944386409314/huge/795a72a2631c658399a05f3bb87a85a06c9d6dcb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Intro to R at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F) </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop is geared towards those who would like to get started with R or need to brush up on their skills. You will learn how to use R, RStudio, how to create objects in R, how to work with different data types, how to read tabular data into R and how to subset tables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649356" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install the following:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to download R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to download RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_intro_to_r_7267</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944421819159/huge/02663a4298f1a8d83514754c7347233506b9a641.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: John Tinnell at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives as author John Tinnell discusses his book,&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/P/bo194495767.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Philosopher of Palo Alto: Mark Weiser, Xerox PARC, and the Orginal Internet of Things&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When developers and critics trace the roots of today&amp;rsquo;s Internet of Things&amp;mdash;our smart gadgets and smart cities&amp;mdash;they may single out the same creative source: Mark Weiser, the first chief technology officer at Xerox PARC and the so-called &amp;ldquo;father of ubiquitous computing.&amp;rdquo; But Weiser, who died young at age 46 in 1999, would be heartbroken if he had lived to see the ways we use technology today. As John Tinnell shows in this thought-provoking narrative, Weiser was an outlier in Silicon Valley. A computer scientist whose first love was philosophy, he relished debates about the machine&amp;rsquo;s ultimate purpose. Good technology, Weiser argued, should not mine our experiences for saleable data or demand our attention; rather, it should quietly boost our intuition as we move through the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Informed by deep archival research and interviews with Weiser&amp;rsquo;s family and colleagues,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;The Philosopher of Palo Alto&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;chronicles Weiser&amp;rsquo;s struggle to initiate a new era of computing. Working in the shadows of the dot-com boom, Weiser and his collaborators made Xerox PARC headquarters the site of a grand experiment. Throughout the building, they embedded software into all sorts of objects&amp;mdash;coffeepots, pens, energy systems, ID badges&amp;mdash;imbuing them with interactive features. Their push to integrate the digital and the physical soon caught on. Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s Bill Gates flagged Weiser&amp;rsquo;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Scientific American&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;article &amp;ldquo;The Computer for the 21st Century&amp;rdquo; as a must-read. Yet, as more tech leaders warmed to his vision, Weiser grew alarmed about where they wished to take it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this fascinating story of an innovator and a big idea, Tinnell crafts a poignant and critical history of today&amp;rsquo;s Internet of Things. At the heart of the narrative is Weiser&amp;rsquo;s desire for deeper connection, which animated his life and inspired his notion of what technology at its best could be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://The Philosopher of Palo Alto: Mark Weiser, Xerox PARC, and the Orginal Internet of Things"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Philosopher of Palo Alto: Mark Weiser, Xerox PARC, and the Orginal Internet of Things&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;a href="http://The Philosopher of Palo Alto: Mark Weiser, Xerox PARC, and the Orginal Internet of Things"&gt;&amp;nbsp;may be purchased here.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_john_tinnell</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42598151996227/huge/300b54e63d4903aba4eacaf9d160e463d63c3d60.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1024" width="697" isDefault="true" fileSize="124498"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 7 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Jun 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_4466</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42833284910385/huge/1cc8c23f3b8b125f36dbe5a2bf4507e21efbcbcb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Data Wrangling at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for those who know the basics of R and would like to get started working with their research data. Here you will learn ways to wrangle and reshape tabular data, specifically using the dplyr and tidyr packages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649358" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or equivalent knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;(c&lt;/a&gt;oming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_intro_to_r_1052</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944437344606/huge/e0e61ae36f1e9ed2d48ded375f0d78b728b2e6e3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Data Visualization at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will review three base plots in R (histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot) before introducing you to the ggplot2 package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649359" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(coming soon)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_data_visualization</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944719635435/huge/893e8f08a85259b763494a2a006cdc6a2ddbd85d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Text Analysis at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in analyzing collections of novels or journal articles? Do you want to understand patterns across collections of tweets or other social media data? In this workshop, you will learn how to import, clean, and analyze collections of text with R using several standard text mining libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649360" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_text_analysis_7829</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944496964984/huge/68b9e506d2ec92729a0bb2f9265e3711c5939797.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for June&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jun 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_4825</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228920445/huge/ecbcf45c53eb8fd88ba5f954cd9fc20c96f8b17b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Machine Learning at Velma Denning Room (Green Library 120F)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a beginner-friendly introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts, quantitative data preprocessing for machine learning, and the SuperLearner R package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10649365" target="_blank"&gt;Click this text to register.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R"&gt;https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2023 09:10:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_machine_learning_5471</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42944517441077/huge/e98a7ed243462c5fcca46067e22ba5fc9c20b4dd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for July&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_4057</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286229107848/huge/a05040354b489bb130246acd26050df9ea7debad.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
