<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Translating Three Japanese Masters, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura, and Kazuko Shiraishi: Selections from the Yumiko Tsumura Collection at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On display at the East Asia Library from 3/6/25-5/13/25, selections from a recent donation from Yumiko Tsumura, a local poet and translator, related to three major modern Japanese authors, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura and Kazuko Shiraishi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yumiko Kurahashi’s meteoric career began with &lt;i&gt;Parutai&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;The Party&lt;/i&gt;), a brilliant satire of the Japanese leftist students movement that she wrote while still a student. As part of a first generation of women writers who had benefited from equal opportunity for education in the post-war period, her innovative writing style, influenced by Satre, Kafka, and Camus, rocked the literary world of the 1960s, exposing structural inequities in Japanese society. Perhaps the most renowned post-WWII Japanese poet, Ryuichi Tamura’s poetry searingly reveals the agony of war and the disorientation induced by rapid modernization. Kazuko Shiraishi, known for performing her provocative poetry to jazz accompaniment, has been called the “Allen Ginsberg of Japan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to introduce this donation in an exhibit in our main exhibit space. Please visit the East Asia Library to learn more about these three authors, who each left a powerful critique of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/east-asia-library-exhibits-selections-yumiko-tsumura-collection-japanese-poetry"&gt;Read an interview with the donor, Yumiko Tsumura, to learn more about her and each of these authors.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/translating-three-japanese-masters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49021026270886/huge/0a889191391152cee3133e7261ae17eb90597460.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="469" width="512" isDefault="true" fileSize="80335"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit runs from April 2 to August &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, 2025, in Green Library’s Hohbach Hall. This exhibit is free and open to the public.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks exploring e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48784006670593/huge/fcc0e4782c3b22ef835cd5a2bc04a6752a27d369.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="858" width="862" isDefault="true" fileSize="1286480"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art of the Ad: Fashion for a New Century  at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pochoir fashion plates and advertisements are part of the allure of early 20th-century Parisian fashion magazines. Art history major, Sita Antel, '26 investigates the role of fashion in her Spring exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On view in Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 1 - June 20th. M-Th 9-7, Fri 9-5, Sun. 12-6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/art-of-the-ad-fashion-for-a-new-century</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49092294783840/huge/f89ef044fd107f813a0005d6667e49c04115261e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="626799"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Thomas Lalevée (ANU): Before Durkheim: Early French Social Science and the Politics of Progress at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before the social sciences were institutionalized as academic disciplines around the turn of the twentieth century, the idea of constructing a science of society was closely tied to a range of ambitious, and often radical, projects of social and political reform. This talk will discuss several of these projects, with the aim of proposing a new genealogy of modern social science, free of pre-determined assumptions about its origins and development. Focusing on France – the birthplace of the concept of social science – it will provide a brief survey of the ideas and arguments that shaped its successive iterations during the period of profound upheaval spanning the decades between the revolutions of 1789 and 1848. Drawing on research from Lalevée's current book project and forthcoming work under the Gustave Gimon Fellowship at Stanford, he will argue that the history of early French social science is best understood as a series of attempts to grapple with the problems posed by the emergence of modern commercial society, or what would later come to be known as capitalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-sponsored by the Stanford Libraries and the France-Stanford Center for Interdisciplinary Research &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please contact &lt;a href="mailto:ssussman@stanford.edu"&gt;ssussman@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; to reserve a lunch.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/thomas-lalevee-anu-before-durkheim-early-french-social-science-and-the-politics-of-progress</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49481504162128/huge/5478f6fb186f0001ebf9e845731d85e464030306.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2674" width="1963" isDefault="true" fileSize="990891"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/83a42ebc28b44fe7b355532da798b938"&gt;view digitally&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 May 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: Play at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here are just a few of 19 distinct meanings of the word play: active bodily exercise or movement; free action, freedom, opportunity, or room for action; exercise or activity engaged in for enjoyment or recreation; jest, fun, sport; an attempt to achieve or gain; a dramatic or theatrical performance; performance on a musical instrument; the control on a tape player, video recorder, etc.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a whole institute in Carmel, California devoted to the study of play as a state of mind brought about by absorption in an activity that “provides enjoyment and a suspension of sense of time.” The National Institute of Play contends that, “[l]ike sleep, dreams, and nutrition, play is critical to our health and well-being.” &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And yet, somehow, no definition seems capacious enough to describe the trove of rare and unique items chosen by subject specialists from Humanities and Area Studies for the latest pop-up, PLAY. Come see for yourself any time between 2-4 PM on Tuesday, May 13th, Hohbach 123 (Silicon Valley Archive classroom, Green Library). &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-play</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49545251760328/huge/b73782b83a3fb0673f9e85e2b70c07c30903712c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2929" width="2854" isDefault="true" fileSize="3433759"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Data Management and Open Science Workshop</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 2:00PM - 3:00PM, Thursday, May 15, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Maricela Abarca, Data Curator for Interdisciplinary Sustainability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Wherever you are in the research data lifecycle, this workshop will help you assess your data hygiene and adopt data management strategies that enhance the integrity, quality, reproducibility, compliance, accessibility and preservation of your data. We will discuss FAIR (Findable, Reproducible, Interoperable, Reusable) and CARE (Collective Benefit, Authority to Control, Responsibility, Ethics) principles, as well as how to implement them in your work. Those interested in open science and open scholarship will also benefit from this session. Register via Zoom to attend live and/or receive a recording. Submit any questions you’d like answered during the workshop through the Zoom registration form. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. A Zoom link will be provided upon registration.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/research-data-management-and-open-science-workshop</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412444113232/huge/1c6091cf89d74a3f912a2fc153e363490794dd0f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Special Collections at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from May 15 to August 31, 2025.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/"&gt;Spotlight Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source digital exhibit platform developed and maintained by Stanford’s Digital Library Systems and Services department (DLSS). Eleven years since its inception, the site hosts 164 online exhibits that span the range of Stanford’s general and special collections and cover such diverse topics as &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mss"&gt;Ancient, Medieval, and Early Modern Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;, Philip Zimbardo’s &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/spe"&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/sunset"&gt;Sunset Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/gardiner-sfba"&gt;Gardiner Transit Collection&lt;/a&gt;, and the photography archives of &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/fitch"&gt;Bob Fitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/bacon"&gt;David Bacon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/menuez"&gt;Douglas Menuez&lt;/a&gt;.  Created by Stanford librarians, faculty, and students, and arranged and described in narrative format, the site’s digital content is accessed thousands of times a day. It helps make the libraries’ collections accessible to a vast audience of researchers at Stanford and beyond.  DLSS continues to add functionality, including the display of streaming media. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition, Spotlight on Special Collections, invites viewers into the deep collections that underlie or form the basis for the digital exhibits by presenting original artifacts, books, and manuscripts represented on the platform. Library curators selected from the approximately 100 Spotlight exhibits that feature Special Collections and University Archives content to show in the galleries. Original objects on display include historical photographs, books, illuminated manuscripts, early printed documents, musical scores, objects related to Stanford’s history, and ephemera representing movements for social change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No single exhibition could capture the full range and diversity of the content available on the Spotlight platform. However, with this exhibition, we have endeavored to represent the depth and breadth of this rich resource as it pertains to our Special Collections and University Archives holdings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Benjamin Lee Stone with Rebecca Wingfield and Franz Kunst, Benjamin Albritton, Ray Heigemeir, Josh Schneider, with Connor Yankowitz, Kathleen Smith, Charlotte Kwok-Glasser, and Natalie Marine-Street; produced by Deardra Fuzzell with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Connor Yankowitz. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49517102456786/huge/ef13e9ac8bc8849ce49f9fa880f7850953f4ff53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="123903"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Special Collections Exhibit Reception at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us in the Green Library Rotunda from &lt;b&gt;4:30 - 6:30 PM on Thursday, May 15th,&lt;/b&gt; for a reception to celebrate the Spotlight on Special Collections exhibition, on view from May 15 through August 31, 2025. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/JGvtEs1nKXpJ3JVG8"&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/"&gt;Spotlight Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source digital exhibit platform developed and maintained by Stanford’s Digital Library Systems and Services department (DLSS). Eleven years since its inception, the site hosts 164 online exhibits that span the range of Stanford’s general and special collections and cover such diverse topics as Ancient, Medieval, and Early Modern Manuscripts, Philip Zimbardo’s Stanford Prison Experiment, Sunset Magazine, the Gardiner Transit Collection, and the photography archives of Bob Fitch, David Bacon, and Douglas Menuez. &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections"&gt;Learn more about the exhibit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections-exhibit-reception</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49517641661596/huge/7c23c5aa857d845f3b74b4dd6a41f73a0b54ae56.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="72269"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Gilded Age: Boss Tweed, American Politics, and the game Tammany Hall (2007) at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The notorious American politician and political fixer William “Boss” Tweed (1823-78) and the powerful political organization Tammany Hall in New York City inspired this month’s Tabletop Tuesday feature, the 2007 board game &lt;a href="http://https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/30645/tammany-hall"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tammany Hall&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Reflecting a rather cynical view of the American political system, &lt;i&gt;Tammany Hall&lt;/i&gt; players pursue power ruthlessly, with the goal of winning elections at all costs through fraud, conspiracy,  backstabbing, corruption, trading political favors, slander, and playing New York City’s immigrant populations against each other.  In this session, we will explore this game and also the real-life factors that caused the downfall of Boss Tweed and curbed the power of Tammany Hall.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-may-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing and Using Open-Source Software Tools: From Neuroinformatics to Biomechanics (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month, the Bay Area Open Science Group will be joined by Sydney Covitz, a Bioengineering PhD Student at Stanford. Sydney graduated from Swarthmore College in 2020 with a double major in Computer Science and English Literature. She is currently working in the Neuromuscular Biomechanics Lab (NMBL), led by PI Scott Delp, using an open-source video-based application the lab developed to analyze upper extremity function in neuromuscular clinic patients. Between college and graduate school, Sydney spent three years as a Senior Software Developer in the University of Pennsylvania's Lifespan Brain Institute where she collaborated with informatics teams around the world to develop software packages and workflows for reproducibly analyzing large neuroimaging datasets. Her talk will touch on her experience in neuroinformatics software development and data management as well as her current work using open-source biomechanics tools for clinical analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/open-source-software-tools-from-neuroinformatics-to-biomechanics</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49338953433312/huge/5fc19a6050ad3f71a4a5fc186f99243db157979f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Studying and Collecting Medieval Badges - A Workshop at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Stanford Manuscript Sciences&lt;/i&gt; will host Dr. Thomas A. Bredehoft, a medieval scholar, rare book and antiques dealer, and novelist, will introduce a collection of medieval badges that he assembled and which now are &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14260088"&gt;housed at Stanford Libraries&lt;/a&gt;. The collection includes a broad variety of materials including pilgrim badges and fragments from the later medieval period, primarily from the Low Countries. He will speak on both the experience of collecting and assembling this group of materials and using these materials in classroom and research settings. The collection will be on display during the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to space constraints, registration is required.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/studying-and-collecting-medieval-badges-a-workshop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49544426972562/huge/3a16902a524d7795d8420c68cd4c146bddc55dd5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2585" width="2264" isDefault="true" fileSize="1285014"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Don't Panic, Don't Panic! The Baltic States in the New World Order at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Daunis Auers&lt;/b&gt; on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Don't Panic, Don't Panic! The Baltic States in the New World Order&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Russia's annexation of Crimea in early 2014 kick-started a process of reassessing security threats to the Baltic region and profound political and social change in the three Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania. Russia's full-scale invasion of Ukraine in February 2022 further raised the temperature and saw sharp rises in defense spending, a restructuring of the party system and new nationalizing domestic policies aimed at increasing social cohesion and tackling intelligence and misinformation threats from the East.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the first few months of the new presidential administration in the U.S.A. have, arguably, accelerated even greater change in the three Baltic states as they are forced to rapidly adjust to a new world order. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk will reflect on how swiftly shifting US-European relations have led the Baltic states to reconsider their security arrangements, realign diplomatic partnerships and refocus core domestic policies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Daunis Auers&lt;/b&gt; is Professor of European Studies and Jean Monnet Chair at the University of Latvia, Director of the Latvia’s Strategy and Economic Research (LaSER) think tank and a member of the Latvian president’s National Competitiveness Council. His recent research interests are in the comparative politics, economics and regional integration of the Baltic and Nordic states and has recently worked on bureaucratic reform and efficiency. He is a member of the Latvian prime minister's working group on "Cutting Bureaucracy". Professor Auers defended his PhD at University College London and previously studied at the London School of Economics. He has been a Fulbright Scholar at the University of California-Berkeley (2005-2006), University of Washington in Seattle (2023-2024) and a Baltic-American Freedom Foundation Scholar at Wayne State University in Detroit (2014).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/sNHNiVzggkHR2Kep6"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/baltic-states-new-world-order</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49420585236523/huge/28b9fa4182e6f12cf993ab2e76bc510107889d38.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2424" width="3636" isDefault="true" fileSize="2654386"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LLM as RA: Leveraging AI for Academic Research at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1:00PM - 3:00PM, Thursday, May 22, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm, Head of Data Science Training and Consultation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Are you looking to harness the potential of AI to streamline your research workflow? This workshop will introduce you to the architecture and applications of Large Language Models (LLMs), empowering you to effectively and responsibly leverage them in your academic research. We will explore the use cases, possibilities, and limitations of LLMs, as well as essential considerations for their ethical use. Key topics will include: pre-processing techniques for data preparation, strategies for working with tabular data, and evaluation measures for LLM-driven research tasks. You will also gain practical experience utilizing both Stanford’s AI Playground API and local language models. By the end of the workshop, you will be equipped with the knowledge, skills, and sample code to integrate AI into your research workflow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Note: To access the registration form, please ensure you are logged into Google on your current browser with your Stanford email, such as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetID@stanford.edu" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;YourSUNetID@stanford.edu&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The registration for this workshop is now closed as we have reached our capacity of 30 participants. Please sign up on the waitlist &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfzUYNkRsz7Udiynu4WABlTqEIJRoPONrD4l-UF1VvpXNNtaw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to be notified about the next session. We will be offering another session to accommodate additional interest. Thank you for your understanding.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/llm-as-ra-leveraging-ai-for-academic-research</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49412447565594/huge/d2ce585febbbcd6af243f661235824ed1929c20f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGulf: Creating Open Historical Data about the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;How can we critically examine, interpret, and repurpose colonial knowledge through creating structured data? Can colonial texts serve as meaningful data sources to explore the histories of understudied regions like the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf? How can historical sources be transformed into datasets, and what insights can such data offer? This symposium addresses these questions and marks the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://opengulf.github.io" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; research collective’s completion and publication of a comprehensive dataset of geocoded place names derived from a seminal early-twentieth-century British colonial Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabian Peninsula, and Oman. This open-access, historical-geographical dataset is the culmination of seven years of collaborative annotation, geolocation, and disambiguation carried out by faculty, students, and OpenGulf community members across several institutions. During the sessions, we will discuss OpenGulf’s collaborative workflows and methods, introduce potential uses among scholars and practitioners, and emphasize the pedagogical potential of historical dataset creation by celebrating the work of student researchers. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;In addition to morning sessions at the David Rumsey Map Center, the event will feature an exhibition of historical materials related to the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at Branner Library and a student-led poster session including lightning talks on undergraduate research.  The afternoon event will include cartographic visualizations created using the OpenGulf dataset such as the one pictured here, a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/camels/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; of mentions of over 66,000 camels in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Oman and Central Arabia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Scholars, students, and members of the public with an interest in advancing and broadening their knowledge of both the history of the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf and digital humanities debates and methodologies will especially benefit from this event. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Detailed program coming soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdlExG8oCxQA7mwF9gL3IdeWS6QRquumozO-DMWwEcHxA4GSA/viewform?usp=sharing" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;register to attend&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/opengulf-creating-open-historical-data-about-the-arabian-peninsula-and-the-persian-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49172453653870/huge/7764bcaf3c34e491522165c573f8173fa768a589.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3146" width="4058" isDefault="true" fileSize="1438579"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colonial Gulf: How Empires Documented a Region -- Exhibit Opening and Student Poster Session at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;How have colonial and imperial regimes imagined and represented the Persian Gulf? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibit explores how the British, Ottoman and American empires documented the human and non-human geography, resources, and landscapes of the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It features historical maps and artifacts from the collections of the Branner Earth Sciences Library and the David Rumsey Map Center alongside cartographic visualizations created by the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/"&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;research collective.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Featured materials include maps derived from a dataset collected from the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia, and Oman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; created using QGIS, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;including the map of mentions of date palms displayed here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.  By placing these historical materials and contemporary analyses in conversation, we uncover a genealogy of geographical thinking alongside the power structures embedded in imperial and colonial record-keeping.  This exhibit aims to illustrate and critically engage the breadth, depth, and nature of colonial and imperial knowledge production regarding the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula, highlighting its varied expressions in texts, maps, and charts. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This event will include a tour of the exhibit followed by a poster session with lighting talks by undergraduate students who have contributed to data creation and developed their own research outputs with the OpenGulf research collective.  Student presentations will include explorations into how the&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia and Oman&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; represented the Gulf’s climate, its religious minorities, its flora and fauna, and its agricultural production. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;A &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/opengulf-creating-open-historical-data-about-the-arabian-peninsula-and-the-persian-gulf"&gt;morning symposium session&lt;/a&gt; will be hosted at the David Rumsey Map Center from 9:00AM-12 noon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/183h5gHJak8tZiFK8"&gt;register to attend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 13:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/opengulf-branner</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49494504258311/huge/56cb699ad9c9105d086250df3a8a744d4d490775.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1598" width="2122" isDefault="true" fileSize="4698528"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> From Ecotopia to NIMBYland:  Environment, Ideology, and the Antigrowth Style in California Politics at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jacob Anbinder and Michael Kahan on May 29, 2025, as they discuss Jacbob Anbinder's upcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation: The War on Growth That Created Our Housing Crisis and Remade American Politics&lt;/i&gt;. This event is co-sponsored by &lt;a href="https://west.stanford.edu"&gt;The Bill Lane Center for the American West&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu/"&gt;The Stanford University Department of History&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1975, a tiny Berkeley press published &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt;. Set in 1999, the novel told the story of a fledgling nation which had declared its independence from the U.S. out of disdain for America’s obsession with growth. &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt; ended up selling more than four hundred thousand copies and won author Ernest Callenbach praise in progressive circles for his visionary environmentalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Callenbach and others, California was ground zero for the disasters wrought by unfettered urbanization. Yet it was also the place where an alternative politics focused on ecological protection and quality of life seemed most likely to emerge. In the seventies and eighties, California liberals embarked on an intensive effort to remake their political agenda in the Ecotopian mold. Whether expressing dismay about freeway traffic, forest fires, water use, overcrowded parks and beaches, the loss of scenic views, or the unsightliness of high-rises, environmental protection became the shared language through which they voiced their objection to growth. This “mood of revulsion,” as one journalist called it, permeated every level of politics and ultimately reshaped the state’s patterns of urban development and land use. Soon, however, the imbalance between people’s demand to live in California and California’s new inability to accommodate them produced one of the most severe housing shortages in American history. No longer the poster child of unchecked sprawl, the state instead found itself at the center of a new epidemic: NIMBYism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on his forthcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation&lt;/i&gt;, Anbinder tells a new history of California’s cost-of-living crisis that moves beyond simplistic caricatures of NIMBYs and their motives. Instead, he instead traces the origins of the housing shortage to a more fundamental shift in liberals’ ideas about whether urban growth could help effect social progress at all. This influential but largely overlooked political movement ultimately dismantled much of the “growth machine” that had built modern California. In doing so, however, antigrowth liberals created the conditions for the paradoxical problem that defines the Golden State today: namely, that America’s most ostensibly progressive place is too expensive for most Americans to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jacob Anbinder&lt;/b&gt; is a historian of the modern United States with a particular focus on the politics of cities and suburbs in the twentieth century. His research interests include the political economy of major infrastructure projects, movements for and against change to the built environment, and the ways in which sprawl and spatial segregation create social inequities. His writing has been published in &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Business History Review&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Week&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Democracy: A Journal of Ideas&lt;/i&gt;, and other outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael Kahan &lt;/b&gt;is the Co-Director of the Program on Urban Studies at Stanford University and a senior lecturer in Sociology at Stanford University. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jacob-anbinder-nimby-nation-the-war-on-growth-that-created-our-housing-crisis-and-remade-american-politics</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48914944947267/huge/6006580a3a1941c248b79331b8954649e74a4a0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="515" width="450" isDefault="true" fileSize="29742"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Stress at Stanford Libraries 2025 at Green Library, east patio</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;DIY calming jars • Dog petting • Cool treats • Succulents • And more! &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stop by the Stanford libraries for some self-care leading up to, and during finals week. De-stress with fun activities, yummy snacks, and more!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Green Library |&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Wednesday, June 4th | 12:00 - 2:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
De-stressing activities at Green will include DIY calming jars, plant-and-take succulents, dog petting, and specialty popsicles. A variety of table activities including games, puzzles, and more will be available outside of Green Library, on the patio nearest Coupa Café throughout the event. Puzzles and coloring books will be available inside Green Library throughout finals week as well! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Green Library has recently &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/green-east-after-hours-study-now-open-all-night-5-nights-week"&gt;extended its late-night study hours&lt;/a&gt; to an all-night shedule, 5 nights a week. See &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/?week=2025W23"&gt;Green Library's open hours during finals week&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Terman Engineering Library |&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Wednesday, June 4th | 3:00 - 4:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Stop by the SEQ quad (Y2E2 Courtyard) to &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7053"&gt;take a break, and pet a dog &lt;/a&gt; Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library | Wednesday, June 4th – Friday, June 6&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Crave some creativity? Stop by Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library for puzzles, origami, and coloring books. Available during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/?week=2025W23"&gt;library hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="x_MsoNormal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library | Thursday, June 5th| 10:00 AM - 3:00 PM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;Take a moment to relax while painting a rock or just stop by the Branner Earth Sciences Library for free coffee, tea, and snacks. We'll have festive coloring pages too! &lt;b&gt;Help us reduce waste, bring a covered mug!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;East Asia Library | Thursday, June 5th | 12:00 - 2:00 PM&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Take a break to play a game at the East Asia Library! Mahjong, Go, Legos, card games, and more will be available from 12:00 - 2:00 PM in Room 224.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;Visit &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/"&gt;library.stanford.edu/hours &lt;/a&gt;to see hours for all libraries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress-at-stanford-libraries-2025</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49419201770189/huge/ece4d413f4d2a73bc378b1a78cc837921238b690.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="675403"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7053</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: June 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-june-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: July 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-july-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
