<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every archival collection that Stanford Libraries acquires must be processed before it can be made available for research. The expertise, thought, and care that goes into processing archival collections often occurs behind-the-scenes. Using the John Perry Barlow papers as a throughline, this exhibit explores the art of processing archival collections. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/paper_trails_the_art_of_processing_archival_collections</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40861265484890/huge/796758a62e11f9aaae17dc593730c2e172be4fbe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="425" width="425" isDefault="true" fileSize="109634"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoze Xie: Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie's new exhibition, &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt;, opening on September 15, 2022, in the main second-floor exhibit space at the Stanford East Asia Library, reminds us that, if "knowledge is power," as the quotation goes, then books can become battlegrounds. For over ten years, Xie has been engaged in an ongoing project titled &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Memories&lt;/em&gt; that focuses on the history of banned books in China. &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; features new works from this project. In addition to books from the artist's own collection, the exhibition will also feature several of Xie's sculptures. Working with photographs of books in public and private collections, Xie has created life-size, hand-sculpted and hand-painted porcelain reproductions of banned books both ancient and modern, some of which will be displayed publicly for the first time in this exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; will be on view from September 15, 2022, through the end of Fall Quarter. An opening reception will be held on October 12, 2022, in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie, the Paul L. &amp; Phyllis Wattis Professor of Art at Stanford University, is an internationally recognized artist who has exhibited extensively in the US and abroad. His work is in the permanent collection of such institutions as the Denver Art Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts Houston, San Jose Museum of Art, the Scottsdale Museum of Contemporary Art, and Oakland Museum of California. Xie received the Asia Game Changer West Award from the Asia Society (2022), the Painter and Sculptor's Grant from the Joan Mitchell Foundation (2013), the Pollock-Krasner Foundation Grant (2003) and artist awards from Phoenix Art Museum (1999) and Dallas Museum of Art (1996).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/xiaoze_xie_flammable_ideas_fragile_objects</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41074045488313/huge/df720f80197b036bed4df7bb0508525112431604.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="195807"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Book at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 6, 2022, through February 5, 2023 in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Elaine Treharne and Benjamin Albritton, produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_handmade_book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127511947685/huge/fa816f484827df107b7a256d92f54535a019c421.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="581" width="581" isDefault="true" fileSize="232881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theodore Roszak Papers in Focus at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This all-day event will feature the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Theodore Roszak papers, c. 1940-2017&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;throughout Hohbach Hall. Acquired in 2019 and recently processed, the manuscript collection is now available for research in the Department of Special Collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theodore Roszak (1933-2011) was an American author, academic, and social critic who first achieved fame for his 1969 book &lt;i&gt;The Making of a Counter Culture&lt;/i&gt;, subsequently writing prolifically about history, science, technology, literature, belief, society, and the life of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Schedule of events:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;All day&lt;/i&gt;: An installation of banners highlighting key items from Roszak&amp;rsquo;s collection in conversation with the John Perry Barlow materials in&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;2:00 PM - 4:00 PM&lt;/i&gt;:&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://events-legacy.stanford.edu/events/945/94555/" target="_blank"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays: Counterculture in Games&lt;/a&gt; (Hohbach Hall 126)&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;2:00 PM - 4:00 PM&lt;/i&gt;: A showcase exhibit featuring selections from the Roszak archive (Hohbach Hall IC Classroom 166)&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;i&gt;4:30 PM - 5:30 PM:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;A conversation between Kathryn Roszak, daughter of Theodore and Betty Roszak and Peter Richardson, scholar of the Counter Culture and author of the recent work&amp;nbsp;Savage Journey: Hunter S. Thompson and the Weird Road to Gonzo (2022) from 4:30-5:30 in Hohbach Hall 122.&amp;nbsp; RSVP for the conversation&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1D2HRJuq9nOunsBn19J1NZ3jwYatDbFBB7GuzVbDLDWw/viewform?edit_requested=true" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is open to the general public. Please visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges/visitor-access-and-borrowing" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our library website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more how visitors without a library card or Stanford ID can join us for this event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Roszakinfocus</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41279394314778/huge/a925fd3f055632993cde49a27533eee7d0babb22.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="399021"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Counterculture in Games at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/Roszakinfocus" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/Roszakinfocus" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Theodore Roszak Papers in Focus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;/strong&gt;we will explore counterculture through board games like &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10589365" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Up against the wall, motherfucker!&lt;/a&gt;, a game created by Columbia students to represent the tensions playing out on campus in the spring of 1968. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/em&gt; is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we'll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives. Note: due to winter closure, there will &lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; be a December event in 2022. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_counterculture_in_games</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41383489252302/huge/dde8396e396f2d5bd72a6e410ec54f6b234ed089.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="145578"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Technology and Journalism at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1gIBi6_Iwzl9LjjkhLg0_eTqrvcHGMMvBLED7aAYDmlY/edit" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;RSVP FOR THIS EVENT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;When Samuel Morse sent the first official telegram from the Supreme Court Chamber, he demonstrated this new media technology with the message, "What hath God wrought?" Journalists today, nearly 180 years later, might well ask the same question about technology's impact on their profession, and on the news business generally.  Please join us for a panel conversation about technology's impact hosted by the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/silicon-valley-archives" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Silicon Valley Archives&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Panelists Kara Swisher, Rich Jaroslovsky and Ken Doctor will speak with us about the successes and failures in journalism's adoption of new digital and media technologies.  The discussion will range across issues such as the fragmentation of audiences, the migration of advertising dollars and new models for news.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kara Swisher&lt;/strong&gt; is the country's foremost technology journalist. Among many other ventures, she is the longtime executive producer and host of the Code Conference, co-host of the popular "Pivot" podcast as well as the new interview podcast "On With Kara Swisher." She is a former reporter for &lt;em&gt;The Washington Post&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, as well as a former &lt;em&gt;New York Times&lt;/em&gt; columnist.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rich Jaroslovsky &lt;/strong&gt;(Stanford '75) is Vice President for Content &amp; Chief Journalist of &lt;em&gt;SmartNews&lt;/em&gt;, the global news-aggregation app. A former political writer and editor at &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt;, he was the founding managing editor of &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal Online&lt;/em&gt;, founded and was the first president of the Online News Association, and teaches a course in the history of online news at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ken Doctor &lt;/strong&gt;spent more than two decades at &lt;em&gt;Knight-Ridder&lt;/em&gt; in key editorial and executive roles, and then became one of the nation's most authoritative and respected experts on the news industry as it struggled to adapt to the new digital world. Then in 2020, he decided to put his expertise to work by founding his own local-news enterprise, &lt;em&gt;Lookout Local&lt;/em&gt;, and launched his first site, Lookout Santa Cruz.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_technology_and_journalism</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41418764491705/huge/50218cf0360e6f6e418f9ef1f1de9e1b32e2fb23.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="112576"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the Winners of the 2022 Saroyan Prize at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Please join us as we celebrate the winners of the &lt;strong&gt;2022 William Saroyan International Prize for Writing!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Claire Oshetsky&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Fiction winner and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Chouette&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&amp;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wayétu Moore&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Nonfiction winner and author of &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Dragons, the Giant, the Women&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Thursday, December 1, 2022&lt;br /&gt;4:30 to 6:00 pm&lt;br /&gt;The event will take place in person in Green Library, 5th floor, Bender Room&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Books will be available for purchase and signing.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/UQWDzE5raGHefwJY7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Please register if you would like to attend&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.harpercollins.com/products/chouette-claire-oshetsky?variant=33105369169954" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Chouette&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;(Ecco, 2021) a novel by Claire Oshetsky, and &lt;a href="https://www.graywolfpress.org/books/dragons-giant-women" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Dragons, the Giant, the Women &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;(Graywolf Press, 2020), a memoir by Wayétu Moore, are the recipients of the 2022 &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/william-saroyan-international-prize-writing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;William Saroyan International Prize for Writing&lt;/a&gt; administered by Stanford Libraries and the &lt;a href="http://williamsaroyanfoundation.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;William Saroyan Foundation&lt;/a&gt;. The biennial prize honors the life and legacy of novelist, playwright, and short-story author William Saroyan by encouraging and recognizing new and emerging writers. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/172905" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Learn more about the winners and their books&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating_the_winners_of_the_2022_saroyan_prize</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41436411440064/huge/633a54b6145fe1a5d90595c863d8f8db7e930831.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="259292"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's war in Ukraine. What's at stake and what we should do about it at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with the Ambassador of Estonia to the U.S. Kristjan Prikk, Rose Gottemoeller, and Steven Pifer, who will discuss:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Russia's war in Ukraine. What's at stake and what we should do about it&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Russia's unprovoked war against Ukraine has brought about the most serious reassessment of the European security realities since the end of the Cold War. The epic clash of political wills, the magnitude of military operations, and the scale of atrocities against the Ukrainian people are beyond anything Europe has seen since World War II. The past nine months have forced many to reassess what is possible and impossible in international security A.D. 2022. What is this war about, after all? What's at stake in this – to paraphrase former British PM Chamberlain – "quarrel in a faraway country, between people of whom most Americans know nothing?" What should be the lessons for U.S. strategists and policymakers? What are the wider implications for U.S. national security interests, particularly those related to the Indo-Pacific? How has the Alliance supported Ukraine since the war started? What should the end of this war look like and how to get there?&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;All these questions are relevant and should be carefully weighed with current information from the war as well as historic perspective and regional knowledge in mind.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panelists:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Estonia's Ambassador to the U.S. &lt;strong&gt;Mr. Kristjan Prikk&lt;/strong&gt; started his mission in Washington, D.C. in May 2021. He is a graduate of the USA Army War College and has served as the National Security Coordinator to the Prime Minister. Prior to arriving in D.C., he was the Permanent Secretary of the Estonian Ministry of Defense. Among his previous assignments are two other tours in Washington as an Estonian diplomat and work on NATO-Russia and NATO-Ukraine topics at a time when these relationships were considerably less charged than today.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rose Gottemoeller&lt;/strong&gt; is the Steven C. Házy Lecturer at Stanford University's Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies and its Center for International Security and Cooperation. Before joining Stanford, Gottemoeller was the Deputy Secretary General of NATO from 2016 to 2019, where she helped to drive forward NATO's adaptation to new security challenges in Europe and in the fight against terrorism.  Prior to NATO, she served for nearly five years as the Under Secretary for Arms Control and International Security at the U.S. Department of State, advising the Secretary of State on arms control, nonproliferation and political-military affairs. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Steven Pifer&lt;/strong&gt; is an affiliate of the Center for International Security and Cooperation as well as a non-resident senior fellow with the Brookings Institution. He was a William J. Perry Fellow at the center from 2018-2022 and a fellow at the Robert Bosch Academy in Berlin from January-May 2021. Pifer's research focuses on nuclear arms control, Ukraine, Russia, and European security. A retired Foreign Service officer, Pifer's more than 25 years with the State Department focused on U.S. relations with the former Soviet Union and Europe, as well as arms control and security issues, and included service as the third US ambassador to Ukraine.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event is co-sponsored by CISAC.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Admission Info&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event is free and open to the public.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This is a hybrid event. In order to attend the event in person, &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/MtLrMbmsLHvZ8Hz7A" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;RSVP is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event can be followed via live stream by clicking on &lt;a href="https://livestream.com/accounts/1973198/events/10676086" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;this link&lt;/a&gt;. No registration is needed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/russias_war_in_ukraine_whats_at_stake_and_what_we_should_do_about_it</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41533776852996/huge/f260d44a901b6c7c41f1572baec5169f9640a8c7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="313" width="313" isDefault="true" fileSize="36075"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, December 7 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_222</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136264572243/huge/1246dc2c65e22d7be1ceaf15d0f29974bdc97991.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Talk with Binh Danh — The Enigma of Belonging at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us as we celebrate the book launch for &lt;a href="https://www.radiusbooks.org/all-books/p/binh-danh-the-enigma-of-belonging" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Enigma of Belonging&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Radius Books, 2022). The event will include an artist's talk by Binh Danh, MFA '04, as well as a panel discussion of the ways in which the physical form and creative content of Danh's work informed the book's design process with Radius Books Creative Director David Chickey. Joining Danh and Chickey are panelists Rachel Phillips from PhotoAlliance, Amanda Minami, co-founder of Camera Obscura (&lt;a href="https://www.camerasobscura.io/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;camerasobscura.io&lt;/a&gt;) and sponsor of the Minami Book Grant for Asian American Visual Artists at Radius Books, and moderator Anna Lee, Stanford Libraries Photography Curator.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, December 7, 2022&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;5:00 to 6:30 pm, in person at Green Library, 5th floor, Bender Room&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Books will be available for purchase and signing. This event is free and open to the public and is co-sponsored by &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; and ​&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.photoalliance.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;PhotoAlliance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, a nonprofit organization dedicated to supporting the understanding, appreciation and creation of contemporary photography. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/kMRZHkeNMV2uN423A" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please register if you would like to attend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABOUT THE BOOK&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binh Danh&lt;/strong&gt; was born in Vietnam and immigrated to the US in 1979. Early in his career, Danh pioneered a technique of printing images directly onto plant matter, activating the plants' chlorophyll with sunlight. Using this process, Danh printed images associated with the war in Vietnam onto the leaves of tropical plants and grasses. Of this work, Danh explains, "This process deals with the idea of elemental transmigration: the decomposition and composition of matter into other forms. The images of war are part of the leaves, and live inside and outside of them." Known for his innovative approach to alternative photographic processes, Binh Danh extends and reconsiders the pursuit of pioneering nineteenth-century photographers. For almost a decade, Danh has traveled across the American West, making daguerreotypes of scenic vistas on silver plates. Danh imbues this scenery with a distinctly personal perspective, negotiating his connection as a Vietnamese American with the landscape and history of the United States. This inaugural monograph features two volumes in a slipcase, bringing together three bodies of work and a separate book of essays and memorabilia that serves to contextualize Danh's work.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;ABOUT THE ARTIST&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://photo.sjsu.edu/faculty/binh-danh/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Binh Danh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an Associate Professor of Art at San José State University's Photography Program. He received an MFA from Stanford and a BFA from San Jose State University and has emerged as an artist of national importance with work that investigates his Vietnamese heritage and our collective memory of war. Danh produces socially engaged work that often involved community outreach and archival research that deals with mortality, memory, history, landscape, justice, evidence, and spirituality. His awards include a 2010 Eureka Fellowship and a 2019 Creative Work Fund. His work has been collected by the deYoung Museum; Museum of Fine Arts, Boston; National Gallery of Art; San Francisco Museum of Modern Art; among others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book_talk_with_binh_danh_the_enigma_of_belonging</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41533777253401/huge/7b8080f5c2d77d667e9a40a4a8960d7cf95addc6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="93086"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for January's &lt;em&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays &lt;/em&gt;(theme and featured games TBD). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/em&gt; is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we'll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286227988551/huge/60c4325950381dcf0c936677dc3856faacafc0d7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
