<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>To the World: China’s Multimedia Campaign during the Cold War at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The call “People of the World, Unite!” was a story China once told itself. When the world was polarized, the vision of global solidarity paradoxically prevailed in the People’s Republic of China during its Cold War isolation, manifested in a myriad of media categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To the World” unveils the diverse and far-reaching multimedia campaign in China. Drawing from the special collection at the East Asia library, this exhibition highlights how the regime propagated its international vision inward to the domestic audience from the 1950s to the 1970, and the interplay of ideas and ideologies shaping China’s self-presentation and portrayal of other countries and ethnicities in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition also contributes to a vibrant and expanding field of scholarship that has significantly advanced our understanding of China’s media in recent history. Scholars such as Andrew Jones, Christine Ho, and Jie Li have explored the complexities of culture and history by integrating media and trans media, encompassing text, photography, film, visual art, music, and radio. The objects on display—multilingual editions of the Little Red Book, vinyl records, English textbooks, cartoon illustrations, and so on—serve as primary sources for understanding media and mediation in the everyday realities of the bygone era. Thus, the exhibition invites students, scholars, and the broader public to reconsider the complexities of China’s media landscape and encourages newlines of inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibition on view from September 22 to December 20, 2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To the World” is curated by Yue Wu (PhD student, East Asian Languages and Cultures) and Zhaohui Xue (Curator for the Chinese Collection), with consultation from Professor Ban Wang (William Haas Professor in Chinese Studies). The exhibition is generously sponsored by the Stanford East Asia Library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/to-the-world-chinas-multimedia-campaign-during-the-cold-war</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50914581553448/huge/bfdc86bf5aa690b3ab09361f6416d06ba5ce252e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="1545" isDefault="true" fileSize="1165829"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Special Collections at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from May 15 to October 26, 2025.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/"&gt;Spotlight Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source digital exhibit platform developed and maintained by Stanford’s Digital Library Systems and Services department (DLSS). Eleven years since its inception, the site hosts 164 online exhibits that span the range of Stanford’s general and special collections and cover such diverse topics as &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mss"&gt;Ancient, Medieval, and Early Modern Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;, Philip Zimbardo’s &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/spe"&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/sunset"&gt;Sunset Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/gardiner-sfba"&gt;Gardiner Transit Collection&lt;/a&gt;, and the photography archives of &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/fitch"&gt;Bob Fitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/bacon"&gt;David Bacon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/menuez"&gt;Douglas Menuez&lt;/a&gt;.  Created by Stanford librarians, faculty, and students, and arranged and described in narrative format, the site’s digital content is accessed thousands of times a day. It helps make the libraries’ collections accessible to a vast audience of researchers at Stanford and beyond.  DLSS continues to add functionality, including the display of streaming media. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition, &lt;i&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/i&gt;, invites viewers into the deep collections that underlie or form the basis for the digital exhibits by presenting original artifacts, books, and manuscripts represented on the platform. Library curators selected from the approximately 100 Spotlight exhibits that feature Special Collections and University Archives content to show in the galleries. Original objects on display include historical photographs, books, illuminated manuscripts, early printed documents, musical scores, objects related to Stanford’s history, and ephemera representing movements for social change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No single exhibition could capture the full range and diversity of the content available on the Spotlight platform. However, with this exhibition, we have endeavored to represent the depth and breadth of this rich resource as it pertains to our Special Collections and University Archives holdings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Benjamin Lee Stone with Rebecca Wingfield and Franz Kunst, Benjamin Albritton, Ray Heigemeir, Josh Schneider, with Connor Yankowitz, Kathleen Smith, Charlotte Kwok-Glasser, and Natalie Marine-Street; produced by Deardra Fuzzell with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Connor Yankowitz. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49517102456786/huge/ef13e9ac8bc8849ce49f9fa880f7850953f4ff53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="123903"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits: The Making of a Children's Book at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibition showcases &lt;i&gt;Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits&lt;/i&gt;, a children’s book by Stanford art historian Emanuele Lugli that explores why portraits matter through the life and work of Lavinia Fontana, Europe’s first professional woman painter. Illustrated by Chiara Palillo, the book is more than a study of portraiture and early modern women—it is an artist’s book in itself, a hybrid creation where collage, acrylic, cyanotype, and digital color converge in playful, unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening reception, Oct. 16, 4-6 pm in the lobby outside the library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lavinias-wondrous-portraits-the-making-of-a-childrens-book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50569364017038/huge/5bb505839ed649401c32d60e7c1b38b22b8da0c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="900" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="77463"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Oceans: Pacific Ocean at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Oceans&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the complexity of deep trenches to the shifting dynamics of sea ice, Earth’s oceans are vital to understanding our planet’s past, present, and future. In the 2025–2026 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature ocean geology, biology, physics, chemistry, and mapping, highlighting their roles in regulating the climate, sustaining biodiversity, and connecting global systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September - October: Explore the unique geology of the Pacific Ocean with its deep trenches, fast-spreading ridges, and volcanic island chains through books, electronic resources, and maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a valid, physical government-issued photo ID to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-exhibit-pacific-ocean</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50659519179157/huge/676fa101f5b2a2b416cc19e1be4c115d8bd765ec.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="379149"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Typography: Mathematics, Chinese, and More at Robin Li and Melissa Ma Science Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibit explores digital typography, and its uses and challenges in a variety of settings, including mathematics and non-Western languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured materials include scholarship on the history and implementation of digital typography. There are texts on LaTeX, a software system for typesetting documents with mathematical notation developed by Donald Knuth, a famous computer scientist who you can sometimes see riding around Stanford on his bicycle. There is also a book on the history of digital input systems for the Chinese language written by Stanford professor Thomas Mullaney. Additionally, there are flyers from Stanford Initiative on Language Inclusion and Conservation in Old and New Media (SILICON), codirected by Prof. Mullaney, showcasing SILICON's work developing typefaces for digitally disadvantaged languages. The juxtaposition of these different lenses through which to view digital typography makes for an interesting and wholistic view of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit dovetails with other happenings at the Stanford Libraries. In particular, there will be workshops on LaTeX in the Li &amp;amp; Ma Science library in late October, one covering &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/latex-fundamentals-workshop"&gt;the fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; and another covering &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/biblatex-and-zotero-workshop"&gt;bibliographies and integration with reference management software&lt;/a&gt;. Also, the East Asia Library has recently acquired the only prototype of the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mingkwai"&gt;MingKwai Chinese typewriter&lt;/a&gt;, which prefigured modern digital Chinese input methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/digital-typography-mathematics-chinese-and-more</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430656</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171414</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50889508210229/huge/1cfb5830478b340405cd8f259238f966bca2984d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="315" width="640" isDefault="true" fileSize="38006"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford: Viewing of the Carolee Schneemann Diaries at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;With a two-day series of events, Stanford University Libraries and the Carolee Schneemann Foundation will celebrate the Libraries’ recent digitization of Schneemann’s diaries alongside the acquisition of additional archival materials preserved by the Schneemann Foundation, building upon the original acquisition of the Carolee Schneemann Papers from the artist in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event listing is for a Viewing of the Carolee Schneemann Papers, on Monday, October 20, from 2:30 - 4 pm in Green Library, Hohbach Hall, Room 123. You are welcome to drop-in at any time during the event to view a selection of materials from the archive, including some of Carolee's diaries. Attendance is free and open to all, but &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSepePeFyA6b4DIAPRzE-KJdZYD4D1W6tpP2MPvFDD3kMQcuOA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;registration is required in advance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;See info and registration for the other "Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford" events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-keynote-and-panel-discussion-with-peggy-phelan-and-kenneth-white"&gt;Keynote and Panel Discussion with Peggy Phelan and Kenneth White&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, 10/20 from 5 - 7:30 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-discussion-on-working-with-the-schneemann-archive"&gt;Discussion on Working with the Schneemann Archive with Katie Anania and Dejan Vasić&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 2 - 4 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-screening-of-three-films"&gt;Screening of Three Films (&lt;i&gt;Viet-Flakes&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Fuses&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Plumb Line&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 5 - 6:30 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Carolee Schneemann:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Carolee Schneemann (1939–2019) was one of the most influential artists of the second part of the twentieth century. Her pioneering work in a range of media—painting, film, video, dance and performance, installation, and the written word—is characterized by radical formal experimentation and critical investigations of subjectivity, the erotic and taboo, and the social construction of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Co-sponsored by Stanford University Libraries, the Carolee Schneemann Foundation, the Department of Art and Art History, the Department of Theater and Performance Studies, and the Department of Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Accessing the Carolee Schneemann Papers at Stanford:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Researchers can access the physical &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9631452"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Carolee Schneemann Papers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including the diaries, in the Special Collections and University Archives reading room at Stanford’s Cecil H. Green Library. More information on how to place requests and access the reading room is on the Libraries’ website at library.stanford.edu under “&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/explore-collections"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Explore Collections&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.” Online public access to the digitized diaries is available via &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Searchworks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Libraries’ catalog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;If you have any questions, please reach out to Lindsay King at kingl@stanford.edu!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-viewing-of-the-carolee-schneemann-diaries</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50898697375384/huge/5dc44344990f276624cb5fa864f2b82a49a965d9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="819" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="320261"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford: Keynote and Panel Discussion with Peggy Phelan and Kenneth White at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;With a two-day series of events, Stanford University Libraries and the Carolee Schneemann Foundation will celebrate the Libraries’ recent digitization of Schneemann’s diaries alongside the acquisition of additional archival materials preserved by the Schneemann Foundation, building upon the original acquisition of the Carolee Schneemann Papers from the artist in 2012. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This event listing is for a Keynote and Panel Discussion on Carolee Schneemann with Peggy Phelan and Kenneth White on Monday, October 20, 2025 from 5 -7:30 pm in the 5th Floor Bender Room of Green Library. Attendance is free and open to all, but &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSepePeFyA6b4DIAPRzE-KJdZYD4D1W6tpP2MPvFDD3kMQcuOA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;registration is required in advance&lt;/a&gt;. A reception will follow the event. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Peggy Phelan is the Ann O’Day Maples Chair in the Arts Professor of Theater and Performance Studies and English at Stanford University. She is the author of numerous books and essays, including &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Unmarked: The Politics of Performance&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (Routledge, 1993); &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Mourning Sex: Performing Public Memories&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (Routledge, 1997); &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Art and Feminism&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (Phaidon, 2001), and, with Richard Meyer, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Contact Warhol: Photography without End&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (MIT, 2021).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Kenneth White is Assistant Professor of Modern and Contemporary Art History and Visual Studies at Eugene Lang College of Liberal Arts at The New School. He earned a BFA in Film from Syracuse University and a PhD in Art History-Film and Media Studies from Stanford University.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;See info and registration for the other "Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford" events:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-viewing-of-the-carolee-schneemann-diaries"&gt;Viewing of the Carolee Schneemann Diaries&lt;/a&gt;, Monday, 10/20 from 2:30 - 4 pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-discussion-on-working-with-the-schneemann-archive"&gt;Discussion on Working with the Schneemann Archive with Katie Anania and Dejan Vasić&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 2 - 4 pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:14.6667px;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-screening-of-three-films"&gt;Screening of Three Films (&lt;i&gt;Viet-Flakes&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Fuses&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Plumb Line&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 5 - 6:30 pm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;About Carolee Schneemann:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Carolee Schneemann (1939–2019) was one of the most influential artists of the second part of the twentieth century. Her pioneering work in a range of media—painting, film, video, dance and performance, installation, and the written word—is characterized by radical formal experimentation and critical investigations of subjectivity, the erotic and taboo, and the social construction of the female body. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;Co-sponsored by Stanford University Libraries, the Carolee Schneemann Foundation, the Department of Art and Art History, the Department of Theater and Performance Studies, and the Department of Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;Accessing the Carolee Schneemann Papers at Stanford:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Researchers can access the physical &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9631452" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Carolee Schneemann Papers&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, including the diaries, in the Special Collections and University Archives reading room at Stanford’s Cecil H. Green Library. More information on how to place requests and access the reading room is on the Libraries’ website at library.stanford.edu under “&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/explore-collections" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Explore Collections&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.” Online public access to the digitized diaries is available via &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Searchworks&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, the Libraries’ catalog. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;If you have any questions, please reach out to akim6@stanford.edu!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-keynote-and-panel-discussion-with-peggy-phelan-and-kenneth-white</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50897516812758/huge/7711cd9aca8d3c5bcae3644a5cddc5218d2bea06.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="819" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="320261"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colonial Gulf: How Empires Documented a Region at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;How have colonial and imperial regimes imagined and represented the Persian Gulf? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibit explores how the British, Ottoman and American empires documented the human and non-human geography, resources, and landscapes of the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It features historical maps and artifacts from the collections of the Branner Earth Sciences Library and the David Rumsey Map Center alongside cartographic visualizations created by the &lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; research collective.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Featured materials include maps derived from a dataset collected from the &lt;i&gt;British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia, and Oman&lt;/i&gt; created using QGIS, including the map of mentions of date palms displayed here.  By placing these historical materials and contemporary analyses in conversation, we uncover a genealogy of geographical thinking alongside the power structures embedded in imperial and colonial record-keeping.  This exhibit aims to illustrate and critically engage the breadth, depth, and nature of colonial and imperial knowledge production regarding the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula, highlighting its varied expressions in texts, maps, and charts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/b90cd597a47f46d39567b4c9824ca6ee"&gt;&lt;span&gt;view digitally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored by: &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dept. of History&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://cesta.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;CESTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;&lt;span&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/colonial-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49820497130375/huge/021478f5ef78e5ba12d6141026a426a42130fff1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="667372"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finding Social and Behavioral Research Data through the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Zoom (link provided upon registration) &amp;amp; Bing Wing Tierney Room 121A, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 11AM–12PM, Tuesday, October 21, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Ron Nakao (Librarian for Social Science Data, Economics and Political Science) and Kate Barron (Research Data Curator)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) is the world's largest archive of digital social science data. As an ICPSR member, Stanford University affiliates receive full access to the data archive of more than 21,000 research studies. Topics include sociology, political science, economics, demography, education, child care, health care, crime, minority populations, aging, terrorism, substance abuse, mental health, public policy, international relations and more. Join us to gain hands-on experience navigating the basic search interface, Social Science Variables Database, specialized data collections, data-related publications, and restricted-use data access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Ron Nakao is the Librarian for Social Science Data, Economics and Political Science at Stanford University Libraries. He also serves as Stanford University's Official Representative to  the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) and the Roper Center for Public Opinion Research.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Kate Barron is a Research Data Curator at Stanford University Libraries. Kate also serves as Stanford University's Designated Representative to the Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br style="font-style:normal;text-align:start;text-decoration:none;"&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Join us in person or via Zoom!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. Once capacity is reached, a waitlist will open. In-person attendees must present a Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/need-social-science-data-introduction-icpsr</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50939883272016/huge/61c2131800a01dcffdca3225d98fd5a0e6aed46a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="722" width="721" isDefault="true" fileSize="175350"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roundtable on French Political Economy  at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Featuring the 2025-2026 Gustave Gimon visiting scholars in French political economy presenting their research projects  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Teddy Paikin&lt;/b&gt; (McGill University): "Michel Chevalier and the Making of French Capitalism: Liberalism, Empire, and Economic Development"&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dakota Ciolkosz&lt;/b&gt; (University of Nevada-Las Vegas): "Water Management and the Enlightenment: Political Economy and Environmental Engineering in Eighteenth-Century France".&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zaka Toto&lt;/b&gt; (Université des Antilles): "Nationalisme, identités et mouvement social aux Antilles Françaises". &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location:  IC Classroom, Green Library (1st floor, ask at Reference)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;please RSVP for lunch by Friday, Oct. 17, including if you have any food allergies. Contact Hannah at &lt;a href="mailto:heise@stanford.edu"&gt;heise@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by the French-Speaking Worlds Research Group and the Stanford University Libraries&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/roundtable-on-french-political-economy</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50966766518526/huge/a3b5179f9f5d4cafbcae21f83584e8f895dc679c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="858" width="842" isDefault="true" fileSize="451845"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford: Discussion on Working with the Schneemann Archive at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a two-day series of events, Stanford University Libraries and the Carolee Schneemann Foundation will celebrate the Libraries’ recent digitization of Schneemann’s diaries alongside the acquisition of additional archival materials preserved by the Schneemann Foundation, building upon the original acquisition of the Carolee Schneemann Papers from the artist in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event listing is for a Discussion on Working with the Schneemann Archive with Katie Anania and Dejan Vasic on Tuesday, 10/21 from 2 - 4 pm in Hohbach Hall, Green Library, Room 123. Attendance is free and open to all, but &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSepePeFyA6b4DIAPRzE-KJdZYD4D1W6tpP2MPvFDD3kMQcuOA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;registration is required in advance&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dejan Vasić is an art historian and curator of late modern and contemporary art and moving image media, specializing in conceptual art and the transnational avant-garde. Vasić has been a member of the International Association of Art Critics AICA since 2012, and he served on the Program Advisory Board of AICA-Serbia from 2020-2023. Vasić earned a BA and an MA from the University of Belgrade. He is currently a PhD candidate in the Department of Art and Art History at Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Katie Anania is Associate Professor of Art History at the University of Nebraska-Lincoln and the author of Out of Paper: Drawing, Environment, and the Body in 1960s America (Yale, 2024). Her work draws upon environmental art history, feminism, and queer theory to articulate the ways in which ideas emerge from outside Western aesthetic canons. Anania earned a BA from the University of Nevada and a PhD from the University of Texas at Austin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See info and registration for the other "Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford" events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-viewing-of-the-carolee-schneemann-diaries"&gt;Viewing of the Carolee Schneemann Diaries&lt;/a&gt;, Monday, 10/20 from 2:30 - 4 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-keynote-and-panel-discussion-with-peggy-phelan-and-kenneth-white"&gt;Keynote and Panel Discussion with Peggy Phelan and Kenneth White&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, 10/20 from 5 - 7:30 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-screening-of-three-films"&gt;Screening of Three Films (&lt;i&gt;Viet-Flakes&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Fuses&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Plumb Line&lt;/i&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 5 - 6:30 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Carolee Schneemann:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolee Schneemann (1939–2019) was one of the most influential artists of the second part of the twentieth century. Her pioneering work in a range of media—painting, film, video, dance and performance, installation, and the written word—is characterized by radical formal experimentation and critical investigations of subjectivity, the erotic and taboo, and the social construction of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Co-sponsored by Stanford University Libraries, the Carolee Schneemann Foundation, the Department of Art and Art History, the Department of Theater and Performance Studies, and the Department of Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Accessing the Carolee Schneemann Papers at Stanford:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers can access the physical &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9631452"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Carolee Schneemann Papers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including the diaries, in the Special Collections and University Archives reading room at Stanford’s Cecil H. Green Library. More information on how to place requests and access the reading room is on the Libraries’ website at library.stanford.edu under “&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/explore-collections"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Explore Collections&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.” Online public access to the digitized diaries is available via &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Searchworks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Libraries’ catalog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please reach out to &lt;a href="mailto:akim6@stanford.edu"&gt;akim6@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-discussion-on-working-with-the-schneemann-archive</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50897848715335/huge/9923e4d63f5307e1b4e11b2f199ff073e3d42159.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="819" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="320261"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford: Screening of Three Films at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With a two-day series of events, Stanford University Libraries and the Carolee Schneemann Foundation will celebrate the Libraries’ recent digitization of Schneemann’s diaries alongside the acquisition of additional archival materials preserved by the Schneemann Foundation, building upon the original acquisition of the Carolee Schneemann Papers from the artist in 2012. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event listing is for a screening of three of Carolee Schneemann's films: &lt;i&gt;Viet-Flakes &lt;/i&gt;(1962-67), &lt;i&gt;Fuses&lt;/i&gt; (1964-1967), and &lt;i&gt;Plumb Line&lt;/i&gt; (1968-1971) on Tuesday, October 21, 2025 from 5 - 6:30 pm in McMurtry Hall, Room 115.  Rachel Churner, the Director of the Schneemann Foundation, will be introducing the films. Attendance is free and open to all, but &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSepePeFyA6b4DIAPRzE-KJdZYD4D1W6tpP2MPvFDD3kMQcuOA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;registration is required in advance&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;b&gt;Please note that there is a cap of 45 people for this event.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See info and registration for the other "Celebrating Carolee Schneemann’s Archives at Stanford" events:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-viewing-of-the-carolee-schneemann-diaries"&gt;Viewing of the Carolee Schneemann Diaries&lt;/a&gt;, Monday, 10/20 from 2:30 - 4 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-keynote-and-panel-discussion-with-peggy-phelan-and-kenneth-white"&gt;Keynote and Panel Discussion with Peggy Phelan and Kenneth White&lt;/a&gt; on Monday, 10/20 from 5 - 7:30 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-discussion-on-working-with-the-schneemann-archive"&gt;Discussion on Working with the Schneemann Archive with Katie Anania and Dejan Vasić&lt;/a&gt; on Tuesday, 10/21 from 2 - 4 pm&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About Carolee Schneemann:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carolee Schneemann (1939–2019) was one of the most influential artists of the second part of the twentieth century. Her pioneering work in a range of media—painting, film, video, dance and performance, installation, and the written word—is characterized by radical formal experimentation and critical investigations of subjectivity, the erotic and taboo, and the social construction of the female body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Co-sponsored by Stanford University Libraries, the Carolee Schneemann Foundation, the Department of Art and Art History, the Department of Theater and Performance Studies, and the Department of Feminist, Gender, and Sexuality Studies.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Accessing the Carolee Schneemann Papers at Stanford:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Researchers can access the physical &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/9631452"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Carolee Schneemann Papers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, including the diaries, in the Special Collections and University Archives reading room at Stanford’s Cecil H. Green Library. More information on how to place requests and access the reading room is on the Libraries’ website at library.stanford.edu under “&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/explore-collections"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Explore Collections&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.” Online public access to the digitized diaries is available via &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Searchworks&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the Libraries’ catalog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any questions, please reach out to Lindsay King at kingl@stanford.edu!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-carolee-schneemanns-archives-at-stanford-screening-of-three-films</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50897904785281/huge/bd186527352502a1ebe4c08575e2ad0086e6e58a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="819" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="320261"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Who's Afraid of the Big Bad Wolf at IC Classroom, Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The fairy tale concept of the Big Bad Wolf, or the wolf as rapacious villain, is a popular topic in popular media, and board games are no exception. Yet these depictions frequently reveal more about human cultural traditions and stories than they do about the actual characteristics of real-life wolves. Join us to explore what depictions of wolves in games tell us about the humans that create and play these games!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-whos-afraid-of-the-big-bad-wolf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50764971049224/huge/0dc1546054b91a5dc449eaad832af2c7ee6fe5fa.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2185" width="2360" isDefault="true" fileSize="1019769"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Introduction to NVivo workshop for social science students.  Please register for this session at the following link below:  &lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current"&gt;https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-2336</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47746634515153/huge/4b7271aa6a1855e0b196ba9e4f4d29d03c880256.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Above &amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library) </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Above &amp;amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, curated by the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/speakers" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2025 Ruderman Conference presenters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, is on view in the David Rumsey Map Center &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Wednesday, October 8, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt; - Friday, February 27, 2026&lt;/b&gt;. The exhibition opens in conjunction with the &lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fifth Biennial Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition explores how cartography depicts the depths of the Earth, the ocean floor, weather systems, the solar system, and even the seemingly intangible internet – anything but the thin boundary that divides land and sky that we tend to associate with maps. This exhibition celebrates the multifaceted nature of mapping, inviting reflection on our interconnected existence and revealing the beauty and complexity of our world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/above-below-cartography-beyond-terrain</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50907645575537/huge/66abcb4b11be9e58c37698de6abc31a76c242b19.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3840" width="4800" isDefault="true" fileSize="5645151"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX Fundamentals Workshop at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn the basics of LaTeX, including mathematical expressions, figures, tables, and document structure! Get acquainted with the features provided by Stanford’s Overleaf subscription, in particular a Google-Docs-style collaboration interface with unlimited collaborators. And, learn where to go to find more information when something comes up that you don’t know how to do or when your LaTeX is not compiling for mysterious reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop will be held in the 4th Floor Training Room of the Li &amp;amp; Ma Science Library. Enter the library on the 3rd floor of the Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning and take the stairs to the 4th floor. For elevator access, stop by the circulation desk to borrow an elevator access keycard or contact the organizers in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Target audience: those who have maybe heard of LaTeX and think it might be useful for them, and are looking for a foundational introduction&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/latex-fundamentals-workshop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50711919275190/huge/c90bef2931265e78af3b5b83282ba35693f047ab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="192239"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LexisNexis API Workshop &amp; Demo at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Zoom (link provided upon registration) &amp;amp; Hohbach Hall 125, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 11AM–12PM, Thursday, October 23, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Katie Frey (Data Curator for Programmatic Access)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The LexisNexis API is a subscription-based service that allows researchers to programmatically access and text-mine NexisUni’s News and Legal News collections.  It provides access to the full text of several thousand sources for newspapers, journals, wire services, and newsletters.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop will dive into crafting queries for the LexisNexis API and tools to help refine and scope your queries. We will also share boilerplate Python scripts for accessing the LexisNexis API and methods for making your LexisNexis data analysis ready. Though Python will be used for the demonstration, having familiarity with a programming language is not required to follow along. In depth orientations for using the LexisNexis API are available for those who apply for access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. Once capacity is reached, a waitlist will open. In-person attendees must present a Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lexisnexis-api-workshop-demo</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50939893117795/huge/343e3863efd84a075732e43c9e0233f2f3a7a07c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="714" width="719" isDefault="true" fileSize="164003"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Essential Engagement: The Works of Joseph DeLappe" Exhibit Opening and Artist Talk at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join us for the opening of &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Essential Engagement: The Works of Joseph DeLappe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, a retrospective exhibit of the works of Joseph DeLappe (b. 1963) in the Silicon Valley Archives exhibition space, Hohbach Hall, Cecil H. Green Library, on the Stanford campus. This event will feature an artist’s talk by Joseph DeLappe, followed by an engaging conversation with Joel Slayton, founding director of the CADRE Lab at San Jose State University, to celebrate the opening of this exhibit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The prolific work of Joseph DeLappe, spanning a wide range of physical and digital mediums, provides an opportunity for critical reflection and thoughtful discussions about our relationship to technology and the post-9/11 political landscape. As the most comprehensive repository of materials related to the history and development of the Silicon Valley region, the Silicon Valley Archives is honored to exhibit a selection of this work and bring the history of recent technology into conversation with our present through this pioneering artist’s work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Growing out of a prior project and conference at San Jose State in 1984, the CADRE Lab was founded as an academic program for exploring the emerging interactions between computation and the arts. It was arguably the first such lab, and the first student to pass through the program was Joseph DeLappe. Joel Slayton, the founding director of the Lab, will join us for a conversation about CADRE’s impact on digital and media arts, particularly in the Bay Area. This conversation will be moderated by Henry Lowood, the Harold C. Hohbach Curator and head of the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A guided tour of the exhibit will follow the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1Jel1ombwQA7e6lQi2YfvsBmMFzJ5V0SziokK1L67oVw/preview" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Registration is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joseph DeLappe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:inherit;"&gt;, born San Francisco 1963, is an artist, activist and educator, he relocated to Scotland from the USA in 2017 where he is the Professor of Games and Tactical Media at Abertay University, Dundee. Working with electronic and digital media since 1983, projects in online gaming performance, sculpture and electromechanical installation have been shown throughout the world. He has developed works for venues such as Eyebeam Art and Technology in New York, The Guangdong Museum of Art, China, the Southern Utah Museum of Art and Transitio MX, Mexico City, among many others. Creative works and actions have been featured widely in scholarly journals, books and in the popular media, including the &lt;i&gt;New York Times, The Australian Morning Herald, Art in America, The Guardian &lt;/i&gt;and the BBC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:inherit;"&gt;Joel Slayton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is a pioneering artist, researcher, and curator with over 35 years of experience involving art and technology. His work engages a wide range of practice including media, installation and performance and has been featured in over 100 exhibitions around the world. Joel is Professor Emeritus at San Jose State University where he was Founding Director of the CADRE Laboratory for New Media. Joel Slayton was 2018-2019 Stanford University Sterling Visiting Scholar in Department of Chemical Sysems and Biology in the School of Medicine. Joel was curator for the 5th LAST Festival Exhibition at the SLAC National Accelerator at Stanford University in 2018. From 2008-2016 Joel was Executive Director of ZERO1, a Silicon Valley based arts organization where he was responsible for the ZERO1 Biennial, an international exhibition program celebrating creativity and innovation in the arts. Joel serves on the Board of Directors of LEONARDO/ISAST (International Society for Arts, Science, and Technology) where he founded the Leonardo-MIT Press Book Series in 1999 and is a Senior Fellow of the Silicon Valley American Leadership Forum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/essential-engagement</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50694747221575/huge/aa065cfa7a962ff74b283e17c41502a5185ded95.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3779" width="3785" isDefault="true" fileSize="10358048"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planetscope Satellite Imagery 101 at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real-Time Satellite Monitoring with Planet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With roughly 200 Dove satellites in orbit, &lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/products/monitoring/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;PlanetScope Monitoring&lt;/a&gt; provides a high-resolution, continuous, and complete view of the world from above, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planet Monitoring provides 3.7 meter resolution images of the entire Earth daily. Access to these ready-to-use images is made simple with Planet’s APIs, web application, and GIS integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for an Introduction to Planetscope Daily Imagery. This event is designed for those keen on advancing their understanding of leveraging Planetscope Imagery, at scale, for research and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll begin with an overview of Planetscope, and how to get access. Then we'll shift to a hands on demonstration of the Planetscope Explorer, for searching and ordering Planet.com imagery. Finally, we'll introduce the Data &amp;amp; Orders APIs from Planet.com, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Attendees should arrive with their own laptops if they wish to participate. Compters will not be provided. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/planetscope_satellite_imagery_101</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45571105672451/huge/c54c26d6fd58659095920e215bde85e78099f1c9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="79561"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> BibLaTeX and Zotero Workshop at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Learn about how to manage your bibliographies in LaTeX documents! We will introduce you to Zotero, a bibliographic manager app, and to BibLaTeX, a bibliographic system for LaTeX. You will also learn how to export .bib files from Zotero, and how to use Overleaf’s Zotero integration for seamless bibliographic management on collaborative documents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Workshop will be held in the 4th Floor Training Room of the Li &amp;amp; Ma Science Library. Enter the library on the 3rd floor of the Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning and take the stairs to the 4th floor. For elevator access, stop by the circulation desk to borrow an elevator access keycard or contact the organizers in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Target audience: those who already have at least a passing familiarity with LaTeX, and want an introduction to the bibliographic functionalities&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/biblatex-and-zotero-workshop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50711969604442/huge/e4f889ea36b0962e05bdabd888880859d7ea1753.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="192599"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, paint a rock, grab a coffee! at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Take a moment to relax while painting a rock or just stop by the Branner Earth Sciences Library for free coffee, tea, and snacks. We'll have festive coloring pages too!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Help us reduce waste, bring a covered mug!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID card at the front-desk to sign-in.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take-a-break-paint-a-rock</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50842748643898/huge/3e31881505da44f83e9de4c1f9e81efa6d3114d2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="406" width="512" isDefault="true" fileSize="64742"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The UC OSPO Survey 2025 (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month Virginia Scarlett will be joining from UC Santa Barbara to discuss the 2025 UC OSPO Survey. Once considered a radical experiment, open source software is now ubiquitous in the modern technology landscape. In the technology industry, the Open Source Program Office (OSPO) is a common way to centralize a company’s open source strategy, knowledge, and diligence. Meanwhile, OSPOs are just beginning to take root in academia. While guidance for university OSPOs is emerging, many questions remain about how OSPOs best support their university’s strategic priorities and their community’s needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University of California (UC) OSPO Network is working to develop infrastructure for open source education, discovery, and sustainability at UC by pooling our resources and knowledge. To develop our strategic priorities and to assess the state of UC open source, we conducted a survey in April 2025 of more than 230 UC-affiliated open source contributors. This survey sheds light on how and why academics contribute to open source projects, as well as some of the barriers holding them back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;a href="https://bayareaopensciencegroup.github.io/"&gt;Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/a&gt; is a growing community for Bay Area academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/uc-ospo-survey-2025</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50904955791923/huge/b8b4122b07f8f2ef0ab24b3c629682520affb3df.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="102446"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis with Python at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM–2:30PM, Wednesday, October 29, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm (Head of Data Science Training and Consultation)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Curious about how to work with text data using Python? Join us for a practical introduction to text analysis, tailored for those new to programming. This workshop will cover key techniques, including text pre-processing, named entity recognition, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis. No prior Python experience is necessary. We’ll guide you through foundational Python concepts, introduce essential libraries and modules for text analysis, and provide hands-on examples to support your learning. This event is a great starting point for discovering the potential of Python in working with text data, and will inspire you to learn Python to gain even greater insights and capabilities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. A waitlist will open once all spots are filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/text-analysis-with-python-707</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50719575533440/huge/f929f96ae33fc533d9a2b342f6fff365b2e2b574.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39152"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in R</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual (link provided upon registration)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;1PM–4PM, Tuesday, November 4, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to working with data visualization in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate common plots (e.g., scatter , and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure R and RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop. You can download both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-visualization-in-r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50722022202099/huge/d0f7d051b95765a98fd23defb55a52282451eec6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Nov. 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-2026</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693397424570/huge/41bca654587cde9ea86a68b313125093dc8f8074.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historic US Land Record Search at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Have you heard of "public lands" but you're not quite sure what that means? Are you curious about what California's land looked like in the past? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Join us for an introduction to searching for historic land records&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; and a tutorial &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;on using the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;US Federal &lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;General &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;Land&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; Office &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;Record&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;s database&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;This publicly-accessible database is maintained by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and contains thousands of land records, maps, and surveys that contain a multifaceted history of the American West (and beyond).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;In this session, we’ll cover how to find master title plats, cadastral surveys, surveyor’s field notes, as well as original patent documents (focusing on California) so if you want to learn how the US Federal government documents federal and private &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; title, rights, and usage, this workshop is for you.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
There are many uses of these primary source documents; whether you have an interest in history, federal law and governance, natural resources (agriculture, mining, forestry etc), land use (urbanization, privatization, environmentalism etc), or surveying and cartography, there should be something in this session for you! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We'll begin with an overview of &lt;b&gt;native lands&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;US federal public land management&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;surveying&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;legal land descriptions&lt;/b&gt;. Then we'll shift to a hands on demonstration of the GLO Records Database for searching and downloading land record documents. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Attendees should arrive with their own laptops if they wish to participate. Compters will not be provided. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/land-record-search</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51004804671114/huge/4ac9f135701ac67ccd68906919ddbfbb03086aad.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="2000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2453555"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Rescue Project: Protecting Knowledge in the Digital Age at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does rescuing data matter for democracy, science, and society? Join us for a hybrid event with Lynda Kellam, co-founder of the Data Rescue Project, as she shares insights from the frontlines of this grassroots movement. From climate records to health statistics, public data is always at risk—but through collective action, the Data Rescue Project works to safeguard endangered government datasets for future generations. Learn how these vital resources are being preserved and discover how you, too, can play a role in protecting public knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-rescue-project-protecting-knowledge-in-the-digital-age</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50939877171293/huge/76e6b2863104139c76dd3bef4dced1c5fc78feb2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="721" width="724" isDefault="true" fileSize="100862"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for Academic Research at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM - 2:30PM, Wednesday, November 12, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm (Head of Data Science Training and Consultation)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Looking to harness AI to streamline your research workflow? This workshop introduces the architecture and applications of large language models (LLMs) and shows you how to use them effectively and responsibly in academic research. We’ll cover common use cases, capabilities and limitations, and key ethical considerations. Topics include data preprocessing, strategies for working with tabular data, and evaluation approaches for LLM-driven research tasks. You’ll also gain hands-on experience with Stanford’s AI Playground API. By the end, you’ll have the knowledge, practical skills, and sample code to integrate AI into your research workflow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is intended for researchers with programming experience who want in-depth knowledge of LLMs. If you’re new to coding, we recommend taking &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/text-analysis-with-python-707"&gt;Text Analysis with Python&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. A waitlist will open once all spots are filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ai-for-academic-research</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50719593830494/huge/5c5f7466f5603c476d3de7e68c4fbe697fb58ec3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data in R at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1–3PM, Wednesday, November 19, 2025 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Claudia Engel, Academic Technology Specialist (Anthropology)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop will introduce you to geospatial libraries and concepts using R. Prior experience using R at an introductory level is expected. You will learn how to read spatial data into R and perform basic spatial analysis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure R and RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop. You can download both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/geospatial-data-in-r</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50722044082493/huge/bc6c1a989566c790ce132f97b50fe628309e8b5c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeannette Estruth in Conversation with Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew on women libertarians in Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming the historian Jeannette Estruth as she discusses her new research on the history of women libertarians in Silicon Valley. Jeannette will be joined in conversation by the Stanford historians Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley today represents not only a specific location in California but also a larger imaginative vision that shapes economic and social realities. In this powerful conceptual landscape, the libertarian political fantasy emerges as a critical factor of cultural reproduction. In this talk and the conversation that follows, Jeannette Estruth will reveal how the Libertarian Party in Silicon Valley of the 1990s built durable and significant connections between technology firms, media, and the voting public in ways that were deeply rooted in the specific geographies and histories of Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This political moment in Silicon Valley rehearsed a powerful political script that combined technology, the free market, sexuality, gender, anti-statism, and electoral politics. Estruth argues that Santa Clara and San Mateo counties’ local Libertarian Parties were crucial to Silicon Valley’s libertarianism, and to its political development as a technology hub, a financial center, and a site of production for a powerful vision of the future. By turning back to the 1990s, we can learn much about the world we live in today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jeannette Estruth&lt;/b&gt; is an assistant professor of history at Santa Clara University. Her writing has appeared in venues ranging from the Washington Post to the Business History Review. She is completing her book manuscript, &lt;i&gt;Think Different: Silicon Valley Activism and the Making of Modern American Politics&lt;/i&gt;, which explores the history of social movements, the technology industry, and economic culture in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jennifer Burns&lt;/b&gt; is a professor of history at Stanford University. She is a historian of the twentieth century United States working at the intersection of intellectual, political, and cultural history, with a particular interest in ideas about the state, markets, and capitalism and how these play out in policy and politics. Her most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Milton Friedman: The Last Conservative,&lt;/i&gt; is the first full biography of the influential economist and political figure. It was awarded the 2025 Reagan Book Prize and was a finalist for the 2024 Hayek Prize. She has published articles about the history of conservatism, libertarianism, and liberalism in a number of academic and popular journals, including &lt;i&gt;Reviews in American History, Modern Intellectual History, Journal of Cultural Economy, The New York Times, The New Republic, &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Dissent&lt;/i&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jenni Depew&lt;/b&gt; is a PhD student in history at Stanford University. She studies the history of American political thought and development from the 18th to 21st centuries. She has previously published work on the role of the U.S. Presidency in regards to civil rights, third parties in the 19th century, and Indigenous food sovereignty in her home state of Wisconsin. Her most recent work focuses on the history of libertarianism. Jennifer is also a Knight-Hennessy Scholar, JD student at Stanford Law School, and former graduate research assistant at the Stanford Internet Observatory (SIO).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jeannette-estruth-in-conversation-with-jennifer-burns-and-jenni-depew-on-women-libertarians-in-silicon-valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50703481059715/huge/870f537346dcff60bfe8880798ff989b9ec4fdab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1572" width="1500" isDefault="true" fileSize="1594716"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MingKwai, Rediscovered at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us on December 2, 2025, as we explore the origins of of the incredible MingKwai typewriter, trace its history across continents, and examine its lasting cultural and technological impact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MingKwai Chinese Typewriter, a milestone in the history of Chinese information technology, was invented by the Chinese-born author, translator, and cultural commentator Lin Yutang in the 1940s. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/22/nyregion/mingkwai-typewriter-china.html"&gt;Discovered in a New York basement&lt;/a&gt;, this extraordinary prototype has been entrusted to the Stanford University Libraries, where it will be used in research, exhibits, and academic programs. Read more about this discovery in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/05/mingkwai-chinese-typewriter-prototype-stanford-libraries"&gt;The Stanford Report&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/07/05/nx-s1-5405452/chinese-typewriter-mingkwai-stanford"&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the typewriter’s rediscovery and new home at Stanford, we will be bringing together scholars and experts from across multiple disciplines to reintroduce the legendary MingKwai Chinese Typewriter to the world. Dr. Thomas S. Mullaney, Professor of Chinese History at Stanford University, will lead a team of researchers and students in exploring the MingKwai&lt;i&gt;'&lt;/i&gt;s historical, technological, and cultural significance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mingkwai"&gt;Learn&lt;/a&gt; about the typewriter, and &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mingkwai-rediscovered-tickets-1752379427039"&gt;secure your ticket&lt;/a&gt; to the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mingkwai-rediscovered</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50916171408489/huge/c7fcfe7688e04b7612519de9f800399d9a68e1b6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="418" width="639" isDefault="true" fileSize="340462"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 3 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7123</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693405343948/huge/daea989242dbe63d8d8d26df0ddd96a0e16e347b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Max Kasy in conversation with Rob Reich on How AI Really Works and Who Benefits at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI is inescapable, from its mundane uses online to its increasingly consequential decision-making in courtrooms, job interviews, and wars. The ubiquity of AI is so great that it might produce public resignation—a sense that the technology is our shared fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how is the technical structure of AI shaped by social power and inequalities? In this book talk and conversation, Max Kasy will discuss how who AI serves is determined not by the technology itself but by who it is built to serve. How can we shape AI to benefit all? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Kasy’s new book, &lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction&lt;/i&gt;, reveals how artificial intelligence, far from being an unstoppable force, is irrevocably shaped by human decisions—choices made to date by the ownership class that steers its development and deployment. The technology of AI, Kasy insists, is ultimately not that complex. It is insidious, however, in its capacity to steer results to its owners’ wants and ends. Kasy clearly and accessibly explains the fundamental principles on which AI works, and, in doing so, reveals that the real conflict isn’t between humans and machines, but between those who control the machines and the rest of us.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction&lt;/i&gt; offers a powerful vision of the future of AI: a future not shaped by technology, but by the technology’s owners. Amid a deluge of debates about technical details, new possibilities, and social problems, Kasy cuts to the core issue: Who controls AI’s objectives, and how is this control maintained? The answer lies in what he calls “the means of prediction,” or the essential resources required for building AI systems: data, computing power, expertise, and energy. As Kasy shows, in a world already defined by inequality, one of humanity’s most consequential technologies has been and will be steered by those already in power.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Against those stakes, Kasy offers an elegant framework both for understanding AI’s capabilities and for designing its public control. He makes a compelling case for democratic control over AI objectives as the answer to mounting concerns about AI’s risks and harms. &lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction &lt;/i&gt;is a revelation, both an expert undressing of a technology that has masqueraded as more complicated and a compelling call for public oversight of this transformative technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kasy is joined in conversation by Rob Reich, the McGregor-Girand Professor of Social Ethics of Science and Technology at Stanford. Reich’s scholarship in political theory engages with the work of social scientists and engineers. His newest work is on governance of frontier science and technology. His most recent books are &lt;i&gt;System Error: Where Big Tech Went Wrong and How We Can Reboot&lt;/i&gt; (with Mehran Sahami and Jeremy M. Weinstein, HarperCollins 2021) and &lt;i&gt;Digital Technology and Democratic Theory&lt;/i&gt; (edited with Lucy Bernholz and Hélène Landemore, University of Chicago Press 2021). Reich has testified before Congress and written widely for the public, including for the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Washington Post&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Wired&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Time&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;Stanford Social Innovation Review&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kasy is a professor of economics at Oxford University, where he coordinates the Machine Learning and Economics Group. His research interests include machine learning theory, publication bias, adaptive experimental design, statistical decision theory, identification and causality, and economic inequality. He has received grants from the Alfred P. Sloan foundation, served as an expert for the EU Directorate for Research and Innovation, and received the Young Economist Award from the Economic Association of Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/max-kasy-in-conversation-with-rob-reich</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50772311503808/huge/436c3c99b75fe5d254c5963d4b9df88a89f17884.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1228" width="1228" isDefault="true" fileSize="482510"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope and Despair: The Emotional Response to the War in Ukraine at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Gabrielius Landsbergis, Bernard and Susan Liautaud Visiting Fellow, and Michael McFaul, Director of the Freeman Spogli Institute, as they discuss the emotional journey surrounding Russia's war against Ukraine, its global implications, and transatlantic support for Ukraine.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hope and Despair: The Emotional Response to the War in Ukraine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few months, new technological developments or limited battlefield successes by either Russia or Ukraine spark sweeping claims that the war's outcome has been decided. Shortly thereafter, these narratives often collapse, leading to a reversal and a cycle of inflated expectations followed by disillusionment. Despite this tumultuous rollercoaster of hope and despair, one fact remains clear: Ukraine has not lost, and Russia has not won. Both outcomes – and their opposites – are still possible. For those of us who support Ukraine, this uncertainty is, in itself, a positive sign. However, hope alone cannot be our only strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a discussion with Michael McFaul, Gabrielius Landsbergis will explore how to cut through the shifting headlines to understand the real picture and what actions must be taken to strengthen Ukraine, so that hope is not our sole approach. He will examine what fuels this state of uncertainty and what factors can help us grasp the balance of power on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gabrielius Landsbergis &lt;/b&gt;served as minister of foreign affairs of Lithuania from 2020 to 2024, a pivotal period for the region. He led Lithuania’s diplomatic service guided by the principle of values-based foreign policy. During his tenure, Lithuania emerged as one of the most vocal supporters of Ukraine, Taiwan, and freedom fighters worldwide. Before that, he served in the Parliament of Lithuania from 2016, was chairman of the Homeland Union (Lithuanian Conservatives), and was elected to the European Parliament in 2014. Prior to entering politics, Gabrielius Landsbergis was a career diplomat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;He currently serves as Bernard and Susan Liautaud Visiting Fellow at Stanford's Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael McFaul&lt;/b&gt; is director at the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies, the Ken Olivier and Angela Nomellini Professor of International Studies in the Department of Political Science, and the Peter and Helen Bing Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1995. He served for five years in the Obama administration, first as special assistant to the President and senior director for Russian and Eurasian affairs at the National Security Council at the White House (2009-2012), and then as U.S. ambassador to the Russian Federation (2012-2014).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This in-person event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/KpygQDtEkUsd4sSZA"&gt;Registration is required.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/hope-and-despair-landsbergis-mcfaul</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50915768794722/huge/1fc6ce93f885bb71e112d46f0af9deb651e3cef7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1010" width="1078" isDefault="true" fileSize="1590047"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
