<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Translating Three Japanese Masters, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura, and Kazuko Shiraishi: Selections from the Yumiko Tsumura Collection at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On display at the East Asia Library from 3/6/25-5/13/25, selections from a recent donation from Yumiko Tsumura, a local poet and translator, related to three major modern Japanese authors, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura and Kazuko Shiraishi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yumiko Kurahashi’s meteoric career began with &lt;i&gt;Parutai&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;The Party&lt;/i&gt;), a brilliant satire of the Japanese leftist students movement that she wrote while still a student. As part of a first generation of women writers who had benefited from equal opportunity for education in the post-war period, her innovative writing style, influenced by Satre, Kafka, and Camus, rocked the literary world of the 1960s, exposing structural inequities in Japanese society. Perhaps the most renowned post-WWII Japanese poet, Ryuichi Tamura’s poetry searingly reveals the agony of war and the disorientation induced by rapid modernization. Kazuko Shiraishi, known for performing her provocative poetry to jazz accompaniment, has been called the “Allen Ginsberg of Japan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to introduce this donation in an exhibit in our main exhibit space. Please visit the East Asia Library to learn more about these three authors, who each left a powerful critique of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/east-asia-library-exhibits-selections-yumiko-tsumura-collection-japanese-poetry"&gt;Read an interview with the donor, Yumiko Tsumura, to learn more about her and each of these authors.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/translating-three-japanese-masters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49021026270886/huge/0a889191391152cee3133e7261ae17eb90597460.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="469" width="512" isDefault="true" fileSize="80335"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ART/WORK at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;ART/WORK | Creative Pursuits of Stanford Libraries Staff&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; on view February 20, 2024, through April 27, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this exhibition, we sought to create a space where staff could share their artistic, creative side that may not otherwise be a part of their work at Stanford. In the Summer of 2024, Special Collections invited current Stanford Libraries staff to enter creative work in any medium to be considered for a Winter 2025 exhibit in Green Library’s Peterson Gallery and Rotunda. Response to the call for entries was hearty. In addition to traditional fine art techniques of drawing, painting, printmaking, and photography, submissions included mixed media sculpture, ceramics, collage, textiles, and poetry. An anonymous selection committee of library staff blind-reviewed over a hundred entries and chose the fifty works displayed in the galleries. We asked the people whose pieces were selected to write a brief statement to accompany their work in the exhibit and posed several questions for their consideration: Why do creative work? What medium do you work in and why? How did you get started? What does it mean to you to be an artist (if you define yourself as one)? Does art need an audience? Who is your audience? What influences your work, and whose work do you admire? As you will see, Stanford library staff are talented and thoughtful, pursuing many forms of creative work after hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo, Associate University Librarian, Director of Special Collections and Frances and Charles Field Curator of Special Collections; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their careful consideration of all staff art submissions, we thank the staff members who served on the jury; For their assessment of materials, Aisha Wahab and Beth Ryan in Conservation Services; For their assistance with logistics Ranelle Sharma and Jacob Cohn in Library Facilities, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/artwork</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48687359684680/huge/603b1fb303d73747de62963ba10e4c95a4135903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="78990"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panoply of Pop-Ups exhibition, Bowes Library, Winter quarter at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: Come see flying playing cards in &lt;i&gt;Alice in Wonderland&lt;/i&gt; to Dada-inspired happenings in &lt;i&gt;Cabaret Voltaire. &lt;/i&gt;Featuring books from the Bowes Locked Stacks collection. Curated by Lorna Corbetta and Katie Keller. On view Winter quarter. M-Th 9-7, F 9-5, Sun 12-6. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/panoply-of-pop-ups-exhibition-bowes-library-winter-quarter</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48536008940945/huge/8a9499777f165c14ff6964627b2ef65d13591452.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3264" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="9109456"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art of the Ad: Fashion for a New Century  at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pochoir fashion plates and advertisements are part of the allure of early 20th-century Parisian fashion magazines. Art history major, Sita Adel, '26 investigates the role of fashion in her Spring exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On view in Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 1 - June 20th. M-Th 9-7, Fri 9-5, Sun. 12-6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/art-of-the-ad-fashion-for-a-new-century</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49092294783840/huge/f89ef044fd107f813a0005d6667e49c04115261e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="626799"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right to Privacy: Lowry Pressly in Conversation with Alexander Nemerov at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Lowry Pressly for a conversation with Alexander Nemerov. The two will discuss Pressly's newly published book, &lt;i&gt;The Right to Oblivion: Privacy and the Good Life&lt;/i&gt;, on April 1, 2025. This event is co-sponsored by the &lt;a href="https://ethicsinsociety.stanford.edu/"&gt;McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/books/9780674260528"&gt;A copy can be purchased here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts of our lives that are not being surveilled and turned into data diminish each day. We are able to configure privacy settings on our devices and social media platforms, but we know our efforts pale in comparison to the scale of surveillance capitalism and algorithmic manipulation. In our hyperconnected era, many have begun to wonder whether it is still possible to live a private life, or whether it is no longer worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Right to Oblivion&lt;/i&gt; argues incisively and persuasively that we still can and should strive for privacy, though for different reasons than we might think. Recent years have seen heated debate in the realm of law and technology about why privacy matters, often focusing on how personal data breaches amount to violations of individual freedom. Yet as Lowry Pressly shows, the very terms of this debate have undermined our understanding of privacy’s real value. In a novel philosophical account, Pressly insists that privacy isn’t simply a right to be protected but a tool for making life meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy deepens our relationships with others as well as ourselves, reinforcing our capacities for agency, trust, play, self-discovery, and growth. Without privacy, the world would grow shallow, lonely, and inhospitable. Drawing inspiration from the likes of Hannah Arendt, Jorge Luis Borges, and a range of contemporary artists, Pressly shows why we all need a refuge from the world: not a place to hide, but a psychic space beyond the confines of a digital world in which the individual is treated as mere data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lowry Pressly&lt;/b&gt; is a lecturer in the Department of Political Science, the McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society, and the Stanford Civics Initiative. His philosophical work, criticism, fiction, and translations appear in a wide variety of publications, both academic and popular, including most recently &lt;i&gt;Ethics&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Asymptote&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;Los Angeles Review of Books&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alexander Nemerov&lt;/b&gt; is the author of many books on American art, most recently &lt;i&gt;The Forest: A Fable of America in the 1830s&lt;/i&gt;, praised by the novelist Annie Proulx as “one of the richest books ever to come my way—deeply beautiful, achingly painful and astonishingly tender”; and &lt;i&gt;Fierce Poise: Helen Frankenthaler and 1950s New York&lt;/i&gt;, named by &lt;i&gt;Vogue&lt;/i&gt; one of its best books of 2021 and a finalist for the National Book Critics Circle Award in Biography. Nemerov is the Carl and Marilynn Thoma Provostial Professor in the Arts and Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-right-to-privacy-lowry-pressly-in-conversation-with-alexander-nemerov</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48906044806136/huge/e36dee4ba12a99217e43e27fa8598bc15e8632f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="480" width="480" isDefault="true" fileSize="39134"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, April 2 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-8571</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exhibit Opening: Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves&lt;/b&gt; and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto &lt;/b&gt;(CISAC) to celebrate the opening of the temporary exhibit in Green Library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;"Why Estonia? The 30-Year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia"&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/a&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit opening features a talk, &lt;b&gt;“What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/b&gt; by former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves&lt;/b&gt;, kicking off &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit"&gt;a series of three talks&lt;/a&gt; on e-Estonia hosted by Stanford Libraries in April-May. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves &lt;/b&gt;is an advisor to the Deputy Prime Minister of Ukraine on questions of AI and digital transformation and a non-resident fellow at the International Center for Defence Studies (Tallinn, Estonia). &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;From 2022–2024, Luukas was Government CIO and Undersecretary for Digital Transformation of Estonia. He previously held various roles with the Government of Estonia and the European Commission, has worked for the cryptography deep tech Guardtime, and as deputy director and senior fellow at the Lisbon Council (a Brussels-based thinktank).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Luukas is a recipient of the Estonian Order of the White Star and President Zelensky’s Ukraine Peace Prize. He is a graduate of Stanford University.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening remarks will be delivered by &lt;b&gt;Michael Keller&lt;/b&gt; (Stanford Libraries) and &lt;b&gt;Ivo Lille &lt;/b&gt;(Vabamu), with &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt; (CISAC) moderating the discussion. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A guided tour of the exhibit will follow the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Z1fuRRkZMSA7v6ZW7"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks that are related to the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit"&gt;"Why Estonia?" exhibit in Green Library &lt;/a&gt;and that explore e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783405896477/huge/51c9ed5ab4294eec599fce1abe366bfc4c9c07ff.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="866" width="870" isDefault="true" fileSize="1387240"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to QGIS (April 4th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis and Map Construction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 09:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-qgis-april-4th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39501269457862/huge/c9436efb55d1fa91fd8c88e2008b705fd725d305.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="422" width="597" isDefault="true" fileSize="284421"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persuasive Data Graphics Practicum with RJ Andrews at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data graphics are magical. Come learn how pictures can help us discover and discuss otherwise invisible phenomena. We will dissect the elements that make charts spectacular, ranging from choosing effective visual metaphors to picturing uncertainty and the subtle art of color-encoding. Our emphasis will be on the hard human decisions necessary to create effective data graphics. Our learning will be anchored by masterpieces of information design, including the study of rare works on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdKbOHdW-so9qbcQvDkTy2s1QnXgom9jH-RKHozcfNj5AAddg/viewform?usp=dialog"&gt;submit a brief application&lt;/a&gt; to apply to take part in the practicum. Applications are due at 5pm PST on &lt;b&gt;Monday, March 24&lt;/b&gt; to be considered. Please note that &lt;u&gt;the practicum is only open to Stanford affiliates.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About RJ Andrews&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ Andrews is a San Francisco data storyteller. By day, he tackles high-stakes problems for clients like The White House and Google. By night, he studies the history of charts, maps, and diagrams. The overlap between Andrews’ hands-on real-world practice and deep historical research gave rise to his latest book, &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/persuasive-data-graphics-practicum-with-rj-andrews</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48871376554133/huge/044bb7d98fcd9be252f9b2100efa95db6ca15d9b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1370" width="2189" isDefault="true" fileSize="2141757"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Info We Trust Book Launch at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for the launch of &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; (Visionary Press, 2025), an illuminating journey through the world of data storytelling. Author RJ Andrews weaves a rich tapestry of insights, combining text and imagery to trace the evolution of data graphics from simple products of civilization to potent instruments of persuasion. With a storyteller’s flair, Andrews navigates narrative artistry and scientific inquiry to get at the heart of information design: creating meaning from space, time, and beyond. Featuring hundreds of hand-drawn illustrations and dotted with fascinating marginalia, &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; is a visual feast that captures the essence and excitement of data storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdS-7qGn9WK7AeICkYNge2698Ax7H9t-AgpcFYHBYOT7aRKZA/viewform?usp=preview"&gt;register in advance&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Copies of &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; will be available to purchase at the talk. This is an in-person-only event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About RJ Andrews&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ Andrews is a San Francisco data storyteller. By day, he tackles high-stakes problems for clients like The White House and Google. By night, he studies the history of charts, maps, and diagrams. The overlap between Andrews’ hands-on real-world practice and deep historical research gave rise to &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/info-we-trust-book-launch</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48810483174129/huge/c952d9edc3be71785e4517ca86bcf5f9053ad9ce.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="4630325"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: Food at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Growing, providing, preparing, sharing, and consuming food are all essential for human life.  At the most fundamental, biological level, food sustains life by delivering nutrients and staving off hunger. But the ways people eat and the ways they think about food, as well as what people eat -- and don’t eat -- are strongly influenced by culture, ritual, ethics, climate, geography, technology, and economics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Drop by Hohbach 123 (Silicon Valley Archive classroom, Green Library) any time between 2-4 PM on Tuesday, April 8th to partake in a curated tasting menu of Special, Unique and Rare delicacies from the Libraries’ collections that have something to say about FOOD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-food</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49217733501357/huge/ab7c67d7c72e72730b1651ea89c8ce0fec92fdda.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3139" width="2271" isDefault="true" fileSize="3502198"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Pop-up! Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library, April 9th, 2-4 PM at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From scallop shells to Chinese menus, stop by to see a variety of artists' books about food selected from our Locked Stacks collection. On view in the Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 9, 2-4 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-april-9th-2-4-pm</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49162378344239/huge/688a1a4421171f961c5744a824d1e228910db6ad.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="310030"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk &amp; Panel on the Work of Visiting Artist Sohei Nishino at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by visiting artist &lt;a href="https://soheinishino.net/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sohei Nishino&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; followed by remarks and reflections on the artist’s work by a distinguished group of panelists including cultural historian Abby Smith Rumsey; poet and Stanford lecturer in creative writing, Sara Michas-Martin; and associate professor of the history of the built environment at the University of California, Santa Cruz, Albert Narath. The program will conclude with a panel discussion and Q&amp;amp;A facilitated by art historian and Stanford ITALIC Associate Director Kim Beil and David Rumsey Map Center staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScURuI9ZRQtdyWABC4zvyvj89HLdi5v0Z8sUaWfk_O756Dziw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;register to attend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/talk-panel-on-visiting-artist-sohei-nishinos-work</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49082204927615/huge/9310b57b1135015f4b941582f3f6981bf4fceb81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1000" width="1000" isDefault="true" fileSize="508439"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: April 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-april-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by &lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet &lt;/b&gt;(University of Southern California) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia is often portrayed as the world’s most advanced „digital state, “ where citizens can vote, do their taxes, and renew their driver’s license, all online. But before the „digital state,“ there was the „National Automated Control System." From the 1960s, cyberneticians, sociologists, and management scientists in Ukraine, Estonia, Novosibirsk, and elsewhere imagined constructing a network of data centers – the NACS – that would revitalize the Soviet empire. They failed in building this network, but their expertise catalyzed large social movements that ultimately contributed to the empire’s collapse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk provides a history of the information age in the Soviet Union. This history is relevant not only because expertise from this period led to some of the most innovative work in digital public infrastructure in 1990s Estonia but also because visionaries then were grappling with questions that remain relevant today: What is the relationship between digital technology and the state? What are the risks and rewards of collecting and processing data about the public? And can technology aid or disrupt the functioning of an authoritarian state?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet&lt;/b&gt; is an Associate Professor of History at the University of Southern California. He is a visiting researcher at the Davis Center at Princeton University and a visiting researcher at the Institute of Social Studies at the University of Tartu. He writes about technological utopias and the history of science in a variety of imperial and post-imperial contexts. His first book, Pasteur’s Empire (Oxford University Press, 2020), looked at how bacteriologists reimagined imperial governance in early twentieth century France. His current project, The Information Revolution, looks at how computer engineers reimagined imperial governance in late twentieth century Soviet Union.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session and screening of the film, &lt;b&gt;"Disco and Atomic War" &lt;/b&gt;(2009). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The film tells the story of a strange kind of information war, where a totalitarian regime stands face to face with the heroes of popular culture. And loses. It was a time when it was possible for erotic film star Emmanuelle to bring down the Red Army and MacGyver to outdo an entire school administration. It is a film about our generation, who were unknowingly brought to the front line of the Cold War. Western popular culture had an incomparable role shaping Soviet children's world views in those days. Finnish television was a window to a world of dreams that the authorities could not block in any way. Though Finnish channels were banned, many households found some way to access the forbidden fruit." – Warsaw Film Festival&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/XqSgxs4Y1R5UGfsj9"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks that are related to the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit"&gt;"Why Estonia?" exhibit in Green Library &lt;/a&gt;and that explore e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783490397155/huge/20687f99a4a0c0a96409655cc6b6787f9e085f1e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="722" width="692" isDefault="true" fileSize="941498"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matteo Maggiori: Geoeconomics and the US-China Great Power Competition at GSB Knight Management Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford University Libraries&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://sccei.fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford Center on China's Economy and Institutions&lt;/a&gt; are pleased to present the &lt;b&gt;2025 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture&lt;/b&gt; featuring &lt;b&gt;Professor Matteo Maggiori &lt;/b&gt;who will be speaking on &lt;i&gt;Geoeconomics and the US-China Great Power Competition.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;To attend in person, please register &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/2rDmd8jGWSbXBioXA" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;To attend online, please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_5XWbHcREQW-7ib6JqIMlRw" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Professor Maggiori&lt;/b&gt; will discuss how the U.S. and China apply economic pressure to achieve their political and economic goals, and the economic costs and benefits that this competition is imposing on the world. A discussion of economic security policies that other countries are implementing to shield their economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.matteomaggiori.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Professor Maggiori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is the Moghadam Family Professor of Finance at the Stanford Graduate School of Business. His research focuses on international macroeconomics and finance. He is a co-founder and director of the Global Capital Allocation Project. His research topics have included the analysis of exchange rates under imperfect capital markets, capital flows, the international monetary system, reserve currencies, geoeconomics, tax havens, very long-run discount rates and climate change, and expectations and portfolio investment. His research combines theory and data with the aim of improving international economic policy. He is a faculty research fellow at the National Bureau of Economic Research and a research affiliate at the Center for Economic Policy Research. He received his PhD from the University of California at Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among a number of honors, he is the recipient of the Fischer Black Prize awarded to an outstanding financial economist under the age of 40, the Carnegie and Guggenheim fellowships, and the Bernacer Prize for outstanding contributions in macroeconomics and finance by a European economist under age 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family of &lt;b&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/b&gt; donated his personal archive to the Stanford University Libraries' Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world's largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia. &lt;a href="https://hsiehlecture.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2025hsiehlecture</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427663</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.162043</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49038974016477/huge/b9018054c15077f158e533c0b97ff90e03f35e75.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="622482"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (April 18th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the More Info link for registration and workshop landing page URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing-in-qgis-april-18th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39519065549929/huge/36ecf7eef696ef2fc4be5cd1cafb4c93c8ea2a25.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Time, Space and Habitat: a talk by Dr. Ben Gitai at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have always shaped and been shaped by the landscapes they inhabit. "Chronomapping" is an innovative methodology developed by Dr. Gitai that investigates landscape transformations through time by integrating data and insights from disciplines such as architecture, landscape architecture, hydrology, urban planning, climatology, ecology, sociology, anthropology, political geography, history, and even the psychology of aesthetics. The methodology is a means to produce visual representations and new conceptual frameworks of territories and habitats across time. It can also cast power dynamics and territorial transformations in new lights by examining the interplay between terrain, territory, and cartography across historical periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is designed to serve as a counterbalance to the short-sightedness that has characterized much development in the Western world. The methodology is explicitly designed to account for the palimpsestic nature of development. It has both scholarly and practical applications with potential utility in fields of governance, urban and spatial planning, and industrial development. Dr. Gitai's lecture will reference two of his forthcoming publications: &lt;i&gt;Mapping Power: History of Landscape in the Jordan Valley&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Landscapes Atlas of Paris&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the speaker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ben Gitai integrates geography, architecture, and related disciplines in his research and practice. He has taught at various institutions in Switzerland (ETHZ, EPFL) and France. His cross-disciplinary approach combines tools and perspectives from landscape architecture, urban planning, political geography, and history, exploring the evolution of geo-spatial configurations over historical periods and how these transformations reflect broader socio-political and economic processes. His work recontextualizes mapping practices as instruments for understanding the complex relationships between human and natural systems, offering innovative perspectives on the forces that shape our environments. Today, he is the head coordinator of the Habitat Research Center and the Paris Atlas of Landscapes at EPFL. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScZfdPIJvqU2suflntJ37WPy2l5DzHRt2LS9IeCbNB-MDnfhw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register to attend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is an in-person-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mapping-time-space-and-habitat-a-talk-by-dr-ben-gitai</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48986076260218/huge/574da834c9fe7204b040f8ea7caab42d6ca0da0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="302" width="454" isDefault="true" fileSize="144870"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, May 7 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-4083</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: May 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-may-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Jacob Anbinder, "NIMBY Nation: The War on Growth That Created Our Housing Crisis and Remade American Politics" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jacob Anbinder on May 29, 2025, as he discusses his upcoming book. &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation: The War on Growth That Created Our Housing Crisis and Remade American Politics. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation&lt;/i&gt; is the first history of the modern urban affordability crisis and the political origins of the liberal “NIMBY.” It traces their roots to the national party realignment of the late twentieth century and, specifically, to the ideological transformations that took place among liberals around the issue of urban growth. During the New Deal Era, Democrats across the country emphatically supported the growth of cities and suburbs. Beginning in the fifties, however, Americans dismayed by the unfulfilled promises of postwar society began to question the idea that “the good life” demanded the continued development of the places in which they lived. Over the decades that followed, a constellation of loosely related citizen efforts to guide, limit, or reverse the course of metropolitan growth coalesced into a powerful movement uniting voters, activists, intellectuals, and politicians who once had little in common. By the late twentieth century, their work had produced a new antigrowth liberalism that appealed to disillusioned New Dealers, lapsed leftists, and moderates abandoning the Republican Party. This new generation of Democrats was much more skeptical of—and in many cases downright hostile toward—not only urban growth itself, but also the idea that such growth was in any way compatible with liberalism as they now defined it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Showing how debates about urban growth were central to the process by which the fragile social order of the twentieth century gave way to the fractious politics of the twenty-first, &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation&lt;/i&gt; offers a new understanding of the thing that we call “liberalism,” the influence of local politics in its creation, and its role in making modern American society. While many on the left believe today that America’s most pressing problems—particularly in its largest cities—originate in the Democratic Party’s supposed rightward turn, the history of antigrowth politics shows that Democrats never abandoned their core principle of using government power to effect social progress. Rather, in “blue” cities across the country, new groups of liberals reworked New Deal liberalism to serve different goals, on different ideological bases, at different levels of governance. Their success at reining in the “growth machine” benefited a fortunate few. Yet, their worldview’s own contradictions—unresolved and perhaps unresolvable—also produced the permanent housing shortages, exorbitant real estate prices, unsustainable commutes, and intensified segregation that plague cities today. Moving away from the popular idea that America followed a linear path from “big government” to “neoliberalism,” NIMBY Nation demonstrates that our current cost-of-living crisis is the result not of the inexorable power of laissez-faire—or of simplistic liberal hypocrisy—but rather of Democrats’ deliberate attempts to improve the cities and suburbs in which they lived.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jacob Anbinder&lt;/b&gt; is a historian of the modern United States with a particular focus on the politics of cities and suburbs in the twentieth century. His research interests include the political economy of major infrastructure projects, movements for and against change to the built environment, and the ways in which sprawl and spatial segregation create social inequities. His writing has been published in &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Business History Review&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Week&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Democracy: A Journal of Ideas&lt;/i&gt;, and other outlets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jacob-anbinder-nimby-nation-the-war-on-growth-that-created-our-housing-crisis-and-remade-american-politics</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48914944947267/huge/6006580a3a1941c248b79331b8954649e74a4a0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="515" width="450" isDefault="true" fileSize="29742"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7053</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: June 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-june-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
