<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Cars &amp; Climbing: Systems for Quantifying Performance at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;This exhibition was scheduled to open on January 9. Due to the recent storms, it has been pushed back to January 11. We apologize for any inconvenience.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, enthusiasts have developed methods to describe and rate performance systematically. Based on archival collections at Stanford, this exhibit explores the genesis of these systems as means for quantifying experiences like the difficulty of a rock climbing route or the quality of the ride that an automobile provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public during library hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plan Your Visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library hours vary throughout the year. The most up-to-date hours of operation are available &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/green" style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit our &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;Access &amp;amp; Privileges page&lt;/a&gt; to learn what you will need to bring with you to gain access to the exhibition space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanford has a large campus. Be prepared to traverse at least 0.5 miles during your visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking regulations are enforced from 8 AM - 4 PM on weekdays unless otherwise posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carsandclimbing</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42058361359334/huge/d8427494bcba670de0789cc450b8d5d221702d27.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="682" width="754" isDefault="true" fileSize="1081299"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Near to Far: a View of a Cold War-era Aerospace Engineer &amp; His Company at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;This exhibition was scheduled to open on January 9. Due to the recent storms, the opening date has been pushed back to January 13. We apologize for any inconvenience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Jack Nielsen was Chief Scientist at NASA Ames, and founder of Vidya Inc., before founding Nielsen Engineering and Research. NEAR today is a division of AMA Inc., but the legacy of Nielsen lives on today in this exhibit. This collection is a rare look inside Cold War aerospace and weapons technology, as well as technical report literature from governments and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public during library hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plan Your Visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library hours vary throughout the year. Green Library&amp;#39;s hours of&amp;nbsp;operation are available &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/green"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Access &amp;amp; Privileges page&lt;/a&gt; to learn what you will need to bring with you to gain access to the exhibition space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanford has a large campus.&amp;nbsp;Be prepared to traverse at least 0.5 miles during your visit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking regulations are enforced from 8 AM - 4 PM on weekdays unless otherwise posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/NeartoFar</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42058301559081/huge/36fafe335d4ba8833cf2adab9aa7e6fd18ce788a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="690" width="766" isDefault="true" fileSize="593167"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Book at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 6, 2022, through February 5, 2023 in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Elaine Treharne and Benjamin Albritton, produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_handmade_book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127511947685/huge/fa816f484827df107b7a256d92f54535a019c421.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="581" width="581" isDefault="true" fileSize="232881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Data Workshop: Interview Analysis with NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join Esha Chatterjee, qualitative data software consultant for Stanford Libraries, for an intermediate level class on interview analysis using NVivo software.&amp;nbsp; Learn how to code your interview transcripts and use the software to identify themes using Nvivo.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_data_workshop_interview_analysis_with_nvivo_5908</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42273482117191/huge/4bf3ba6dfa2b4f8f0b12f6d88d8cb15f43509e0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="405" width="720" isDefault="true" fileSize="33409"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction To R</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to the R programming language for those who have never (or barely) programmed in R, and especially to those who are new to programming in general. If you are unfamiliar with working with variables, vectors, and dataframes, then you are a good fit for this class! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned some of what R can do, explored the ecosystem of R and RStudio, modified/extracted data, and discovered resources to continue your learning even after this session. Please have R and RStudio Desktop installed on your device prior to the course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42274405141714/huge/6172948485c2bd1912b802afad5dd23599831816.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="230" width="230" isDefault="true" fileSize="18155"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: Passion at Green Library, Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The month of February has a long-standing relationship with romance.&amp;nbsp; Next&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, February 7th, from 2-4PM in Green Library&amp;#39;s Hohbach Seminar Room (126)&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;stop by our latest pop-up exhibit to find&amp;nbsp;your&amp;nbsp;PASSION.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overpowering feeling? Physical suffering? Intense enthusiasm? Religious fervor? Burning love? All of the above? Our exhibit of special items from the Library&amp;rsquo;s collections showcases creative interpretations of passion from around the world and across time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Special, Unique, and Rare! is a monthly series held on the first&amp;nbsp;Tuesday of most months, from 2-4PM in Hohbach Hall. Each month will explore the Libraries&amp;#39; collections through a different theme.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special_unique_and_rare_passion</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42280924417894/huge/1173d8587c42c694cfbd9504c8414faafe554f5a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="928" width="800" isDefault="true" fileSize="607030"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction To HPC</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;SRCC and Stanford Libraries will be teaching an introduction to HPC course on Feb 08. This workshop is an introduction to using high-performance computing systems effectively. We obviously can&amp;rsquo;t cover every case or give an exhaustive course on parallel programming in just a few hours of teaching time. Instead, this workshop is intended to give students a good introduction and overview of the tools available and how to use them effectively. By the end of this workshop students will know how to:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Connect to a cluster&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Write simple batch scripts&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Submit and manage jobs on a cluster&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Use a job scheduler (SLURM)&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Transfer files&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Use software through environment modules with LMOD.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp; &amp;nbsp; Estimate job RAM and CPU requests&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Please note: &amp;nbsp;This class is for people who are beginners to HPC and SLURM. We will not be going into a deep dive on SLURM or sbatch directives. The class is not for people who already have HPC/SLURM experience. Some Linux command line experience with navigating the filesystem (ls, and cd commands) and editing files (nano) is required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_hpc</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42274443874577/huge/13102c6f3321b5bc18b8a9687d879c9cb7785b0d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="230" width="230" isDefault="true" fileSize="18155"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of an archival collection: The Edith Anna Strauss papers, 1921-1942 at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where do rare and unusual materials come from, and how do they end up at Stanford? Join the Stanford curators who were involved in the acquisition and the rare book dealer who acquired this collection, David Rueger of Editio Altera, who will be on hand to display and discuss this and other fascinating research materials.  &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14182528" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Edith Anna Strauss papers, 1921-1942&lt;/a&gt; (Stanford MSS 2845) consist of 484 items, mainly letters and postcards, documenting daily life as a Jew in Germany during the pre-war and early war periods and Jewish refugee life in New York City during the same period. Edith Strauss was born in Frankfurt in 1917 and emigrated to the US in 1937, and she corresponded frequently with her mother, who remained in Germany, and other family members and friends. One striking feature of the archive is the bizarre standards of "normalcy" faced by Jews during this period: for example, several of the postcards sent from Edith's mother feature images of Hitler – presumably simply because these were the only available postcards to hand. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Materials on display will also include a wide range of material on the antiquarian market today, from a 1485 "Encyclopedia of Everything" to mid-15th century vellum passports for travel to Persia, rules and regulations for 18th century women's clothing; a secretly-published list of banned books; and a set of travel guides aimed at gay men in 1980s Germany. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;David will also represent the antiquarian book world and its professional organizations, including the rigorous process for accreditation through the Antiquarian Booksellers' Association of America (ABAA), and he is looking forward to learning more about the researcher perspective and the library point of view.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/behind_the_scenes_of_an_archival_collection_the_edith_anna_strauss_papers_1921-1942</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42293709511869/huge/d693a46006ecdddbbd5b3a4e651be54abb2c3d9b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="300" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="61055"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Introduction to Python</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides an introduction to the Python programming language: basic syntax, variable assignment, functions, data import, and how to understand error messages and find help. You will learn enough Python to perform common tasks and explore the rich environment of Python packages available.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080952" target="_blank"&gt;Register Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/2_Python_environments.html#google-colaboratory" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to set up your Google Colab environment before the workshop.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_introduction_to_python_2990</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Engine 101: Introduction to Earth Engine for beginners at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meet Earth Engine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine &lt;/a&gt;is a geospatial processing service. With Earth Engine, you can perform geospatial processing at scale, powered by Google Cloud Platform. The purpose of Earth Engine is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive platform for geospatial algorithm development at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable high-impact, data-driven science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make substantive progress on global challenges that involve large geospatial datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine&lt;/a&gt; combines a multi-petabyte catalog of satellite imagery and geospatial datasets with planetary-scale analysis capabilities and makes it available for scientists, researchers, and developers to detect changes, map trends, and quantify differences on the Earth&amp;#39;s surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presenter: &lt;/b&gt;Stace Maples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that this workshop is for Stanford University affiliates, only.&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description&lt;/b&gt;: The Earth Engine API (application programming interface) provides the ability to create your own algorithms to process raster and vector imagery. This session is geared toward people who would like to analyze satellite and vector data. The session will be hands-on, using the Earth Engine Javascript code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of the class will be an introduction to Remote Sensing, in general. The second half will&amp;nbsp;focus on introducing the Google Earth Engine Platform, and accessing imagery, creating composites, and running analyses over stacks of images, computing statistics on imagery, creating charts and exporting the results of your analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;No previous experience with Earth Engine or JavaScript is necessary for the beginner workshop, but programming experience, basic knowledge of remote sensing and/or GIS are highly desirable. Willingness to learn programming is required. Participants with no programming experience will require additional attention.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/google_earth_engine_101_introduction_to_earth_engine_for_beginners</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42050362260014/huge/d958a8dc85ad748b3a2b279b0d99029ddd53648c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1305" width="1722" isDefault="true" fileSize="2577889"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Maritime Spaces Exhibition at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Imagining Maritime Spaces&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;draws together maps of the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans and seas to explore how cartographers, navigators, and others have historically come to know and to represent these dynamic spaces. Charts, tools, and other visualizations illustrate elements of navigation by stars, winds, and waves, exploration of unknown waters and depths, and shifting coasts. This exhibit coincides with the Computational Archaeology &amp;amp; Seafaring Theory Workshop being sponsored by the Archaeology Center and collaborating centers and institutions both on and beyond campus. The exhibition was curated by Justin Leidwanger, Beth Minney and Nicole Constantine; it was coordinated and mounted by Kristina Larsen.&amp;nbsp; The exhibition opens at the same time as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Micronesian&amp;nbsp;Seafaring System&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;talk and can be viewed during the Center&amp;#39;s open hours until Feb 10, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ImaginingMaritimeSpacesExhibition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426818</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.16714</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41768402192589/huge/c260d776d652a9531faad55d7e816255851dad66.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="866" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="321602"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>R Package Development</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;One of the most powerful features of R is the giant library of packages that users develop. While some of these are well known, many others are created by an individual or group to solve a particular problem that they have. In this workshop, we will take you through the process of making your own packages to use in R. Some prior knowledge of using R is recommended.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/r_package_development</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42274466823705/huge/1243a430c615417f2e391cb03c152321e7916d34.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="230" width="230" isDefault="true" fileSize="18155"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Black Music on Record: The Dijkstra Black Music Collection at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A major collection of 8,000 vinyl records has been donated to Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Music Library &amp;amp; Archive of Recorded Sound, documenting the full sweep of jazz history and Jamaican popular music with additional selections in soul, blues, R&amp;amp;B, hip hop, and other genres. What can recorded music reveal about Black history, creativity, and culture? What new avenues of thinking does this collection open up? Join us for a lively conversation about Black music research and pedagogy at Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our panel will feature the donor, Bram Dijkstra, Prof. Ato Quayson, Prof. Adam Banks, and Prof. Stephen Hinton. A reception will follow to celebrate Bram and Sandra Dijkstra&amp;rsquo;s generous donation of the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/173238" target="_blank"&gt;Dijkstra Black Music Collection&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/CGtMPTLyRbo8HMmd7"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; to attend the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;ABOUT THE PANELISTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bram Dijkstra&lt;/b&gt;, Professor Emeritus of American and Comparative Literature at UC San Diego, was born on a small Indonesian island and raised in Holland. He devoted countless hours over his lifetime developing the Dijkstra Black Music Collection, which includes deep runs and exceptional rarities, including a full run of the Blue Note 1500 series of the late 1950s; virtually all John Coltrane commercial releases; a strong representation of avant-garde artists on small label releases from the U.S., Europe, and Japan; Bob Marley&amp;rsquo;s original 12-inch 45 r.p.m. single of &amp;ldquo;Buffalo Soldiers;&amp;rdquo; Sun Ra&amp;rsquo;s original Saturn issues with blank or hand-made covers; and a significant complement of artists&amp;rsquo; private-issue and limited-edition releases. He traces his passion for jazz to hearing John Coltrane&amp;rsquo;s playing in the mid-1950s, a transformative experience that inspired a relocation to the United States, an immersion in African American music, and a commitment to creative work. His books include &lt;i&gt;American Expressionism: Art and Social Change, 1920&amp;ndash;1950&lt;/i&gt; (2010) and &lt;i&gt;Cubism, Stieglitz, and the Early Poetry of William Carlos Williams&lt;/i&gt; (2020).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://english.stanford.edu/people/ato-quayson"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ato Quayson&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the Jean G. and Morris M. Doyle Professor in Interdisciplinary Studies and Professor of English at Stanford. He is chair of the English Department and chairs the Framework Task Force subcommittee focused on the departmentalization of African and African American Studies. His monograph, &lt;i&gt;Accra: City Life and the Itineraries of Transnationalism&lt;/i&gt; (2014), was co-winner of the Urban History Association&amp;#39;s 2015 Best Book Prize (non-North America) and was named in &lt;i&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt; as one of the 10 Best Books on Cities in 2014. His most recent book is &lt;i&gt;Tragedy and Postcolonial Literature&lt;/i&gt; (2021); works-in-progress include &lt;i&gt;Accra Chic: A Locational History of Fashion in Accra&lt;/i&gt; (with Grace Tolequ&amp;eacute;) and &lt;i&gt;Decolonizing English Literary Studies&lt;/i&gt; (with Ankhi Mukherjee).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://ed.stanford.edu/faculty/ajbanks"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adam Banks&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a Professor at the School of Education and Faculty Director of the Institute for Diversity in the Arts at Stanford. His scholarship lies at the intersections of writing, rhetoric and technology issues; his specialized interests include African American rhetoric, community literacy, digital rhetorics and digital humanities. His book, &lt;i&gt;Digital Griots: African American Rhetoric in a Multimedia Age&lt;/i&gt; (2011), shows how African American storytelling traditions and their digital manifestations can help scholars and teachers shape composition studies, thoroughly linking oral, print, and digital production in ways that centralize African American discursive practices as part of a multicultural set of ideas and pedagogical commitments. His current digital/book project is &lt;i&gt;Technologizing Funk/Funkin Technology: Critical Digital Literacies and the Trope of the Talking Book.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/people/stephen-hinton"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stephen Hinton&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the chair of the Music Department at Stanford, is the Avalon Foundation Professor in the Humanities at Stanford University, Professor of Music and, by courtesy, of German. From 2011-15 he served as the Denning Family Director of the Stanford Arts Institute. From 2006&amp;ndash;2010 he was Senior Associate Dean for Humanities &amp;amp; Arts, and from 1997&amp;ndash;2004 chair of the Department of Music. His publications include &lt;i&gt;The Idea of Gebrauchsmusik&lt;/i&gt;; &lt;i&gt;Kurt Weill: The Threepenny Opera&lt;/i&gt; for the series Cambridge Opera Handbooks; the critical edition of &lt;i&gt;Die Dreigroschenoper&lt;/i&gt; for the Kurt Weill Edition (edited with Edward Harsh); &lt;i&gt;Kurt Weill, Gesammelte Schriften&lt;/i&gt; (Collected Writings, edited with J&amp;uuml;rgen Schebera, and issued in 2000 in an expanded second edition); and the edition of the &lt;i&gt;Symphony Mathis der Maler&lt;/i&gt; for Paul Hindemith&amp;rsquo;s Collected Works.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2023 17:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating_the_dijkstra_black_music_collection</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42210766372557/huge/c2d1a2a85d1b0f6dc4b3344cb5b195e717668eac.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="218485"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GDAL/OGR: Working with spatial data at scale.</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Geospatial Data Abstraction Library (GDAL/OGR) is an open-source translator library for working with geospatial data. GDAL/OGR contains a variety of useful command line utilities that can be easier or more efficient to use than standalone GIS software or rolling your own code. In this workshop you will learn how to use GDAL to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Inspect and query datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Convert data between different formats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Update and transform spatial reference systems (projections)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clip and subset data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create tile indexes and mosaics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop will be held online via Zoom.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_gdalogr_working_with_spatial_data_at_scale</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42209543349519/huge/41f5b406ae508746b5010ed2c752a5c52e640809.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="949595"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing 101 at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Note: Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing_101_9322</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42094555601095/huge/1521e9ccc0b2b38767150706422e5f85bba16422.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Data Drop-in workshop: Intro to NVivo with Esha Chatterjee at Hohbach Hall - Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stop by Green Library for the &lt;b&gt;Love Data Fair&lt;/b&gt; and learn about &lt;b&gt;NVivo from Qualitaitve Data Consultant, Esha Chatterjee.&lt;/b&gt; Esha will be available to demo NVivo and show you how to get started with this qualitative data analysis software.&amp;nbsp; She will be in Green Library - Hohbach Hall from 1-2:30PM on Feb 14th.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1zDfhnuxKChR4Cfde9AfvMXt-edsUCAAM"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://drive.google.com/drive/folders/1zDfhnuxKChR4Cfde9AfvMXt-edsUCAAM" /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_data_drop-in_workshop_intro_to_nvivo_with_esha_chatterjee</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42271309913068/huge/3c610ee4a20b3be1964fee793be90446ebd6bae0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="405" width="720" isDefault="true" fileSize="42886"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Data Fair at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Celebrate Love Data Week at the Stanford Libraries!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Love Data Week is an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. Love Data Week 2023 will feature a &lt;b&gt;Love Data Fair&lt;/b&gt; on the afternoon of Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day, February 14th, in Hohbach Hall, Green Library.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everyone in the Stanford community is welcome to attend - come to learn, share, and discuss quantitative and qualitative data management, analysis, sharing, privacy, preservation, reuse, delivery, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/love_data_fair</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42299176645113/huge/4eec400a5eab8054430b7d9a67dec2b44cadd8c1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="166500"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bonbons, books, and board games at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking for the perfect book? Tired of browsing bookshelves to come away empty-handed? We have the perfect solution! Speed dating&amp;hellip; but with books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Valentine&amp;#39;s Day with Stanford Libraries&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us this Valentine&amp;rsquo;s Day to eat bonbons, play board games, and yes, speed date some books.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:00 PM | Dessert&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;7:20 PM | Book Speed Dating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8:00 PM | Board Games&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;I﻿f you would like to volunteer for this event, we would be happy to have you facilitate a board game. Please use&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdhlXSagXLMkbNr7lycRa8I9OwPHJY7G606ie-bdlWiBmA8Pw/viewform?usp=share_link" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;this form&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;&amp;nbsp;to contact us.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;If you are not affiliated with Stanford, you are still welcome. You will need to first register at the front desk though, and to check any books, you will need to get a fee-based library card. Read more about&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges/visitor-access-and-borrowing" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;visitor access and borrowing&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bonbons_books_and_board_games</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42290888373023/huge/37cf33d3db0625d7c66b51a9fcf6666c958e2da0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="2160" isDefault="true" fileSize="175170"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GeoPandas</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GeoPandas is an extension of the open-source Python Data Analysis Library, Pandas, which can be used to read, write, and analyze vector geospatial data formats. GeoPandas enables you to easily do operations in Python that would otherwise require a spatial database such as PostGIS. In this workshop, we will introduce GeoPandas and learn how to perform a variety of geospatial data science tasks to work efficiently with geographic vector datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_geopandas</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38511017081751/huge/7b0ef630b5f952971c64fe176deb4cc90b89f01f.jpg" type="image/png" medium="image" isDefault="true"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Wrangling</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080959" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python (or similar knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_wrangling_3961</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArcGIS StoryMaps 101 with the Esri StoryMaps Editorial Team at The David Rumsey Map Center at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join members of Esri&amp;rsquo;s ArcGIS StoryMaps Editorial Team for an introduction to ArcGIS StoryMaps, a digital storytelling tool that enhances your narrative using multimedia and custom maps. Co-hosted by the David Rumsey Map Center (DRMC) and Stanford Geospatial Center (SGC) at Stanford Libraries, this session will include hands-on skill building with a focus on utilizing resources available through Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by ArcGIS StoryMaps Editorial Team members:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Asbury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andria Olson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heidi Daulton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome observers but if you would like to participate in the hands-on skill building, please come prepared with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account access to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;storymaps.arcgis.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account with Georeferencer through &lt;a href="https://davidrumsey.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;davidrumsey.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account with MapTiler through Georeferencer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information on how to navigate Georeferencer through davidrumsey.com, please refer to the &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/8851fafab37a4674b7a75b5bbf000280" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Working with Historical Maps Online: David Rumsey Map Center guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/arcgis_storymaps_101_with_the_esri_storymaps_editorial_team</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42209996034508/huge/f6c8183e757ae52e0fd59fbef8b22cd5d4b19beb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="903" width="1341" isDefault="true" fileSize="1402740"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Decoding the Game of Love at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the context of LoveData Week, this event explores board games that model or simulate the human emotion of love. These games are intended as entertainment but can also function as data simulations modeling complex relationships and complicated social contexts. In this event, we will evaluate the usefulness of such simulations in modeling human emotions in general and we will examine the specific data points chosen as part of both games. What is really being modeled/studied here? What can we learn from the simulations of human behavior that are on display? What data points are not present in these games?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_1402</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228185169/huge/ddf789d493dcf668db5b32d412bd7bbf85a5b603.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Visualization</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will introduce you to three basic visualizations using the Python matplotlib and seaborn libraries: histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080962" target="_blank"&gt;Register Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_visualization</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Orwell &amp; Peter Stansky: Then and Now at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join us for a discussion of Professor Peter Stansky&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=36169" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Socialist Patriot: George Orwell and War&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Stanford University Press, 2023), with remarks from John Rodden and Peter Stansky.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;By carefully combing through Orwell&amp;#39;s published works, Stansky&amp;#39;s book teases apart Orwell&amp;#39;s often paradoxical views on patriotism and socialism.&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Socialist Patriot&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is ultimately an attempt to reconcile the apparent contradictions between Orwell&amp;#39;s commitment to socialist ideals and his sharp critique of totalitarianism by demonstrating the centrality of his wartime experiences, giving twenty-first century readers greater insight into the inner world of one of the most influential writers of the modern age.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Rbi5stUCmGVkA6mY8" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to attend the event in person.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Vi-FH0YbRheaEvPQ7v4MLQ" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to attend the event online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A reception will follow the presentation. &lt;i&gt;The Socialist Patriot &lt;/i&gt;along with other copies of books about Orwell by Stansky and Rodden will be available for purchase and signing. This event is free and open to the public and is co-sponsored by Stanford Libraries and ​the Department of History.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu/people/peter-stansky" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Peter Stansky&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is the Frances and Charles Field Professor of History Emeritus at Stanford University. His scholarship addresses many of the main themes of modern British history: the dissipation of the Liberal and growth of the Labour parties; the rise of aesthetic modernism (and the central role played by the Bloomsbury Group); the impact of two world wars and the Spanish Civil War on British intellectuals; and postwar manifestations of an &amp;quot;austere,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;swinging,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;cool&amp;quot; Britain. He has written extensively on such topics as William Morris, the Bloomsbury Group and George Orwell.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;John Rodden&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span&gt;&amp;nbsp;is widely regarded as the world&amp;rsquo;s leading authority on the legacy of George Orwell. Beginning with T&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;he Politics of Literary Reputation: The Making and Claiming of &amp;lsquo;St George&amp;rsquo; Orwell in 1989&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Every Intellectual&amp;rsquo;s Big Brother in 2006&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;, and continuing with editing&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Cambridge Companion to George Orwell&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;in 2007 and&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to George Orwell&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;in 2012,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;The Unexamined Orwell&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;in 2011 and more, he has established himself as the foremost expert on the cultural and political impact of Orwell on the world. His latest book,&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span&gt;Becoming George Orwell: Life and Letters, Legend and Legacy,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;more than justifies that reputation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 17:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/orwell_stansky</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42245742235756/huge/11d23c7d54d935c6a69f75ee2f0c43643e0c2149.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="178413"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Data Workshop: Content Analysis with NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join Esha Chatterjee, qualitative data software consultant for Stanford Libraries, for an intermediate level class on content analysis.&amp;nbsp; Learn how to upload your collection of textual data for content analysis using NVivo software.&amp;nbsp; Esha will cover coding and other tips.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_data_workshop_interview_analysis_with_nvivo</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42274114270008/huge/61e20aa9c07b03a264098d5b96f01d901a7f4207.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="405" width="720" isDefault="true" fileSize="31435"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, March 1 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_7735</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42276290636813/huge/cc37f9dab80213bb241bf110c991f3375e9808d7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Text Analysis</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in analyzing collections of novels or journal articles? Do you want to understand patterns across collections of tweets or other social media data? In this workshop, we&amp;#39;ll learn how to import, clean, and analyze collections of text with R using several standard text mining libraries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080964" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_text_analysis_971</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Machine Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a beginner-friendly introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts, quantitative data preprocessing for machine learning, and the SuperLearner R package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080965" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R"&gt;https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_machine_learning_3970</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Text Analysis</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to working with text data using the spaCy and textacy Python libraries. You will learn to effectively streamline text preprocessing, understand word tokenization, sentence segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, and named entity recognition using a single document (a short excerpt from H.G. Wells&amp;#39;s A Short History of the World) and across a corpus of legal documents.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080968" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_text_analysis_2832</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for March&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_9290</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228363356/huge/ad3516023ce1e1e5a75f977c9365d3d5f498fb28.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Sea Routes on Maps: A conversation on the European and Asian contexts with Sara Caputo and Elke Papelitzky</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;Two leading experts will discuss the appearance and function of sea routes on European and East Asian maps, showing the interconnections of the early modern global maritime world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have all seen tracks marching across the oceans of a map. Have you ever wondered where they came from and why they are there? In this online event, Sara Caputo (Cambridge) and Elke Papelitzky (KU Leuven) will share their ongoing research on route lines on European and East Asian maps, respectively. They will each give a brief presentation, followed by a conversation moderated by Katherine Parker (BLR Antique Maps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trailblazers&amp;rsquo; wakes: Ship tracks in Western imperial mapping&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sara Caputo, University of Cambridge (UK)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ancient and medieval European world, the seas on maps were trackless. The few extant itinerary maps never seem to extend their lines onto the water. In the sixteenth century, however, European mapmakers began to include route lines on their representations of the oceans. These lines were closely linked to the navigational practice of pricking a course on portolan charts. They may have also drawn inspiration from the routes that had long featured in East Asian maritime mapping. However, in a Western context, tracks became a powerful tool to recount individual journeys and establish imperial claims, in relation to developing notions of &amp;lsquo;discovery&amp;rsquo;. This half of the talk will include some material from Caputo&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming book, Tracks on the Ocean (under contract with Profile Books).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Red lines in the ocean: Sea routes on early modern East Asian maps&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Elke Papelitzky, KU Leuven&lt;br /&gt;
Many early modern Chinese, Japanese, and Korean maps draw lines in ocean areas that represent sea routes. These lines appear on maps of a single country, of a larger region, or on maps of the globe. They serve a range of different functions from providing information about (imagined) travel to visually integrating East Asia into global networks, reflecting a perception of East Asian mapmakers of their countries being integrated in these networks. Setting East Asian maps in conversations with European ones shows that when map images shift context between Western Europe and East Asia, the function of the route-lines changes. In the case of East Asian maps, these changes further promote the mapmakers&amp;rsquo; narrative of early modern East Asia not being isolated but being a part of the global, maritime world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tracing_sea_routes</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42220224768727/huge/30f4aa3b35fc82ab05d2f5edd48ab981f1d4a2fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1789" width="1909" isDefault="true" fileSize="7565547"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Machine Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for classifying text and images using the scikit-learn, lime, and tensorflow Python libraries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080983" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_machine_learning_240</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for April&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_2015</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228556903/huge/0b8000d865e38646ca9cfca163ffacd123b4d682.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
