<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>The Colonial Gulf: How Empires Documented a Region at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;How have colonial and imperial regimes imagined and represented the Persian Gulf? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibit explores how the British, Ottoman and American empires documented the human and non-human geography, resources, and landscapes of the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It features historical maps and artifacts from the collections of the Branner Earth Sciences Library and the David Rumsey Map Center alongside cartographic visualizations created by the &lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; research collective.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Featured materials include maps derived from a dataset collected from the &lt;i&gt;British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia, and Oman&lt;/i&gt; created using QGIS, including the map of mentions of date palms displayed here.  By placing these historical materials and contemporary analyses in conversation, we uncover a genealogy of geographical thinking alongside the power structures embedded in imperial and colonial record-keeping.  This exhibit aims to illustrate and critically engage the breadth, depth, and nature of colonial and imperial knowledge production regarding the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula, highlighting its varied expressions in texts, maps, and charts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/b90cd597a47f46d39567b4c9824ca6ee"&gt;&lt;span&gt;view digitally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored by: &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dept. of History&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://cesta.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;CESTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;&lt;span&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/colonial-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49820497130375/huge/021478f5ef78e5ba12d6141026a426a42130fff1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="667372"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Special Collections at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from May 15 to October 26, 2025.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/"&gt;Spotlight Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source digital exhibit platform developed and maintained by Stanford’s Digital Library Systems and Services department (DLSS). Eleven years since its inception, the site hosts 164 online exhibits that span the range of Stanford’s general and special collections and cover such diverse topics as &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mss"&gt;Ancient, Medieval, and Early Modern Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;, Philip Zimbardo’s &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/spe"&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/sunset"&gt;Sunset Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/gardiner-sfba"&gt;Gardiner Transit Collection&lt;/a&gt;, and the photography archives of &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/fitch"&gt;Bob Fitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/bacon"&gt;David Bacon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/menuez"&gt;Douglas Menuez&lt;/a&gt;.  Created by Stanford librarians, faculty, and students, and arranged and described in narrative format, the site’s digital content is accessed thousands of times a day. It helps make the libraries’ collections accessible to a vast audience of researchers at Stanford and beyond.  DLSS continues to add functionality, including the display of streaming media. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition, &lt;i&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/i&gt;, invites viewers into the deep collections that underlie or form the basis for the digital exhibits by presenting original artifacts, books, and manuscripts represented on the platform. Library curators selected from the approximately 100 Spotlight exhibits that feature Special Collections and University Archives content to show in the galleries. Original objects on display include historical photographs, books, illuminated manuscripts, early printed documents, musical scores, objects related to Stanford’s history, and ephemera representing movements for social change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No single exhibition could capture the full range and diversity of the content available on the Spotlight platform. However, with this exhibition, we have endeavored to represent the depth and breadth of this rich resource as it pertains to our Special Collections and University Archives holdings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Benjamin Lee Stone with Rebecca Wingfield and Franz Kunst, Benjamin Albritton, Ray Heigemeir, Josh Schneider, with Connor Yankowitz, Kathleen Smith, Charlotte Kwok-Glasser, and Natalie Marine-Street; produced by Deardra Fuzzell with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Connor Yankowitz. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49517102456786/huge/ef13e9ac8bc8849ce49f9fa880f7850953f4ff53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="123903"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Acquisitions exhibition, Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library, Summer 2025 at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stop by to visit a selection of new artists' books acquired for the Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library Locked Stacks collection. Works range from Chinese takeout menus to a photobook about a team measuring ice cores in Antarctica. Curated by Lorna Corbetta and Katie Keller. Opening June 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-acquisitions-exhibition-summer-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49854519808297/huge/56ab3bf03905c7e4495658677692b27b2c03a073.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3360" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="2379979"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition is only available to view during the &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/Rumsey"&gt;David Rumsey Map Center's public drop-in hours&lt;/a&gt;. Please check our website for our most updated information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/83a42ebc28b44fe7b355532da798b938"&gt;view digitally&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - California Coastal Ecosystems at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: California Coast&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Explore the dynamic beauty and complexity of California’s coastal ecosystems. From salt marshes, sage scrubs, kelp forests, and rocky intertidal zones, these habitats are among the most biodiverse regions on the planet and are essential for coastal economies. However, they are threatened by climate change and human activities, including sea level rise, habitat pollution, coastal erosion, and the impacts of extreme weather events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The display showcases the diverse range of titles that highlight the ecology, geology, biology, climate, environmental management, and conservation of our state’s rich coastal environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a valid, physical government-issued photo ID to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-california-coast</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50046574829097/huge/b0a0b86bb068a4fb4d09d1d314ceeab8550659b1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="900" width="679" isDefault="true" fileSize="322185"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Aug 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terman Engineering Library Open House at Jen-Hsun Huang Building (School of Engineering)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Welcome to our new and returning engineering students, faculty, and staff! Join the Terman Library staff for a range of activities including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Collaborative art projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Board games and puzzles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;A retro gaming tournament (including prizes for three winners)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Free food and drink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Terman staff will also offer tours of the space and answer any questions you may have about library services!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/terman-engineering-library-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427784</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.174323</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50517884480279/huge/2929b204d53bbbc588451aefd0fab6e89fd2a91c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="581527"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescuing Federal Research Data (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This month Yea-Hung Chen and Ariel Deardorff from UCSF will present on efforts to safeguard disappearing government data. Since early 2025 several federal research datasets have been altered or deleted in response to executive orders from the White House. These actions have raised significant concerns about the accessibility and integrity of government data. For example, in February, several datasets from the US Census Bureau suddenly became unavailable, and others from the CDC were removed and then later restored. In this presentation, we will explore the latest developments in data censorship and the current efforts to rescue and preserve government datasets. You’ll learn about the organizations that have worked to preserve data, alternative sources of government data, and how you can get involved to protect valuable public information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://bayareaopensciencegroup.github.io/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is a growing community for Bay Area academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rescuing-federal-research-data</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50570231024589/huge/8c5ce33cf0980d250cc52255f5b27b4daffd904d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="102446"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Introduction to NVivo workshop for social science students.  Please register for this session at the following link below:  &lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current"&gt;https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-2336</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47746634515153/huge/4b7271aa6a1855e0b196ba9e4f4d29d03c880256.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits: The Making of a Children's Book at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibition showcases &lt;i&gt;Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits&lt;/i&gt;, a children’s book by Stanford art historian Emanuele Lugli that explores why portraits matter through the life and work of Lavinia Fontana, Europe’s first professional woman painter. Illustrated by Chiara Palillo, the book is more than a study of portraiture and early modern women—it is an artist’s book in itself, a hybrid creation where collage, acrylic, cyanotype, and digital color converge in playful, unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lavinias-wondrous-portraits-the-making-of-a-childrens-book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50569364017038/huge/5bb505839ed649401c32d60e7c1b38b22b8da0c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="900" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="77463"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for the fifth biennial Ruderman Conference on Cartography, to be held &lt;b&gt;October 8-10, 2025&lt;/b&gt; at the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers from a variety of disciplinary backgrounds and specializations will share their expertise about cartography of anything but the earth's surface, from the ocean's depths to the stars. Keynote speakers include &lt;b&gt;Betsy Mason&lt;/b&gt; (freelance science journalist) and &lt;b&gt;Peter Bellerby&lt;/b&gt; (Bellerby and Co. Globemakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference speaker info can be found on the &lt;a href="https://ruderman.sites.stanford.edu/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer ugc" target="_blank"&gt;Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/barry-lawrence-ruderman-conference-on-cartography</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50162629646370/huge/4c9881418fd324cfb22f8e4eb2bd13c195a6e2c7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1562" width="3374" isDefault="true" fileSize="2814865"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
