<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view February 24, 2022, through August 28, 2022, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Robert Trujillo; produced, designed, and installed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Aug 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/materialia_lumina_contemporary_artist_books_from_the_codex_international_book_fair</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118485903850/huge/23c7599baa91e1cd67c67e00d6c403ed88b088a4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="151056"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: War Games at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop war games with titles like &lt;em&gt;Tactics, Stalingrad&lt;/em&gt;, and&lt;em&gt; Panzerblitz &lt;/em&gt;were arguably the historical foundation for modern gaming culture. The creators of these games formed the first community of game designers in the United States during the 1960s and 1970s. How did players deal with the challenges of playing these complex games, and how did game designers and players innovate in their design and play practices in the pre-digital, pre-Internet age? What was the appeal of historical games and who designed and played them? &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Join us on Tuesday, August 16th, from 2-4pm in Hohbach Hall to explore these questions and more! We will start with a showcase of some historic games, then move on to some examples of design and play innovation. Henry Lowood, head of the SVA, will give a short talk at 2:30pm about these innovations and the historical context and importance of wargame design. After that, we will play &lt;em&gt;The Grizzled, &lt;/em&gt;a recent game that deals with the experiences of soldiers in the trenches of World War I, featuring illustrations by the late graphical artist Tignous, of Charlie Hebdo fame. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_unpacking_nationalism_in_war_games</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40754874022907/huge/224e70b5c8c76060f5f32d006670db0cd1968e7b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="165047"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting its 2nd annual Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair to highlight social justice projects, collections, and efforts happening within the Libraries and at other departments across the Stanford campus.   &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Hear featured speakers, see live demonstrations of the Know Systemic Racism (KSR) database and highlights from the Libraries existing social justice collections, attend a new book release and signing by co-authors Stephen Shames and Ericka Huggins, and pick up lots of great giveaways. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Following the Fair, starting at 4:30 pm in Green Library's Hohbach Hall presentation room, join co-authors Stephen Shames and Ericka Huggins of the newly released book, &lt;a href="https://www.marcusbooks.com/book/9781788841757" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comrade Sisters: Women of the Black Panther Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and other former Black Panther Party members for a panel discussion. Book sales and signing will follow outside of Green Library on the patio nearest Coupa Café.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check back for updates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice_equity_diversity_and_inclusion_jedi_fair_8413</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40621750570646/huge/c2b7a9495971b7d8f110b5dab27e32fc73fa9c8e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="181353"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
