<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;黛文洵美：山水記憶&lt;br&gt;
Victoria Yau: “I slept in the mountain cloud” &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford Libraries, the East Asia Library, and the Center for East Asian Studies. Organized and guest curated by Beryl Zhou, graduate student, Center for East Asian Studies, and Ellen Huang, Ph.D, distinguished practitioner at the Center for East Asian Studies and associate professor of art history and material culture at ArtCenter College of Design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shanghai-born artist Victoria Yau (1939–2023) created around 300 works of abstract ink paintings, watercolors, multimedia collages, prints, and textiles after she moved to the United States from Taipei. These artworks, spanning nearly half a century of art-making in Chicago, New York and the Southwest, testify to her commitment to abstraction and investment in material experimentation. Featuring a selection of works in a range of media—and complemented by the artist’s own writings, collections, and poetry—this exhibition asks viewers to consider the transformation of East Asian landscape painting from compositional structure into abbreviated form emphasizing texture and line. Gathered together here for the first time since her passing, the works and texts on display explore how Yau negotiated disparate experiences of geopolitical flux, immigration, and physical struggle throughout her seventy-year career. Modern in their simplicity but complex in their historical and international references, Victoria Yau’s mountain clouds, her own poetic reworking of the historical term for landscape painting, “mountain-water 山水,” signal the intricacies of international contemporary art through the vantage of an Asian diasporic woman artist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/victoria-yau-i-slept-in-the-mountain-cloud</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46252014368895/huge/6eb4274218d52cea507377e8acbd22c97908c505.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="839" width="838" isDefault="true" fileSize="552389"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The New Deal &amp; The Federal Writers' Project at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/document/d/1-UT_h28D9ylo9I3qEOfJJXmbaL_Ol8wq4VIw_k6PEU4/edit?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The New Deal &amp;amp; The Federal Writers' Project | Selections from the Bruce and Rachel Jeffer Collection&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view May 6, 2024, through January 26, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inspired by childhood automobile trips across the U.S. with his father and a lifelong love of American history and literature, Los Angeles attorney Bruce Jeffer assembled a magnificent collection—totaling nearly two thousand titles—of the Federal Writers’ Project and related WPA and New Deal publications. He and his wife Rachel gifted it to the Stanford Libraries Department of Special Collections in 2021. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Created as a New Deal program within the Works Progress Administration in 1935, the Federal Writers’ Project (Federal Writers’ Program 1939–1943) employed as many as six thousand writers, researchers, and editors in fifty-two state and territorial offices and produced a prodigious number of publications—including the American Guide Series, oral histories, ethnographies, collections of folklore and books for children—well over one thousand, but likely many more: the exact number is unknowable, and new discoveries have surfaced in the wake of each successive bibliography. Over sixty years, Jeffer’s passion for collecting the output of the Federal Writers’ Project and its offshoots brought him into contact with the foremost antiquarian book dealers of the day, former Writers’ Project employees, and leading collectors across the United States. With his wife Rachel, he made great use of auctions, eBay, and trades with other notable collectors and dealers. Through the decades, he searched for these publications by visiting bookstores in towns and cities around the country, directly contacting booksellers, and later maintaining a private network of like-minded collectors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two core influences in Jeffer’s collecting activities were his close relationship with collector Fred Board of Connecticut and collector/book dealer Arthur Scharf of Pennsylvania. Board’s own collection of the State Guides (apart from his larger FWP collection) later served as an inspiration to his great-nephew Scott Borchert, which led Borchert to write his recent excellent history of the Project, &lt;i&gt;Republic of Detours: How the New Deal Paid Broke Writers to Rediscover America&lt;/i&gt; (New York, 2021). Besides selling and trading, Arthur Scharf was a source of bibliographic information on the FWP publications. Like most serious collectors of the FWP, when Evanell Powell self-published her ambitious (if amateur) WPA Writers’ Publication: &lt;i&gt;A complete bibliographic checklist… of items, major and minor, of the Federal Writers' Project and Program&lt;/i&gt; (Palm Beach, 1974), Jeffer took advantage of the information there to hunt for more titles—and to find many titles unknown to Powell, historians, and scholars. Of the over twelve hundred published FWP titles in the Jeffer collection, approximately one hundred and fifty FWP items were unknown to Powell and historians, thus representing an excellent opportunity for further research. The presence of sixteen original, unpublished FWP works adds significantly to the prospects for research in the collection. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In collecting the often ephemeral publications that characterized the richness and diversity, as well as controversy, of the project’s output, Jeffer has been guided by a desire to document this seminal period in American history, preserve it for posterity, and make it broadly available to students and researchers. In addition to rare published items, Jeffer sought out unpublished material as well—always with an eye for unique material that, in the words of one FWP catalog, embodied the project’s mission of “presenting America to all Americans.”  His collection contains copies of a number of exceedingly scarce titles, typescripts of unpublished works, and presentation copies gifted to New Deal luminaries such as Harry L. Hopkins, as well as publications from allied agencies such as the Federal Art Project, the Museum Extension Project, the Federal Theatre Project, and the Federal Music Project.  &lt;br&gt;
As demonstrated throughout the exhibit, The FWP’s lasting influence on literary and ethnographic work since the 1930s is strong, and the cultural resonance of the project continues unabated—including serving as the inspiration for a proposed twenty-first-century FWP, congressional legislation (Bill # HR 3054) introduced during the COVID-19 Pandemic in 2021 by Reps. Ted Lieu (D-CA and Stanford, B.A., B.S., '91) and Teresa Leger Fernandez (D-NM).  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Benjamin Stone, Associate Director of Special Collections and Curator for American and British History; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their expert cataloging of books and manuscripts: Nancy Lorimer, Kay Teel, and their staff in the Metadata Department; For their assessment of materials Kristen St. John and Kimberly Kwan in Conservation Services; For his photography services Wayne Vanderkuil in the Digital Production Group; Glynn Edwards, Ann Myers, Brian Bethel, Gurudarshan Khalsa and especially Esther Wan in the Collection Services division of the Department of Special Collections, and Ben Albritton and Ever Rodriguez in Rare Books, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-deal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46210554145667/huge/5835b820fcd4b2c26aeb7ed65aab8559a0126e81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="71541"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Display: Paris Olympics 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Paris Olympics are here! Come to Green Library and check out our book display on the Olympics. Find a title you like? Check it out at the Circulation Desk!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 12:44:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book-display-paris-olympics-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47075248354262/huge/9fda291e1a16148db525504055d8d1669519e173.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1344" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="119574"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Cryptids Around the World at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection presents an exhibit on cryptids!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Our August library exhibit tells the tales of rumored cryptids around the world. Through maps and books, discover when these legends originated and where they might be found.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;This month’s exhibit was curated by high school interns, Ambree James and Cristal Lozano. Both are 2024 graduates from East Palo Alto Academy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  The exhibit is available for viewing throughout the month during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-cryptids</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47118677397866/huge/8ed02b3ef31a5f05faeef5506ca38172f837f3c0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="244" width="244" isDefault="true" fileSize="61351"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Four Games by Friedemann Friese at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this month's Tabletop Tuesday, we look at the prolific German game designer &lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgamedesigner/141/friedemann-friese"&gt;Friedemann Friese&lt;/a&gt;, who has designed &lt;a href="https://de.wikipedia.org/wiki/Friedemann_Friese"&gt;over sixty games&lt;/a&gt;. In 1992, Friese started his own game publishing company to produce his first game, Wucherer (literally "usurer" or "profiteer," although it was published as "Landlord" by Rio Grande Games in 1998). The majority of his game titles begin with the letter "F" and are colored green, but another hallmark of his game design is thematic focus and unusual mechanisms. We will be looking at four Friese games--&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/43570/friday"&gt;Friday&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/175878/504"&gt;504&lt;/a&gt;, Fortress, and Fremde Federn--to explore his use of engaging mechanisms and quirky themes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-four-games-by-friedemann-friese</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47251953493632/huge/c3a2b344d9c7fdd7b3d60a762ac43380f1c1e8cb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="610" width="730" isDefault="true" fileSize="860124"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A World In The Making: Urbano Monte's Global Map Circa 1587 at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;In late July 1585, the Milanese noble Urbano Monte (1544-1613) decided to make an ambitious world map. The first Japanese embassy to Europe had just visited his city. Monte witnessed the spectacle surrounding the four young Japanese Christians and their Portuguese Jesuit confessor, returning to Lisbon after visiting Rome in preparation for their voyage home. The Japanese traveled with a gift of Abraham Ortelius’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Theatrum orbis terrarum&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; (1572), presumably to show the Japanese what Europe looked like in this famous Renaissance atlas. Monte was eager to create a map of Japan to satisfy European curiosity about this part of Asia. How could he bridge the vast distance separating Italy and Japan? His answer was to create a paper planisphere composed of sixty maps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition reconstructs the world of a virtually unknown Renaissance mapmaker.  Monte was inspired by the great geographers and cartographers of the day such as Mercator and Ortelius without choosing to imitate how they made their famous maps. He was curious about long-distance travel and eagerly read travel narratives, yet never got on a ship to go far from home. An avid consumer of global knowledge, Monte wanted to share what he learned. Take a close look at Urbano Monte’s &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;mappamundi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, and the books, artifacts, and experiences that inspired his intellectual voyage.  See how this armchair traveler envisioned his world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This exhibition is ongoing and will be available until September 27th, 2024. To view the exhibit, visit the David Rumsey Map Center during its public drop-in hours.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/a-world-in-the-making-urbano-montes-global-map-circa-1587</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47199841550603/huge/2a75e74ad04e7ab9fd0679d6e3bae1f5cf2c88d2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2466" width="2482" isDefault="true" fileSize="4230919"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Library Open House at Jen-Hsun Huang Building (School of Engineering)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the subject librarians and staff of the Terman Engineering Library as we celebrate and gear up for the start of the 2024-25 academic year.  Activities include:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn about Terman library services and resources, including our Maker Bar.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate in a collaborative art project or make a button.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compete on our vintage video gaming machine - winners entered into a prize raffle!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet fellow students, both new and returning, over light refreshments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is located on the 2nd floor of the Huang Engineering Center, in the octagon above Forbes Cafe.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/engineering-library-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427784</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.174323</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47234172448605/huge/56229dc7d17c0a1cbcc3789303e56876a4ce47d8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="581527"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: September 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-sept24</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Jason Schreier, "Play Nice: The Rise, Fall, and Future of Blizzard Entertainment" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jason Schreier as he discusses &lt;i&gt;Play Nice: The Rise, Fall, and Future of Blizzard Entertainment&lt;/i&gt; on October 14, 2024. &lt;a href="https://www.hachettebookgroup.com/titles/jason-schreier/play-nice/9781538725429/?lens=grand-central-publishing"&gt;A copy of &lt;i&gt;Play Nice &lt;/i&gt;can be purchased using this link&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For video game fans, the name Blizzard Entertainment was once synonymous with perfection. The renowned company celebrated the joy of gaming over all else, and every product it released was an instant classic: StarCraft, Diablo, Overwatch, Hearthstone, and World of Warcraft, which forever changed the video game landscape. What was once two UCLA students' simple mission — to make games they wanted to play — launched an empire with thousands of employees, millions of fans, and billions of dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But when Blizzard cancelled a buzzy project in 2013, it gave Bobby Kotick, the infamous CEO of corporate parent Activision, the excuse he needed to start cracking down on Blizzard's proud autonomy. Led by executives from McKinsey and Procter &amp;amp; Gamble, Activision began invading Blizzard from the inside, driving away throngs of key employees in a push for predictability over creativity. Glitchy products, PR disasters, and mass layoffs followed, marring the company’s once pristine image. In 2021, the state of California filed a staggering lawsuit against the company for sexual misconduct and discrimination, leading to a widespread reckoning and a $69 billion acquisition that sent shockwaves through the industry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on firsthand interviews with more than 300 current and former employees, PLAY NICE chronicles the creativity, frustration, beauty, and betrayal across the epic 33-year saga of Blizzard Entertainment — and explores the delight and despair of what it really means to "bleed Blizzard blue." Full of colorful personalities and dramatic twists, PLAY NICE is The Social Network for the video game industry&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ABOUT THE AUTHOR&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jason Schreier is the New York Times bestselling author of Press Reset and Blood, Sweat, and Pixels and a reporter at Bloomberg News, where he covers the video game industry. He lives in Westchester, New York with his wife and two children.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jason-schreier-press-play-the-rise-fall-and-future-of-blizzard-entertainment</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46676503105277/huge/817c4038d6199c955ba7aa5bb39f440cd4faca45.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2201" width="2400" isDefault="true" fileSize="498418"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-5048</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/46852978301307/huge/2b270820ca810e4fdfc0686a17d1af5570e00af3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: October 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-october-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
