<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Naturally Hazardous: Sea Level Rise at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Naturally Hazardous&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the cosmically unavoidable to the anthropogenically-induced, Earth can be naturally hazardous to humans. In the 2024-25 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature the science and impact of volcanoes, wildfires, drought, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
February 3 - February 26: Explore the causes and impacts of sea level rise, from past changes to assessing the impacts of predicted variations through books and maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-naturally-hazardous-sea-level-rise</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48764313820306/huge/731c7d4a49924fd33ee2cedf8c67f83fe4b5b41a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="294552"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cheonggea Ilsu Cha: Grasp the essence, and the form fades away at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;청계 차일수: 득의망상 (得意忘象)&lt;br&gt;
Cheonggea Ilsu Cha: Grasp the Essence, and the Form Fades Away&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Stanford East Asia Library presents an exhibition by the South Korean artist Cheonggea Ilsu Cha from November 18, 2024 to February 20, 2025. Artist Cha has dedicated his 40-year career to the mastery of ‘literati’ painting.  The literati genre combines written word with a painterly interpretation of text, a form of art that has been practiced by the scholarly elite in Korea for over 400 years. His work has been featured at the prestigious Grand Art Exhibition of Korea, and he has held eight solo exhibitions.&lt;br&gt;
A significant number of Korean scholars practiced literati painting during the Joseon Dynasty, which extended from 1392 to 1897. Literati painting reflects the scholar’s observation, understanding and interpretation of a poetic topic. The artist strives for aesthetic discipline; the text must be no longer than what the topic minimally requires. So too must the artist seek simplicity in his visual vocabulary.  The exhibition is inspired by the philosophy of Tŭgŭi mangsang (得意忘象), which emphasizes abandoning artifice in order to seek the true nature of things.  The works at the exhibition employ the use of ink and a constrained palette of color using materials such as traditional Korean paper, scrolls, and fans. The paintings touch on a wide variety of topics, from nature to philosophical reflections to expressions of human emotion. Cha’s work is inspired by the artistic sensibility of his predecessors. Visitors to the museum will find paintings imbued with a classic aesthetic, timeless charm, and a lively wit.&lt;br&gt;
This exhibition of Cha’s Korean literati paintings was curated by Jee-Young Park, Korean Studies Librarian at Stanford East Asia Library; Ji Soo Kim, M.A. in  Museum Studies from San Francisco State University; and Wooju Chong, M. A. in Center for East Asian Studies from Stanford University, in consultation with the East Asia Library Exhibits Committee.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cheonggea-ilsu-cha-grasp-the-essence-and-the-form-fades-away</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48041771240023/huge/261eed6631f369912267440e775bf36888eaba1c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3391" width="3342" isDefault="true" fileSize="1588901"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To Trust or Not to Trust: Authenticity by Design at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The internet is at an inflection point. With the growth of artificial intelligence and synthetic media, trust in information faces unprecedented threats. Authenticity is not guaranteed. At the same time, new technologies–referred to as “Web 3”–present opportunities to protect the integrity of data. These solutions can be applied to critical practices including investigative journalism, historical archiving, and the admissibility of legal evidence. This exhibit, curated by the &lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/"&gt;Starling Lab for Data Integrity&lt;/a&gt;, asks: How might we design information systems for authenticity?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Joshua Roberts/Reuters, “Day 69" (&lt;a href="https://www.starlinglab.org/78daysarchive/"&gt;78 Days Archive&lt;/a&gt;), January 11, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/to-trust-or-not-to-trust-authenticity-by-design</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47436587901093/huge/641630e9442e946525a91d66b21735740fa8d98c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="475" width="718" isDefault="true" fileSize="492778"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panoply of Pop-Ups exhibition, Bowes Library, Winter quarter at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: Come see flying playing cards in &lt;i&gt;Alice in Wonderland&lt;/i&gt; to Dada-inspired happenings in &lt;i&gt;Cabaret Voltaire. &lt;/i&gt;Featuring books from the Bowes Locked Stacks collection. Curated by Lorna Corbetta and Katie Keller. On view Winter quarter. M-Th 9-7, F 9-5, Sun 12-6. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/panoply-of-pop-ups-exhibition-bowes-library-winter-quarter</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48536008940945/huge/8a9499777f165c14ff6964627b2ef65d13591452.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3264" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="9109456"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epicenters: Navigating Recovery and Renewal from Disasters at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;In the wake of disaster, maps play many roles, shaping understanding of the event in the immediate aftermath, serving as visceral portrayals for those who were not there, and communicating both scale and extent of the tragedy. They gavanize support for rebuilding by showing new possible futures and can be used to memorialize the event, inscribing the memory over the landscape. Drawing upon sources from historical representations to contemporary satellite imagery, the maps in this exhibition explore various ways communities use maps to make sense of calamity and move forward from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford student Muhammad Dhafer, winner of the 2024 California Map Society student exhibition competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This exhibition is ongoing and will be available until Friday, March 7th, 2025. To view the exhibit, visit the David Rumsey Map Center during its public drop-in hours.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/epicenters-navigating-recovery-and-renewal-from-disasters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426635</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167076</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47684547090877/huge/3760917787646284b7c17d5db40811eb358972fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1229" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="562133"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Data Week 2025 BioBlitz</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2025 Love Data Week BioBlitz begins with the Generating and Using Biodiversity Big Data virtual workshop where participants will learn about locating, downloading, and cleaning biodiversity data for research. Following the workshop, participants will be invited to join an asynchronous &lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/projects/stanford-love-data-week-2025-bioblitz"&gt;Bioblitz&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/"&gt;iNaturalist platform&lt;/a&gt; to generate biodiversity data that will be shared with the open data repository GBIF (Global Biodiversity Information Facility). Participants will learn how to search for data of interest, learn about some of the caveats of using biodiversity big data, how to clean and properly attribute data, and will also contribute data themselves by participating in a week-long Bioblitz across Stanford campuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/vKuOzqPKQlqBNn2CwE_pqg"&gt;Register for the virtual workshop&lt;/a&gt;, taking place on Monday, February 10, 1-2:30PM PT.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/love-data-week-2025-bioblitz</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713560296680/huge/b0a2fa943f353bdd19f861504b50ba2283e003cd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="1151688"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Paper to Points, Lines, and Polygons: Transforming Historic Maps into Data at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This workshop will guide participants through the process of transforming images of historical paper maps into computationally accessible geospatial data. Using web native tools and workflows, participants will learn to locate, georeference, extract data, and integrate images and data into interactive web applications. This hands-on experience is ideal for anyone interested in the use of historical cartography in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Participants will explore:  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Locating maps of interest in digital collections using various search strategies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working with map images served via the International Image Interoperability Framework (IIF)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Georeferencing images of paper maps into modern coordinate systems.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating new spatial data from georeferenced map images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building and publishing interactive web maps using modern web tools. By the end of the workshop, participants will have created their own interactive web maps from images of paper maps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Monday, February 10, 2025, from 10 AM to 4 PM PT &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;David Rumsey Map Center, Green Library &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/from-paper-to-points-lines-polygons-tickets-1231696039009?aff=oddtdtcreator"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register for this event. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;To access Green Library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID to sign in.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/from-paper-to-points-lines-and-polygons-transforming-historic-maps-into-data</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48776156672296/huge/11de48f410749c3605f96a5dfc4c33808d2ae96b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="388698"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Cite Data and Acknowledge Data Collaborators at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of our Stanford scholars are beginning to utilize data, and with that come the question of how to cite that data as well as collaborators who worked with them on it. This is an in-person/online hybrid workshop on how to properly cite data in their scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/Yv6wXYqCQ02RBykNDJRCXw#/registration"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot for this workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Zoom and Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 10:00AM to 11:00AM on Monday, February 10, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Instructor:  Dr. Anne Ladyem McDivitt (Academic Technology Specialist for History)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This hybrid event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/how-to-cite-data-and-acknowledge-data-collaborators</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48782953056752/huge/f5754502fdcaaefd2b46278e8dcb760a01cf6431.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Generating and Using Biodiversity Big Data Workshop</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Generating and Using Biodiversity Big Data &lt;/b&gt;is a multipart activity that begins with a virtual workshop on locating, downloading, and cleaning biodiversity data for research. Following the workshop, participants will be invited to join an asynchronous &lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/projects/stanford-love-data-week-2025-bioblitz"&gt;Bioblitz&lt;/a&gt; using the &lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/"&gt;iNaturalist platform&lt;/a&gt; to generate biodiversity data that will be shared with the open data repository GBIF (Global Biodiversity Information Facility). Participants will learn how to search for data of interest, learn about some of the caveats of using biodiversity big data, how to clean and properly attribute data, and will also contribute data themselves by participating in a week-long Bioblitz across Stanford campuses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;February 10, 2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1:00 PM - 2:30 PM PT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/vKuOzqPKQlqBNn2CwE_pqg#/registration"&gt;Register here to attend&lt;/a&gt;. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/generating-and-using-biodiversity-big-data-workshop</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48791361224290/huge/4023ec6fce15e6c563a5ad16ae8efd4cc094510f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5217174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Words Into Data: Basic Workflows for Natural Language Processing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Words Into Data is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This interactive workshop will familiarize users with a basic natural language processing (NLP) research pipeline using the Huggingface/transformers framework. You will learn to ingest, process, and tokenize text; extract Named Entity (people, places, events, etc.) data from it; and reformat that data so it can be used in higher-order research workflows like mapping, social network analysis, and more. Time allowing, we might even make a map or network graph ourselves!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdPwzFuXAo1j6tJXeLenM9eOmA6ofbw2yyeFIatZd49MONlWA/viewform?usp=dialog"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only and will be offered on a first-come, first-serve basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your Stanford email, such as &lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetid@stanford.edu"&gt;YourSUNetid@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;, to access the registration form.)&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Virtual (A zoom link will be sent to registrants.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and Time: 2:00PM to 3:00PM PT on Monday, February 10, 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructor: Brad Rittenhouse, Research Data Facilitator, Stanford Research Computing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/words-into-data-basic-workflows-for-natural-language-processing</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48749271346038/huge/9680fdff569ad84e418490b066e381faac1b1b14.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5218174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redivis Workshop: A Data and Computational Environment for Reproducible Data Science</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data Farm is Stanford University's research data exploration, extraction, and analysis tool for datasets. Stanford contracts with &lt;a href="https://redivis.com/"&gt;Redivis&lt;/a&gt; for use of their SaaS platform for storing, distributing, and analyzing research data. Redivis offers a modern, high-performance web-based interface that enables researchers to work with a wide variety of datasets. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;What can Data Farm do?&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data Farm allows highly efficient and fast queries (using either the visual query editor or writing SQL) directly in the browser. After performing a query, such as: filter-aggregate-combine, you can explore descriptive statistics and visualizations right away or move into integrated notebooks for further data manipulation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Datasets on Data Farm are interoperable with common data analysis tools such as: Python, R, SAS, and Stata and can be easily exported to on-premise computing environments such as &lt;a href="https://web.stanford.edu/group/farmshare/cgi-bin/wiki/index.php/Main_Page"&gt;Farmshare&lt;/a&gt; / &lt;a href="https://www.sherlock.stanford.edu/"&gt;Sherlock&lt;/a&gt;, into cloud compute services like GCP, AWS, Azure, or downloaded for local analysis (usage rights permitting).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdq7vL2Tob2wvUdTofvPe4q11Uo7ZS2gNSuobVUQ4e4Dby3Mw/viewform?usp=dialog"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only and will be offered on a first-come, first-serve basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your Stanford email, such as &lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetid@stanford.edu"&gt;YourSUNetid@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;, to access the registration form.)&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Location: Zoom and Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date and Time: 3:00PM to 4:00PM, Monday, February 10, 2025&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Instructors: Ian Matthews (Redivis) &amp;amp; Vijoy Abraham (Assistant Director and Head, Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research, Stanford University Libraries)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;This hybrid event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/redivis-workshop-a-data-and-computational-environment-for-reproducible-data-science</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48793375504580/huge/65388dcecbab50aee87b6c89145be5a35f8a291b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wikidata Edit-a-thon at IC Classroom, Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part of  &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://wikidata.org/"&gt;Wikidata&lt;/a&gt; is an open, multilingual structured knowledge base that can be read and edited by both humans and machines and is made by people like you. Digital assistants like &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q582159"&gt;Siri&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q28022144"&gt;Alexa&lt;/a&gt; use Wikidata, as do search engines like &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q9366"&gt;Google&lt;/a&gt;. You can think of Wikidata as a database of databases, linking items through identifiers. This creates a centralized location of information about anything and everything: from the &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q1"&gt;universe&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q184067"&gt;pika&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q316"&gt;love&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Q3141050"&gt;Chicago-style hot dog&lt;/a&gt;. With over &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:Statistics"&gt;114,683,910&lt;/a&gt; data &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:MyLanguage/Help:Items"&gt;items&lt;/a&gt;, there’s likely to be an item for your favorite band, and your birthplace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Join us online and in person for an introduction to Wikidata followed by a Wikidata Edit-a-thon! Learn more about Wikidata’s impact, how to make edits, create references, and query Wikidata in this 2-hour hands-on session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, February 11, 11am – 1pm &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In-person, IC Classroom, Green Library and on Zoom.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://goto.stanford.edu/wikidata"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for Event&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;goto.stanford.edu/wikidata. &lt;/b&gt;Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:CreateAccount"&gt;create an account&lt;/a&gt; in advance, and enroll in the &lt;a href="https://outreachdashboard.wmflabs.org/courses/Stanford_University/LDW_Wikidata_Edit-a-thon?enroll=yugnhepj"&gt;Edit-a-thon Dashboard&lt;/a&gt; to track our edits during Love Data Week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For those attending the in-person workshop, please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/wikidata-edit-a-thon-workshop</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713002528370/huge/f549fcc59887304cdad4929903c1734542397541.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5217174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Data Visualization in R</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This is part of a series of workshops for &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities, and services relevant to data in research.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
This workshop is an introduction to working with data visualization in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate common plots, and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSf1alkaw991YYyVmSyri_7M9meo8poib_6Je1XsFIBWN3hhUg/viewform"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only and will be offered on a first-come, first-serve basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your Stanford email, such as &lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetid@stanford.edu"&gt;YourSUNetid@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;, to access the registration form.)&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Location: Virtual (A zoom link will be sent to registrants one week before the event.)&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 1:00PM - 4:00PM, Tuesday, February 11, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Earth Sciences Library&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
This session will not be recorded, but lesson materials will be shared with participants after the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries-stanford-data-visualization-in-r-2025-02-11</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713884985964/huge/f33596ef6804345f6b533844fede13406d964e13.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="486443"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GeoPandas Workshop at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GeoPandas is an extension of the open-source Python Data Analysis Library, Pandas, which can be used to read, write, and analyze vector geospatial data formats. GeoPandas enables you to easily do operations in Python that would otherwise require a spatial database such as PostGIS. In this workshop, we will introduce GeoPandas and learn how to perform a variety of geospatial data science tasks to work efficiently with geographic vector datasets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfEKcfx2ZhfAAp-gXyMhB22OCZ4TIXiM2GLw6AUPU9UvKAkUQ/viewform?usp=dialog"&gt;Register here to attend&lt;/a&gt;. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only and will be offered on a first-come, first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all spots are full. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, February 11, 1pm – 3pm &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Velma Denning Room, Green Library 120F&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;To access Green Library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID to sign in.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-geopandas-workshop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48773524637434/huge/79a00cf725288853b60b99e48b001ea8de77f996.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5217174"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Introduction to Research Data Management</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part of  &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your research data is important. In this session, we’ll discuss how to properly store, organize, and document your work to ensure that important data isn’t lost and that you are meeting expectations set by the parties that fund and publish your research. After this session, you’ll have the tools required to assess your current data management practices, information about how to advance your practices as necessary or desired, and an understanding of some of the data-related resources available to you through Stanford Medicine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tuesday, February 11, 2025&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;2:00-3:30 PM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note: This class will be held via Zoom and recorded. You will receive the Zoom link after registering and again an hour before the session. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://lanecal.stanford.edu/event/13685411"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-research-data-management</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48738406040509/huge/81f2b01921f798a1e668efa21ba6b12db2795850.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5217174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: California at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This month’s Special, Unique and Rare popup exhibit highlights curated items from Stanford Libraries’ Special Collections and Green Library collections – artistic, geographical, historical, journalistic, institutional – that have something to say about &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;CALIFORNIA&lt;/b&gt;.  Drop by &lt;b&gt;Hohbach 126 (Silicon Valley Archive seminar room, Green Library) any time between 2-4 PM on Tuesday, February 11th&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Green Library's pop-up is the first of three around the Libraries on the theme of California, to be followed by: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-feb-12-2-4-pm"&gt;California Pop-Up at Bowes Art and Architecture Library&lt;/a&gt; on Wednesday, February 12, 2025, from 2-4 pm (2nd Floor, McMurtry Building), and &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-exhibit-branner-earth-sciences-library"&gt;California Pop-Up Exhibit at Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/a&gt; on Thursday, February 13, 2025 from 1-3pm(2nd Floor, Mitchell Earth Sciences Building).&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-california</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783541525447/huge/6ae27ac2113f83587eceeb6818d6261f9a1510bd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2755" width="2914" isDefault="true" fileSize="2512896"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Velma Denning Room and Research Data Services Open House at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us in the Velma Denning Room (120F) in Green Library for an interactive Open House event, where we will showcase the exciting resources and services available for digital research methods. This show and tell event will highlight our programming, computational resources, and consultation services. Discover how to use our GPU-equipped computers and the LM Studio for local language models. We’ll also introduce upcoming workshops and explain how you can access both in-person and online R and Python consultations. Walk-ins are welcome! Come chat with us and explore how Research Data Services can support your research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This on-site event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID to sign in.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/velma-denning-room-and-research-data-services-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48712412635853/huge/37edab2bd91ce9096115bee09e0ea349e42f7b51.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everything You Wanted to Know about ICPSR, But Were Afraid to Ask at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Inter-university Consortium for Political and Social Research (ICPSR) is the world's largest collection of digital social science data. These data can be used for secondary research, instructional activities, and to write articles, papers or theses. ICPSR data cover topics from sociology, political science, economics, demography, education, child care, health care, crime, minority populations, aging, terrorism, substance abuse, mental health, public policy, international relations and more. All Stanford University staff, students, and faculty have access to the extensive ICPSR data holdings. Join us to learn how ICPSR can help you in your research or instruction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSd8d3kt16aaJHpvS3YsuR1ytobtdfg-slcDvdYaIZ9Xa8lvWw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot for this workshop!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Catherine M. Tierney Room (121A), Green Library&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 11:00AM to 12:00PM PT on Wednesday, February 12, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Instructors: Kate Barron (Research Data Curator) &amp;amp; Dr. Ron Nakao (Librarian for Social Science Data)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This on-site event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID to sign in.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/everything-you-wanted-to-know-about-icpsr</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48712888166509/huge/084f503eedfc1a27ce84be31eaf5a33968927b29.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-1029</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48614558710645/huge/db2640587d11bfcf27b116ed03820fb4bab9b488.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="77711"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Scan Demonstration at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The Digital Production Group will demonstrate scanning of 3D objects, in particular a selection of fossils from the Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability Geoscience Specimen Collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This event will be held in Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or valid government-issued ID.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/3d-scan-demonstration</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48793032649251/huge/d7a862e324f00bfbd0cf50c9c5d670ffc88a54db.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="1056092"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>California Pop-Up @ Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Stanford Libraries pop-up exhibits on &lt;b&gt;California&lt;/b&gt;, Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library will feature photobooks and artists' books about the natural beauty of California and the cultures of San Francisco and Los Angeles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, February 12, 2025, from 2-4 pm in Bowes Library (2nd Floor, McMurtry Building). &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-feb-12-2-4-pm</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48748360118486/huge/5c80832b452f2644bf4f0e66167d999af489f6fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1200" width="1800" isDefault="true" fileSize="2512872"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Emulation as a Service Workshop at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Emulation as a Service Infrastructure (EaaSI) is an open source community development to provide access to legacy computing environments and datasets. Please join us for a demo of the EaaSI application and discussion of how this service could enhance research at Stanford by providing access to legacy software applications.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 2:00PM to 4:00PM PT, Wednesday, February 12, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Instructor: Michael Olson (Service Manager, Born-Digital Preservation Lab) and Annie Schweikert (Digital Archivist, Special Collections)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This on-site event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/emulation-as-a-service-workshop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713762314150/huge/a1754b58d6ffe335dee388f140e0649dc2bd5717.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> Intro to Working with API Authentication</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is an introduction to methods of API authentication, with a focus on different approaches for securely storing API credentials and how to avoid publishing them online by accident.  We will cover common types of authentication systems that someone may encounter when using APIs for research purposes, such as API keys, Bearer tokens, and Basic Authentication. Basic boilerplate scripts will be provided in Python and R that can be used to authenticate with these kinds of APIs. The workshop will also discuss general pointers on how to obtain API keys and tokens. Attendees to this workshop should have familiarity with Python or R. There may be portions of the workshop that you will want to follow along with on your own computer if you have Python or R installed, but this is not required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Location: Zoom (Please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/IflvKiwmRsqzcm2GzMKj8Q#/registration"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot and receive a Zoom link for this workshop!)&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 3:00PM to 4:00PM PT, Wednesday, February 12, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Instructor: Katie Frey (Data Curator for Programmatic Access)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro-to-working-with-api-authentication</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713712203043/huge/158a7262115215db4531bf442d673827b2b70d76.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Celebrating the Life and Work of Amatzia Porat at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The behind-the-scenes work of editor and translator &lt;b&gt;Amatzia Porat&lt;/b&gt; is credited with shaping Hebrew and Israeli literature in the late 20th century. As Stanford Libraries has acquired &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/in00000181273"&gt;Porat’s papers&lt;/a&gt; we will celebrate his life and work:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;3:00pm&lt;/b&gt; Celebrating the Editor, a panel&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Eitan Kensky &lt;/b&gt;- Moderator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Vered Shemtov&lt;/b&gt; -The Editor as a translator&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Giddon Ticotsky&lt;/b&gt; - On Editing&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Uri Cohen&lt;/b&gt; - The contribution of the Archive to the study of Hebrew Literature&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4:00pm&lt;/b&gt; &lt;b&gt;Yiftah Porat&lt;/b&gt; on his father&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;4:15pm&lt;/b&gt; Taube Center doctoral candidate &lt;b&gt;Ariel Horowitz &lt;/b&gt;will read from his new bestseller The Ghost Editor (עורך צללים).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;5:15pm&lt;/b&gt; A reception in celebration of Amatzia Porat.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/celebrating-the-life-and-work-of-amatzia-porat</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48668048093385/huge/845f38328a9619327c238ed4f66d31e74cba2307.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="818" width="818" isDefault="true" fileSize="364692"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Crafts &amp; DeStress @ Branner Library at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Take a moment to relax with snacks, crafts, and a guessing game @ Branner Earth Sciences LIbrary! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.  So grab a coffee while you create your own data inspired crafts!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Available activies:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Make a map without a computer&lt;/b&gt; - Make a meaningful map in this data physicalization activity! We provide the raw materials for you to embroider a personal mini-map, you bring the creativity. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Textile Data Weaving&lt;/b&gt; - You’re probably used to seeing data represented in charts and graphs, but have you ever seen a data set turned into a textile? With this activity, you can weave a data set into cloth to destress and learn a fun method of displaying data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Color by Numbers&lt;/b&gt; - Just want to sit and color a cute picture of a kittten in a basket? Make it data inspired! We'll have various color-by-number sheets of cute and science related images.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Guess the Dataset!&lt;/b&gt; - Try to guess the underlying dataset from an unlabeled graph. This is a fun way to put your knowledge of trends in the world to the test. We'll put it up on a bit screen so you can play with your friends, and maybe make some new friends! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All activities are free, no experience necessary (we'll show you how!), and will be available while supplies last!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Help us reduce waste, bring your own covered mug and reusable plate!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Branner Library will also be hosting several data inspired events throughout the day, be sure to check them out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;11:00 am - 12:00 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/literature-search-smarter-use-scix-to-accelerate-your-research"&gt;Power Up your Literature Search with SciX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;01:00 pm - 03:00 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-exhibit-branner-earth-sciences-library"&gt;California Pop-up Exhibit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;05:00 pm - 06:00 pm&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/ccrma-data-sonification-ensemble-performance"&gt;CCRMA Data Sonification Ensemble Performance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-crafts-destress-branner-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48745592760522/huge/1ac51ec8130a425834af0ce30994fd02be9a7a7e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="2228698"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Make Your ORCID Bloom</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for this interactive workshop to learn more about how to build out your ORCID profile with institutional integrations, how to connect your ORCID to other profiles, and how to link to citation services. For those unfamiliar with ORCID, we will include a short presentation introducing the basics of the service.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday, February 13&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;10-11 AM PT&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/F82m4fCnR2y5vNzFRA4PNw#/registration"&gt;Please register for this workshop&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/make-your-orcid-bloom</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48738354202002/huge/7e639342f3f38c2dcf6629e61006261df88d7889.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="5217174"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Literature Search Smarter: Use SciX to Accelerate Your Research at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Are you starting a new research project and doing literature review? Perhaps you just want to keep up with the most recent publications in certain topics across all different journals? &lt;a href="http://scixplorer.org"&gt;Science Explorer (SciX)&lt;/a&gt; is a NASA-funded new literature search online library specially designed for Earth and space sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Come to Branner Earth Science Library 11-12 pm on Feb 13th to learn about how SciX can accelerate and elevate your research. As a part of the Love Data Week events, SciX Ambassadors, &lt;a href="https://epsci.stanford.edu/people/yueyi-che"&gt;Yueyi Che&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://magnetism.stanford.edu/people/thom-chaffee"&gt;Thom Chaffee&lt;/a&gt;, are delivering a hands-on workshop on how to use SciX. Bring your laptop if you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Space is limited &lt;a href="https://tinyurl.com/StanfordSciX"&gt;Register now! &lt;/a&gt; Snacks will be provided at the library.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/literature-search-smarter-use-scix-to-accelerate-your-research</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48701716202163/huge/35f335d604eccc5d655ea69a74b59d2ee3ded618.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="476" width="1026" isDefault="true" fileSize="101151"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>California Pop-up Exhibit @ Branner Earth Sciences Library at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Stanford Libraries pop-up exhibits on &lt;b&gt;California&lt;/b&gt;, Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collections will be featuring maps, reports, and minerals created as part of the&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/sgs-collection"&gt; &lt;b&gt;Stanford Geological Survey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday, February 13, 2025 from 1-3pm in Branner Library (2nd Floor, Mitchell Earth Sciences Building). &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On display will be several items including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/7594435"&gt;Herbert Hoover's student topographic map of the Stanford campus created c. 1893.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/5968665"&gt;Report and map by Mary Balch Kennedy (1929)&lt;/a&gt; who was not allowed to attend the required Summer Geology Camp because she was a woman, instead she had to map the geology of the New Almaden Quadrangle alone in rugged terrain.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/4793992"&gt;R.B. Marshall's map (1895) covering a large amount, if not all, of the Stanford lands&lt;/a&gt;.  He notes the "marsh line" which extended to present day HIghway 101 as a dotted line across the top section of the map. This may be the only map from this time depicting the marshlands with such detail at this time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We will also feature several minerals from the Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability Specimen Collection, collected during the surveys or in surveyed areas, including Epidote, Gold, Jade, Actinolite, and Quartz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Before heading to Branner on Thursday, check out the two other California Pop-up Exhibits happening Tuesday (2/11) and Wednesday (2/12)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tues 2- 4pm, &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-california"&gt;Special, Unique and Rare: California @ Green Library&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wed, 2-4pm, &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-feb-12-2-4-pm"&gt;California Pop-Up @ Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/california-pop-up-exhibit-branner-earth-sciences-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48701549748781/huge/4aec8816918800c9b951d7a3d7fb4bd28ec8816a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="985" width="785" isDefault="true" fileSize="132577"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using LLMs to Extract Structured Data from PDFs at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This workshop is part of Stanford's &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Love Data Week 2025&lt;/a&gt;. The topic is the use of large language models (LLMs) to extract structured data from PDFs or other data. Imagine that you have a PDF with some tabular data in it, like a table. You want that data to work in a computable form (like CSV) for use in Excel or other tools. Large language models (LLMs) might be able to help with this task. &lt;a href="https://uit.stanford.edu/service/aiplayground" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;The Stanford AI Playground&lt;/a&gt; provides an easy mechanism to experiment with LLMs to help with data extraction or manipulation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Please register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1lPtEvL8wRO6HHYCLkHAXKAdqdtTe54F6i9-qR9aGWnw/viewform?edit_requested=true"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to reserve your spot for this workshop!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Location: &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/j/99304416100?pwd=maeD4Xg4fV7kozrfNg0MXQ71sRI7FK.1"&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt; and Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 1:00PM to 2:00PM PT on Thursday, February 13, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Instructor:  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Peter Mangiafico (Product Manager and Software Engineer, Digital Library Systems and Services)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This hybrid event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/using-llms-to-extract-structured-data-from-pdfs</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48712960508838/huge/27332e6fa801488e16c8c46fc8b23694386df9d6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1275" width="1275" isDefault="true" fileSize="3486553"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CCRMA Data Sonification Ensemble Performance at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;The Branner Earth Sciences Library and Terman Engineering Library proudly present the &lt;a href="https://ccrma.stanford.edu/"&gt;CCRMA&lt;/a&gt; Data Sonification Ensemble live @ Branner Library on February 13, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The group, composed of students of all levels and led by instructors Chris Chafe and Nilam Ram, will use software, acoustic, and electric instruments to present temporal data as audiovisual material, allowing users to interact with existing information in novel ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Not sure what data sonification is? Check out this &lt;a href="https://ccrma.stanford.edu/~cc/153d/playingSpectra2024.webm"&gt;previous performance&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ccrma-data-sonification-ensemble-performance</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48738107403845/huge/2b2e9d5c7083fcbebd07fd39170b42bf662e27be.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2000" width="2024" isDefault="true" fileSize="2568301"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Performance</category>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Love Data Week Movie Night at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us in the Hohbach Hall Presentation Palace for a screening of &lt;a href="https://www.imdb.com/title/tt1210166/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Moneyball&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (2011), with an introduction by by Eno Sarris (BA '01, MA ‘02), senior writer for &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/athletic/"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Athletic&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; covering Baseball Analytics. Eno will place the film’s approach to data within its historical context and discuss more recent developments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday, February 13&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Event begins at 7PM.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This on-site event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2025 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/love-data-week-movie-night</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48749142323761/huge/ec410be0bc4844ecde2b2d51c6a5ec3093c58709.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="1039585"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Using Spatial Data with R at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;This workshop will introduce you to geospatial libraries and concepts using R. Prior experience using R at an introductory level is expected. If you need a refresher on R, please check out &lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-intro/"&gt;Introduction to R&lt;/a&gt;. In this workshop, you will learn how to read spatial data into R and perform basic spatial analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeckyIinDLaYOG0JirEUz0iFVW6HzStGs6AJD6dHfzvY0lasA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only and will be offered on a first-come, first-serve basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Please note: You must be logged in to Google Drive with your Stanford email, such as &lt;a href="mailto:YourSUNetid@stanford.edu"&gt;YourSUNetid@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;, to access the registration form.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;br&gt;
Date and Time: 10:00AM - 12:00PM, Friday, February 14, 2025&lt;br&gt;
Lead Instructor: Dr. Claudia Engel, Academic Technology Specialist (Anthropology)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This on-site event will be held at Green Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries-stanford-using-spatial-data-with-r</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48713823025006/huge/bd5c60e246227fc00fe34665e57cd74feae4bdfb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="486443"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Studying Data with the game Rescue Polar Bears: Data &amp; Temperature at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month's Tabletop Tuesdays is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;a series for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rescue Polar Bears: Data &amp;amp; Temperature is a cooperative game based on Rescue Polar Bears with a new data and temperature system added to the game design to make the strategy more diversified. The consumption of fossil fuel and releasing of greenhouse gases yield the global warming. Around the North Pole, the last icebergs are melting and the polar bears are facing the risk of being extinct. The players form a scientific organization. They try to collect data about climate change to persuade the governments to change their energy policy. At the same time, they also need to prevent polar bears from sinking into the freezing water. Each player drives a rescue ship of different ability to complete the mission on the Arctic Ocean. As long as the players collectively gather enough data, they win together. However, if too many polar bears sink into the water, everyone loses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-february-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48614616309971/huge/d26413cae41f3fe72930280191cfec9afe6e7e47.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2500" width="2500" isDefault="true" fileSize="901922"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ART/WORK at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;ART/WORK | Creative Pursuits of Stanford Libraries Staff&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; on view February 20, 2024, through April 27, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this exhibition, we sought to create a space where staff could share their artistic, creative side that may not otherwise be a part of their work at Stanford. In the Summer of 2024, Special Collections invited current Stanford Libraries staff to enter creative work in any medium to be considered for a Winter 2025 exhibit in Green Library’s Peterson Gallery and Rotunda. Response to the call for entries was hearty. In addition to traditional fine art techniques of drawing, painting, printmaking, and photography, submissions included mixed media sculpture, ceramics, collage, textiles, and poetry. An anonymous selection committee of library staff blind-reviewed over a hundred entries and chose the fifty works displayed in the galleries. We asked the people whose pieces were selected to write a brief statement to accompany their work in the exhibit and posed several questions for their consideration: Why do creative work? What medium do you work in and why? How did you get started? What does it mean to you to be an artist (if you define yourself as one)? Does art need an audience? Who is your audience? What influences your work, and whose work do you admire? As you will see, Stanford library staff are talented and thoughtful, pursuing many forms of creative work after hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo, Associate University Librarian, Director of Special Collections and Frances and Charles Field Curator of Special Collections; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their careful consideration of all staff art submissions, we thank the staff members who served on the jury; For their assessment of materials, Aisha Wahab and Beth Ryan in Conservation Services; For their assistance with logistics Ranelle Sharma and Jacob Cohn in Library Facilities, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/artwork</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48687359684680/huge/603b1fb303d73747de62963ba10e4c95a4135903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="78990"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Science for Preterm Birth Research: Advancing Discovery Through a Public Data Repository and a DREAM Crowdsourcing Challenge (Bay Area Open Science Group)</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This month, the Bay Area Open Science Group will be joined by Tomiko Oskotsky, a physician-scientist in the Sirota Lab at the Bakar Computational Health Sciences Institute, UCSF. She earned her B.S. in Biochemistry from UCLA and her M.D. from the Medical College of Wisconsin, where she was elected to the Alpha Omega Alpha (AOA) National Medical Honor Society. Her research involves interrogating diverse datasets, including electronic health records, to better understand human health and disease. Her leadership roles include co-leading the March of Dimes preterm birth research data repository and directing the UCSF AI4ALL program, which teaches AI to underrepresented youth. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This talk will be centered around the development and administration of a March of Dimes-funded public data-sharing repository for preterm birth research, emphasizing its role in promoting open science and collaboration. She will discuss the organization of a DREAM crowdsourcing challenge that leveraging data from this repository and other publicly available datasets with the goal of predicting preterm risk among expectant individuals. The session will demonstrate how open data initiatives can accelerate discovery in preterm birth. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/open-science-for-preterm-birth</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48800579421092/huge/5585a699b6f2d640ccf6677af406d47819e07d6f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Mar. 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-983</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coup 53: Documentary Film Screening at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Stanford University Libraries are pleased to host a special in-person screening of &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Coup 53,&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;b&gt; a documentary feature film from Taghi Amirani and Walter Murch.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While making a documentary about the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/1953_Iranian_coup_d'%C3%A9tat"&gt;CIA/MI6 coup in Iran in 1953&lt;/a&gt;, Iranian director &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taghi_Amirani"&gt;Taghi Amirani&lt;/a&gt; and editor &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Walter_Murch"&gt;Walter Murch&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;Apocalypse Now, The Conversation, The English Patient&lt;/i&gt;) discover never seen before archive material hidden for decades. The 16mm footage and documents not only allow them to tell the story of the overthrow of the Iranian government in unprecedented detail but also lead to explosive revelations about dark secrets buried for 67 years. Working with &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ralph_Fiennes"&gt;Ralph Fiennes&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;i&gt;The Grand Budapest Hotel, Schindler’s List, The English Patient&lt;/i&gt;) to help bring the lost material to life, what begins as a historical documentary about four days in August 1953 turns into a live investigation, taking the filmmakers into uncharted cinematic waters. The roots of Iran's volatile relationship with America and Britain have never been so forensically and dramatically exposed.  &lt;a href="https://youtu.be/4Bf2CB45ndo?si=Qv-ENhQf5eM4Xj15"&gt;View the trailer &lt;/a&gt;for &lt;i&gt;Coup 53 &lt;/i&gt;and read &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1rmCNVGFpirpUwrvsvb8sV0lHF1rj2C2z/view?usp=sharing"&gt;press reviews&lt;/a&gt;&lt;i&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Schedule&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:15 am: Introduction &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;9:30 - 11:30 am: Film Screening&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;11:30 am - 12 pm: Q&amp;amp;A session with director Taghi Amirani and editor Walter Murch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is free and open to the public, but registration is required to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeiopxkhJzJ0NKITnaPYMGFeYhtBk9yZyria112fCE40DE8VA/viewform?usp=sharing"&gt;RSVP Form to register&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 09:15:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/coup-53-documentary-film-screening</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48775042759457/huge/99e021a8e0f1668eadfd9d90ecf8697cb7ac237e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="223502"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archiving the History of Modern Iranian Women at In person at Stanford (RSVP for location)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From Houri Moghadam to Homa Sarshar: Iranian Women Archives at Stanford &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a half-day conference celebrating important archival collections at Stanford University created by or about Iranian women. Scholars will explore the intricacies of archival creation, the vital role these collections play in preserving the modern history of Iranian women, and the pressing need for continued archival research and scholarship in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford's Green Library and the Hamid and Christina Moghadam Program in Iranian Studies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Agenda details and RSVP forthcoming. Conference is in English.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;PANELISTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kioumars Ghereghlou&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kioumars Ghereghlou" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/ghereghlou_web.jpg" style="height:300px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kioumars Ghereghlou is the Curator for Middle East Collections at the Stanford University Libraries. His most recent book is a critical edition of Hayati Tabrizi’s (d. after 1554) newly-found chronicle of the early Safavids and the opening years of the reign of Shah Isma’il I (New Haven, Conn.: American Oriental Society, 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sepideh Mohammadian&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sepideh Mohammadian" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/mohammadian_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sepideh Mohammadian was born in 1986 in Tehran, Iran. She is an author, screenwriter and researcher. She earned her BA in Law and MA in sociology and is fluent in Farsi, English, French and Turkish. Mohammadian has been writing for 20 years now, working with Roshangaran Publication since the beginning of her career as a writer. She has worked with several literary magazines in Iran having published short stories and also is a member of Pen America. Mohammadian’s research works focus on semiotics in films and the difficulties social, racial and sexual minorities face in society. She has written eight books some of which are banned in Iran. Her latest book, &lt;i&gt;The Assembly of the Forgotten&lt;/i&gt;, which was banned in Iran, was recently published by Mehri Publication in London. Since she has been advocating for the freedom to write, particularly for marginalized voices, she actively promotes and highlights banned books by fellow writers on her social media platforms, aiming to raise awareness of their work and the unjust censorship they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Negar Mottahedeh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Negar Mottahedeh" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/mottahedeh_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negar Mottahedeh is a Professor of Literature at Duke University. Her research on film, social media, and social movements in the Middle East has been published with Stanford University Press, Syracuse University Press, Duke University Press. This includes her monographs &lt;i&gt;Whisper Tapes: Kate Millet in Iran&lt;/i&gt; which was published with Stanford UP in 2019, &lt;i&gt;Displaced Allegories: Iranian Cinema 1980-2000&lt;/i&gt; published with DUP in 2008 and&lt;i&gt; #iranelection: hashtag solidarity and the transformation of online life&lt;/i&gt;. She has written for WIRED magazine, The Hill, Salon.com, The Observer and The Wall Street Journal. She holds a PhD in Comparative Studies in Discourse and Society from the University of Minnesota and a BA in International Relations from Mount Holyoke College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abbas Milani&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Abbas Milani" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/abbas-milani_sm.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abbas Milani is the Director of the Hamid and Christina Moghadam Program in Iranian Studies at Stanford University, an Adjunct Professor, and co-director of the Iran Democracy Project and a research fellow at the Hoover Institution. His expertise is U.S.-Iran relations as well as Iranian cultural, political, and security issues. Milani is the author of numerous books in Persian and English. Most recently, he published &lt;i&gt;30 Portraits&lt;/i&gt; (Persian Circle). Milani has also translated numerous books and articles into Persian and English. He has published more than 250 essays and book reviews in journals and papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Farzaneh Milani&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Farzaneh Milani" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/events/91716-1.jpg" style="height:300px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farzaneh Milani is Raymond J. Nelson Professor Emerita of Iranian literature and Gender Studies at the University of Virginia. She has published several articles and books, most recently, &lt;i&gt;The Literary Biography of Forugh Farrokhzad and Unpublished Letters&lt;/i&gt;. Milani is currently working on a book project tentatively titled, “Iranian Women Writers at the Threshold of the Local and the Global.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nahid Pirnazar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nahid Pirnazar" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/pirnazar_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nahid Pirnazar is a lecturer of Iranian Studies at UCLA where she received her Ph.D. in 2004 in Iranian Studies with an emphasis on Judeo-Persian literature and Iranian Jewish History. She has been teaching the Habib Levy Visiting Professorship of Judeo-Persian Literature at UCLA since 2000, and the History of Iranian Jews at UCLA since 2007. Pirnazar is the founder and president of The House of Judeo-Persian Manuscripts, an academic organization, which collects, preserves, transliterates and publishes Judeo-Persian manuscripts. She presents her research internationally, which focuses on varied aspects of Judeo-Persian writings and Iranian literature as well as the history, culture and national identity of Iranian Jews. Among her many publications in both English and Persian, the most recent ones are: &lt;i&gt;Judeo-Persian Writings, A Manifestation of Intellectual and Literary Life&lt;/i&gt; (Routhledge, 2020); &lt;i&gt;Ketab-e Anusi, Poetic Narratives of the Life of Iranian Jews in the Safavid Era&lt;/i&gt;, which is the latest volume in the series  of “Ketab-e Iran Namag”, published jointly by University of Toronto, Elahe Omidyar Mir-Djalali Institute of Iranian Studies &amp;amp; Houses of Judeo-Persian Manuscripts, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Homa Sarshar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Homa Sarshar" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/sarshar_sq_0.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homa Sarshar is a published author, award-winning journalist, writer, and media personality. She is the author of five books and the editor of nine volumes. From 1964 to 1978, she worked as a correspondent, reporter, and columnist for Zan-e Ruz weekly magazine and Kayhan daily newspaper in Iran. From 1972 to 1978 she worked as a television producer, director, and talk-show host for National Iranian Radio &amp;amp; Television. In 1978, Sarshar moved to Los Angeles where she resumed her career as a freelance journalist, radio and television producer, and on-air host. In 1982 as the co-producer, writer, and talk-show host of Omid Radio she co-founded a daily AM radio broadcast. In 1996, Sarshar founded the Center for Iranian Jewish Oral History (CIJOH) in Los Angeles. In 2006, she founded Honar Foundation in Los Angeles. From 2006 until March 2021 Sarshar has been producing, writing, and hosting a two hour weekly radio show at 670AM KIRN. She earned a BA in French literature from Tehran University; a MA in journalism from the Annenberg School of Communications, USC; and a Ph.D. (HC) in Journalism from College of Letters and Science at the American World University – LA, CA. She has received numerous awards for her work, including the Medal for Special Achievement in Women's Rights, given by The Iranian Women's Organization of Tehran, Iran; Journalism Award: Distinguished Iranian Women by the Encyclopaedia Iranica; Commendation for Community Affairs Services by the County of Los Angeles; 2013 Ellis Island Medal of Honor; 2016 American Heritage Award by American Immigration Council; and in 2023 the 13th Bita Prize for Persian Arts - Stanford University, Iranian Studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mona Tajali&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img alt="Mona Tajali" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/tajali_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mona Tajali is a scholar of gender and politics, specializing in women's political participation and representation in Muslim countries, with a comparative focus on Iran, Afghanistan, and Turkey. Her research includes analysis of feminist mobilization against patriarchal structures as well as the experiences of institutionalization of women's rights in semi-democratic and non-democratic contexts. She is the author of &lt;i&gt;Women’s Political Representation in Iran and Turkey: Demanding a Seat at the Table&lt;/i&gt; (2022) and co-author of &lt;i&gt;Electoral Politics: Making Quotas Work for Women&lt;/i&gt; (2011), both published as open access. She is also the co-editor of &lt;i&gt;Women and Constitutions in Muslim Contexts&lt;/i&gt; (2024), the first compilation analyzing several national constitutions of the Muslim world through a gender lens. A firm believer in engaging across the academic-practitioner divide, Tajali has been a long-term collaborator with transnational solidarity network and Women Living Under Muslim Laws (WLUML), and, since 2019, has served as a member of its executive board. She is published in both academic and popular outlets, among them the Middle East Journal, Politics &amp;amp; Gender, The Conversation, and The Washington Post. Tajali is a former associate professor of international relations and women’s, gender, and sexuality studies at Agnes Scott College in Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mandana Zandian&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mandana Zandian" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/zandian_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandana Zandian graduated from Shahid Beheshti Medical School in 1997. She worked as a researcher at Cedars-Sinai Hospital in Los Angeles for 20 years, specializing in research on aggressive forms of advanced cancers.  Dr. Zandian is also a published poet, author, and journalist, actively collaborating with "Rahavard" quarterly journal. Her books include: &lt;i&gt;Omid o Azadi&lt;/i&gt; (Hope and Liberty, Los Angeles, 2012) on the life and works of Iraj Gorgin; &lt;i&gt;Baz-khani-e Dah Shab&lt;/i&gt; (The Ten-Nights Revisited, Los Angeles, 2014); &lt;i&gt;Ehsan Yarshater in Conversation with Mandana Zandian&lt;/i&gt; (Los Angeles, 2016); She also edited &lt;i&gt;Yaddashtha&lt;/i&gt; (Diaries, Washington DC, 2021), a collection of notes written between 1986-2012 for the journals "Irannameh" and "Iranshenasi" by Dr. Ehsan Yarshater. Zandian's most recent collection of poems is titled &lt;i&gt;Seda-ye Saye-haye Ham Boodim&lt;/i&gt; (Our Voice Echoed the Shadows of All, Los Angeles, 2019).  Dr. Zandian is also the host and producer of a podcast on Persian Literature titled "A Window of Freedom." She collaborated on a section of Homa Sarshar's weekly radio program, introducing Persian contemporary poets, for 10 years. Zandian's latest book is titled &lt;i&gt;Persian Cypress and the Booms of Modernity, in Conversation with Abbas Milani&lt;/i&gt; (Los Angeles, 2023).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford is committed to ensuring its facilities, programs and services are accessible to everyone. To request access information and/or accommodations for this event, please complete&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://tinyurl.com/AccessStanford"&gt;https://tinyurl.com/AccessStanford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;at the latest one week before the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/archiving-the-history-of-modern-iranian-women</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48775571599842/huge/da820662f31878a6ae8794708d915c9d42f646f0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="3566195"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: March 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-march-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exhibit Opening: Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto &lt;/b&gt;(CISAC) to celebrate the opening of the temporary exhibit in Green Library:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;"Why Estonia? The 30-Year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit opening features a talk, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;“What America and DOGE can learn from 30 years of digital government success in Estonia?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; by former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves&lt;/b&gt;, kicking off a series of three talks on e-Estonia hosted by Stanford Libraries in April-May. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Luukas Ilves &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;is an advisor to the Deputy Prime Minister of Ukraine on questions of AI and digital transformation and a non-resident fellow at the International Center for Defence Studies (Tallinn, Estonia). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From 2022–2024, Luukas was Government CIO and Undersecretary for Digital Transformation of Estonia. He previously held various roles with the Government of Estonia and the European Commission, has worked for the cryptography deep tech Guardtime, and as deputy director and senior fellow at the Lisbon Council (a Brussels-based thinktank).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Luukas is a recipient of the Estonian Order of the White Star and President Zelensky’s Ukraine Peace Prize. He is a graduate of Stanford University.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Opening remarks will be delivered by &lt;b&gt;Michael Keller&lt;/b&gt; (Stanford Libraries) and &lt;b&gt;Ivo Lille&lt;/b&gt; (Vabamu), with &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt; (CISAC) moderating the discussion. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;A guided tour of the exhibit will follow the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/ivBxjGKUBXHxjvt19"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783405896477/huge/51c9ed5ab4294eec599fce1abe366bfc4c9c07ff.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="866" width="870" isDefault="true" fileSize="1387240"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: April 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-april-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Information Revolution:  How Soviet Cyberneticists Built the Liberal Information Age at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by &lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet &lt;/b&gt;(University of Southern California) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Information Revolution:  How Soviet Cyberneticists Built the Liberal Information Age&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia is often portrayed as the world’s most advanced „digital state,“ where citizens can vote, do their taxes, and renew their driver’s license, all online. According to this story, after fifty years of Soviet occupation, Estonia understood the dangers of monopolizing information and chose to break with the Soviet legacy by building a state where information was transparent, available, and online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk offers a different perspective. It explores the role of Soviet cybernetics and late socialist reform movements in the construction of the first iterations of the digital state. Why did Soviet thinkers imagine information technology as the solution to political and economic stagnation? And what can the long history of the information processing state tell us about late modern politics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet&lt;/b&gt; is an associate professor of history at the University of Southern California. He is a visiting researcher at the Davis Center at Princeton University and a visiting researcher at the Institute of Social Studies at the University of Tartu. He writes about technological utopias and the history of science in a variety of imperial and post-imperial contexts. His first book, Pasteur’s Empire (Oxford University Press, 2020), looked at how bacteriologists reimagined imperial governance in early twentieth century France. His current project, The Information Revolution, looks at how computer engineers reimagined imperial governance in late twentieth century Soviet Union.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session and screening of the film, &lt;b&gt;"Disco and Atomic War" &lt;/b&gt;(2009). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The film tells the story of a strange kind of information war, where a totalitarian regime stands face to face with the heroes of popular culture. And loses. It was a time when it was possible for erotic film star Emmanuelle to bring down the Red Army and MacGyver to outdo an entire school administration. It is a film about our generation, who were unknowingly brought to the front line of the Cold War. Western popular culture had an incomparable role shaping Soviet children's world views in those days. Finnish television was a window to a world of dreams that the authorities could not block in any way. Though Finnish channels were banned, many households found some way to access the forbidden fruit." – Warsaw Film Festival&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Q73EoNMCSZB28UrH9"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783490397155/huge/20687f99a4a0c0a96409655cc6b6787f9e085f1e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="722" width="692" isDefault="true" fileSize="941498"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Author &lt;b&gt;Joel Burke &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto &lt;/b&gt;(CISAC) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three decades after gaining independence from the Soviet Union, Estonia is a nation transformed. Today, the country is known around the world as a startup hub, with numerous local billion-dollar companies including Wise, Veriff, and Bolt. More impressive are Estonia’s pioneering efforts in e-government. With 99% of government services digitalized and accessible online, citizens can vote via computer and file their taxes online in minutes, and the use of artificial intelligence (AI) to enhance and automate government services long predates ChatGPT. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book talk, the author of &lt;a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/rebooting-a-nation-9781805263012?cc=us&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Joel Burke offers unique insight into Estonia’s rapid rise as a tech and e-government powerhouse since the turn of the century. From the founding of Skype to the future of the e-state, he unveils the tactics and stories behind Estonia’s spectacular journey—after years of Soviet occupation and mismanagement to global tech leadership. For those hoping to learn from Estonia’s incredible journey, Burke offers insights into the government’s use of AI, its creation of a digital society, and its cultivation of a culture driving public-sector creativity and innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joel Burke&lt;/b&gt; is a research fellow at fp21. A former AI Fellow for Senator Mike Rounds, Joel advised the office on AI, technology, and security issues. Previously, he worked in various roles and geographies including in Tallinn as Head of Business Development for e-Residency, the Republic of Estonia’s flagship digital initiative. Other experiences include working as a fellow in Cameroon staffed to a local startup via Venture for Africa; serving as a NYCx Fellow; working as a Partner at Tribe.AI, a managed marketplace for top AI talent; and leading a venture for a Rocket Internet AG subsidiary in Berlin. He started his career at a YC and Andreessen Horowitz-backed startup. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk is moderated by &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt;, Research Scholar, Center for International Security and Cooperation (FSI). &lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783921187599/huge/ba7c5becb4781871efc08f684638d2ea994bc6da.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="586" width="722" isDefault="true" fileSize="730084"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
