<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
   <channel>
      <title>Events at Stanford: stanford university libraries</title>
      <link>http://events.stanford.edu</link>
      <description>Comprehensive, university-wide event calendar for Stanford University</description>
      <copyright>Copyright (C) The Board of Trustees of the Leland Stanford Junior University</copyright>
      <language>en-us</language>
      <atom:link href="http://events.stanford.edu/xml/byOrganization/411/rss.xml"
                 rel="self"
                 type="application/rss+xml"/>
      <image>
         <url>http://events.stanford.edu/images/events_logo.gif</url>
         <title>Events at Stanford: stanford university libraries</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu</link>
      </image>
      <item>
         <title>Say Their Names - No More Names</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/889/88910</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/889/88910</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Ongoing every day from September 4, 2020 through January 31, 2022.  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Green Library and online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Say Their Names – No More Names&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt; is an online and in-person exhibit that highlights Black Americans who have been killed or impacted by police brutality and systemic racism. The exhibit originated in direct response to the global Black Lives Matter movement.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The physical exhibition in Green Library includes names affixed to glass panels in the Bing Wing as well as banners throughout the first floor that contain the names and faces of the featured victims.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/saytheirnames" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;online exhibit&lt;/a&gt; displays the images and individual stories of victims, including Emmett Till, Kalief Browder, Salecia Johnson and Bettie Jones; it also calls attention to events like the Tulsa riots, the Tuskegee syphilis experiment and the Chicago Police Department Midnight Crew.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Those who visit Stanford can also see a large banner featuring the words "Know Justice Know Peace," which was hung on the front entrance of Green Library commemorating the opening of the exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Please note the physical exhibit in Green Library is currently limited to authorized Stanford ID cardholders due to COVID-19.  However, the online exhibit, which also includes photos of the physical exhibit is available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibit is sponsored by the Stanford Libraries and is a follow up to a &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/171904" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;statement of solidarity and support&lt;/a&gt; against systemic racism published by Stanford Libraries over the summer. It offers opportunities for learning, reflection and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 13:17:08 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/889/88910/88910-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="94833"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Rise Up for Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders exhibit</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92483</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92483</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Ongoing every day from September 20, 2021 through June 30, 2022.  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online and in the East Asia Library&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;In response to the precipitous increase in Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) hate crimes throughout the United States, the staff of Stanford Libraries created the Rise Up against AAPI exhibit which focuses on the history of systemic racism against the AAPI community. The aim of this exhibit is to help educate our community and provide support and resources so that we can start the process of healing and prevent future incidents. In this exhibit, we discuss past events that have led to these reprehensible acts, including institutionalized policies that have pitted minority groups in our country against each other to weaken the other’s influence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We hope that through education, our community at large can rise to action against racism at all levels of our society. From the nuanced exclusions on the playground and in the workplace, to the blatant disregard for human life demonstrated in the murders of Asian American women in Atlanta and the brutal attacks on elderly AAPI community members in California and New York—we must all take an active stand against the scourge that racism is to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This exhibit has both an online and physical presence. You can access the online exhibit at &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup&lt;/a&gt;. The physical exhibit is in the East Asia Library and is a companion to the online exhibit. The physical exhibit highlights material from the Stanford Libraries collection and other sources that illustrate the racial struggle of the Asian American and Pacific Islander community throughout US history. Please note the physical exhibit is only open during the East Asia Library's open hours. Visit &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;library.stanford.edu/hours&lt;/a&gt; to see current hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is a work in progress and just the beginning of our efforts to combat racism in this country. Look for expanded content covering more ethnic groups and a broader range of issues as this exhibit continues to grow over the fall 2021 quarter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries stands with the AAPI community and denounces all hate crimes, including the recent surge in hate crimes specifically targeted at the AAPI community. We hope you will join our efforts to learn about the history of violence against the AAPI community so that we can prevent history from repeating itself.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 16:19:15 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92483/92483-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="88951"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Between: Artist Books, Albums, and Portfolios from the Mark Ruwedel Photography Archive at Stanford</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/913/91383</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/913/91383</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Ongoing  from May 27, 2021 through September 26, 2021.  See details for exact dates and times.  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Exhibition to show May 27, 2021 — September 26, 2021, in Green Library&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;Between: Artist Books, Albums, and Portfolios from the Mark Ruwedel Photography Archive at Stanford&lt;/em&gt;, on view May 27, 2021, through September 26, 2021, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Green Library Bing Wing. The exhibition celebrates the Mark Ruwedel Photography Archive, recently acquired by Stanford Libraries’ Special Collections.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Although known primarily as a Western landscape photographer, Ruwedel has acknowledged a highly varied range of artistic influences from such crucial 19th-century photographers as Carleton Watkins (&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/watkins" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;held in-depth by Stanford Libraries Special Collections&lt;/a&gt;) and William Henry Jackson, the 1970s New Topographics photographers such as Lewis Baltz and Robert Adams, Earthworks artists such as Robert Smithson and Michael Heizer, the conceptual works of Richard Long, even the Surrealists Man Ray, and Andre Breton. Ruwedel has acknowledged that he fits somewhere “in between” a host of sometimes competing, sometimes complementary inspirations. Consequently, his work is of particular value within a teaching institution such as Stanford University, providing multiple opportunities to investigate diverse aspects of 19th, 20th, and 21st-century art and photographic practices. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the exhibition’s opening, a virtual event: &lt;a href="/events/913/91367/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;In-Conversation: The Mark Ruwedel Photography Archive at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by the Department of Special Collections and Stanford Libraries, will occur online on May 27th, 2021, from 2:30 pm - 4:00 pm. This event is free and open to the public; &lt;a href="/events/913/91367/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;registration is required&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: In addition to the physical exhibition, there is a forthcoming online exhibition and print catalog; stay tuned to the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Current Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; page for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Between&lt;/em&gt; will be on display in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda exhibit cases from May 27, 2021 – September 26, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Monday - Friday, and Sunday. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 01:18:04 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/913/91383/91383-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="239706"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Intro to QGIS (Sept 24th)</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92344</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92344</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Friday, September 24, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: virtual/online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This introductory session will focus upon the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics will include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;What is GIS?&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Analysis using Visualization&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will be held online. Participation will be via a short initial Zoom meeting followed by a self directed lab. Your instructor will be available via Zoom during the full workshop for help and questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit the "More Info" or "Ticketing" links to register via Eventbrite. The Eventbrite registration contains the workshop landing page and Zoom links.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:23:49 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/about/defaultimages/default_image.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="28030"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Intro to Python: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92414</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92414</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, September 28, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides an introduction to the Python programming language, covering basic syntax, variables, functions, and control flow. You will learn enough Python to write basic scripts, and to allow you to explore the rich environment of Python packages available. Prior experience with programming in another language is helpful, but not required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Thu, 16 Sep 2021 11:23:15 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92414/92414-9.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="69078"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>The Summer of 2021: Consolidation of the New Chinese Economic Model</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92314</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92314</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, September 28, 2021.  5:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries and the Stanford Center on China’s Economy and Institutions are pleased to present the 2021 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture featuring &lt;strong&gt;Professor Barry Naughton&lt;/strong&gt; who will be speaking on &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The Summer of 2021: Consolidation of the New Chinese Economic Model&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;During the summer of 2021, a “regulatory storm” shook markets in China. While the crackdown had its most immediate effects on private education, internet business, and finance, the government has also rolled out new policies to shape manufacturing and infrastructure, and even household fertility and income distribution. In this talk, Naughton interprets these actions as an extension of the ongoing Chinese government effort to exercise “grand steerage” of the economy. The new policies of summer 2021 in fact represent the consolidation of a new model, in which the Chinese government decisively steers a predominantly market economy.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Barry Naughton&lt;/strong&gt; is the So Kwan Lok Chair of Chinese International Affairs at the School of Global Policy and Strategy at UC San Diego. He is one of the world’s most highly respected economists working on China. He is an authority on the Chinese economy with an emphasis on issues relating to industry, trade, finance and China's transition to a market economy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Naughton’s recent research focuses on regional economic growth in China and its relationship to foreign trade and investment. He has addressed economic reform in Chinese cities, trade and trade disputes between China and the United States and economic interactions among China, Taiwan and Hong Kong.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Naughton has written the authoritative textbook “The Chinese Economy: Transitions and Growth,” which has now been translated into Chinese. His groundbreaking book “Growing Out of the Plan: Chinese Economic Reform, 1978-1993” received the Ohira Memorial Prize, and he most recently translated, edited and annotated a collection of articles by the well-known Chinese economist Wu Jinglian. Naughton writes a quarterly analysis of the Chinese economy for China Leadership Monitor. &lt;a href="https://gps.ucsd.edu/faculty-directory/barry-naughton.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Read more about Professor Naughton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The family of &lt;strong&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/strong&gt; donated his personal archive to the Stanford Libraries' Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world's largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/hsieh-lecture" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 09:16:01 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92314/92314-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="92126"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Slave Revolt on Screen: The Haitian Revolution in Film and Video Games</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92404</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92404</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Wednesday, September 29, 2021.  12:30 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Join us as Alyssa Goldstein Sepinwall disucsses her latest book &lt;a href="https://www.upress.state.ms.us/Books/S/Slave-Revolt-on-Screen" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Slave Revolt on Screen: The Haitian Revolution in Film and Video Games&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Haitian Revolution (1791 – 1804) was one of the most important events of modern world history. Taking place in what was then a French colony called Saint-Domingue, the Revolution was the first successful uprising of enslaved Africans in the New World. The Revolution sent shockwaves throughout the Atlantic world, terrifying enslavers while stirring hope among enslaved people. Despite its importance, the Haitian Revolution rarely appears on film; however, an increasing number of video games have featured stories about slave resistance in Haiti. Why has this topic seemed so radioactive to Hollywood executives, but attractive to certain game studios? What films and games on the Revolution exist, and how do they portray this key episode in Black history? And why should historians pay attention to games on topics like the Haitian Revolution, as sites of memory? &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://faculty.csusm.edu/sepinwal/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Alyssa Goldstein Sepinwall&lt;/a&gt; is Professor of History at California State University – San Marcos, where she is a past winner of the Harry E. Brakebill Outstanding Professor Award. She earned her Ph.D. in History from Stanford University in 1998. Her newest book, &lt;em&gt;Slave Revolt on Screen: The Haitian Revolution in Film and Video Games&lt;/em&gt;, was published in June 2021 by the University Press of Mississippi. Her previous works include &lt;em&gt;The Abbé Grégoire and the French Revolution: The Making of Modern Universalism&lt;/em&gt; (UC Press, 2005; released in paperback, 2021) and &lt;em&gt;Haitian History: New Perspectives&lt;/em&gt; (Routledge, 2012). Her research interests include the Haitian and French Revolutions; film and history; slavery and memory; and representations of history in video games.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;__________________________________________________________________&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This event is co-sponsored by Stanford Libraries' Silicon Valley Archives and by the Intercollegiate Media Studies at Claremont Colleges and the Dean of Faculty at Scripps College. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 22 Sep 2021 14:12:26 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92404/92404-5.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="287612"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92520</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92520</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Thursday, September 30, 2021.  1:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Green Library, Centennial Fountain area&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting the 1st Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair to highlight the social justice projects and efforts that have taken place within our Libraries over the past year, as well as to highlight projects to come and to showcase our existing social justice collections.   &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The JEDI Fair will feature speakers: University Librarian Michael Keller; the Libraries new Racial Justice and Social Equity Librarian Felicia Smith; Senior Associate Vice Provost for Undergrad Education and Professor in Humanities Gordon Chang; and George Brown, Stanford's new Director of the Center for Racial Justice. Each of them will speak broadly on the topic of racial justice and more specifically on what it means within their disciplines and departments. A questions and answers period will follow.  &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;See live demonstrations of the Know Systemic Racism (KSR) database and highlights from the Libraries existing social justice collections and receive fun giveaways. Come expecting to leave empowered to help end racism!&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check back for updates to the featured guest list&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 13:45:27 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92520/92520-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="184193"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Intro to R: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92416</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92416</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 5, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop is geared towards those who would like to get started with R or need to brush up on their skills. You will learn how to use R, RStudio, how to create objects in R, how to work with different data types, how to read tabular data into R and how to subset tables.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: None. Please come with R and RStudio installed: &lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-intro" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-intro&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:32:13 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92416/92416-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Precession: R. Buckminster Fuller's Creative Connections</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92480</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92480</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Ongoing  from October 7, 2021 through January 3, 2022.  See details for exact dates and times.  &lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exhibition to show October 7, 2021 — January 3, 2022, in Cecil H. Green Library &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Precession: The effect of bodies in motion on other bodies in motion.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All the inner effects of all, or most bodies in motion, and all other bodies in motion in [the] Universe is all "precessional." So I hope that instead of this just being a word that seems remote to you now, it suddenly begins to be important.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;-R. Buckminster Fuller&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;Precession: R. Buckminster Fuller’s Creative Connections&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 7, 2021, through January 3, 2022, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library Bing Wing. Fuller is perhaps best known as the patent-holder of the geodesic dome. Yet his projects were quite varied and touched upon many principles of creative scientific inquiry. The exhibition celebrates the creative connections between R. Buckminster Fuller and his contemporaries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In 1999, Stanford University Libraries acquired the archive of R. Buckminster Fuller, currently our largest single manuscript collection with over 1300 linear feet of papers and numerous recordings and models spanning the years 1920—1983. This massive collection has brought new insights about Fuller to light and illuminated key relationships with Fuller and other creative thinkers across the course of his multifaceted career as a mathematician, professor, and public intellectual. More than just acquaintances, these meetings of minds created what Fuller might have called “precessional” effects, with each exerting incremental influences on one another’s paths.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Fuller had hundreds of friendships, professional relationships, and collaborators throughout his life, which he maintained through travel as well as copious correspondence. This exhibit focuses on just a handful of the many well-documented relationships within the Fuller Collection and other manuscript collections at Stanford University Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with the exhibition’s opening, a virtual &lt;a href="/events/924/92478/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Panel Discussion: R. Buckminster Fuller’s Creative Connections&lt;/a&gt;, hosted by the Department of Special Collections and Stanford Libraries, will occur online on October 14th, 2021, from 4:00 pm - 5:00 pm PT. This event is free and open to the public; &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_VtdxQ1vyRN-CSEHLTeaq3Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;registration is required&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: In addition to the physical exhibition, there is a forthcoming online exhibition; stay tuned to the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Current&lt;/a&gt; Exhibits page for updates.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Fuller's Creative Connections&lt;/em&gt; will be on display in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda exhibit cases from October 7, 2021—January 3, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 01:30:17 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92480/92480-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="279939"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - R Introduction</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92488</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92488</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Thursday, October 7, 2021.  09:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Thursday, October 07, 2021 / 09:00 - 12:00 (Pacific Daylight Time) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/w1aEgFdaP1M3YBKK6&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Magdalena Matusiak, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Pathology)&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Menglan Xiang, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Pathology)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to the R programming language for those who have never (or barely) programmed in R, and especially to those who are new to programming in general. If you are unfamiliar with working with variables, vectors, and dataframes, then you are a good fit for this class! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned some of what R can do, explored the ecosystem of R and RStudio, modified/extracted data, and discovered resources to continue your learning even after this session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:56:44 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92488/92488-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Intro to QGIS (Oct 8th)</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92347</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92347</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Friday, October 8, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: virtual/online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This introductory session will focus upon the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics will include:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;What is GIS?&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Simple Analysis using Visualization&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This workshop will be held online. Participation will be via a short initial Zoom meeting followed by a self directed lab. Your instructor will be available via Zoom during the full workshop for help and questions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Please visit the "More Info" or "Ticketing" links to register via Eventbrite. The Eventbrite registration contains the workshop landing page and Zoom links.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 01 Sep 2021 11:22:59 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/about/defaultimages/default_image.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="28030"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Data Management: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92417</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92417</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 12, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop is geared toward those working with humanities data and will teach the foundations of data organization and best practices for building a structured dataset. Working through use cases, we’ll cover both good data management practices and working with data in spreadsheets to make them useful for a variety of research applications.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:32:20 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92417/92417-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - R Statistics</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92489</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92489</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Wednesday, October 13, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Wednesday, October 13, 2021 / 09:00 - 12:00 (Pacific Daylight Time) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/bL3hKiurLw9o7jax8&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Melissa Ko, Science and Engineering Education Fellow (Bioengineering)&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Magdalena Matusiak, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Pathology)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;In this workshop, we will introduce concepts of statistical modeling in R. Some prior use of R is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:56:49 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92489/92489-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Panel Discussion: R. Buckminster Fuller's Creative Connections</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92478</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92478</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Thursday, October 14, 2021.  4:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online via Zoom&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries invites you to a panel discussion on the subject of creative connections between R. Buckminster Fuller and his contemporaries to commemorate Stanford University Libraries’ opening of the exhibition &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="/events/924/92480/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Precession: R. Buckminster Fuller’s Creative Connections&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thursday, October 14, 2021 &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:00 - 5:30 pm PT: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panel Discussion&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;: R. Buckminster Fuller’s Creative Connections followed by Q&amp;A&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This event is free and open to the public. Registration is required; &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_VtdxQ1vyRN-CSEHLTeaq3Q" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;please register here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eva Diaz&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.pratt.edu/faculty_and_staff/bio/?id=ediaz3" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Associate Professor of Contemporary Art History at Pratt&lt;/a&gt;. Her teaching and scholarship are informed by historical and contemporary interdisciplinary collaborations between artists and other cultural producers. She has written extensively on Black Mountain College and R. Buckminster Fuller.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dakin Hart&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href="https://www.noguchi.org/about/contact/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Senior Curator&lt;/a&gt; at The Noguchi Museum in Long Island City, New York. He has extensive experience in both nonprofit arts administration and curatorial work, having worked with or for the Fine Arts Museum of San Francisco, the Montalvo Arts Center, the Nasher Sculpture Center, and Gagosian Gallery, among others.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Daniel López-Pérez&lt;/strong&gt; is an &lt;a href="https://www.sandiego.edu/directory/biography.php?profile_id=385" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Associate Professor of Architecture&lt;/a&gt; and a founding faculty member of the Architecture Program at the University of San Diego. In addition to other honors, López-Pérez was awarded a Barr Ferree Foundation Publication Grant from Princeton University to author &lt;em&gt;R. Buckminster Fuller, Pattern-Thinking &lt;/em&gt;(Lars Müller Publishers, 2020). It provides a major contextual reassessment of Fuller’s legacy by investigating his unique design process, and redefines our understanding of the relationships between geometry, structure, language, and intellectual property.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fred Turner&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href="https://comm.stanford.edu/faculty-turner/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Harry and Norman Chandler Professor of Communication at Stanford University&lt;/a&gt; and Professor by courtesy appointment in the Departments of History and Art &amp; Art History. An award-winning author and former journalist, his research and writing explore media, technology, and American cultural history.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Moderators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hsiao-Yun Chu&lt;/strong&gt; is a &lt;a href="https://design.sfsu.edu/people/faculty/hsiao-yun-chu" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Professor of Design&lt;/a&gt; at San Francisco State University and former Assistant Curator of the R. Buckminster Fuller Collection at Stanford University Libraries. Her research work investigates the role and meaning of nature in Fuller’s work, among other topics. She was the guest curator for the current exhibition on Precession.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robert G. Trujillo&lt;/strong&gt; is &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/trujillo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Associate University Librarian and Director of Special Collections&lt;/a&gt; at Stanford University Libraries. Among many other accomplishments, he championed the acquisition of the R. Buckminster Fuller Collection, the Ruth Asawa Collection, the Herbert Matter Collection, and the World Game Collection, all of which are featured in the current exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;This talk is hosted by the Stanford Libraries Department of Special Collections.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Tue, 21 Sep 2021 16:50:46 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92478/92478-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="268485"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - R Visualization</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92490</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92490</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Friday, October 15, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Friday, October 15, 2021 / 09:00 - 12:00 (Pacific Daylight Time) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/oMXxq1dGNRhPVZna8&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Menglan Xiang, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Pathology)&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Melissa Ko, Science and Engineering Education Fellow (Bioengineering)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to working with the ggplot2 visualization library in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate 1D and 2D plots, and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 13:56:53 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92490/92490-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Data Manipulation with Pandas: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92418</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92418</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 19, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;You should be familiar with basic Python syntax and fundamental programming concepts such as variables, functions, and control flow. If you need a refresher, check out A Byte of Python (https://python.swaroopch.com/).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:32:26 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92418/92418-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Data Wrangling with R: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92419</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92419</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, October 26, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for those who know the basics of R and would like to get started working with their research data. We will look into the tools that R provides to manipulate and explore tabular data, including reshaping, summarizing, and plotting. You will learn how to use the tidyverse package, in particular dplyr, tidyr, and ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Introduction to R. Please come with R and RStudio installed: &lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:32:32 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92419/92419-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>QGIS Cartography (Oct 29th)</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92348</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/923/92348</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Friday, October 29, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: virtual/online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Cartographic design and better map making in QGIS. Discussion covers general design concepts with a focus on issues and best practices for GIS mapping. Hands on sessions will cover a narrower set of the most common issues:&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;ul&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;Why design matters in map making?&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;Most common GIS map design issues&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;Establishing a good Visual Hierarchy&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;Methods for simplifying busy or complex data&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;How to use (and not abuse) color in maps&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;li&gt;Map layout&lt;/li&gt;&#xD;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Fri, 03 Sep 2021 09:39:50 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/about/defaultimages/default_image.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="28030"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - Sequence Data Processing</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92493</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92493</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, November 2, 2021.  12:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Tuesday, 2021-11-02 / 12:00 - 15:00 (Pacific Daylight Time)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/7RcGVxFsD7yVY2ef6&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Alma Parada, Librarian (Earth Science)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;This workshop will examine a sequence processing structure based on the Holmes Lab dada2 pipeline. Some scripting in a Unix/Shell environment, and use of R, is recommended.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:25:56 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92493/92493-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>ProQuest TDM Studio: Digital Tools and Methods for Humanities and Social Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92420</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92420</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, November 2, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop is an introduction to ProQuest TDM Studio, ProQuest’s new text and data mining platform. ProQuest TDM Studio allows researchers to mine and computationally analyze large volumes of published content from news, scholarly and other publications provided to the Stanford Libraries via current ProQuest subscriptions. We will demonstrate how to access the data repositories, perform searches, extract and develop a text corpus and how to link the extracts to the computational environment (Jupyter Notebook) to process and analyze the data with R or Python.&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;We recommend that you &lt;a href="https://guides.library.stanford.edu/c.php?g=1126780&amp;p=8224052" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;apply for a ProQuest TDM Studio accoun&lt;/a&gt;t in advance of the workshop. Account sign-up is not required to attend the workshop, but there will be time to troubleshoot and answer additional questions about the platform at the end of the session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 14:37:57 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92420/92420-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - R Introduction</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92582</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92582</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Wednesday, November 3, 2021.  9:00 AM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Wednesday, November 03, 2021 / 09:00 - 11:00 (Pacific Daylight Time) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/PHUsqeZyH8WPzijR6&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Lead Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Dr. Binglan Li, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Biomedical Data Sciences)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to the R programming language for those who have never (or barely) programmed in R, and especially to those who are new to programming in general. If you are unfamiliar with working with variables, vectors, and dataframes, then you are a good fit for this class! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned some of what R can do, explored the ecosystem of R and RStudio, modified/extracted data, and discovered resources to continue your learning even after this session.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:48:58 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92582/92582-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Personal &amp; Professional Websites w/GitHub Pages: Digital Tools and Methods for Hum. and Soc Sciences</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92422</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92422</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Tuesday, November 9, 2021.  2:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Online&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to using the free GitHub Pages service to host website and web pages online. We will take you through creating a GitHub account and a GitHub Pages site, and then show you how to create simple but useful web pages you can use to create an online presence for yourself or for a project or team. No prior experience is assumed or expected, and no special tools or software is required.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Tue, 14 Sep 2021 16:31:58 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/924/92422/92422-2.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="60813"/>
      </item>
      <item>
         <title>Carpentries @ Stanford - Unix/Terminal Introduction</title>
         <link>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92581</link>
         <guid>http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92581</guid>
         <description>
          &lt;div class="stanford-events-date"&gt;Date: Wednesday, November 10, 2021.  1:00 PM.&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-location"&gt;Location: Virtual Zoom (will be distributed to participants)&lt;/div&gt;

        &lt;div class="stanford-events-description"&gt;&lt;p&gt;Time and Date: &lt;br /&gt;Wednesday, 2021-11-10 / 13:00 - 16:00 (Pacific Standard Time)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Location: &lt;br /&gt;Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately) &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Admission: &lt;br /&gt;Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full. &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Registration: &lt;br /&gt;Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (you may need to sign out of your personal account first in order to do this), sign up here: https://forms.gle/nfo73h8KQFr5DaZ87&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Audience: &lt;br /&gt;Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Sponsor: &lt;br /&gt;Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Event Contact: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, zwp@stanford.edu &lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Instructors: &lt;br /&gt;Zac Painter, Librarian (Engineering)&lt;br /&gt;Dr. Binglan Li, Postdoctoral Research Fellow (Biomedical Data Sciences)&lt;br /&gt;Kalani Ratnasiri, PhD Candidate (Immunology)&lt;/p&gt;&#xD;
&lt;p&gt;Course Description: &lt;br /&gt;The command-line shell is one of the oldest and most powerful methods for you to operate a computer. Many people familiar with using a mouse to click on a screen find typing commands into a shell or terminal to be unfamiliar or scary. But, many programs or high performance computing environments require using a command line to connect with them. In this two hour workshop, the bash shell command line environment and its use in connecting to remote computers (SSH) will be introduced. No prior experience is needed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
      </description>
         <pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 11:44:20 PDT</pubDate>
         <enclosure url="http://events.stanford.edu/events/925/92581/92581-1.jpg"
                    type="image/jpeg"
                    length="17930"/>
      </item>
   </channel>
</rss>
