<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Encoding: Computers as a Global Medium at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;11/10 update:&lt;/b&gt; For scheduling reasons related to Winter Closure, the portion of this exhibit on display in the wall case will be deinstalled on Dec. 5, 2023.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing from the Libraries&amp;rsquo; extensive collections, &lt;i&gt;Encoding&lt;/i&gt; illustrates two fundamental shifts in the history of computing: recasting computers as a communications medium rather than solely as a means for calculation by &amp;ldquo;number crunching&amp;rdquo; and developing encoding systems that encompassed more of the world&amp;rsquo;s text and language systems. The result was global computing: a technology that today encompasses virtually all the world&amp;rsquo;s cultural, financial, educational and entertainment media. Notable collections include &lt;i&gt;the Unicode Collection&lt;/i&gt;, t&lt;i&gt;he Louis Rosenblum Papers&lt;/i&gt;, &amp;amp; &lt;i&gt;the Thomas S. Mullaney East Asian Information Technology History Collection&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Encodingexhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43777083471902/huge/fe5b6405c13574f4b206a4a8d6c3fb17509313a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3098" width="4000" isDefault="true" fileSize="1126422"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acclaimed photographer &lt;a href="https://www.marybethmeehan.com/"&gt;Mary Beth Meehan&lt;/a&gt; collaborated with Stanford professor &lt;a href="https://fredturner.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fred Turner&lt;/a&gt; to highlight an often overlooked side of Silicon Valley: the people who are struggling to make ends meet in a region known as the center of technological innovation.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A selection of portraits and text from their award-winning book &lt;a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/S/bo90479007.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Seeing Silicon Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on display throughout Hohbach Hall&amp;#39;s study spaces. This long-term exhibition will be up through 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/seeing_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44632871153947/huge/9bdd0a6a9240812158b5f139c218c34bb9b226f2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="384" width="576" isDefault="true" fileSize="293286"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Native American Heritage Book Display at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come to Green Library and check out a book display that celebrates the indigenous peoples of the United States, in honor of Native American Heritage Month. The display will be up for the entire month of November.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/native_american_heritage_book_display</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44712690624875/huge/e3e156c9c556449c262868c85c031f902bbc7348.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2832" width="2124" isDefault="true" fileSize="1166452"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science Before Silicon Valley  at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition to show August 11, 2023 &amp;mdash; March 24, 2024, in Cecil H. Green Library&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;for the reception.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;An extension of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition entitled:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; Early Stanford Women in STEM &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;will show from September 25 &amp;mdash; December 15, 2023, in the Hohbach Hall Entrance Case, Silicon Valley Archives, Green Library.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. It showcases Stanford&amp;rsquo;s considerable holdings for this subject, including the role of our own university in this history. Our exhibition displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East. We invite viewers to see them as building blocks in a global history of gender and knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Many women participated in making knowledge. Long before the rise of the institutional laboratory, the body and the home were domestic laboratories. Largely denied access to institutions of research and learning, women improvised their own opportunities. We have looked for patterns rather than exceptions, documenting women&amp;rsquo;s scientific labor and the practical realities of earning a living. The variety of scientific and medical publications written by, for, and about women reminds us that this is a history of the many rather than the few. Every author has a reading public&amp;mdash;the most successful ones reached large international audiences. Individual histories reveal larger networks and often exist in relationship to institutions. We explore the evolution of women&amp;rsquo;s scientific education, research, publications, and careers with these questions in mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Hypatia of Alexandria (355&amp;ndash;415 CE) provides a symbolic point of departure for our exhibition. She was renowned for her lectures in Greek philosophy, mathematics, and astronomy in Alexandria and was brutally murdered by Christians; none of her writings survive, but her reputation endured. Our opening case also includes Maria Sibylla Merian&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous and insightful Metamorphosis of Surinamese Insects (1705). Merian (1647&amp;ndash;1717) was a trained artist and self-educated naturalist who left her husband, collaborated with her daughters, and traveled all the way to Dutch Surinam to observe insects. There she learned about the medicinal uses of Caribbean plants from indigenous and enslaved women. Her life and career were their own metamorphosis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Bringing a long global story home, we end our exhibition by reflecting on women and science &amp;quot;before Silicon Valley.&amp;quot; From its inception in 1891, Stanford educated and encouraged women of science. Focusing on the early decades, we have extracted interesting Stanford women scientists, engineers, and physicians&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;from the archives, exploring their intellectual passions and pursuits. Louise Brown Nash&amp;rsquo;s portfolio of scientific illustrations in the opening case illuminates the kind of opportunity talented women unexpectedly discovered at Stanford, where Nash was the first &amp;quot;Artist of the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory.&amp;quot; This pioneering generation of Stanford women found possibilities even as they confronted their limits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The next generations of Stanford women bridge the gap between the growth of women&amp;rsquo;s higher education in the late nineteenth century, the era of women&amp;rsquo;s suffrage, and the postwar boom in American universities, scientific research, and technological innovation. A 1957 memo of one of the earliest meetings of Stanford women faculty records three women in science and engineering&amp;mdash;Myra Keen (paleontology), Mary Sunseri (mathematics), and Irmgard Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz (aeronautical engineering). Keen and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz also open this exhibition. Keen&amp;rsquo;s career as a curator and professor illuminates the end of an era when natural history was an important part of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s mission. Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz&amp;rsquo;s arrival at Stanford marks the growth of aeronautical engineering. Her work brought her great acclaim in Germany, where she headed a research institute, and led to a spousal lectureship at postwar Stanford. In 1957, Keen was in her third year as an assistant professor and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz was still a lecturer&amp;mdash;until 1960 when the conspicuous gap between her reputation and status became too uncomfortable. Both women help us to understand the importance of second careers, a subject explored with selections from two major Stanford archives in the exhibit case downstairs in the Silicon Valley Archive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The renowned physicist and chemist Marie Curie would have surely enjoyed meeting the Stanford women we have encountered, had she been able to come as a visiting professor in the early 1930s. Every episode in this exhibition deserves further study, as do others we could not include. We invite you to explore these histories and their artifacts and get to know some very interesting scientific women.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. M-F, 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Sat, and 12 p.m. to 5 p.m. Sun. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Library Hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; page to confirm hours and access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Libraries&amp;#39; entry requirements and available services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge_women_and_science_before_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43725646356122/huge/283f182485005a2848d9ad5d0707f7c7355c1020.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="730683"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>This Is Not Here: Some Fluxus Things from Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Art Locked Stacks at Bowes Library holds Fluxus publications by John Cage, Nam June Paik, Allan Kaprow, Alison Knowles, and Yoko Ono, among others. The humor and absurdity that animated Fluxus encourages us to find art in the everyday, or at least not to take art so seriously. This is not a history of Fluxus, nor even an exhibition of everything at Bowes Library that could be considered Fluxus, but rather, in the Fluxus spirit, just some Fluxus things. Curated by Lindsay King, Head Librarian, Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/this_is_not_here_some_fluxus_things_from_bowes_art_architecture_library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44660422258187/huge/224fdad983c1575db9527b8ac13856d453522540.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1262923"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recoding America: Book Talk With Jennifer Pahlka at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Jennifer Pahlka &lt;/b&gt;(Code for America&lt;b&gt;)&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;Ingrid Pappel&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(Tallinn University of Technology), and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;(Stanford University) on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Recoding America: Why Government is Failing in the Digital Age and How We Can Do Better&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just when we most need our government to work &amp;ndash; to decarbonize our infrastructure and economy, to help the vulnerable through a pandemic, to defend ourselves against global threats &amp;ndash; it is faltering. Government at all levels has limped into the digital age, offering online services that can feel even more cumbersome than the paperwork that preceded them and widening the gap between the policy outcomes we intend and what we get.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But it&amp;rsquo;s not more money or more tech we need. Government is hamstrung by a rigid, industrial-era culture, in which elites dictate policy from on high, disconnected from and too often disdainful of the details of implementation. Lofty goals morph unrecognizably as they cascade through a complex hierarchy. But there is an approach taking hold that keeps pace with today&amp;rsquo;s world and reclaims government for the people it is supposed to serve. Jennifer Pahlka shows why we must stop trying to move the government we have today onto new technology and instead consider what it would mean to truly recode American government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPEAKER: Jennifer Pahlka&lt;/b&gt; is the author of &lt;a href="https://us.macmillan.com/books/9781250266774/recodingamerica"&gt;Recoding America: Why Government is Failing in the Digital Age and How We Can Do Better&lt;/a&gt;. She founded Code for America in 2010 and led the organization for ten years. In 2013, she took a leave of absence to serve as U.S. Deputy Chief Technology Officer under President Obama and helped found the United States Digital Service. She served on the Defense Innovation Board under Presidents Obama and Trump. At the start of the pandemic, she also co-founded United States Digital Response, which helps government meet the needs of the public with volunteer tech support. She received the Skoll Award for Social Entrepreneurship, and was named by Wired as one of the 25 people who has most shaped the past 25 years. Jennifer is a graduate of Yale University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DISCUSSANT: Ingrid Pappel &lt;/b&gt;is the 2023 Global Digital Governance Fellow at Stanford University,&amp;nbsp;Associate Professor at the Department of Software Science and Vice-Dean for Master&amp;#39;s studies at the School of IT, Tallinn University of Technology. She has more than 20 years of experience in different development projects related to e-governance solutions in Estonia and abroad. She is the head of the Digi-State Technologies and Architecture research group, which addresses the complexity related to how governments can satisfy the demands of their citizens in times of need. Her research focuses on digital government ecosystems by investigating technologies that support digital transformation. Her research topics are related to the development activities in launching paperless management by creating interoperability with state registries and external and internal systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;MODERATOR: Andrew J. Grotto&lt;/b&gt; is a William J. Perry International Security Fellow at the Center for International Security and Cooperation (CISAC) and&amp;nbsp;a Research Fellow at the Hoover Institution, both at Stanford University. He is also Director of the&amp;nbsp;Program on Geopolitics, Technology, and Governance (FSI).&amp;nbsp;Grotto&amp;rsquo;s research interests center on the national security and international economic dimensions of America&amp;rsquo;s global leadership in information technology innovation, and its growing reliance on this innovation for its economic and social life.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/CVscSgY3mbaawRrm9"&gt;RSVP is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jennifer-pahlka-recoding-america</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44322743688727/huge/4e274a188e9ac83d33078730af2214eac8a11142.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1899" width="1542" isDefault="true" fileSize="562453"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Henry Lowood, Replayed at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archies in welcoming Henry Lowood, the Harold C. Hohbach Curator for History of Science &amp;amp; Technology Collections, as he discusses his most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Replayed&lt;/i&gt;, on November 14, 2023.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the early 2000s, Henry Lowood has had a key role in initiatives devoted to the preservation and documentation of virtual worlds, digital games, and interactive simulations, establishing himself as a major scholar of game studies. Replayed offers Lowood&amp;rsquo;s far-flung and significant publications on these subjects in a single volume.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_henry_lowood_replayed</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44031985006928/huge/119a5a308f4be1b23e01bd2782fd90f3eb11c802.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="219" width="290" isDefault="true" fileSize="120474"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GISDay@Stanford with Planet Labs at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;GISDay@Stanford with Planet Labs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Real-Time Satellite Monitoring with Planet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With roughly 200 Dove satellites in orbit, &lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/products/monitoring/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;PlanetScope Monitoring&lt;/a&gt; provides a high-resolution, continuous, and complete view of the world from above, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;img alt="" src="https://img.evbuc.com/https%3A%2F%2Fcdn.evbuc.com%2Fimages%2F631425029%2F153479166967%2F1%2Foriginal.20231030-191123?h=2000&amp;amp;w=720&amp;amp;auto=format%2Ccompress&amp;amp;q=75&amp;amp;sharp=10&amp;amp;s=d22257a8b60a056f254d59174a634553" style="height:196px; width:720px" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planet Monitoring provides 3.7 meter resolution images of the entire Earth daily. Access to these ready-to-use images is made simple with Planet&amp;rsquo;s APIs, web application, and GIS integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a comprehensive day of workshops and discussions centered around improving your skills using Planetscope Daily Imagery, particularly focusing on the utilization of Planet&amp;#39;s APIs and image processing with Python. This event is designed for those keen on advancing their understanding of leveraging Planetscope Imagery, at scale, for research and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Schedule:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:30am - 9:40am: Welcome and Introduction of Instructors &amp;amp; Facilitators.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;9:40am - 10:40am: &lt;b&gt;Workshop 1: Introduction to Planet and Basic API (Search &amp;amp; Ordering)&lt;/b&gt; - A brief overview of Planetscope followed by a hands-on introduction to the Planet APIs.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:40am - 10:50am: Break - A short pause for attendees to stretch and refresh.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;10:50am - 11:50am: &lt;b&gt;Workshop 2: Image Processing with Python&lt;/b&gt; - Explore basic image processing techniques using Python, Rasterio, &amp;amp; Geopandas with Planetscope imagery.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;11:50am - 1:20pm: &lt;b&gt;Lunch Break&lt;/b&gt; - An opportunity for participants to have lunch, network, or relax.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;1:20pm - 2:20pm: &lt;b&gt;Workshop 3: Advanced Orders API Use&lt;/b&gt; - Delve into bulk ordering, server-side processing with Orders API, and cloud delivery to Google Earth Engine including a demonstration on automation and function creation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:20pm - 2:30pm: &lt;b&gt;Break&lt;/b&gt; - A moment for participants to stretch, refresh, or check emails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2:30pm - 3:30pm: &lt;b&gt;Symposium Special Session&lt;/b&gt; - Featuring Stanford Researchers using Planet data: Lightning Talks on diverse topics such as Human Trafficking, Dams, Nomads, Landslides, and Jasper Ridge, followed by a presentation on Stanford&amp;rsquo;s Planet.com E&amp;amp;R Subscription by Stace Maples, and concluding with an overview of Planet.com&amp;rsquo;s roadmap.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3:30pm - 3:45pm: &lt;b&gt;Closing Remarks &lt;/b&gt;- Expressing gratitude to participants, offering further resources, distributing swag, and sharing announcements on upcoming events.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This structured day promises a blend of technical skill-building, insightful discussions, and networking opportunities for Stanford researchers using Planet Lab&amp;#39;s data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seating for this event is very limited. Please do not register unless you are certain you will be available to attend for the entire day. There will not be a streaming version of the event. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/gisdaystanford_with_planet_labs</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44686490093903/huge/1e8d6d9147c048a04e9cd7381f494d54463dd013.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="780" width="994" isDefault="true" fileSize="1499461"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Citation Mgmt with Zotero at Building 200, History Corner</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop is a basic introduction to the free reference management software, Zotero. Attendees will learn how to use Zotero to organize their research, create citations, separate their research into different projects or chapters, and connect Zotero to their web browsers for citations. Zotero can help create an environment where your research is organized into one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is suitable for beginners to Zotero, including undergraduates, graduate students, and faculty.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_citation_mgmt_with_zotero</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427405</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.1697</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44463633246351/huge/eeae15a3d8e3445a5e4de3aa77fe197c6301e8bd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="69078"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Europe’s New North?  Enduring stereotypes in the Nordic and Baltic regions at Encina Commons</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with &lt;b&gt;Daunis Auers&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(University of Latvia) and&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Amir Weiner&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;(Stanford University) on&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Europe&amp;rsquo;s New North? &amp;nbsp;Enduring stereotypes in the Nordic and Baltic regions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stereotypes (deeply ingrained beliefs or assumptions) about nations are central to country images which in turn impact domestic economic developments and relations with other states. Stereotypes are also resistant to change and can become outdated and themselves stymie change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The contemporary images of the three Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania and the five Nordic states of Denmark, Finland, Iceland, Norway and Sweden present an interesting case study of the durability of stereotypes despite a radically changed reality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three decades ago, the three Baltic states regained their sovereign independence following the collapse of the Soviet Union and started out on a path of democratic and economic development that would eventually lead them to accession to the European Union and NATO in 2004. Baltic-Nordic cooperation in the 1990s was quite intense and the initial expectation (and hope) on both sides of the Baltic Sea was that the Baltic states would gradually converge with the Nordic states, passively adopting &amp;ldquo;Nordic models&amp;rdquo; of democracy, economy and the welfare state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thirty years later, both Baltic and Nordic regions have changed drastically, although national stereotypes have barely shifted. This talk examines the radical transformations in politics, economics and culture in the Northern Europe and discusses why, despite these changes, stereotypes of the &amp;ldquo;good&amp;rdquo; Nordics and the &amp;ldquo;shifty&amp;rdquo; Baltics persist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SPEAKER: Daunis Auers&lt;/b&gt; is Professor of European Studies and Jean Monnet Chair at the University of Latvia, and serves as Director-at-large of the Association for the Advancement of Baltic Studies (AABS). He studied at the London School of Economics and defended his PhD at University College London. He has been a Fulbright Scholar at the University of California-Berkeley (2005-2006) and a Baltic-American Freedom Foundation Scholar at Wayne State University in Detroit (2014) and published widely on political parties, elections, referendums, populism and the radical right and economic competitiveness in the Baltic states. His book on The Comparative Government and Politics of the Baltic States: Estonia, Latvia and Lithuania in the 21st Century &amp;ndash; was published by Palgrave Macmillan in 2015. He is currently working on a monograph analyzing Nordic-Baltic integration and is a Fulbright program Visiting Professor at the University of Washington in Seattle during the fall and winter of 2023/2024.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;DISCUSSANT: Amir Weiner&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;is Director of Stanford&amp;#39;s Center for Russian, East European, and Eurasian Studies and Associate Professor of Soviet History. Professor Weiner teaches and writes on totalitarian movements and regimes with a focus on the Soviet polity; population politics; the Second World War; and modern mass violence. His current research is on the KGB and the Soviet surveillance state.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Nq94qHjW6cqh6Dna8"&gt;RSVP is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;,&amp;nbsp;a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/europes-new-north-daunis-auers</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426792</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.164842</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44341897853465/huge/0ba80a797f361c8bb369a5c8b513232c7b883e7f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="532" width="800" isDefault="true" fileSize="58818"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Delightful Dragons: Examining “Cozy” Games   at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The &amp;ldquo;dragon&amp;rdquo; of many games and RPGs is a mighty foe to be vanquished, an enemy that determines the course of the plot and whose defeat becomes the source of rewards. Sometimes this dragon is a vicious or mindless animal, at other times a devious intelligence. It can also be, in the heartbreaking game That Dragon, Cancer, a metaphor for an entirely different kind of struggle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if&amp;hellip; it doesn&amp;#39;t have to be this way? What if dragons can be gentle and friendly?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us as we explore the genre of &amp;ldquo;cozy&amp;rdquo; games, a genre of low-stakes life-simulator games that often feature idyllic scenery and anthropomorphized animals. We&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the roots and growing popularity of this genre in both video and board games, before we dive into the fantastical worlds of artisan dragons created by the designers of&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/236709/tea-dragon-society-card-game"&gt;Tea Dragon Society Card Game&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/336986/flamecraft"&gt;Flamecraft&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="background-color:transparent"&gt;&lt;b&gt;First time visiting Stanford?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;Stanford University is a large campus and it is important to plan ahead. Please see our &lt;a href="https://svarchives.sites.stanford.edu/about/plan-your-visit"&gt;&amp;quot;Plan Your Visit&amp;quot; guide&lt;/a&gt; for helpful information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_625</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44570321490885/huge/24f1ee7b07b87615c54b237b9ca66b1156ac4dbb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="730" width="810" isDefault="true" fileSize="1215055"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 6 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_9797</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Open Gaming at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a study break with one of the games in our collection at this special Tabletop Tuesday. We&amp;rsquo;ll have casual, drop-in style games that you can start playing in less than 5 minutes with Library staff, as well as access to longer games for group play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;First time visiting Stanford?&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;Stanford University is a large campus and it is important to plan ahead. Please see our &lt;a href="https://svarchives.sites.stanford.edu/about/plan-your-visit"&gt;&amp;quot;Plan Your Visit&amp;quot; guide&lt;/a&gt; for helpful information.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_open_gaming</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44632172959083/huge/bf5bd6cd39e17dec046d2da47c933d8c914057ee.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
