<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Oceans: Pacific Ocean at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Oceans&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the complexity of deep trenches to the shifting dynamics of sea ice, Earth’s oceans are vital to understanding our planet’s past, present, and future. In the 2025–2026 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature ocean geology, biology, physics, chemistry, and mapping, highlighting their roles in regulating the climate, sustaining biodiversity, and connecting global systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September - October: Explore the unique geology of the Pacific Ocean with its deep trenches, fast-spreading ridges, and volcanic island chains through books, electronic resources, and maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a valid, physical government-issued photo ID to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-exhibit-pacific-ocean</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50659519179157/huge/676fa101f5b2a2b416cc19e1be4c115d8bd765ec.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="379149"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Digital Typography: Mathematics, Chinese, and More at Robin Li and Melissa Ma Science Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibit explores digital typography, and its uses and challenges in a variety of settings, including mathematics and non-Western languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featured materials include scholarship on the history and implementation of digital typography. There are texts on LaTeX, a software system for typesetting documents with mathematical notation developed by Donald Knuth, a famous computer scientist who you can sometimes see riding around Stanford on his bicycle. There is also a book on the history of digital input systems for the Chinese language written by Stanford professor Thomas Mullaney. Additionally, there are flyers from Stanford Initiative on Language Inclusion and Conservation in Old and New Media (SILICON), codirected by Prof. Mullaney, showcasing SILICON's work developing typefaces for digitally disadvantaged languages. The juxtaposition of these different lenses through which to view digital typography makes for an interesting and wholistic view of the topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit dovetails with other happenings at the Stanford Libraries. In particular, there will be workshops on LaTeX in the Li &amp;amp; Ma Science library in late October, one covering &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/latex-fundamentals-workshop"&gt;the fundamentals&lt;/a&gt; and another covering &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/biblatex-and-zotero-workshop"&gt;bibliographies and integration with reference management software&lt;/a&gt;. Also, the East Asia Library has recently acquired the only prototype of the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mingkwai"&gt;MingKwai Chinese typewriter&lt;/a&gt;, which prefigured modern digital Chinese input methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/digital-typography-mathematics-chinese-and-more</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430656</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171414</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50889508210229/huge/1cfb5830478b340405cd8f259238f966bca2984d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="315" width="640" isDefault="true" fileSize="38006"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Essential Engagement: The Works of Joseph DeLappe at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;"The theoretical basis for my work lies in the belief that it is essential, as an artist and citizen of the world, to engage in and challenge the norms and expectations of the digital present and the larger cultural context." &lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
- Joseph DeLappe, artist statement&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The prolific work of Joseph DeLappe, spanning a wide range of physical and digital mediums, provides an opportunity for critical reflection and thoughtful discussions about our relationship to technology and the post-9/11 political landscape. As the most comprehensive repository of materials related to the history and development of the Silicon Valley region, the Silicon Valley Archives is honored to exhibit a selection of this work and bring the history of recent technology into conversation with our present through this pioneering artist’s work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/about-stanford-libraries/visit-us"&gt;&lt;u&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on the Libraries’ website&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joseph DeLappe&lt;/b&gt;, born San Francisco 1963, is an artist, activist and educator, he relocated to Scotland from the USA in 2017 where he is the Professor of Games and Tactical Media at Abertay University, Dundee. Working with electronic and digital media since 1983, projects in online gaming performance, sculpture and electromechanical installation have been shown throughout the world. He has developed works for venues such as Eyebeam Art and Technology in New York, The Guangdong Museum of Art, China, the Southern Utah Museum of Art and Transitio MX, Mexico City, among many others. Creative works and actions have been featured widely in scholarly journals, books and in the popular media, including the &lt;i&gt;New York Times, The Australian Morning Herald, Art in America, The Guardian &lt;/i&gt;and the BBC. &lt;a href="https://www.delappe.net/"&gt;More information about DeLappe and his artwork is available on his website. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/essential-engagement-delappe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51098140948140/huge/ef40edb24cecc6805858877a461379e186df194c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="716" width="720" isDefault="true" fileSize="1011063"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>To the World: China’s Multimedia Campaign during the Cold War at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The call “People of the World, Unite!” was a story China once told itself. When the world was polarized, the vision of global solidarity paradoxically prevailed in the People’s Republic of China during its Cold War isolation, manifested in a myriad of media categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To the World” unveils the diverse and far-reaching multimedia campaign in China. Drawing from the special collection at the East Asia library, this exhibition highlights how the regime propagated its international vision inward to the domestic audience from the 1950s to the 1970, and the interplay of ideas and ideologies shaping China’s self-presentation and portrayal of other countries and ethnicities in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition also contributes to a vibrant and expanding field of scholarship that has significantly advanced our understanding of China’s media in recent history. Scholars such as Andrew Jones, Christine Ho, and Jie Li have explored the complexities of culture and history by integrating media and trans media, encompassing text, photography, film, visual art, music, and radio. The objects on display—multilingual editions of the Little Red Book, vinyl records, English textbooks, cartoon illustrations, and so on—serve as primary sources for understanding media and mediation in the everyday realities of the bygone era. Thus, the exhibition invites students, scholars, and the broader public to reconsider the complexities of China’s media landscape and encourages newlines of inquiry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exhibition on view from September 22 to December 20, 2025&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“To the World” is curated by Yue Wu (PhD student, East Asian Languages and Cultures) and Zhaohui Xue (Curator for the Chinese Collection), with consultation from Professor Ban Wang (William Haas Professor in Chinese Studies). The exhibition is generously sponsored by the Stanford East Asia Library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/to-the-world-chinas-multimedia-campaign-during-the-cold-war</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50914581553448/huge/bfdc86bf5aa690b3ab09361f6416d06ba5ce252e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="1545" isDefault="true" fileSize="1165829"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits: The Making of a Children's Book at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibition showcases &lt;i&gt;Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits&lt;/i&gt;, a children’s book by Stanford art historian Emanuele Lugli that explores why portraits matter through the life and work of Lavinia Fontana, Europe’s first professional woman painter. Illustrated by Chiara Palillo, the book is more than a study of portraiture and early modern women—it is an artist’s book in itself, a hybrid creation where collage, acrylic, cyanotype, and digital color converge in playful, unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Opening reception, Oct. 16, 4-6 pm in the lobby outside the library.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lavinias-wondrous-portraits-the-making-of-a-childrens-book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50569364017038/huge/5bb505839ed649401c32d60e7c1b38b22b8da0c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="900" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="77463"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Text Analysis with Python at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM–2:30PM, Wednesday, October 29, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm (Head of Data Science Training and Consultation)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Curious about how to work with text data using Python? Join us for a practical introduction to text analysis, tailored for those new to programming. This workshop will cover key techniques, including text pre-processing, named entity recognition, topic modeling, and sentiment analysis. No prior Python experience is necessary. We’ll guide you through foundational Python concepts, introduce essential libraries and modules for text analysis, and provide hands-on examples to support your learning. This event is a great starting point for discovering the potential of Python in working with text data, and will inspire you to learn Python to gain even greater insights and capabilities. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. A waitlist will open once all spots are filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/text-analysis-with-python-707</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50719575533440/huge/f929f96ae33fc533d9a2b342f6fff365b2e2b574.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39152"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Above &amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library) </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Above &amp;amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, curated by the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/speakers" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2025 Ruderman Conference presenters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, is on view in the David Rumsey Map Center &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Wednesday, October 8, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt; - Friday, February 27, 2026&lt;/b&gt;. The exhibition opens in conjunction with the &lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fifth Biennial Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition explores how cartography depicts the depths of the Earth, the ocean floor, weather systems, the solar system, and even the seemingly intangible internet – anything but the thin boundary that divides land and sky that we tend to associate with maps. This exhibition celebrates the multifaceted nature of mapping, inviting reflection on our interconnected existence and revealing the beauty and complexity of our world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/above-below-cartography-beyond-terrain</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50907645575537/huge/66abcb4b11be9e58c37698de6abc31a76c242b19.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3840" width="4800" isDefault="true" fileSize="5645151"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colonial Gulf: How Empires Documented a Region at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;How have colonial and imperial regimes imagined and represented the Persian Gulf? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibit explores how the British, Ottoman and American empires documented the human and non-human geography, resources, and landscapes of the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It features historical maps and artifacts from the collections of the Branner Earth Sciences Library and the David Rumsey Map Center alongside cartographic visualizations created by the &lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; research collective.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Featured materials include maps derived from a dataset collected from the &lt;i&gt;British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia, and Oman&lt;/i&gt; created using QGIS, including the map of mentions of date palms displayed here.  By placing these historical materials and contemporary analyses in conversation, we uncover a genealogy of geographical thinking alongside the power structures embedded in imperial and colonial record-keeping.  This exhibit aims to illustrate and critically engage the breadth, depth, and nature of colonial and imperial knowledge production regarding the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula, highlighting its varied expressions in texts, maps, and charts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/b90cd597a47f46d39567b4c9824ca6ee"&gt;&lt;span&gt;view digitally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored by: &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dept. of History&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://cesta.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;CESTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;&lt;span&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Oct 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/colonial-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49820497130375/huge/021478f5ef78e5ba12d6141026a426a42130fff1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="667372"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in R</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Virtual (link provided upon registration)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;1PM–4PM, Tuesday, November 4, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada, Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to working with data visualization in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate common plots (e.g., scatter , and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure R and RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop. You can download both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-visualization-in-r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50722022202099/huge/d0f7d051b95765a98fd23defb55a52282451eec6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Democracy Day Redistricting 101 at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Redistricting 101: California’s Prop 50 and beyond!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join the Stanford Libraries for an interactive redistricting mapping workshop this Democracy Day! On Tuesday Nov. 4th, California’s voters weigh in on &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://voterguide.sos.ca.gov/quick-reference-guide/50.htm" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Proposition 50&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, a state constitutional amendment to modify Congressional district maps. Cast your ballot (check out our &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.library.stanford.edu/voterinformation" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;LibGuide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; for registration and voting information) and come on by our hands-on workshop on how to make your own mathematically-sound redistricting map. What does democratic representation look like? The choice is yours.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;We will be using online cartographic tools like &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://davesredistricting.org/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;DRA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/b&gt;(Dave’s Redistricting) and &lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://planscore.org/upload.html" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;PlanScore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; &lt;/b&gt;to draw and evaluate voting district maps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Guest speaker &lt;b&gt;Mike Migurski &lt;/b&gt;will share how PlanScore participates in the redistricting process!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Learn about: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Proposition 50: The Election Rigging Response Act &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Measures of fairness&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Census Data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Partisan versus independent redistricting commissions&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/democracy-day-redistricting-101</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51137943120690/huge/afbb140193c550452431e23879bc95adc660c2ec.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="147467"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Nov. 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-2026</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693397424570/huge/41bca654587cde9ea86a68b313125093dc8f8074.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Historic US Land Record Search at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Have you heard of "public lands" but you're not quite sure what that means? Are you curious about what California's land looked like in the past? &lt;/i&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Join us for an introduction to searching for historic land records&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; and a tutorial &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;on using the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;US Federal &lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;General &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;Land&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; Office &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;Record&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://glorecords.blm.gov/"&gt;s database&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;This publicly-accessible database is maintained by the Bureau of Land Management (BLM) and contains thousands of land records, maps, and surveys that contain a multifaceted history of the American West (and beyond).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;In this session, we’ll cover how to find master title plats, cadastral surveys, surveyor’s field notes, as well as original patent documents (focusing on California) so if you want to learn how the US Federal government documents federal and private &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt;land&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="text-align:start;"&gt; title, rights, and usage, this workshop is for you.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
There are many uses of these primary source documents; whether you have an interest in history, federal law and governance, natural resources (agriculture, mining, forestry etc), land use (urbanization, privatization, environmentalism etc), or surveying and cartography, there should be something in this session for you! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;We'll begin with an overview of &lt;b&gt;native lands&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;US federal public land management&lt;/b&gt;, &lt;b&gt;surveying&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;legal land descriptions&lt;/b&gt;. Then we'll shift to a hands on demonstration of the GLO Records Database for searching and downloading land record documents. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Attendees should arrive with their own laptops if they wish to participate. Compters will not be provided. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/land-record-search</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51004804671114/huge/4ac9f135701ac67ccd68906919ddbfbb03086aad.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="2000" width="2000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2453555"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planetscope Satellite Imagery 101 (Friday Nov, 7) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real-Time Satellite Monitoring with Planet&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With roughly 200 Dove satellites in orbit, &lt;a href="https://www.planet.com/products/monitoring/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;PlanetScope Monitoring&lt;/a&gt; provides a high-resolution, continuous, and complete view of the world from above, every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planet Monitoring provides 3.7 meter resolution images of the entire Earth daily. Access to these ready-to-use images is made simple with Planet’s APIs, web application, and GIS integrations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Description:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for an Introduction to Planetscope Daily Imagery. This event is designed for those keen on advancing their understanding of leveraging Planetscope Imagery, at scale, for research and teaching.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We'll begin with an overview of Planetscope, and how to get access. Then we'll shift to a hands on demonstration of the Planetscope Explorer, for searching and ordering Planet.com imagery. Finally, we'll introduce the Data &amp;amp; Orders APIs from Planet.com, using Python.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Attendees should arrive with their own laptops if they wish to participate. Compters will not be provided. &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note that this workshop series is only open to current Stanford University Affiliates, with full SunetID privileges.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/planetscope_satellite_imagery_101</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45571105672451/huge/c54c26d6fd58659095920e215bde85e78099f1c9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="79561"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Rescue Project: Protecting Knowledge in the Digital Age at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Why does rescuing data matter for democracy, science, and society? Join us for a hybrid event with Lynda Kellam, co-founder of the Data Rescue Project, as she shares insights from the frontlines of this grassroots movement. From climate records to health statistics, public data is always at risk—but through collective action, the Data Rescue Project works to safeguard endangered government datasets for future generations. Learn how these vital resources are being preserved and discover how you, too, can play a role in protecting public knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-rescue-project-protecting-knowledge-in-the-digital-age</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50939877171293/huge/76e6b2863104139c76dd3bef4dced1c5fc78feb2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="721" width="724" isDefault="true" fileSize="100862"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: Humor at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If it was funny to Stanford students in 1927 or to Germans in the 16th century, is it still funny now? Humor is more likely to age like fish than a fine wine, but no matter how a joke smells, it can reveal a great deal about the times in which it was told.  Test your historical funny bone at this month's Special, Unique, and Rare popup exhibit, where the Libraries' Humanities and Area Studies curators have selected items from Special Collections that have something to say about HUMOR.  Drop in any time between 2-4 PM on Tuesday, November 11th, Hohbach 123 (Silicon Valley Archive classroom, Green Library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For monthly notifications about upcoming Special, Unique &amp;amp; Rare pop-up exhibits, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfhg8-4BOFO5D1lCDh2q3rzbtQfwZjuMS-Y29lSQAzQjDn21A/viewform"&gt;join our mailing list.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Nov 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-humor</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51128302931746/huge/6ea7af489c28ff399f785fbfdd346931f86f3cdb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1698" width="1899" isDefault="true" fileSize="1445014"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Introduction to NVivo workshop for social science students.  Please register for this session at the following link below:  &lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current"&gt;https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-2336</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47746634515153/huge/4b7271aa6a1855e0b196ba9e4f4d29d03c880256.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AI for Academic Research at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1PM - 2:30PM, Wednesday, November 12, 2025&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm (Head of Data Science Training and Consultation)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Looking to harness AI to streamline your research workflow? This workshop introduces the architecture and applications of large language models (LLMs) and shows you how to use them effectively and responsibly in academic research. We’ll cover common use cases, capabilities and limitations, and key ethical considerations. Topics include data preprocessing, strategies for working with tabular data, and evaluation approaches for LLM-driven research tasks. You’ll also gain hands-on experience with Stanford’s AI Playground API. By the end, you’ll have the knowledge, practical skills, and sample code to integrate AI into your research workflow.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is intended for researchers with programming experience who want in-depth knowledge of LLMs. If you’re new to coding, we recommend taking &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/text-analysis-with-python-707"&gt;Text Analysis with Python&lt;/a&gt; first.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is required and limited to current Stanford affiliates on a first-come, first-served basis. A waitlist will open once all spots are filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ai-for-academic-research</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50719593830494/huge/5c5f7466f5603c476d3de7e68c4fbe697fb58ec3.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="36343"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The DREAM WORLDS of Arthur Tress: A Journey in Film and Photography at Hewlett Teaching Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;img src="https://mcusercontent.com/00f6b1b49f4cbb7355c0d9a29/images/9c1b1390-2648-ad01-60ab-c3d8b14bb16e.png" style="height:715px;width:672px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arthur Tress &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;one of the leading artists in the landscape of postwar American photography. His extraordinary photographs,&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt; 2 million&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; over more than six decades, are in the Cantor Art Museum collection, and both the De Young Museum and the Getty Collection have featured critically acclaimed major retrospective exhibits.  Now a spry 85, Arthur’s body of work encompasses and spans poverty in Appalachia, Southern Sharecroppers, San Francisco in the 1960s, Civil Rights, Urban Environmental issues and Gay Rights, evolving into magical realism/social surrealism exploring fantastical provocative dreamscapes as he continues his evocative portraits of nature along the California coast and haunting images of urban landscapes. In 2019, the Stanford Libraries acquired Arthur’s archive as part of the launch of their new Photography Initiative. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arthur’s 1970 landmark series &lt;i&gt;Open Space in the Inner City: Ecology and the Urban Environment &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;established him as a pioneer of urban environmental and environmental justice photography. His 1972 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;book, &lt;i&gt;The Dream Collector&lt;/i&gt;, a haunting exploration of children’s dreams, established him as a master photo artist with a unique vision.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Photography is my way of defining the confusing world that rushes constantly at me. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Where are the photographs we can pray to, that will make us well again, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;or scare the hell out of us?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:center;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arthur Tress&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The kaleidoscopic artistry of Arthur Tress is a creative universe unto itself – documentary works, haunting portraits, personal narrative expressions, his own fables and fairy tales. There is Arthur Tress of the big city, submerged in the New York school of photography and the eccentric portraits he makes for magazines. There is Arthur Tress running from the Vietnam War, instead doing sociological photography in Japan, Mexico and China – the power of ritual. There is the artist fearlessly documenting and exploring his life as a Gay man. Then there’s Arthur Tress of the West Coast, who spent 25 years living in Cambria and now resides in San Francisco, taking daily photographic trips to nearby towns or capturing &lt;i&gt;The Life Cycle of The Orange Rubber Traffic Cone,&lt;/i&gt; as one of his recent photo books is titled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;The evening will consist of the Stanford Premiere of the acclaimed film, &lt;i&gt;Arthur Tress: Water’s Edge, &lt;/i&gt;an intimate journey as &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Arthur grapples with relationships, legacy, the aging process, and loneliness all while continuing to develop his photographic art within the hidden, desolate, and decaying corners of California.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;A conversation and Q &amp;amp; A with the audience and Stanford Professor Richard Meyer, Arthur Tress and the filmmaker, Stephen Lewis, will follow the screening.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This special event is presented by the Bill Lane Center for the American West &amp;amp; Planet Earth Arts @Stanford and &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Co-Sponsored by: Stanford Departments of African &amp;amp; African American Studies, Art &amp;amp; Art History, Communication &amp;amp; Sociology, Doerr School of Sustainability&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Haas Center for Public Service&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford Humanities Center&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;American Studies, Continuing Studies, Urban Studies, Stanford Libraries, Institute for &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Diversity in the Arts and Taube Center for Jewish Studies.. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;For more information about Arthur Tress, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.arthurtress.com/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;please visit here&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:10pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2025 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-dream-worlds-of-arthur-tress-a-journey-in-film-and-photography</link>
      <geo:lat>37.428953</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172839</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51042113670584/huge/19fd384c374abc6af88663ce16b08e1eb55f6caf.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="236" width="265" isDefault="true" fileSize="95608"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Čiurlionis in Glass with Gleb Pyšniak and Rokas Zubovas at Braun Music Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for a concert with cellist Gleb Pyšniak and pianist Rokas Zubovas, celebrating the anniversary of Mikalojus Konstantinas Čiurlionis, Lithuania’s most prominent artist:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Čiurlionis in Glass with Gleb Pyšniak and Rokas Zubovas&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concert is dedicated to the 150th anniversary of the birth of Mikalojus Konstantinas Čiurlionis, the exceptional Lithuanian composer and painter. His art, infused with cosmic vision and delicate sensitivity, continues to inspire artists worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the heart of the concert lies Čiurlionis’ music and its dialogue with works from different epochs and cultures. The program reflects the cultural ties between Lithuania and the United States – from composers with Lithuanian roots or close ties to Lithuania, such as Anatolijus Šenderovas and Žibuoklė Martinaitytė, to American musical icons Philip Glass and George Gershwin, who both have ancestral ties to Lithuania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Martinaitytė, who has resided in the U.S. for many years, often explores themes of time, space, and emotional perception in her work. Her latest opus, “unda, unda… inundare…”, was written specifically for Čiurlionis’ 150th birth anniversary. Gershwin’s music, once especially beloved by the Lithuanian émigré community in America, here becomes a symbol of cultural connection, while Glass’s minimalism intriguingly resonates with Čiurlionis’s visionary spirit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thus, the program is not only a tribute to Čiurlionis’ legacy but also a living dialogue between Lithuanian and American musical cultures, between past and present.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Lithuanian cellist &lt;b&gt;Gleb Pyšniak&lt;/b&gt; is regarded as one of the most distinctive artists of his generation in the Baltic region. He made his debut at the age of fourteen with the Lithuanian Chamber Orchestra under the direction of Prof. Saulius Sondeckis and went on to study at the Lithuanian Academy of Music and Theatre with Prof. Rimantas Armonas. He later continued his education in Vienna with Prof. Natalia Gutman at the Konservatorium Wien (graduating with distinction) and studied chamber music with Prof. Johannes Meissl at the University of Music and Performing Arts Vienna. A laureate of the Karl Davydov International Cello Competition and winner of the Antonio Janigro Competition, he has also received the Yamaha Music Foundation Award and was named a “New Master on Tour” by the Holland Music Sessions.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pyšniak has performed at prestigious venues such as the Amsterdam Concertgebouw, Vienna Musikverein, Moscow Conservatory Great Hall, Quirinal Palace in Rome, Porto Casa da Música, and Lisinski Concert Hall in Zagreb, among many others. His discography includes Baltic Prayer, LEGENDOS, Window to Lithuania, Duettissimo, Aerogramme, Exclusively Piazzolla, and Vilos Trio – Johanna Doderer Piano Trios. Since 2019, he has been teaching at the Lithuanian Academy of Music and Theatre and serves as Artistic Director of the International Joseph Achron Festival, Kintai Festival, and Kalėdinis Vilnius festival&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Pianist &lt;b&gt;Rokas Zubovas&lt;/b&gt; has taught piano in Chicago (Saint Xavier University), Vilnius (Lithuanian Academy of Music and Theatre), and Kaunas (Vytautas Magnus University), where he was granted full professorship in 2013.  He is also the director of M. K. Čiurlionis House in Vilnius. Mr. Zubovas completed bachelor studies at the Lithuanian Academy of Music and Theatre and received his Master's Degree in piano performance from DePaul University in Chicago, USA. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Mr. Zubovas toured with concerts in South and North America, performed in most countries of Europe, and in Asia. His discography includes over 20 releases, in both vinyl and CD format. In 2010, he recorded all piano works of Čiurlionis releasing 6 CD set. Mr. Zubovas has delivered papers on various aspects of Čiurlonis’ art at international conferences in Lithuania, Estonia, Argentina, and Belgium. He organizes music festivals and other cultural events, writes articles on music and culture for various publications in and outside of Lithuania, and has created the main character in a feature film about M. K. Čiurlionis, "Letters to Sofija." He is a great grandson of &lt;/i&gt;Čiurlionis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This in-person event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/G4B7SPsWnvPn8gju6"&gt;Registration is required.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The event is organized in collaboration with the SF Lithuanian Community and will feature their popup art exhibit, "Floral Symphonies: Echos Čiurlionis."&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and cultural events hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 20:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ciurlionis-in-glass</link>
      <geo:lat>37.423758</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.169296</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51045529278179/huge/64269a409f5e017b550685eb12cc87be3ed9f05b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="933" isDefault="true" fileSize="285295"/>
      <category>Performance</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amos Gitai Archive at Stanford at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="http://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;The Amos Gitai Archive at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from November 14, 2025 to February 15, 2026.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Ayda Melika and Eitan Kensky with text by Marie-José Sanselme; produced by Deardra Fuzzell, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Pasha Tope. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Nov 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/amos-gitai-archive-at-stanford</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51101333905443/huge/db5941e86abbb11d09bf845e9c8b28d8347051dc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2500" width="3750" isDefault="true" fileSize="3919561"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Science, Data, and Software in the Natural Capital Project (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This month we will be joined by Emily Pavia, Dave Fisher, and James Douglass, members of Stanford's Natural Capital Project (NatCap), a Stanford-based partnership among interdisciplinary researchers, professionals, and leaders around the world that supports nature-informed decision-making about policies and investments. Representing NatCap's software &amp;amp; data management teams, Emily, James and Dave will discuss NatCap's open source software including a suite of computational models for quantifying ecosystem services (&lt;a href="https://github.com/natcap/invest" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;InVEST&lt;/a&gt;), supporting Python libraries for geoprocessing (&lt;a href="https://github.com/natcap/pygeoprocessing" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;PyGeoprocessing&lt;/a&gt;) and for generating human- and machine-readable metadata (&lt;a href="https://github.com/natcap/geometamaker" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;GeoMetaMaker&lt;/a&gt;) and the recently-launched &lt;a href="https://data.naturalcapitalproject.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Natural Capital Project Data Hub&lt;/a&gt; that facilitates open access to ecosystem services data. Together, these and other efforts by the Natural Capital Project enhance the ability of researchers and policymakers to easily access and reuse data that supports informed decision-making about natural resources.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The &lt;a href="https://bayareaopensciencegroup.github.io/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/a&gt; is a growing community for Bay Area academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/natural-capital-project-baosg</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51073761721219/huge/6a46fed96a01dcc00d037e421c7da4c66232c548.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="102446"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data in R at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Velma Denning Room (120F), Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1–3PM, Wednesday, November 19, 2025 &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Claudia Engel, Academic Technology Specialist (Anthropology)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop will introduce you to geospatial libraries and concepts using R. Prior experience using R at an introductory level is expected. You will learn how to read spatial data into R and perform basic spatial analysis.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure R and RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop. You can download both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This is an in-person, interactive session. Please bring your laptop, and your Stanford ID or a valid government-issued ID for library access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/geospatial-data-in-r</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50722044082493/huge/bc6c1a989566c790ce132f97b50fe628309e8b5c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="39961"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeannette Estruth in Conversation with Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew on women libertarians in Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming the historian Jeannette Estruth as she discusses her new research on the history of women libertarians in Silicon Valley. Jeannette will be joined in conversation by the Stanford historians Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley today represents not only a specific location in California but also a larger imaginative vision that shapes economic and social realities. In this powerful conceptual landscape, the libertarian political fantasy emerges as a critical factor of cultural reproduction. In this talk and the conversation that follows, Jeannette Estruth will reveal how the Libertarian Party in Silicon Valley of the 1990s built durable and significant connections between technology firms, media, and the voting public in ways that were deeply rooted in the specific geographies and histories of Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This political moment in Silicon Valley rehearsed a powerful political script that combined technology, the free market, sexuality, gender, anti-statism, and electoral politics. Estruth argues that Santa Clara and San Mateo counties’ local Libertarian Parties were crucial to Silicon Valley’s libertarianism, and to its political development as a technology hub, a financial center, and a site of production for a powerful vision of the future. By turning back to the 1990s, we can learn much about the world we live in today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jeannette Estruth&lt;/b&gt; is an assistant professor of history at Santa Clara University. Her writing has appeared in venues ranging from the Washington Post to the Business History Review. She is completing her book manuscript, &lt;i&gt;Think Different: Silicon Valley Activism and the Making of Modern American Politics&lt;/i&gt;, which explores the history of social movements, the technology industry, and economic culture in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jennifer Burns&lt;/b&gt; is a professor of history at Stanford University. She is a historian of the twentieth century United States working at the intersection of intellectual, political, and cultural history, with a particular interest in ideas about the state, markets, and capitalism and how these play out in policy and politics. Her most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Milton Friedman: The Last Conservative,&lt;/i&gt; is the first full biography of the influential economist and political figure. It was awarded the 2025 Reagan Book Prize and was a finalist for the 2024 Hayek Prize. She has published articles about the history of conservatism, libertarianism, and liberalism in a number of academic and popular journals, including &lt;i&gt;Reviews in American History, Modern Intellectual History, Journal of Cultural Economy, The New York Times, The New Republic, &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Dissent&lt;/i&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jenni Depew&lt;/b&gt; is a PhD student in history at Stanford University. She studies the history of American political thought and development from the 18th to 21st centuries. She has previously published work on the role of the U.S. Presidency in regards to civil rights, third parties in the 19th century, and Indigenous food sovereignty in her home state of Wisconsin. Her most recent work focuses on the history of libertarianism. Jennifer is also a Knight-Hennessy Scholar, JD student at Stanford Law School, and former graduate research assistant at the Stanford Internet Observatory (SIO).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jeannette-estruth-in-conversation-with-jennifer-burns-and-jenni-depew-on-women-libertarians-in-silicon-valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50703481059715/huge/870f537346dcff60bfe8880798ff989b9ec4fdab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1572" width="1500" isDefault="true" fileSize="1594716"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>MingKwai, Rediscovered at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us on December 2, 2025, as we explore the origins of of the incredible MingKwai typewriter, trace its history across continents, and examine its lasting cultural and technological impact. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The MingKwai Chinese Typewriter, a milestone in the history of Chinese information technology, was invented by the Chinese-born author, translator, and cultural commentator Lin Yutang in the 1940s. &lt;a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2025/07/22/nyregion/mingkwai-typewriter-china.html"&gt;Discovered in a New York basement&lt;/a&gt;, this extraordinary prototype has been entrusted to the Stanford University Libraries, where it will be used in research, exhibits, and academic programs. Read more about this discovery in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://news.stanford.edu/stories/2025/05/mingkwai-chinese-typewriter-prototype-stanford-libraries"&gt;The Stanford Report&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/i&gt;and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.npr.org/2025/07/05/nx-s1-5405452/chinese-typewriter-mingkwai-stanford"&gt;NPR&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To celebrate the typewriter’s rediscovery and new home at Stanford, we will be bringing together scholars and experts from across multiple disciplines to reintroduce the legendary MingKwai Chinese Typewriter to the world. Dr. Thomas S. Mullaney, Professor of Chinese History at Stanford University, will lead a team of researchers and students in exploring the MingKwai&lt;i&gt;'&lt;/i&gt;s historical, technological, and cultural significance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mingkwai"&gt;Learn&lt;/a&gt; about the typewriter, and &lt;a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/mingkwai-rediscovered-tickets-1752379427039"&gt;secure your ticket&lt;/a&gt; to the symposium.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mingkwai-rediscovered</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50916171408489/huge/c7fcfe7688e04b7612519de9f800399d9a68e1b6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="418" width="639" isDefault="true" fileSize="340462"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 3 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7123</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693405343948/huge/daea989242dbe63d8d8d26df0ddd96a0e16e347b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Max Kasy in conversation with Rob Reich on How AI Really Works and Who Benefits at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;AI is inescapable, from its mundane uses online to its increasingly consequential decision-making in courtrooms, job interviews, and wars. The ubiquity of AI is so great that it might produce public resignation—a sense that the technology is our shared fate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But how is the technical structure of AI shaped by social power and inequalities? In this book talk and conversation, Max Kasy will discuss how who AI serves is determined not by the technology itself but by who it is built to serve. How can we shape AI to benefit all? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Kasy’s new book, &lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction&lt;/i&gt;, reveals how artificial intelligence, far from being an unstoppable force, is irrevocably shaped by human decisions—choices made to date by the ownership class that steers its development and deployment. The technology of AI, Kasy insists, is ultimately not that complex. It is insidious, however, in its capacity to steer results to its owners’ wants and ends. Kasy clearly and accessibly explains the fundamental principles on which AI works, and, in doing so, reveals that the real conflict isn’t between humans and machines, but between those who control the machines and the rest of us.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction&lt;/i&gt; offers a powerful vision of the future of AI: a future not shaped by technology, but by the technology’s owners. Amid a deluge of debates about technical details, new possibilities, and social problems, Kasy cuts to the core issue: Who controls AI’s objectives, and how is this control maintained? The answer lies in what he calls “the means of prediction,” or the essential resources required for building AI systems: data, computing power, expertise, and energy. As Kasy shows, in a world already defined by inequality, one of humanity’s most consequential technologies has been and will be steered by those already in power.&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;br&gt;
Against those stakes, Kasy offers an elegant framework both for understanding AI’s capabilities and for designing its public control. He makes a compelling case for democratic control over AI objectives as the answer to mounting concerns about AI’s risks and harms. &lt;i&gt;The Means of Prediction &lt;/i&gt;is a revelation, both an expert undressing of a technology that has masqueraded as more complicated and a compelling call for public oversight of this transformative technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kasy is joined in conversation by Rob Reich, the McGregor-Girand Professor of Social Ethics of Science and Technology at Stanford. Reich’s scholarship in political theory engages with the work of social scientists and engineers. His newest work is on governance of frontier science and technology. His most recent books are &lt;i&gt;System Error: Where Big Tech Went Wrong and How We Can Reboot&lt;/i&gt; (with Mehran Sahami and Jeremy M. Weinstein, HarperCollins 2021) and &lt;i&gt;Digital Technology and Democratic Theory&lt;/i&gt; (edited with Lucy Bernholz and Hélène Landemore, University of Chicago Press 2021). Reich has testified before Congress and written widely for the public, including for the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Washington Post&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Wired&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Time&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The Guardian&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;Stanford Social Innovation Review&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kasy is a professor of economics at Oxford University, where he coordinates the Machine Learning and Economics Group. His research interests include machine learning theory, publication bias, adaptive experimental design, statistical decision theory, identification and causality, and economic inequality. He has received grants from the Alfred P. Sloan foundation, served as an expert for the EU Directorate for Research and Innovation, and received the Young Economist Award from the Economic Association of Austria.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 19:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/max-kasy-in-conversation-with-rob-reich</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50772311503808/huge/436c3c99b75fe5d254c5963d4b9df88a89f17884.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1228" width="1228" isDefault="true" fileSize="482510"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hope and Despair: The Emotional Response to the War in Ukraine at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Gabrielius Landsbergis, Bernard and Susan Liautaud Visiting Fellow, and Michael McFaul, Director of the Freeman Spogli Institute, as they discuss the emotional journey surrounding Russia's war against Ukraine, its global implications, and transatlantic support for Ukraine.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Hope and Despair: The Emotional Response to the War in Ukraine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every few months, new technological developments or limited battlefield successes by either Russia or Ukraine spark sweeping claims that the war's outcome has been decided. Shortly thereafter, these narratives often collapse, leading to a reversal and a cycle of inflated expectations followed by disillusionment. Despite this tumultuous rollercoaster of hope and despair, one fact remains clear: Ukraine has not lost, and Russia has not won. Both outcomes – and their opposites – are still possible. For those of us who support Ukraine, this uncertainty is, in itself, a positive sign. However, hope alone cannot be our only strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a discussion with Michael McFaul, Gabrielius Landsbergis will explore how to cut through the shifting headlines to understand the real picture and what actions must be taken to strengthen Ukraine, so that hope is not our sole approach. He will examine what fuels this state of uncertainty and what factors can help us grasp the balance of power on the battlefield.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gabrielius Landsbergis &lt;/b&gt;served as minister of foreign affairs of Lithuania from 2020 to 2024, a pivotal period for the region. He led Lithuania’s diplomatic service guided by the principle of values-based foreign policy. During his tenure, Lithuania emerged as one of the most vocal supporters of Ukraine, Taiwan, and freedom fighters worldwide. Before that, he served in the Parliament of Lithuania from 2016, was chairman of the Homeland Union (Lithuanian Conservatives), and was elected to the European Parliament in 2014. Prior to entering politics, Gabrielius Landsbergis was a career diplomat.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;He currently serves as Bernard and Susan Liautaud Visiting Fellow at Stanford's Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael McFaul&lt;/b&gt; is director at the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies, the Ken Olivier and Angela Nomellini Professor of International Studies in the Department of Political Science, and the Peter and Helen Bing Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1995. He served for five years in the Obama administration, first as special assistant to the President and senior director for Russian and Eurasian affairs at the National Security Council at the White House (2009-2012), and then as U.S. ambassador to the Russian Federation (2012-2014).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;This in-person event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/KpygQDtEkUsd4sSZA"&gt;Registration is required.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/global-conversations-talk-series/"&gt;Global Conversations&lt;/a&gt;, a series of talks, lectures, and seminars hosted by Stanford University Libraries and &lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/"&gt;Vabamu&lt;/a&gt; with the goal of educating scholars, students, leaders, and the public on the benefits of but also challenges related to sustaining freedom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/hope-and-despair-landsbergis-mcfaul</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50915768794722/huge/1fc6ce93f885bb71e112d46f0af9deb651e3cef7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1010" width="1078" isDefault="true" fileSize="1590047"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Patrick McCray, "README: A Bookish History of Computing from Electronic Brains to Everything Machines" at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Patrick McCray to talk about his latest book, &lt;i&gt;README: A Bookish History of Computing from Electronic Brains to Everything Machines&lt;/i&gt;, on January 21, 2026, at 4:00 p.m. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;i&gt;README&lt;/i&gt;, historian Patrick McCray argues that in order for computers to become ubiquitous, people first had to become interested in them, learn about them, and take the machines seriously. A powerful catalyst for this transformation was, ironically, one of the oldest information technologies we have: books. The author uses a carefully chosen selection of books, some iconic and others obscure, to describe this technological revolution as it unfolded in the half century after 1945. The book begins with a fundamental question: How does a new technology become well-known and widespread? McCray answers this by using books as a window into significant moments in the history of computing, books, publishing, and American culture.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;i&gt;README&lt;/i&gt; offers a literary history of computers and, more broadly, information technologies between World War II and the dot.com crash of the early twenty-first century. From the electronic brains and cybernetics craze of the 1940s to the birth of AI, the rise of the personal computer, and the Internet-driven financial frenzy of the 1990s, books have proven a durable and essential way for people to learn how to use and think about computers. By offering a readable half-century of bookish history, &lt;i&gt;README &lt;/i&gt;explains how computers became popular and pervasive.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2026 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-patrick-mccray-readme</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50145731152489/huge/9e036fcdf2458402c8b5aedcaebd305988a77e0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1030" width="800" isDefault="true" fileSize="120032"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
