<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Designing Radically Inclusive Solutions Exhibition at Green Library, Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Intersectional design drives innovation while supporting social justice and environmental sustainability. It's about getting the design right for people across all of society -- from the very beginning. This exhibit takes visitors through the &lt;em&gt;Intersectional Design Cards&lt;/em&gt;, a design activity to create radically inclusive products, processes, and paradigms that was developed by an interdisciplinary team from Stanford University's Hasso Plattner Institute of Design (the d.school). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibition is free and open to active Stanford ID cardholders during Green Library's operating hours. Face coverings are strongly recommended. For the most up-to-date information regarding library access, please visit &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;library.stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/designing_radically_inclusive_solutions_exhibition</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39330967402362/huge/e59d353aaacb05b45bf3619ea04781ce2fbfd838.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="196230"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Up for Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders exhibit</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the precipitous increase in Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) hate crimes throughout the United States, the staff of Stanford Libraries created the Rise Up against AAPI exhibit which focuses on the history of systemic racism against the AAPI community. The aim of this exhibit is to help educate our community and provide support and resources so that we can start the process of healing and prevent future incidents. In this exhibit, we discuss past events that have led to these reprehensible acts, including institutionalized policies that have pitted minority groups in our country against each other to weaken the other&amp;rsquo;s influence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that through education, our community at large can rise to action against racism at all levels of our society. From the nuanced exclusions on the playground and in the workplace, to the blatant disregard for human life demonstrated in the murders of Asian American women in Atlanta and the brutal attacks on elderly AAPI community members in California and New York&amp;mdash;we must all take an active stand against the scourge that racism is to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently, this exhibit is only available online. You can access the online exhibit at &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries stands with the AAPI community and denounces all hate crimes, including the recent surge in hate crimes specifically targeted at the AAPI community. We hope you will join our efforts to learn about the history of violence against the AAPI community so that we can prevent history from repeating itself.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rise_up_for_asian_americans_and_pacific_islanders_exhibit_6719</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574964232972/huge/c5939c8e08f2ce84e461c0551677315644bf9910.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="89766"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Say Their Names - No More Names</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Say Their Names &amp;ndash; No More Names&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is an online and in-person exhibit that highlights Black Americans who have been killed or impacted by police brutality and systemic racism. The exhibit originated in direct response to the global Black Lives Matter movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical exhibition in Green Library includes names affixed to glass panels in the Bing Wing as well as banners throughout the first floor that contain the names and faces of the featured victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/saytheirnames" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;online exhibit&lt;/a&gt; displays the images and individual stories of victims, including Emmett Till, Kalief Browder, Salecia Johnson and Bettie Jones; it also calls attention to events like the Tulsa riots, the Tuskegee syphilis experiment and the Chicago Police Department Midnight Crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who visit Stanford can also see a large banner featuring the words &amp;#39;Know Justice Know Peace,&amp;#39; which was hung on the front entrance of Green Library commemorating the opening of the exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note the physical exhibit in Green Library is currently limited to authorized Stanford ID cardholders due to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp; However, the online exhibit, which also includes photos of the physical exhibit is available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit is sponsored by the Stanford Libraries and is a follow up to a &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/171904" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;statement of solidarity and support&lt;/a&gt; against systemic racism published by Stanford Libraries over the summer. It offers opportunities for learning, reflection and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/say_their_names_-_no_more_names_5200</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574945719380/huge/cd40212aa73b14c75ec2704fcb2307127e1e9400.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="108932"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view February 24, 2022, through August 28, 2022, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Robert Trujillo; produced, designed, and installed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/materialia_lumina_contemporary_artist_books_from_the_codex_international_book_fair</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118485903850/huge/23c7599baa91e1cd67c67e00d6c403ed88b088a4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="151056"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Behind the scenes of a manuscript collection: A German-Russian Mennonite archive from the early 20th at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Where do manuscript collections come from, and how do they end up at Stanford? Join the Stanford curators who are involved in the acquisition and the rare book dealers who are selling this collection, Mark and Joanna Funke of Funke Books and Kate Mitas, Bookseller, who will be on hand to display and discuss this research material.&lt;br aria-hidden="true" /&gt;Mark, Joanna, and Kate will also be happy to share information about the antiquarian book world and their own experiences with it, and they are looking forward to hearing from the researcher perspective and the library point of view. Bring your questions about the bookselling business, antiquarian book fairs, and the Antiquarian Booksellers' Association of America (ABAA).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/behind_the_scenes_of_a_manuscript_collection_a_german-russian_mennonite_archive_from_the_early_20th</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40019969574031/huge/5bf5090c33b334a38d7c238942590ed5a7a99097.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="318" width="318" isDefault="true" fileSize="63823"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>De-Stress at Stanford Libraries at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Boba tea, DIY calming jars, Ice cream, llamas, Moon Pies, and more! You don't want to miss this!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;After 3 years, Stanford Libraries will once again be hosting its De-Stress Fest!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stop by&lt;strong&gt; Green Library &lt;/strong&gt;on &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, June 2nd between 3:00-5:00 pm&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;Highlights at Green include DIY calming jars, specialty ice cream, pizza and swag compliments of the Stanford Federal Credit Union, the lively Stanford Band, and llama petting. A variety of table activities including games, puzzles, and more will be available outside of Green Library, on the patio nearest Coupa Café throughout the event.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Branch Libraries around campus will be hosting their own activities too. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2022/05/libraries-annual-de-stress-fest-back" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Learn more&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/de-stress_at_stanford_libraries</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39993332012177/huge/c19466589300a1949bb114935b2724aac8ed131b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="277567"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
