<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Encoding: Computers as a Global Medium at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drawing from the Libraries&amp;rsquo; extensive collections, &lt;i&gt;Encoding&lt;/i&gt; illustrates two fundamental shifts in the history of computing: recasting computers as a communications medium rather than solely as a means for calculation by &amp;ldquo;number crunching&amp;rdquo; and developing encoding systems that encompassed more of the world&amp;rsquo;s text and language systems. The result was global computing: a technology that today encompasses virtually all the world&amp;rsquo;s cultural, financial, educational and entertainment media. Notable collections include &lt;i&gt;the Unicode Collection&lt;/i&gt;, t&lt;i&gt;he Louis Rosenblum Papers&lt;/i&gt;, &amp;amp; &lt;i&gt;the Thomas S. Mullaney East Asian Information Technology History Collection&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Encodingexhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43777083471902/huge/fe5b6405c13574f4b206a4a8d6c3fb17509313a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3098" width="4000" isDefault="true" fileSize="1126422"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Poisonous Green Book of  the Victorian Era at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the Victorian Era, the toxic compound copper acetoarsenite was frequently used to create a bright green binding color. Inspired by the Winterthur Poison Books project, this exhibit examines the context and history behind copper acetoarsenite and the field of chemistry during this period, as well as the rise of workplace safety regulations. It explores the available testing methods for identifying this toxic compound and gives practical tips and advice for safe handling of books and materials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/poisonousexhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43777130546735/huge/a05e2aace9f020f1783e4f70e5837a1592200e3d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2222" width="1452" isDefault="true" fileSize="332005"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science Before Silicon Valley  at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition to show August 11, 2023 &amp;mdash; March 24, 2024, in Cecil H. Green Library&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;An extension of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Exhibition entitled:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; Early Stanford Women in STEM &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;will show from September 25 &amp;mdash; December 15, 2023, in the Hohbach Hall Entrance Case, Silicon Valley Archives, Green Library.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. It showcases Stanford&amp;rsquo;s considerable holdings for this subject, including the role of our own university in this history. Our exhibition displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East. We invite viewers to see them as building blocks in a global history of gender and knowledge.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Many women participated in making knowledge. Long before the rise of the institutional laboratory, the body and the home were domestic laboratories. Largely denied access to institutions of research and learning, women improvised their own opportunities. We have looked for patterns rather than exceptions, documenting women&amp;rsquo;s scientific labor and the practical realities of earning a living. The variety of scientific and medical publications written by, for, and about women reminds us that this is a history of the many rather than the few. Every author has a reading public&amp;mdash;the most successful ones reached large international audiences. Individual histories reveal larger networks and often exist in relationship to institutions. We explore the evolution of women&amp;rsquo;s scientific education, research, publications, and careers with these questions in mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Hypatia of Alexandria (355&amp;ndash;415 CE) provides a symbolic point of departure for our exhibition. She was renowned for her lectures in Greek philosophy, mathematics, and astronomy in Alexandria and was brutally murdered by Christians; none of her writings survive, but her reputation endured. Our opening case also includes Maria Sibylla Merian&amp;rsquo;s gorgeous and insightful Metamorphosis of Surinamese Insects (1705). Merian (1647&amp;ndash;1717) was a trained artist and self-educated naturalist who left her husband, collaborated with her daughters, and traveled all the way to Dutch Surinam to observe insects. There she learned about the medicinal uses of Caribbean plants from indigenous and enslaved women. Her life and career were their own metamorphosis.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Bringing a long global story home, we end our exhibition by reflecting on women and science &amp;quot;before Silicon Valley.&amp;quot; From its inception in 1891, Stanford educated and encouraged women of science. Focusing on the early decades, we have extracted interesting Stanford women scientists, engineers, and physicians&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;from the archives, exploring their intellectual passions and pursuits. Louise Brown Nash&amp;rsquo;s portfolio of scientific illustrations in the opening case illuminates the kind of opportunity talented women unexpectedly discovered at Stanford, where Nash was the first &amp;quot;Artist of the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory.&amp;quot; This pioneering generation of Stanford women found possibilities even as they confronted their limits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The next generations of Stanford women bridge the gap between the growth of women&amp;rsquo;s higher education in the late nineteenth century, the era of women&amp;rsquo;s suffrage, and the postwar boom in American universities, scientific research, and technological innovation. A 1957 memo of one of the earliest meetings of Stanford women faculty records three women in science and engineering&amp;mdash;Myra Keen (paleontology), Mary Sunseri (mathematics), and Irmgard Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz (aeronautical engineering). Keen and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz also open this exhibition. Keen&amp;rsquo;s career as a curator and professor illuminates the end of an era when natural history was an important part of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s mission. Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz&amp;rsquo;s arrival at Stanford marks the growth of aeronautical engineering. Her work brought her great acclaim in Germany, where she headed a research institute, and led to a spousal lectureship at postwar Stanford. In 1957, Keen was in her third year as an assistant professor and Fl&amp;uuml;gge-Lotz was still a lecturer&amp;mdash;until 1960 when the conspicuous gap between her reputation and status became too uncomfortable. Both women help us to understand the importance of second careers, a subject explored with selections from two major Stanford archives in the exhibit case downstairs in the Silicon Valley Archive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The renowned physicist and chemist Marie Curie would have surely enjoyed meeting the Stanford women we have encountered, had she been able to come as a visiting professor in the early 1930s. Every episode in this exhibition deserves further study, as do others we could not include. We invite you to explore these histories and their artifacts and get to know some very interesting scientific women.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. M-F, 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Sat, and 12 p.m. to 5 p.m. Sun. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Library Hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt; page to confirm hours and access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:none"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Libraries&amp;#39; entry requirements and available services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Aug 2023 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge_women_and_science_before_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43725646356122/huge/b706b17e1c18706af16cf5fc01aa45f51ff5bdf6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="730683"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for September&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays. &lt;/i&gt;Theme and featured games will be announced closer to the event date!&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Sep 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_4115</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43466372701087/huge/05ad723c5889ed93acdc1a50059c0a9306c08f43.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lessons of History: The Rise and Fall of Technology in Chinese History at Green Library, 5th floor, Bender Room</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;and the&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://sccei.fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stanford Center on China&amp;#39;s Economy and Institutions&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;are pleased to present the&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;2023 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;featuring&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Professor Yasheng Huang &lt;/b&gt;who will be speaking on&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Lessons of History: The Rise and Fall of Technology in Chinese History. &lt;/i&gt;This will be a hybrid event, with a &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_ixqW297LTj2lThgZEXz18Q#/registration"&gt;Zoom Webinar&lt;/a&gt; available for those unable to attend in-person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China was once the most technologically advanced civilization in the world.&amp;nbsp;Ancient Chinese achievements in technology are simply staggering. China led Europe in metallurgy, ship construction, navigation techniques, and many other fields, often by several centuries. The Chinese also invented gunpowder, paper, the water clock, the moveable printing press, and other consequential technologies way ahead of the West. For example, the Chinese invented the seismograph 1,700 years before the French.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But China&amp;rsquo;s technological development stalled, stagnated, and eventually collapsed and its early technological leadership did not set the country on a modernization path. This lecture examines the factors behind the rise and the fall of Chinese historical technology and draws lessons for today&amp;rsquo;s China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Professor &lt;a href="https://mitsloan.mit.edu/faculty/directory/yasheng-huang"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Yasheng Huang&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the International Program Professor in Chinese Economy and Business and a professor of global economics and management at the MIT Sloan School of Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huang founded and runs China Lab and India Lab, which aim to help entrepreneurs in these countries improve their management skills. He is an expert source on international business, political economy, and international management. In collaboration with other scholars, Dr. Huang is conducting research on human capital formation in China and India, entrepreneurship, and ethnic and labor-intensive foreign direct investment (FDI). Prior to MIT Sloan, he held faculty positions at the University of Michigan and at Harvard Business School. Huang also served as a consultant to the World Bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family of&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;donated his personal archive to the Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world&amp;#39;s largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia.&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://hsiehlecture.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lessons_of_history_the_rise_and_fall_of_technology_in_chinese_history_7887</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44039748929265/huge/738a220a659bb477427c7332e1e6c18f97105076.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="411" width="565" isDefault="true" fileSize="294163"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reception for Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley Exhibition at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us in the&amp;nbsp;Green Library Rotunda&amp;nbsp;from&amp;nbsp;4:30 - 6:30 PM&amp;nbsp;on&amp;nbsp;Thursday, October 5th,&amp;nbsp;for a reception to celebrate Professor Paula Findlen&amp;#39;s&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Embodied Knowledge&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. The exhibition showcases&amp;nbsp;Stanford&amp;rsquo;s considerable holdings for this subject, including the university&amp;#39;s role in this history, and displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Embodied Knowledge&lt;/i&gt; was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge_women_and_science_before_silicon_valley_reception</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43979943702075/huge/c60d54cf08d92f73afab3f86b45d2e071b7e11a4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="236022"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VOICES TO BE HEARD, STORIES TO BE TOLD: Exploring the Dijkstra Black Music Collection at Stanford’s Archive of Recorded Sound</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tamar Barzel&lt;/b&gt;, head of Stanford&amp;rsquo;s &lt;i&gt;Music Library and Archive of Recorded Sound&lt;/i&gt;, will present an illustrated webinar on a recently acquired, transformative collection of historic vinyl records of African-American and Afro-diasporic music, especially jazz and reggae. The webinar will focus on the origins of the Dijkstra Collection, explore its gems, and consider the role sound archives play in preserving diverse sonic legacies for future generations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tamar Barzel (PhD in Ethnomusicology, University of Michigan, 2004) came to Stanford in 2021 from New York University Libraries. She has taught at NYU, Harvard, and Wellesley College.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;This event is sponsored by&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://music.stanford.edu/friends-of-music"&gt;Friends of Music at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Oct 2023 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/voices_to_be_heard_stories_to_be_told_exploring_the_dijkstra_black_music_collection_at_stanfords_archive_of_recorded_sound</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43200823850481/huge/46c4f7d1845d1055899b5c6ad0e8328726fafcee.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="312" width="468" isDefault="true" fileSize="258253"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bob Stein on The Tapestry Project at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Bob Stein as he leads a discussion on The Tapestry Project.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s call it . . . the print era is officially over. We now live in a networked digital world. As a result everything is breaking and everything is being born anew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New forms of expression are emerging. We may not know the specifics, but two aspects are coming into focus &amp;mdash; a) expository text is being dislodged as the principal medium of intellectual discourse and b) the creation and consumption of media are increasingly social activities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From this perspective, people need tools that foster collaboration &amp;mdash; finally realizing the vision of the internet&amp;rsquo;s founders who understood that the problems facing humanity are too complex for individuals to solve on their own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Tapestry Project answers this challenge with a paradigm-breaking new tool that anyone can use to construct a non-linear landscape of ideas and the connections between them &amp;mdash; a new form of writing which allows readers to interact directly with the author&amp;rsquo;s ideas and the sources they are based on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bob Stein was the founder of The Criterion Collection, The Voyager Company and The Institute for the Future of the Book. Currently, he heads up The Tapestry Project at the Internet Archive. In 2018 Bob donated his extensive analog and digital archives to Stanford.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bob_stein_on_the_tapestry_project</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42669238566991/huge/a8d42572f76f6496f6d7d59ac24e1d5e8f575f5b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="881" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="1139204"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Abby Smith Rumsey: Memory, Edited at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a book talk with Abby Smith Rumsey who will discuss her recent publication, &lt;a href="https://mitpress.mit.edu/9780262048477/memory-edited/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Memory, Edited: Taking Liberties with History&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The book is an exploration of historical memory and networks of meaning in the context of today&amp;#39;s crises of extremism and polarization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As authoritarianism continues to rise around the world, the stories we tell ourselves about what has happened and what is happening become ever more relevant. In &lt;i&gt;Memory, Edited&lt;/i&gt;, Abby Smith Rumsey examines collective memory, how it binds us, and how it can be used by bad actors to manipulate us. Bringing forward the voices of a rich cast of Eastern European artists from the past two hundred years&amp;mdash;from Fyodor Dostoevsky to Gerhard Richter&amp;mdash;Rumsey shows how their work and lives illustrate the devastation wrought by regimes dependent on entrenched lies to survive. This hijacking of the narrative polarizes communities even as it commandeers our future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through an interdisciplinary lens that includes the best thinking from history, the arts, cognitive science, psychology, and political philosophy, Rumsey lays bare our narratives, showing how they are constructed and how they have changed over time. Ever-aware of resisting the false promise of utopia, Rumsey argues that only by confronting the past and reckoning with the crimes that were committed can we ever hope to heal and gain self-knowledge. &lt;i&gt;Memory, Edited&lt;/i&gt; is an indispensable text for anyone who cares about democracy, equality, and freedom in our current age of crisis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://rumseywrites.com/" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abby Smith Rumsey&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is an intellectual and cultural historian. She chairs the board of the Center for Advanced Study in the Behavioral Sciences at Stanford University and is the author of &lt;i&gt;When We Are No More: How Digital Memory Is Shaping Our Future&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/memory_edited</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44033532455425/huge/c7989b913454674fda703c02e63b95a68e3a059f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1719" width="2357" isDefault="true" fileSize="1515469"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for October&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;. Theme and featured games will be announced closer to the event date!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Oct 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_5542</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43466372701087/huge/05ad723c5889ed93acdc1a50059c0a9306c08f43.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b style="font-size:13.125px; font-style:normal; text-align:start"&gt;The conference, hosted by the David Rumsey Map Center and Barry Lawrence Ruderman Antique Maps, will focus on maps &amp;amp; data visualization.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Maps can communicate all kinds of information. While geographic features and toponyms are frequently highlighted, arraying information in a spatial layout has proven useful for centuries. Maps and data visualization go hand-in-hand, but in ways that are complex and deserve critical examination; this is why they are the focus of the fourth biennial Ruderman Conference on Cartography, held October 18-20, 2023 at the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford University. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Speakers from a variety of disciplinary backgrounds and specializations will share their expertise about historical, design, and digital applications of data visualization. Attendees will examine examples of maps that share information in a variety of ways and discuss the potential and limitations of the medium in the past, present, and for the future. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none"&gt;Keynote speakers include Michael Friendly (York University, Canada), who will discuss the history of data visualization, and Karen Lewis (the Ohio State University), who will share the mapping methodology and design behind the recovery of Underground Railway routes and stories.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Oct 2023 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/barry_lawrence_ruderman_conference_on_cartography</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43890725953540/huge/4219ec240fa19856c53741ec4c2b1bdc27215702.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1754" width="2357" isDefault="true" fileSize="1839021"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Raja Adal  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Raja Adal on October 19 in Hohbach Hall.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rethinking the Role of the Printing Press and Typewriter Outside of the World of Latin Characters: A Large-Scale Analysis of Writing and Reproduction Technologies in the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine Archive, 1889-1941&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the last few decades, the history of the book, of bureaucratic cultures, and of information societies has introduced us to the centrality of printing presses and typewriters in European and North American offices. This presentation explores the material history of writing outside of the world of Latin characters through the indexing of one of the largest business archives in modern Japan, the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine archive. Over several years, this indexing project ordered the 38,096 pages in this archive into 20,713 individual documents, categorized according to criteria that reveal the practice of document production, circulation, storage, and consumption in the offices of a large Japanese firm over the course of a half century from 1889 to 1941. Although the printing press and typewriter have a role in the offices of the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine, when we look not at discourses but at practices, it turns out that in a society in which most texts are composed of thousands of logographic and phonographic symbols, writing and reproduction technologies other than the printing press and typewriter are much more prominent. Through the large-scale analysis of the Mitsui Mi&amp;rsquo;ike Mine archive, this presentation begins to chart a theory of the practice of writing and reproduction, from the brush to Unicode, in the context of global scripts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_raja_adal</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44031837526865/huge/74fc815b8e2c310c2c82bb8eff41501358945268.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1440" width="2560" isDefault="true" fileSize="1993381"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rainbow Coalition Alumni Panel at Green Library, East Wing, 1st floor Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join Stanford Libraries as we host what is sure to be an insightful discussion. Professor David Palumbo-Liu will moderate a panel of former activist alumni who were a part of the original Rainbow Coalition at Stanford. &amp;nbsp;Listen to their experience and learn how their activism changed Stanford as we know it today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScBuILP5ZaIW5xbnImlrlvbHrDfsM7-PPy6-BktVK0XwRPu5Q/viewform" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;if you would like to attend the event &lt;b&gt;in person&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_a5d5LeyPSKCPhZdA4SNZrw" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;if you would like to attend the event &lt;b&gt;online&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is being held in conjunction with Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; 3rd annual &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/jedi2023" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; on October 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and find out how you can get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following the fair in the same location from 3:30 to 5:30 pm, celebrate with us as we listen to selections from the recently acquired &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/stanford-libraries-receives-major-black-music-collection-supporting-new-department-and" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dijkstra Black Music Collection&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a vast collection of Black music on vinyl spanning a wide range of genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rainbow_coalition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44032895838931/huge/fc52b7b997689ee0d1c901c1ac1afb1768bc9700.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1276" width="2294" isDefault="true" fileSize="1434109"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair at Centennial Green</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting its 3rd annual &lt;b&gt;Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See social justice collections from the library, learn about DEI initiatives happening around campus, and find out how you can get involved in making the university and your community more just and equitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Directly following the fair in the same location from 3:30 to 5:30 pm, celebrate with us as we listen to selections from the recently acquired &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/stanford-libraries-receives-major-black-music-collection-supporting-new-department-and" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Dijkstra Black Music Collection&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a vast collection of Black music on vinyl spanning a wide range of genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The day before, on &lt;b&gt;October 24 &lt;/b&gt;from 3:00 to 4:00 pm, join us for the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rainbow_coalition" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rainbow Coalition Alumni Panel&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;Professor David Palumbo-Liu will moderate a panel of former activist alumni who were a part of the original Rainbow Coalition at Stanford. Listen to their experience and learn how their activism changed Stanford as we know it today. Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/DUrvKkPURY3eEh5a9" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;register&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; if you would like to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Check back for updates.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jedi2023</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427136</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.168622</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40621750570646/huge/4fac2a857cffbbe07b7fa5dd9c09ed4ffc7c1db1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="181353"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Henry Lowood, Replayed at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archies in welcoming Henry Lowood, the Harold C. Hohbach Curator for History of Science &amp;amp; Technology Collections, as he discusses his most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Replayed&lt;/i&gt;, on November 14, 2023.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the early 2000s, Henry Lowood has had a key role in initiatives devoted to the preservation and documentation of virtual worlds, digital games, and interactive simulations, establishing himself as a major scholar of game studies. Replayed offers Lowood&amp;rsquo;s far-flung and significant publications on these subjects in a single volume.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_henry_lowood_replayed</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44031985006928/huge/119a5a308f4be1b23e01bd2782fd90f3eb11c802.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="219" width="290" isDefault="true" fileSize="120474"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
