<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every archival collection that Stanford Libraries acquires must be processed before it can be made available for research. The expertise, thought, and care that goes into processing archival collections often occurs behind-the-scenes. Using the John Perry Barlow papers as a throughline, this exhibit explores the art of processing archival collections. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/paper_trails_the_art_of_processing_archival_collections</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40861265484890/huge/796758a62e11f9aaae17dc593730c2e172be4fbe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="425" width="425" isDefault="true" fileSize="109634"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoze Xie: Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie's new exhibition, &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt;, opening on September 15, 2022, in the main second-floor exhibit space at the Stanford East Asia Library, reminds us that, if "knowledge is power," as the quotation goes, then books can become battlegrounds. For over ten years, Xie has been engaged in an ongoing project titled &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Memories&lt;/em&gt; that focuses on the history of banned books in China. &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; features new works from this project. In addition to books from the artist's own collection, the exhibition will also feature several of Xie's sculptures. Working with photographs of books in public and private collections, Xie has created life-size, hand-sculpted and hand-painted porcelain reproductions of banned books both ancient and modern, some of which will be displayed publicly for the first time in this exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; will be on view from September 15, 2022, through the end of Fall Quarter. An opening reception will be held on October 12, 2022, in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie, the Paul L. &amp; Phyllis Wattis Professor of Art at Stanford University, is an internationally recognized artist who has exhibited extensively in the US and abroad. His work is in the permanent collection of such institutions as the Denver Art Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts Houston, San Jose Museum of Art, the Scottsdale Museum of Contemporary Art, and Oakland Museum of California. Xie received the Asia Game Changer West Award from the Asia Society (2022), the Painter and Sculptor's Grant from the Joan Mitchell Foundation (2013), the Pollock-Krasner Foundation Grant (2003) and artist awards from Phoenix Art Museum (1999) and Dallas Museum of Art (1996).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/xiaoze_xie_flammable_ideas_fragile_objects</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41074045488313/huge/df720f80197b036bed4df7bb0508525112431604.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="195807"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Wrangling at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python (or similar knowledge). (If you need a refresher, check out A Byte of Python (&lt;a href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://python.swaroopch.com/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_wrangling_8825</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250516570/huge/4d275d9c657eed9acee248c0b43a6ffecfc8dbca.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Book at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 6, 2022, through February 5, 2023 in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Elaine Treharne and Benjamin Albritton, produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_handmade_book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127511947685/huge/fa816f484827df107b7a256d92f54535a019c421.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="581" width="581" isDefault="true" fileSize="232881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The business data resources most popular with science researchers [Gear-Up]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Todd Hines and Rashelle Pragar, GSB Library business librarians, will give summary overviews of several of the business data resources most heavily used by science researchers, including how to access Wall Street analyst reports and recommended sources for researching science-related industries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructors: Todd Hines and Rashelle Nagar&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a virtual presentation. You will receive a Zoom link after registration. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_business_data_resources_most_popular_with_science_researchers_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41047357212047/huge/2567c54e7f4f2448025ecad164352ec0b95c24ea.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Messy Time Series Data [Gear-Up] at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop introduces you to working with messy time series data. We will teach you about common pitfalls for data sourcing and continuity through use of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) as a rough measure of global societal well-being. The first hour will introduce GDP to discuss these issues when different reporting agencies, incentives, and approaches are considered. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second hour will dive into code that compares results of different models based on endogenous and exogenous data filling methods, along with useful guidance on tools for vectorized approaches to your data. Basic Python proficiency is assumed if you want to run the examples, but all are welcome to attend and learn about data robustness issues and how the concepts might be useful to apply to your own data and research. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to learn basic Python, visit us at &lt;a href="https://ssds.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://ssds.stanford.edu &lt;/a&gt;to register for the upcoming Text Analysis and Machine Learning (TAML) Bootcamp (September 19, 21, and 23) or Introduction to Python workshop (October 5). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructors: &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/research/software-and-services-data-science/people" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Anthony Weng&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/muzzall" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Evan Muzzall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a hybrid workshop. Upon registering you can select to attend in-person at the Li &amp; Ma Science Library in the SAPP Center or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/understanding_messy_time_series_data_gear-up</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40994207358413/huge/174c1eb8cee1cfcdfb1b422fa9b75147921740d5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Opening reception for Xiaoze Xie: Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us in room 224 of the East Asia Library from 4:00 - 6:00 PM on Wednesday, October 12, for a reception to commemorate the opening of our new exhibition, &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt;, curated and featuring work by Xiaoze Xie, the Paul L. &amp; Phyllis Wattis Professor of Art at Stanford University. Prof. Xie will open the reception with a brief introduction to the exhibition. Light refreshments will be served.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/opening_reception_for_xiaoze_xie_flammable_ideas_fragile_objects</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41233221246575/huge/cc550c6542f6197bcb921dcbb0feb4a5f21e8479.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="195807"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gear-Up for Science Data Symposium  [Gear-Up] at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real data is not always perfect. Sometimes, it is messy. Sometimes, it is not nice to work with. The Fall 2022 Gear-Up for Science Data Symposium will conclude a series of workshops, talks and demos (Oct. 10-12) exploring the techniques used by experts to find, prepare, manage and analyze non-idealized data for research and analytics. This in person event will provide a forum to present and discuss the obstacles scientists face when collecting and analyzing data, as well as showcasing the variety of library services available for researchers to help in the acquisition and analysis of research data.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:00p Introduction&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:05p Student and Postdoc Lightning Talks&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:30p Keynote Speakers&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;3:45p Panel Discussion&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;4:05p Social Hour &amp; Library Resource Fair  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;At Koret Park (courtyard adjacent to Green Library East Wing Exit &amp; Coupa Cafe)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynote Speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/elliott-white-jr-" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Elliott White Jr.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Sauntering Through Swamps to Scanning Satellite Scenes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Coastal forested wetlands are critical components of the coastal ecosystem mosaic; however, climate change threatens their existence. Remote sensing offers a powerful tool to examine this ecosystem at a broad scale, but there are challenges to using these data.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/maria-monzani" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Maria Elena Monzani&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Data-Intensive searches for Dark Matter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The nature and origin of dark matter are among the most compelling mysteries of contemporary science. There is strong evidence for dark matter from its role in shaping the galaxies and galaxy clusters that we observe in the universe. Still, for over three decades, physicists have been trying to detect the dark matter particles themselves with little success. Given the extremely elusive nature of the hypothetical dark matter particle, the experiments trying to discover it have collected increasingly massive datasets, which pose tremendous "needle in a haystack" challenges. In my talk, I will describe two of the experiments currently looking to detect dark matter, together with their associated datasets, and some of the data handling tools employed for their analysis.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/dominique-bergmann" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Dominique Bergmann&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Following biology (and data) across spatial scales in a changing world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract: &lt;/strong&gt;When considering how plants adapt their development to prevailing climates, data vary in type and completeness. One on end of the scale, detailed microscopy-based imaging may capture how cells divide in a single growing leaf, or the genes expressed in each in of those cells in the leaf. On the other end, characterizing the genetic variation of in genomes of plant populations growing across the world, or preserved in the last 300 years in herbaria involves a massive collaborative effort to obtain, compare and standardize samples. In my talk, I will highlight how we evaluate data from diverse sources, and some challenges we've encountered when data originate from disciplines with different norms and expectations. I will also answer questions about the changing publishing landscape from the perspective of an author and of an editorial board member for general audience and specialty journals.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/gear-up_for_science_data_symposium_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41047357469095/huge/9d95e34a77ed256b03d1046eb415f94ebbd1c69f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Introduction To Unix/Git</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Time and Date:&lt;br /&gt;
Friday, October 14, 2022 / 13:00 - 16:00 (Pacific Daylight Time)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Location:&lt;br /&gt;
Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Admission:&lt;br /&gt;
Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Registration:&lt;br /&gt;
Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (&lt;span&gt;YOU MAY NEED TO SIGN OUT OF YOUR PERSONAL ACCOUNT FIRST IN ORDER TO DO THIS&lt;/span&gt;), sign up here: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/PA889AuGyXJtjPKy9"&gt;https://forms.gle/PA889AuGyXJtjPKy9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Audience:&lt;br /&gt;
Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Sponsor:&lt;br /&gt;
Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Contact/Instructor: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zac Painter, &lt;a href="mailto:zwp@stanford.edu"&gt;zwp@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; , Librarian (Engineering)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Other Instructors:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kalani Ratnasiri, PhD Candidate (Immunology)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Viraj Manwadkar, PhD Candidate (Physics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Course Description:&lt;br /&gt;
This is an introduction for to the most basic, text-based ways to do things with a computer: the Unix command line. We will also cover the basics of Git with a secondary look at GitHub, the near-universal version-control system that is one of basic toolkits of digital scholarship and collaboration. This workshop is a safe space for people of all experience levels, with no question too basic to ask!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries_stanford_introduction_to_unixgit</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41244060878177/huge/fd4814e9af257e7507a548e07dc31e85bd4094b6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="320" width="320" isDefault="true" fileSize="17930"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOWLoween 2022: Celebrating Wolf Awareness Week at Stanford Libraries on Oct. 17-22 at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2021/10/howloween-2021-celebrating-wolf-awareness-week-stanford#:~:text=We%20love%20Halloween%20at%20Stanford,October%2018%2D22%2C%202021." rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;2021 celebration of HOWLoween: Wolf Awareness Week&lt;/a&gt; was such a success that we&amp;#39;re holding it again this year! Join us at Green Library for National Wolf Awareness Week on October 16-22, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;SCHEDULE OF EVENTS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Tabletop Tuesday: Our Werewolves, Ourselves&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This session of Tabletop Tuesday will begin with an exploration of werewolves and their depictions in popular media. What does the long historical tradition of werewolf mythology and literature reveal about humans and our fascination with wolves? After this discussion, we will play the game Werewolf to discover who among us has the drive to survive using our all-too-human skills of deception and treachery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Library, SVA Seminar Room in Hohbach Hall&lt;br /&gt;
2-4:00PM on Tuesday, Oct. 18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Howling Lesson&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/stephanie-hunt" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Stephanie Hunt&lt;/a&gt; (Theater and Performance Studies) will teach us how to properly and safely howl using correct vocal techniques while thinking about the biological adaptations that make wolves such good howlers. The lesson will be followed by a &amp;quot;Group Howl.&amp;quot; Although wolves are pack animals, physical distancing will be observed, esp. for the loudest howls.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Koret Park, outside Green Library&lt;br /&gt;
5:00PM on Tuesday, Oct. 18&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Skull School&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Maria Viteri (Biology postdoc) will display animal skulls incl. the gray wolf and discuss comparative vertebrate anatomy and classification.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Library, SVA Seminar Room in Hohbach Hall&lt;br /&gt;
2-3:00PM on Wednesday, Oct. 19&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&amp;quot;The Return of the Wolf&amp;quot;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amaroq-weiss-64806932" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Amaroq Weiss&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Wolf Advocate with the Center for Biological Diversity, will discuss the return of wolves to California and other limited parts of the lower 48 United States. Her talk will cover legal and policy issues around wolf recovery, wolf biology/behavior/ecology, and challenges wolves continue to face which require ongoing public involvement to protect and recover this magnificent representative of the wild.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;**This talk is free but &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://act.biologicaldiversity.org/oosEBqfO8E6tAJllAH6xeA2?sourceid=1008034&amp;amp;utm_source=action&amp;amp;utm_medium=email&amp;amp;contactdata=&amp;amp;emci=f09d165c-6a46-ed11-b495-002248258d38&amp;amp;emdi=ea000000-0000-0000-0000-000000000001&amp;amp;ceid="&gt;pre-registration is required&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Green Library, SVA Symposium/Presentation Room 122 in Hohbach Hall&lt;br /&gt;
7-8:00PM on Thursday, Oct. 20&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Wolf&lt;/i&gt; (1994), a Mike Nichols film&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/kensky" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Eitan Kensky&lt;/a&gt; will introduce this 1994 &amp;quot;romantic horror office comedy&amp;quot; starring Jack Nicholson, Michelle Pfeiffer, James Spader, Christopher Plummer, etc., in which mild-mannered editor Jack Nicholson is bitten by a wolf and then discovers how well-suited his new werewolf abilities are for the cut-throat world of office politics.&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
Green Library, IC Classroom&lt;br /&gt;
1:00PM on Friday, Oct. 21&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;----------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;i&gt;Image credit Gary Kramer. Public domain image from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Front_view_of_a_resting_Canis_lupus_ssp.jpg&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/howloween_2022_celebrating_wolf_awareness_week_at_stanford_libraries_on_oct_17-22</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41197888250497/huge/2fcebaaefed65aa9b6ea2df535e0dbff2c7addca.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="300" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="72838"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Visualization at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will review three base plots in R (histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot) before introducing you to the ggplot2 package. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_visualization_4198</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250671203/huge/8466ae85e8a11a7e9b960861425e96bcc3352b3c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Our Werewolves, Ourselves at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;As part of &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/howloween_2022_celebrating_wolf_awareness_week_at_stanford_libraries_on_oct_17-22"&gt;Wolf Awareness Week&lt;/a&gt;, this session of &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;will begin with an exploration of werewolves and their depictions in popular media. What does the long historical tradition of werewolf mythology and literature reveal about humans and our relationship with wolves? After this discussion, we will play the game &lt;i&gt;Werewolf&lt;/i&gt; to discover who among us has the drive to survive using our all-too-human skills of deception and treachery.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;rsquo;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;rsquo;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;rsquo;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives. Note: due to winter closure, there will &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;not&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; be a December event in 2022.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/October18_Tabletop</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41235324055467/huge/2e96b4977058431964899d32f80012bc131b944f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2500" width="2500" isDefault="true" fileSize="373672"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Visualization at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will introduce you to three basic visualizations using the Python matplotlib and seaborn libraries: histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" rel="noopener"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_visualization_2716</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250833004/huge/7f2578af5e30ac5ea3aceed9f6cbe8ae89e73601.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Madness by Denise Gigante at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Book Launch! Celebrating the publication of:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300248487/book-madness/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Book Madness: A Story of Book Collectors in America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
(Yale University Press, 2022)&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;by Denise Gigante&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sadie Dernham Patek Professor of Humanities&lt;br /&gt;
Department of English,&amp;nbsp;Stanford University&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Featured speakers:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Gavin Jones, Frederick P. Rehmus Family Professor of Humanities&lt;br /&gt;
Peter Stansky, Frances and Charles Field Professor of History, Emeritus&amp;nbsp;&lt;br /&gt;
John Windle, Antiquarian Bookseller, San Francisco&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Book signing to follow. Learn more about &lt;i&gt;Book Madness&lt;/i&gt; by viewing &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1J18vKTXFNyrA5iYaLr5jFLDpkCdN2aRf/view?usp=sharing" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
The event will also be livestreamed. Please&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/6SmcvneAWJnCfpEPA" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; for the event and indicate if you will be attending in person or virtually.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book_madness_by_denise_gigante</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127520396854/huge/dc241f1b975930653e5b7d88abae4c143550cdd7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="508" width="508" isDefault="true" fileSize="145548"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Introduction To Python</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Time and Date:&lt;br /&gt;
Thursday, October 20, 2022 / 13:00 - 16:00 (Pacific Daylight Time)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Location:&lt;br /&gt;
Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Admission:&lt;br /&gt;
Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Registration:&lt;br /&gt;
Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (YOU MAY NEED TO SIGN OUT OF YOUR PERSONAL ACCOUNT FIRST IN ORDER TO DO THIS), sign up here: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/hc4pcr43m4c41Ee17"&gt;https://forms.gle/hc4pcr43m4c41Ee17&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Audience:&lt;br /&gt;
Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Sponsor:&lt;br /&gt;
Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Contact:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Zac Painter, &lt;a href="mailto:zwp@stanford.edu"&gt;zwp@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; , Librarian (Engineering)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Lead Instructors:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Kalani Ratnasiri, PhD Candidate (Immunology)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Viraj Manwadkar, PhD Candidate (Physics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Course Description:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Python has rapidly become the programming language of choice for many people across the world, thanks to its flexibility and ease of use. In this hands-on workshop, attendees will learn some of the basics behind how to program in Python, and how they can leverage the language for different tasks. No prior experience is required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries_stanford_introduction_to_python</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41244095059377/huge/2d470ad242ef80255c28297e0e0b2b5d3ee99271.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="320" width="320" isDefault="true" fileSize="17930"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Text Analysis at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to working with text data using the spaCy and textacy Python libraries. You will learn to effectively streamline text preprocessing, understand word tokenization, sentence segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, and named entity recognition using a single document (a short excerpt from H.G. Wells's A Short History of the World) and across a corpus of legal documents. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_text_analysis</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250984565/huge/82224d6b0b7e89960e809345e84f0eabb5679551.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Text Analysis at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in analyzing collections of novels or journal articles? Do you want to understand patterns across collections of tweets or other social media data? In this workshop, we'll learn how to import, clean, and analyze collections of text with R using several standard text mining libraries. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_text_analysis</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251165822/huge/372a5a9c3001e8a2ff66d0837b6be7a5386ecf09.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: Introduction To R</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Time and Date:&lt;br /&gt;
Tuesday, October 25, 2022 / 12:00 - 15:00 (Pacific Daylight Time)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Location:&lt;br /&gt;
Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Admission:&lt;br /&gt;
Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Registration:&lt;br /&gt;
Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (&lt;span&gt;YOU MAY NEED TO SIGN OUT OF YOUR PERSONAL ACCOUNT FIRST IN ORDER TO DO THIS&lt;/span&gt;), sign up here: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/huLymfwLz1gjnx2P6"&gt;https://forms.gle/huLymfwLz1gjnx2P6&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Audience:&lt;br /&gt;
Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Sponsor:&lt;br /&gt;
Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Contact:&lt;br /&gt;
Zac Painter, &lt;a href="mailto:zwp@stanford.edu"&gt;zwp@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; , Librarian (Engineering)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lead Instructors: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dr. Alma Parada, Librarian (Earth Sciences &amp;amp; Life Sciences)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dr. Mika Braginsky, Postdoctoral Scholar (Pediatrics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;Course Description:&lt;br /&gt;
This workshop is a gentle introduction to the R programming language for those who have never (or barely) programmed in R, and especially to those who are new to programming in general. If you are unfamiliar with working with variables, vectors, and dataframes, then you are a good fit for this class! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned some of what R can do, explored the ecosystem of R and RStudio, modified/extracted data, and discovered resources to continue your learning even after this session. Please have R and RStudio Desktop installed on your device prior to the course.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries_stanford_introduction_to_r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41244119444868/huge/9713906edf5f67bfc7cd047919b026415f937d93.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="320" width="320" isDefault="true" fileSize="17930"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Machine Learning at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for classifying text and images using the scikit-learn, lime, and tensorflow Python libraries. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_machine_learning</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251322503/huge/4e467a322bbe91a3a909617185decb2273c1ed77.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Obi Mbu (The Primordial House) at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Obi Mbu (The Primordial House)&lt;/em&gt; (2021) is a 30-minute experimental film that captures the movement of dancers illuminated with fluorescent paint and ultraviolet light as they enact an Igbo-Nigerian myth of creation. The story follows Eke-Nnechukwu and Chukwu (the feminine and masculine polarities of the cosmos) as they move from existing in perfect unity in and as the Blackness of space to a stage of conflict and separation that allows our world to come into existence. After successful screenings in New York City, Los Angeles, Pittsburgh, Martha's Vineyard, and more, &lt;em&gt;Obi Mbu&lt;/em&gt; makes its Bay Area debut at Stanford. The creative team includes Co-Directors Mikael Owunna and Marques Redd who will engage the audience in an in-person Q&amp;A session following the screening.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Watch the film trailer: &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/587000703" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-linkindex="0" data-safelink="true" data-cke-saved-href="https://vimeo.com/587000703" rel="noopener"&gt;https://vimeo.com/587000703&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_obi_mbu_the_primordial_house</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41242052249263/huge/376c9fe7af59b6ccee09e9e9073972cd35af851d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="388" width="388" isDefault="true" fileSize="164121"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carpentries @ Stanford: R Visualization Methods</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Time and Date:&lt;br /&gt;
Friday, October 28, 2022 / 12:00 - 15:00 (Pacific Daylight Time)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Location:&lt;br /&gt;
Virtual via Zoom (will be emailed to participants separately)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Admission:&lt;br /&gt;
Free. Open to Current Stanford Affiliates only. Registration is required, and offered on a first-come first-serve basis. Space is limited, with a waitlist when all slots are full.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Registration:&lt;br /&gt;
Logging into Google using your Stanford email address and sign-on credentials (YOU MAY NEED TO SIGN OUT OF YOUR PERSONAL ACCOUNT FIRST IN ORDER TO DO THIS), sign up here: &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/uxW53vp6TGmdwxvAA"&gt;https://forms.gle/uxW53vp6TGmdwxvAA&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Audience:&lt;br /&gt;
Faculty / Staff / Students / Postdocs&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Sponsor:&lt;br /&gt;
Stanford University Libraries - Carpentries Program&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Event Contact:&lt;br /&gt;
Zac Painter, &lt;a href="mailto:zwp@stanford.edu"&gt;zwp@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt; , Librarian (Engineering)&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
Lead Instructors: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dr. Alma Parada, Librarian (Earth Sciences &amp;amp; Life Sciences)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dr. Mika Braginsky, Postdoctoral Scholar (Pediatrics)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Course Description:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;span&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to working with the ggplot2 visualization library in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate 1D and 2D plots, and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2022 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carpentries_stanford_r_visualization_methods</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41244136408250/huge/88bf559dad3e1a6eb011a4f2f94d75c07776eb68.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="320" width="320" isDefault="true" fileSize="17930"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Machine Learning at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a beginner-friendly introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts, quantitative data preprocessing for machine learning, and the SuperLearner R package.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_machine_learning</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251469968/huge/51f6a2e7e1fcbaa0a3d6d5ed9d0d7aa5582da0ac.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Blob vs. The Witch at Jen-Hsun Huang Building (School of Engineering)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Halloween is on a Monday, the worst possible day, but have no fear. (Wait. Scratch that. It's Halloween, so...) Have fear. We have you covered with this double feature. Join us for refreshments and two frightfully, fantastic films. Wear a costume, and you may also win a raffle prize&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Blob (1958) at 6 pm&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Witch (2015) at 8 pm&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;You must have an active Stanford ID to join. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/7G4fwdATXe7Wr4fK7" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;RSVP today&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 18:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_blob_vs_the_witch</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427784</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.174323</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41250962587714/huge/7a96414da74fcd69dc5c83c7842ecfdcf97b948d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="67571"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: John Markoff at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming author John Markoff as he discuss his latest book, &lt;em&gt;Whole Earth: The Many Lives of Stewart Brand.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stewart Brand has long been famous if you know who he is, but for many people outside the counterculture, early computing, or the environmental movement, he is perhaps best known for his famous mantra "Stay Hungry. Stay Foolish." Steve Jobs's endorsement of these words as his code to live by is fitting; Brand has played many roles, but one of the most important is as a model for how to live.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;The contradictions are striking: A blond-haired WASP with a modest family inheritance, Brand went to Exeter and Stanford and was an army veteran, but in California in the 1960s he became an artist and a photographer in the thick of the LSD revolution. While tripping on acid on the roof of his building, he envisioned how valuable it would be for humans to see a photograph of the planet they shared from space, an image that in the end landed on the cover of his &lt;em&gt;Whole Earth Catalog&lt;/em&gt;, the defining publication of the counterculture. He married a Native American woman and was committed to protecting indigenous culture, which connected to a broader environmentalist mission that has been a through line of his life. At the same time, he has outraged purists because of his pragmatic embrace of useful technologies, including nuclear power, in the fight against climate change. The famous tagline promise of his catalog was "Access to Tools"; with rare exceptions he rejected politics for a focus on direct power. It was no wonder, then, that he was early to the promise of the computer revolution and helped define it for the wider world.&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Brand's life can be hard to fit onto one screen. John Markoff, also a great chronicler of tech culture, has done something extraordinary in unfolding the rich, twisting story of Brand's life against its proper landscape. As Markoff makes marvelously clear, the streams of individualism, respect for science, environmentalism, and Eastern and indigenous thought that flow through Brand's entire life form a powerful gestalt, a California state of mind that has a hegemonic power to this day. His way of thinking embraces a true planetary consciousness that may be the best hope we humans collectively have.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.penguinrandomhouse.com/books/554161/whole-earth-by-john-markoff/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whole Earth: The Many Lives of Stewart Brand &lt;/em&gt;is now available for purchase&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon_valley_talks_john_markoff</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41242052433597/huge/a0e8ad50276eb6293a006c4acba1838c2bada590.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="435" width="435" isDefault="true" fileSize="121738"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, October 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_5863</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136264145214/huge/5ee944b777d1875b9aef6589a53800ffffa7793d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Bash and GitHub at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first half of this workshop you will learn how to use the Bash programming language to interface with your computer's operating system and perform basic actions to navigate your file system and create and edit files and directories. In the second half you will apply these principles to use the collaborative version tracking platform GitHub to store your coding projects.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with computers&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop - Mac users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have the Xcode developer toolset installed. Open a Terminal and type&lt;br /&gt;xcode-select --install&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;When asked if you want to install the command line developer tools, click "yes/install"&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop - Windows users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Install git/gitbash by clicking here: &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/downloads" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://git-scm.com/downloads" rel="noopener"&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download the file and double-click it to run the installer&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt; coming soon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_bash_and_github</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251619481/huge/23472b806847b1b93e55fe970a9c1640ab9a0de9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR GitHub Pages at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this workshop you will build on the skills you learn in CIDR Intro to Bash and GitHub to create free static webpages for your CV, projects, and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Bash and GitHub (or equivalent knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_github_pages</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251771042/huge/d6401eae129ace21d99e2c11ead4f4364066f364.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Opening of Hohbach Hall at Green Library, East Wing, 1st floor</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Join us for the Grand Opening of Hohbach Hall!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Experience Silicon Valley like never before during a self-paced Open House celebrating the opening of Hohbach Hall, the home of the Silicon Valley Archives in Green Library. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During the open house you will have the opportunity to engage with:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I Never Knew I Could Study That"&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Join Professor of History Thomas Mullaney as he discusses how archival research is key to inclusion, engagement and belonging in the classroom. Using items from the Libraries' collection that illustrate the global history of computing, he will demonstrate how he continues to upstream, scale-up, and diversify the hands-on research experience within the Humanities and Social Sciences. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Storytelling&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Meet digital storyteller and documentary film-maker Kathy Cotton who produced &lt;em&gt;A Place at the Table: The Story of African American Pioneers of Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;. Kathy is also the host of the Cottontails podcast that presents interviews with African Americans who have contributed to the on-going story of their communities' successes and the contributions that are made every day to African American history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collection Processing&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Enjoy a sneak peek into the papers of John Perry Barlow, Electronic Frontier Foundation founder and Grateful Dead lyricist in the exhibition &lt;em&gt;Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections&lt;/em&gt;. This exhibit not only presents selections from his papers, but carefully explores the work that occurs behind-the-scenes in the library to organize, preserve and make archival collections accessible for research and teaching.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/7ihUzrTfxtLoMN9M6" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please register if you would like to attend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Hohbach Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The renovated first floor of Green Library's East Wing reopened Monday, January 3, 2022, as the newly named Hohbach Hall. The makeover was made possible by the &lt;strong&gt;Harold and Marilyn Hohbach Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; and has created a modern and inspiring space for research, collaboration, and study. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Anchored within Hohbach Hall is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/silicon-valley-archives" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Silicon Valley Archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which now has a physical space for students and scholars to engage with archival material focused on the history of Silicon Valley. Library patrons will be welcomed by a combined service desk that includes circulation and privileges staff, as well as reference librarians. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Designed by CAW Architects, the space offers myriad ways for patrons to engage with the space. Down the central corridor of Hohbach Hall is a promenade of exhibition cases with a walnut ceiling overhead mimicking a sine wave, a subtle nod to the audio oscillator developed in the region. A large presentation space is at the center of the Hall and outfitted for events and seminars. Sprinkled around the presentation space are group and individual study desks, several with views looking out to the Red Fountain or green spaces. Librarians will also be able to welcome students, faculty, and library guests into a new secure Special Collections room to examine rare objects and treasures. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;With the opening of Hohbach Hall, students and scholars have additional study and collaboration spaces, and visitors can discover a variety of objects, ephemera, and archives from the Stanford Libraries collection. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is much more to explore in the space! We look forward to welcoming you to Hohbach Hall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/grand_opening_of_hohbach_hall</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41118625206593/huge/d3e23650ec58d2989f8af42e7cb75f603174bf79.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="255467"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Theodore Roszak Papers in Focus at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This all-day event will feature the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Theodore Roszak papers, c. 1940-2017&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;throughout Hohbach Hall. Acquired in 2019 and recently processed, the manuscript collection is now available for research in the Department of Special Collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Theodore Roszak (1933-2011) was an American author, academic, and social critic who first achieved fame for his 1969 book &lt;i&gt;The Making of a Counter Culture&lt;/i&gt;, subsequently writing prolifically about history, science, technology, literature, belief, society, and the life of the mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Stay tuned for a detailed schedule of events, including a Showcase Exhibit &amp;amp; a conversation with &lt;a href="https://www.dlkdance.com/kathryn-roszak" target="_blank"&gt;Kathryn Roszak,&lt;/a&gt; daughter of Theodore and Betty Roszak.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is open to the general public. Please visit&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges/visitor-access-and-borrowing" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;our library website&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;to learn more how visitors without a library card or Stanford ID can join us for this event.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/Roszakinfocus</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41279394314778/huge/aa1b6344980863cd875a0cdf125efcfd22cd2f9c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="399021"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, October 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_222</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136264572243/huge/1246dc2c65e22d7be1ceaf15d0f29974bdc97991.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
