<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Religion in Manga and Anime: A Poster Exhibition by IntroSems RELIGST 6N at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the Introductory Seminar RELIGST 6N “Religion in Anime and Manga,” taught by Professor Michaela Mross, students explored religious themes and imagery in manga (Japanese comics) and anime (animated films or TV series). The exhibit on display in the East Asia Library features academic posters on manga and anime, such as &lt;i&gt;My Neighbor Totoro&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Kamisama Kiss&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Deathnote&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Jujutsu Kaisen&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;The Tale of the Princess Kaguya&lt;/i&gt;, that the students created as their final projects. The posters aim to contribute to a deeper understanding of the cultural and religious background of these modern works, produced for mainly entertainment purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is located in the 3rd floor exhibit cases at the East Asia Library. An opening reception will be held on Wednesday, March 13, from 1:30 - 2:45 PM in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is sponsored by Stanford Libraries, the East Asia Library, the Introductory Seminars Program, and the Department of Religious Studies&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/religion_in_manga_and_anime_a_poster_exhibition_by_introsems_religst_6n</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45819348362183/huge/11f1619bda59edc32f082749030e0c86f539da8d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3409" width="2206" isDefault="true" fileSize="5320448"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeing Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Acclaimed photographer &lt;a href="https://www.marybethmeehan.com/"&gt;Mary Beth Meehan&lt;/a&gt; collaborated with Stanford professor &lt;a href="https://fredturner.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fred Turner&lt;/a&gt; to highlight an often overlooked side of Silicon Valley: the people who are struggling to make ends meet in a region known as the center of technological innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A selection of portraits and text from their award-winning book &lt;a href="https://press.uchicago.edu/ucp/books/book/chicago/S/bo90479007.html"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Seeing Silicon Valley&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is on display throughout Hohbach Hall's study spaces. This long-term exhibition will be up through 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/seeing_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44632871153947/huge/9bdd0a6a9240812158b5f139c218c34bb9b226f2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="384" width="576" isDefault="true" fileSize="293286"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Apes &amp; Us: A Century of Representations of Our Closest Relatives at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Centering upon a set of paintings by the Austrian artist and evolutionist Gabriel von Max (1840-1915), &lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Apes &amp;amp; Us&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt; explores a century of of representations of primates in relation to humans. Come tour the cultural fascination with apes that began in the decades after Darwin published &lt;i&gt;On the Origin of Species&lt;/i&gt; (1859) as it spread into art, literature, and film, science and pseudoscience, the scholarly and the sensational.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image: Gabriel von Max, &lt;i&gt;Abelard and Heloise&lt;/i&gt;, c. 1900, oil on canvas. The Jack Daulton Collection. Photography by Don Tuttle/Marty Kelly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_apes_and_us</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45093763636988/huge/1d58a0f9333c80310003fd0cd4499fbca4a6c367.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1600" width="1248" isDefault="true" fileSize="430715"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science Before Silicon Valley  at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Exhibition to show August 11, 2023 — March 24, 2024, in Cecil H. Green Library &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1XI86kAgaFf0qg6EU61aYFhe7fHT18gvg/view?usp=sharing"&gt; &lt;/a&gt;in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing.&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;Register &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; for the reception. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;An extension of the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Embodied Knowledge &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Exhibition entitled:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; Early Stanford Women in STEM &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;will show from September 25 — December 15, 2023, in the Hohbach Hall Entrance Case, Silicon Valley Archives, Green Library.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Embodied Knowledge: Women and Science before Silicon Valley&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; explores the long history of women pursuing scientific, medical, and technical knowledge from the Middle Ages through the mid-twentieth century. It showcases Stanford’s considerable holdings for this subject, including the role of our own university in this history. Our exhibition displays these materials from colonial Mexico, North America, Western Europe, Britain, Japan, Korea, South Asia, and the Middle East. We invite viewers to see them as building blocks in a global history of gender and knowledge. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Many women participated in making knowledge. Long before the rise of the institutional laboratory, the body and the home were domestic laboratories. Largely denied access to institutions of research and learning, women improvised their own opportunities. We have looked for patterns rather than exceptions, documenting women’s scientific labor and the practical realities of earning a living. The variety of scientific and medical publications written by, for, and about women reminds us that this is a history of the many rather than the few. Every author has a reading public—the most successful ones reached large international audiences. Individual histories reveal larger networks and often exist in relationship to institutions. We explore the evolution of women’s scientific education, research, publications, and careers with these questions in mind.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Hypatia of Alexandria (355–415 CE) provides a symbolic point of departure for our exhibition. She was renowned for her lectures in Greek philosophy, mathematics, and astronomy in Alexandria and was brutally murdered by Christians; none of her writings survive, but her reputation endured. Our opening case also includes Maria Sibylla Merian’s gorgeous and insightful Metamorphosis of Surinamese Insects (1705). Merian (1647–1717) was a trained artist and self-educated naturalist who left her husband, collaborated with her daughters, and traveled all the way to Dutch Surinam to observe insects. There she learned about the medicinal uses of Caribbean plants from indigenous and enslaved women. Her life and career were their own metamorphosis. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Bringing a long global story home, we end our exhibition by reflecting on women and science "before Silicon Valley." From its inception in 1891, Stanford educated and encouraged women of science. Focusing on the early decades, we have extracted interesting Stanford women scientists, engineers, and physicians &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;from the archives, exploring their intellectual passions and pursuits. Louise Brown Nash’s portfolio of scientific illustrations in the opening case illuminates the kind of opportunity talented women unexpectedly discovered at Stanford, where Nash was the first "Artist of the Hopkins Seaside Laboratory." This pioneering generation of Stanford women found possibilities even as they confronted their limits.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The next generations of Stanford women bridge the gap between the growth of women’s higher education in the late nineteenth century, the era of women’s suffrage, and the postwar boom in American universities, scientific research, and technological innovation. A 1957 memo of one of the earliest meetings of Stanford women faculty records three women in science and engineering—Myra Keen (paleontology), Mary Sunseri (mathematics), and Irmgard Flügge-Lotz (aeronautical engineering). Keen and Flügge-Lotz also open this exhibition. Keen’s career as a curator and professor illuminates the end of an era when natural history was an important part of Stanford’s mission. Flügge-Lotz’s arrival at Stanford marks the growth of aeronautical engineering. Her work brought her great acclaim in Germany, where she headed a research institute, and led to a spousal lectureship at postwar Stanford. In 1957, Keen was in her third year as an assistant professor and Flügge-Lotz was still a lecturer—until 1960 when the conspicuous gap between her reputation and status became too uncomfortable. Both women help us to understand the importance of second careers, a subject explored with selections from two major Stanford archives in the exhibit case downstairs in the Silicon Valley Archive.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The renowned physicist and chemist Marie Curie would have surely enjoyed meeting the Stanford women we have encountered, had she been able to come as a visiting professor in the early 1930s. Every episode in this exhibition deserves further study, as do others we could not include. We invite you to explore these histories and their artifacts and get to know some very interesting scientific women.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford History Professor Paula Findlen with contributions from a diverse group of faculty, curators, and graduate students across the institution. Deardra Fuzzell, exhibits designer, managed the production and installation of the exhibition assisted by Elizabeth Fischbach, retired exhibits designer. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. M-F, 10 a.m. to 5 p.m. Sat, and 12 p.m. to 5 p.m. Sun. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Library Hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; page to confirm hours and access.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.5pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Libraries' entry requirements and available services&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/embodied_knowledge_women_and_science_before_silicon_valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/43725646356122/huge/283f182485005a2848d9ad5d0707f7c7355c1020.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="730683"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit: Women's History Month at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection presents an exhibit celebrating women's history!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book display includes a selection of titles exploring the history and influence of women in the diverse fields of earth and planetary sciences and biographies highlighting the remarkable contributions of Marie Tharp, Mae Jemison, and Isabella Aiona Abbott. Curated by student worker Alex Cessna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map exhibit highlights the history of women's suffrage and political engagement around the world, featuring 13 countries that have major elections occurring in 2024, from the United States, El Salvador, Brazil, to Finland, Liberia, and Pakistan. Curated by student workers Raiyan Haque and Karen Rodriguez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  The exhibit is available for viewing throughout March during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner_library_monthly_book_map_exhibit_black_history_month</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45765804879487/huge/fd8f8af4a778925564e0139425d01ec602b30f21.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="540" width="540" isDefault="true" fileSize="247881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Canceled: Georeferencing in QGIS (March 27th - Branner Earth Sciences Library) at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Required:&lt;/b&gt; Attendees MUST have a laptop in order to follow along with workshop exercises. You will need to have a current version of QGIS installed and must have at least some experience using QGIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;L﻿anding page:&lt;/b&gt; &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/e8d1d13ca8894643970f315d16010ee9" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Georeferencing in QGIS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&lt;/b&gt; Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing-in-qgis-march-27th-branner</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45863702407160/huge/964cf05ac7de6cba8ae54b7686bd7cc804625eb5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="101089"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Engine 101 (Mar 29, 2024) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Google Earth Engine 101: Introduction to Earth Engine for beginners&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meet Earth Engine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine &lt;/a&gt;is a geospatial processing service. With Earth Engine, you can perform geospatial processing at scale, powered by Google Cloud Platform. The purpose of Earth Engine is to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide an interactive platform for geospatial algorithm development at scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable high-impact, data-driven science&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make substantive progress on global challenges that involve large geospatial datasets&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Google Earth Engine&lt;/a&gt; combines a multi-petabyte catalog of satellite imagery and geospatial datasets with planetary-scale analysis capabilities and makes it available for scientists, researchers, and developers to detect changes, map trends, and quantify differences on the Earth's surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Presenter: &lt;/b&gt;Stace Maples&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note that this workshop is for Stanford University affiliates, only. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Description&lt;/b&gt;: The Earth Engine API (application programming interface) provides the ability to create your own algorithms to process raster and vector imagery. This session is geared toward people who would like to analyze satellite and vector data. The session will be hands-on, using the Earth Engine Javascript code editor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of the class will be an introduction to Remote Sensing, in general. The second half will focus on introducing the Google Earth Engine Platform, and accessing imagery, creating composites, and running analyses over stacks of images, computing statistics on imagery, creating charts and exporting the results of your analyses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;No previous experience with Earth Engine or JavaScript is necessary for the beginner workshop, but programming experience, basic knowledge of remote sensing and/or GIS are highly desirable. Willingness to learn programming is required. Participants with no programming experience will require additional attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get Access to Google Earth Engine Immediately!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are registering with a @Stanford.edu email address, it is possible that you already have access to Google Earth Engine, through the Stanford Geospatial Center's collaboration with The Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability. You can test this by going to &lt;a href="https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://code.earthengine.google.com/f983a2d843739e23ffb77f336ad6d4fb&lt;/a&gt; and logging in with your Stanford.edu credentials. The link should load a script that will produce a "Tanaka Hillshade" map of the terrain in the Yosemite Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that you do not currently have access to Google Earth Engine, through your Stanford.edu credentials, please email &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="mailto:maples@stanford.edu"&gt;maples@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/b&gt;to request to be added to the Stanford Geospatial Center's organizational GEE account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please note that we are only able to provide access to users with valid Stanford.edu credentials, and a fully sponsored SUNetID. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Slides&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The slides below are the same as those covered in the webinar video. You can open these slides in a separate widow in order to follow along and have access to the linked URLs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://slides.com/staceymaples/gee101/embed&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Sample Scripts&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have signed up for and received confirmation of your Google Earth Engine account, you can copy the script repository for this webinar by clicking on the following link, which will redirect you to the Google Earth Engine Code Editor and import a series of scripts designed to introduce you to the basic mechanics of working in Google Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://goo.gl/9f9NgB" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://goo.gl/9f9NgB&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 09:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/google_earth_engine_101_feb_16_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44323412923648/huge/57a46e2861a7a56bdf31331bc5da314632a5300e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1307" width="1722" isDefault="true" fileSize="2541518"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center (DRMC) at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the DRMC, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the DRMC, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the DRMC to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Mar 2024 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>A Stranger Quest - DRMC 8th Anniversary Celebration at Traitel Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us in April 1, 2024 for an afternoon celebrating the David Rumsey Map Center's 8th Anniversary! At 4:30pm inside the Traitel Building's Hauck Auditorium, a special screening of &lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;A Stranger Quest&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt; will highlight the event, with opening remarks by David Rumsey and the film's award winning director Andrea Gatopoulos. After the film we'll convene for food, refreshments, and discussions with the film's director. The film is a documentary about David Rumsey's 30-year endeavor to build one of the world's largest map collections, and saw its debut at the 2023 Torino Film Festival last November. We're very excited to be the first to show the film on the West Coast! &lt;a href="https://player.vimeo.com/video/882830488" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;View the film's trailer here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;When:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; April 1, 2024 from 4:30pm to 7:00pm&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Where:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Hauck Auditorium, Traitel Building, Stanford Campus. 435 Lasuen Mall, Stanford, CA 94305&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/a_stranger_quest_-_drmc_8th_anniversary_celebration</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427563</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167691</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45801958907948/huge/d98bb61bac871c9dfc83d04ad21a8f13959402e8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="906309"/>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>There, beyond the borders of codes: a history of game maps and glitches at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Signaling the border of the Western world, the Pillars of Hercules have for centuries been the symbol of the end of the known and the beginning of a mystery that has always attracted humanity: the promise of an elsewhere where the rules of reality were organized by other demiurges. In the age of satellites, traces of this apparently disappeared human feeling survive within the simulacra of the contemporary age: video games. A short history of maps in video games will explore how they have organized and evolved not only to sort out data and orient players, but also to respond to the mysteries of life and the human condition, hiding Easter eggs, surprises, glitches and soliciting obsessions, funny missions and odysseys of entire online communities, demonstrating how, even on the margins of the digital world, the enigmas of the human being continue to survive, multiply and proliferate.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Starting from the research carried out for the film A stranger Quest, shot inside the David Rumsey Map Center, Andrea Gatopoulos will talk about his journey within the existential folds of the virtual through video-essays, short films and stories orbiting around maps.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Andrea Gatopoulos is a film director and producer. His productions have been presented at the most prestigious festivals in the world, including Cannes, Berlinale, Venice, Locarno, Rotterdam and hundreds of other film festivals around the world. His projects address virtual realities, uncanny valleys and criticisms of progressivism, but maintain their intimate, sweet longing for simple feelings.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/author_talk_a_short_history_of_maps_in_video_games_and_virtual_worlds</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45802109978268/huge/8b63f50ec64d41e559a64074864cb4887d024b14.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1080" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="1113656"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silicon Valley Talks: Anna Shechtman at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Anna Shechtman and Moira Donegan as they discuss &lt;i&gt;The Riddles of the Sphinx: Inheriting the Feminist History of the Crossword Puzzle&lt;/i&gt; on April 4, 2024, at 2:30 p.m. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Riddles of the Sphinx&lt;/i&gt; is one of the most exciting debuts of the year, with excerpts in the &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.newyorker.com/books/page-turner/what-turned-crossword-constructing-into-a-boys-club" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;New Yorker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://harpers.org/archive/2024/03/cross-purposes-2/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Harper’s&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt; and a starred review in &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.publishersweekly.com/9780063275478" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Publisher’s Weekly&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;. Only Anna Shechtman could have written it. A rising star in English and Media Studies as much as contemporary cultural criticism, Shechtman is both a newly appointed &lt;a href="https://english.cornell.edu/anna-shechtman" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;assistant professor&lt;/a&gt; at Cornell University and, as the &lt;i&gt;Guardian&lt;/i&gt; described her in 2019, the “&lt;a href="https://www.theguardian.com/global/2019/may/12/anna-shechtman-the-new-queen-of-crosswords" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;queen of crosswords&lt;/a&gt;.” She became assistant to Will Shortz at the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt; in 2013 and later went on to found the &lt;i&gt;New Yorker’s &lt;/i&gt;crossword section. She is, in short, one of the most celebrated crossword constructors of our time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But &lt;i&gt;The Riddles of the Sphinx&lt;/i&gt; is no straightforward memoir of coming of age in the strange community of crossword obsessives. It is also an exploration of the attractions of a world defined both by the firm rules of a crossword and the limitless significations of words — where one must fit the free associations of a clue into the slot of a predetermined grid. The book is also a story about the relationship between gender and technology in modern America. Once largely the preserve of women, crossword constructing became in the second half of the twentieth century the nearly exclusive domain of men. Both through history and through her own experience, Shectman draws out the relationship between this shift and the rise of new crossword technology. “As puzzle-making became increasingly informed by computer programming,” she recently observed in the &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt;, “it began to replicate the imbalance of tech culture.” But through both her own efforts and those of her peers, this has begun to change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Riddles of the Sphinx&lt;/i&gt; documents this story while opening up rich new historical and intellectual territory to explore, drawing on Shechtman’s &lt;a href="https://www.annashechtman.com/" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;scholarly expertise&lt;/a&gt; in the history of media and the history of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shechtman will be joined in conversation by Moira Donegan, &lt;a href="https://gender.stanford.edu/news/moira-donegan-joins-clayman-institute-writer-residence" rel="noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;writer in residence&lt;/a&gt; at the Clayman Institute for Gender Research at Stanford. A regular opinion columnist for the &lt;i&gt;Guardian&lt;/i&gt;, Donegan is a leading public intellectual and a contributor to the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, the &lt;i&gt;New Yorker&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;New York Review of Books&lt;/i&gt;. She is currently at work on her first book, &lt;i&gt;Gone Too Far: MeToo, Backlash, and the Future of Feminist Politics&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-anna-shechtman</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45951207417239/huge/53eef37f4d9742d48f59043f99ebf8368ba8fd1c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2001" width="1500" isDefault="true" fileSize="572924"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Big Earth Hackathon 2024 Spatial Data Bootcamp: Sources and methods for Wildfire applications at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the &lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big Earth Hackathon 2024 Spatial Data Bootcamp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;! Join us for a morning of learning about sources and methods for wildfire applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This Spatial Data Bootcamp event kicks off the &lt;i&gt;&lt;i&gt;Spring 2024 Quarter &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;of &lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;CEE 165H:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Big Earth Hackathon Wildland Fire Challenge (CEE 265H). &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session will include basic introductions to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://arcg.is/0z9y8b" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Spatial Data with QGIS&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - An introduction to spatial data models and formats, with the open-source GIS Desktop, QGIS. Get the latest version for Mac/Windows/Linux at &lt;a href="https://QGIS.org" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;QGIS.org&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://arcg.is/0DmS590" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Intro to Google Earth Engine&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Learn to access and use Google Earth Engine, 600+ Earth observation datasets with the power of Google Cloud Platform for processing and analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://github.com/StanfordGeospatialCenter/Planet_API_101" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Intro to Planet.com&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; - Accessing and analyzing Planet.com's multispectral daily image of the Earth.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2024 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/big-earth-hackathon-2024-spatial-data-bootcamp-sources-and-methods-for-wildfire-applications</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864203950933/huge/a5512d6d9d1d0f1bcd1cad4e1a6d2075de47ee29.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="470" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="117439"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: April 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more information on the featured game for April! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_april_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45446035612546/huge/adcdbfb0f6f09ab7ea8fc4c739372bdeddb022a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="192066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionary Concepts:  From “Self-Management” to “Sovereignty” in the Soviet Union (1987-1990) at Encina Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for an engaging talk by Juhan Saharov, Visiting Fellow at the Center for Russian, East European, and Eurasian Studies, who will discuss:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Revolutionary Concepts: From “Self-Management” to “Sovereignty” in the Soviet Union (1987-1990)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Soviet Estonia was the first republic to declare its “sovereignty” (asserting the supremacy of the union republic’s laws over all-Union laws) in the Soviet Union in November 1988, setting the model for all other Soviet republics to follow. One by one, the Soviet republics declared themselves sovereign in 1989–1990, earning the name “the parade of sovereignties.” Several historians and political scientists, but also Russian presidents (from Yeltsin to Putin) have later acknowledged that the concept of “sovereignty” killed the Soviet Union, acting as the main catalyst for the dissolution of the state. But how did “sovereignty“ suddenly emerge in October 1987, when nobody had been discussing it a month earlier? Why did it start in Estonia and not in other republics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lecture tells the story of Estonian scholars from the communist party membership who turned the central Soviet perestroika campaign into a local “conceptual revolution.” In September 1987, a group of Estonian scholars introduced the project of “Self-Manageable Estonia” – the idea of an economically self-sufficient Soviet republic, which aimed to place all economies under local and not Moscow's jurisdiction. Within a year, this intellectual movement mobilized the whole nation, eventually shifting the focus from “self-management” to “sovereignty.” The lecture illustrates how the debate on the economic model of Soviet Estonia led to the unintended discovery of the concept “sovereignty” in 1987, and how both concepts were exported to other Soviet republics in 1988–1990.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Juhan Saharov is a Research Fellow of Political Theory at the Johan Skytte Institute of Political Studies, University of Tartu. His research is focused on the intellectual history of perestroika in the Soviet republics, market socialism, and expert languages during the late Cold War period. His doctoral dissertation „From Economic Independence to Political Sovereignty: Inventing “Self-Management” in the Estonian SSR“ was awarded Main Prize for a PhD dissertation by the Estonian Research Council in 2021. He has published on the role of experts and academic communities in the Soviet perestroika in the journals like &lt;/i&gt;Contributions to the History of Concepts, Europe-Asia Studies, &lt;i&gt;and&lt;/i&gt; Acta Historica Tallinnensia.&lt;i&gt; He is a member of the research grant „Self-Determination of Peoples in Historical Perspective” at the University of Tartu.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Juhan Saharov is holding a visiting fellowship with Stanford's Center for Russian, East European, and Eurasian Studies from March–April, 2024.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The event is free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/82LJ9hfo53fq5ZYm7"&gt;RSVP is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/juhan-saharov-estonian-reindependence</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427319</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.164625</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45827522481824/huge/6c04f1223d0daf987695c5b7413d2586c7e6a562.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="791" width="592" isDefault="true" fileSize="71721"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bo Li: The Macroeconomics of Climate Change at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford University Libraries&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://sccei.fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford Center on China's Economy and Institutions&lt;/a&gt; are pleased to present the &lt;b&gt;2024 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture&lt;/b&gt; featuring &lt;b&gt;Bo Li &lt;/b&gt;who will be speaking on &lt;i&gt;The Macroeconomics of Climate Change: Key Issues, Policy Responses, and International Cooperation.&lt;/i&gt; Prof. Chenggang Xu will be moderating the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;To attend in person, please register &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/QuduP48VPwkdHVC78" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;To attend online, please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_glmyQXwxTAehzGu4M4hCgg#/registration" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bo Li&lt;/b&gt; will be speaking on the macroeconomic impacts of climate change. He will discuss fiscal and financial policy priorities to meet Paris Agreement goals; key policy recommendations ranging from carbon taxation to scaling up climate finance; and challenges and opportunities for international cooperation on climate action.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.imf.org/en/About/senior-officials/Bios/bo-li"&gt;Mr. Bo Li&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; assumed the role of Deputy Managing Director at the IMF on August 23, 2021. He is responsible for the IMF’s work on about 90 countries as well as on a wide range of policy issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before joining the IMF, Mr. Li worked for many years at the People’s Bank of China, most recently as Deputy Governor. He earlier headed the Monetary Policy, Monetary Policy II, and Legal and Regulation Departments, where he played an important role in the reform of state-owned banks, the drafting of China’s anti-money-laundering law, the internationalization of the renminbi, and the establishment of China’s macroprudential policy framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside of the PBoC, Mr. Li served as Vice Mayor of Chongqing—China’s largest municipality, with a population of over 30 million—where he oversaw the city’s financial-sector development, international trade, and foreign direct investment. Mr. Li was also Vice Chairman of the All-China Federation of Returned Overseas Chinese. He started his career at the New York law firm of Davis Polk &amp;amp; Wardwell, where he was a practicing attorney for five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mr. Li holds a Ph.D. from Stanford University and an M.A. from Boston University, both in economics, as well as a J.D., magna cum laude, from Harvard Law School. He received his undergraduate education from Renmin University of China in Beijing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family of &lt;b&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/b&gt; donated his personal archive to the Stanford Libraries' Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world's largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia. &lt;a href="https://hsiehlecture.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2024 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2024hsiehlecture</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45809822247115/huge/b5588afd597413dfea9f3a0f912da2c5d9bd5d3a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="267966"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Rising Waters at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us as we explore how board game designers are creating games like &lt;i&gt;Rising Waters&lt;/i&gt; to help educators teach historical events in the classroom. &lt;a href="https://boardgamegeek.com/boardgame/357416/rising-waters"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rising Waters&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is a cooperative game where players experience the Mississippi flood of 1927 through the lens of the local African-American population. The game is deliberately designed to foster difficult conversations about the Jim Crow South by having players confront two forces at the same time–racism and nature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_may_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45625089926766/huge/8263dea88abf9e7d6751d1e34fccc73d0ea70108.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="322" width="352" isDefault="true" fileSize="216345"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Russia's War in Ukraine and its Implications on European Security: Why should America care? at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us for an engaging discussion with Ambassador of Estonia to the U.S. Kristjan Prikk and Director of the Freeman-Spogli Institute Michael McFaul on:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Russia's War in Ukraine and its Implications on European Security: Why should America care?&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than ten years into Russia's war against Ukraine and more than two years after Moscow launched a full-scale aggression, there is still no end in sight to the largest military conflict in Europe after WWII. What are the implications of this war on the security of Europe but also on the United States? What would it take to end the war and in what kind of a world will we all live on the day after it's all over? The event will feature a discussion on the possibility of a viable Western strategy for success that not only saves Ukraine but also strengthens the United States' role as the leader of the free world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Estonia's Ambassador to the U.S. &lt;b&gt;Kristjan Prikk&lt;/b&gt; started his mission in Washington, D.C. in May 2021. He is a graduate of the US Army War College and has served as the National Security Coordinator to the Prime Minister. Prior to arriving in D.C., he was the Permanent Secretary of the Estonian Ministry of Defense. Among his previous assignments are two other tours in Washington as an Estonian diplomat and work on NATO-Russia and NATO-Ukraine topics at a time when these relationships were considerably less charged than today.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael McFaul&lt;/b&gt; is Director at the Freeman Spogli Institute for International Studies, the Ken Olivier and Angela Nomellini Professor of International Studies in the Department of Political Science, and the Peter and Helen Bing Senior Fellow at the Hoover Institution. He joined the Stanford faculty in 1995. He served for five years in the Obama administration, first as Special Assistant to the President and Senior Director for Russian and Eurasian Affairs at the National Security Council at the White House (2009-2012), and then as U.S. Ambassador to the Russian Federation (2012-2014).&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The hybrid event is free and open to the public. To attend in person, &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/rwxd4BtZj1vHqhJ56"&gt;RSVP is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/russias-war-in-ukraine-2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45934446946489/huge/a99b8beae5392bf6e1ff3130d0374049d45f9989.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="586" width="862" isDefault="true" fileSize="374293"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: June 2024 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned for more information on the featured game for June! &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays i&lt;/i&gt;s an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2024 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_june_2024</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45446035612546/huge/adcdbfb0f6f09ab7ea8fc4c739372bdeddb022a2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="192066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
