<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Cars &amp; Climbing: Systems for Quantifying Performance at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;This exhibition was scheduled to open on January 9. Due to the recent storms, it has been pushed back to January 11. We apologize for any inconvenience.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout history, enthusiasts have developed methods to describe and rate performance systematically. Based on archival collections at Stanford, this exhibit explores the genesis of these systems as means for quantifying experiences like the difficulty of a rock climbing route or the quality of the ride that an automobile provides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public during library hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plan Your Visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library hours vary throughout the year. The most up-to-date hours of operation are available &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/green" style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit our &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges" style="text-decoration:underline"&gt;Access &amp;amp; Privileges page&lt;/a&gt; to learn what you will need to bring with you to gain access to the exhibition space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanford has a large campus. Be prepared to traverse at least 0.5 miles during your visit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking regulations are enforced from 8 AM - 4 PM on weekdays unless otherwise posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/carsandclimbing</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42058361359334/huge/d8427494bcba670de0789cc450b8d5d221702d27.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="682" width="754" isDefault="true" fileSize="1081299"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Near to Far: a View of a Cold War-era Aerospace Engineer &amp; His Company at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;This exhibition was scheduled to open on January 9. Due to the recent storms, the opening date has been pushed back to January 13. We apologize for any inconvenience.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Jack Nielsen was Chief Scientist at NASA Ames, and founder of Vidya Inc., before founding Nielsen Engineering and Research. NEAR today is a division of AMA Inc., but the legacy of Nielsen lives on today in this exhibit. This collection is a rare look inside Cold War aerospace and weapons technology, as well as technical report literature from governments and companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibit is free and open to the public during library hours.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Plan Your Visit&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Library hours vary throughout the year. Green Library&amp;#39;s hours of&amp;nbsp;operation are available &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/green"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Visit our&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/using/access-and-privileges"&gt;Access &amp;amp; Privileges page&lt;/a&gt; to learn what you will need to bring with you to gain access to the exhibition space.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stanford has a large campus.&amp;nbsp;Be prepared to traverse at least 0.5 miles during your visit.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Parking regulations are enforced from 8 AM - 4 PM on weekdays unless otherwise posted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/NeartoFar</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42058301559081/huge/36fafe335d4ba8833cf2adab9aa7e6fd18ce788a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="690" width="766" isDefault="true" fileSize="593167"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accelerating the Use of Public Geophysical Data for Recharging California's Groundwater</title>
      <description>&lt;div style="text-align:start"&gt;Discover the Power of Electromagnetic (EM) Imaging in Improving Groundwater Sustainability in California. Learn about our innovative web-based application, designed to make use of publicly available resistivity data for identifying the ideal locations for managed aquifer recharge. This presentation will highlight the importance of the managed aquifer recharge for enhancing groundwater sustainability and the crucial role of EM imaging for mapping subsurface sediment types. Join us as we delve into our use of open-source tools such as Jupyter and Redivis, and discover how you can transfer these ideas to your own projects to drive research into action.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:start"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/seogi-kang"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seogi Kang&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a postdoctoral fellow in the the Department of Geophysics at Stanford. His current research focuses on developing an effective workflow to image subsurface hydrostratigraphy at Central Valley of California using airborne electromagnetic method. Seogi is a core contributor to SimPEG, an open source software project for geophysical simulation and inversions.&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:start"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div style="text-align:start"&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/j/93607079281?pwd=T3NCaGR4WnBJUVlmV3liQ0FNWGJQdz09"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zoom Link&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/accelerating_the_use_of_public_geophysical_data_for_recharging_californias_groundwater</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42360946209249/huge/639a4792e4fd3f392e714bd19e9b8c965d2e3b55.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="515" width="515" isDefault="true" fileSize="356976"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Maritime Spaces Exhibition at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Imagining Maritime Spaces&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;draws together maps of the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans and seas to explore how cartographers, navigators, and others have historically come to know and to represent these dynamic spaces. Charts, tools, and other visualizations illustrate elements of navigation by stars, winds, and waves, exploration of unknown waters and depths, and shifting coasts. This exhibit coincides with the Computational Archaeology &amp;amp; Seafaring Theory Workshop being sponsored by the Archaeology Center and collaborating centers and institutions both on and beyond campus. The exhibition was curated by Justin Leidwanger, Beth Minney and Nicole Constantine; it was coordinated and mounted by Kristina Larsen.&amp;nbsp; The exhibition opens at the same time as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Micronesian&amp;nbsp;Seafaring System&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;talk and can be viewed during the Center&amp;#39;s open hours until Feb 10, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ImaginingMaritimeSpacesExhibition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426818</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.16714</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41768402192589/huge/c260d776d652a9531faad55d7e816255851dad66.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="866" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="321602"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Implementing Privacy Reviews in Digital Archival Collections</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries&amp;rsquo; digital collections contain personally identifiable information and other forms of high-risk data, such as student, medical, and otherwise sensitive records. Archives staff must abide by archival ethics, state law, federal law, and data security requirements set by Stanford University, while making as much material available to the public as possible. Implementing workflows for high-risk data review creates challenges of scale and sustainability. This presentation will outline why and how to review collections for high-risk data, technical approaches, the ongoing evolution of review guidelines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/aschweik"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Annie Schweikert&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (she/her/hers) is a digital archivist at Stanford Libraries, where she processes, preserves, and makes accessible born-digital archival collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Victor Aguilar III &lt;/b&gt;is&amp;nbsp;Lab Assistant in Digital Library Systems and Services at Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_a_92bmJERzSINrrDfmp0Yg"&gt;Click here to register for the Zoom link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/implementing_privacy_reviews_in_digital_archival_collections</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42299316948918/huge/5944cc50da0faa935ff223c87474905b6a08c728.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="165944"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to GeoPandas</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GeoPandas is an extension of the open-source Python Data Analysis Library, Pandas, which can be used to read, write, and analyze vector geospatial data formats. GeoPandas enables you to easily do operations in Python that would otherwise require a spatial database such as PostGIS. In this workshop, we will introduce GeoPandas and learn how to perform a variety of geospatial data science tasks to work efficiently with geographic vector datasets.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_geopandas</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38511017081751/huge/7b0ef630b5f952971c64fe176deb4cc90b89f01f.jpg" type="image/png" medium="image" isDefault="true"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preserving Born-Digital Library Materials and Access through Emulation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford University Libraries&amp;rsquo; Born-Digital Preservation lab will demonstrate the preservation of born-digital source media, offering a virtual walk-through of the disk imaging process and demonstration of how emulation can be used as a potential access strategy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this webinar lab staff will describe how we preserve the contents of born digital source media and can use emulation to make these resources available to researchers.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="http://https://stanford.zoom.us/s/99709760067?pwd=a05aZHNVQzhvK0dKdERPMTJab3I4QT09"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zoom link&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/preserving_born-digital_library_materials_and_access_through_emulation</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42299420250297/huge/fa0e2033b16dbe6308f9fabff82cd3caf458fdac.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="165944"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Your Data Love You Back? Ensuring Credit for Data Scholarship</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Datasets are increasingly recognized as valuable contributions to the scholarly record. Join &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/zach-chandler"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Zach Chandler&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Director of Open Scholarship Strategy, and &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/rochelle-lundy"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rochelle Lundy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, Director of the Office of Scholarly Communications, to learn how to maximize the impact of your research data.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/j/91018991106?pwd=aC9TcjFxYW1SV3Z4R2E1MDlHaStuUT09"&gt;Click here for the Zoom link&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;i&gt;To request a copy of the presentation slides, &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfycnqHjvhBy249TmeWb_dqrWVm-o5fkoCKX1FggvQIvxR8dQ/viewform?usp=sf_link"&gt;click here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="http://lovedata.stanford.edu"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; at Stanford Libraries. Check out &lt;a href="http://lovedata.stanford.edu"&gt;other events&lt;/a&gt; during the week of February 13th - 17th, including an in-person Fair and Lightning Talks at Green Library on the afternoon of February 14th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/does_your_data_love_you_back_ensuring_credit_for_data_scholarship</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42299454085453/huge/1b7def79f59e19b3e0d4a2025ece84e645f9c8bb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="165944"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Wrangling</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080959" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python (or similar knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Feb 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_wrangling_3961</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ArcGIS StoryMaps 101 with the Esri StoryMaps Editorial Team at The David Rumsey Map Center at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Join members of Esri&amp;rsquo;s ArcGIS StoryMaps Editorial Team for an introduction to ArcGIS StoryMaps, a digital storytelling tool that enhances your narrative using multimedia and custom maps. Co-hosted by the David Rumsey Map Center (DRMC) and Stanford Geospatial Center (SGC) at Stanford Libraries, this session will include hands-on skill building with a focus on utilizing resources available through Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presented by ArcGIS StoryMaps Editorial Team members:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;David Asbury&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Andria Olson&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Heidi Daulton&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We welcome observers but if you would like to participate in the hands-on skill building, please come prepared with the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account access to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;storymaps.arcgis.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account with Georeferencer through &lt;a href="https://davidrumsey.com" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;davidrumsey.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Account with MapTiler through Georeferencer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For more information on how to navigate Georeferencer through davidrumsey.com, please refer to the &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/8851fafab37a4674b7a75b5bbf000280" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;Working with Historical Maps Online: David Rumsey Map Center guide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 09:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/arcgis_storymaps_101_with_the_esri_storymaps_editorial_team</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42209996034508/huge/f6c8183e757ae52e0fd59fbef8b22cd5d4b19beb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="903" width="1341" isDefault="true" fileSize="1402740"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Decentralized Social Media: Mastodon and the Fediverse</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There has been a recent surge of interest in the social media platform Mastodon. Although it appears similar to Twitter in that it is oriented around composing posts and sharing them with followers, Mastodon is very differently organized: rather than join a single corporate-owned platform, users join one of thousands of decentralized &amp;quot;instances&amp;quot; of the open source Mastodon software, each run by different people and catering to different communities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session will offer an informal tour of Mastodon, discuss how to migrate your social media network from Twitter, and highlight factors to consider when deciding what instance to join, including issues of governance, community moderation and standards development.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/meeting/register/tJUrc-Ctrj4tE9dGZDLTJSsa7s0h_2aivEw9"&gt;Click here to &lt;b&gt;register&lt;/b&gt; for this online event&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/exploring_decentralized_social_media_mastodon_and_the_fediverse</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42299472461182/huge/3d72c37e74f2d4a4aa6bfb05a9c722a27d940f0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="165944"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: Decoding the Game of Love at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Within the context of LoveData Week, this event explores board games that model or simulate the human emotion of love. These games are intended as entertainment but can also function as data simulations modeling complex relationships and complicated social contexts. In this event, we will evaluate the usefulness of such simulations in modeling human emotions in general and we will examine the specific data points chosen as part of both games. What is really being modeled/studied here? What can we learn from the simulations of human behavior that are on display? What data points are not present in these games?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_1402</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228185169/huge/55c529468b999eccd1478cbb548c74216410679f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro To Python</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Python has rapidly become the programming language of choice for many people across the world, thanks to its flexibility and ease of use. In this hands-on workshop, attendees will learn some of the basics behind how to program in Python, and how they can leverage the language for different tasks. No prior experience is required.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro_to_python</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42367544798878/huge/81ae07de37b37c4f4fd70c35aac0ed7574825881.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="230" width="230" isDefault="true" fileSize="18155"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Visualization</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will introduce you to three basic visualizations using the Python matplotlib and seaborn libraries: histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080962" target="_blank"&gt;Register Here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_visualization</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>George Orwell &amp; Peter Stansky: Then and Now at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a discussion of Professor Peter Stansky&amp;#39;s &lt;a href="https://www.sup.org/books/title/?id=36169" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Socialist Patriot: George Orwell and War&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; (Stanford University Press, 2023), with remarks from John Rodden and Peter Stansky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By carefully combing through Orwell&amp;#39;s published works, Stansky&amp;#39;s book teases apart Orwell&amp;#39;s often paradoxical views on patriotism and socialism. &lt;i&gt;The Socialist Patriot&lt;/i&gt; is ultimately an attempt to reconcile the apparent contradictions between Orwell&amp;#39;s commitment to socialist ideals and his sharp critique of totalitarianism by demonstrating the centrality of his wartime experiences, giving twenty-first century readers greater insight into the inner world of one of the most influential writers of the modern age.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/Rbi5stUCmGVkA6mY8" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to attend the event in person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_Vi-FH0YbRheaEvPQ7v4MLQ" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; to attend the event online.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
A reception will follow the presentation. &lt;i&gt;The Socialist Patriot &lt;/i&gt;along with other copies of books about Orwell by Stansky and Rodden will be available for purchase and signing. This event is free and open to the public and is co-sponsored by Stanford Libraries and ​the Department of History.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu/people/peter-stansky" style="text-decoration:underline" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Peter Stansky&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the Frances and Charles Field Professor of History Emeritus at Stanford University. His scholarship addresses many of the main themes of modern British history: the dissipation of the Liberal and growth of the Labour parties; the rise of aesthetic modernism (and the central role played by the Bloomsbury Group); the impact of two world wars and the Spanish Civil War on British intellectuals; and postwar manifestations of an &amp;quot;austere,&amp;quot; &amp;quot;swinging,&amp;quot; and &amp;quot;cool&amp;quot; Britain. He has written extensively on such topics as William Morris, the Bloomsbury Group and George Orwell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;John Rodden&lt;/b&gt; is widely regarded as the world&amp;rsquo;s leading authority on the legacy of George Orwell. Beginning with &lt;i&gt;The Politics of Literary Reputation: The Making and Claiming of &amp;lsquo;St George&amp;rsquo; Orwell in 1989&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Every Intellectual&amp;rsquo;s Big Brother in 2006&lt;/i&gt;, and continuing with editing &lt;i&gt;The Cambridge Companion to George Orwell &lt;/i&gt;in 2007 and &lt;i&gt;The Cambridge Introduction to George Orwell&lt;/i&gt; in 2012, &lt;i&gt;The Unexamined Orwell &lt;/i&gt;in 2011 and more, he has established himself as the foremost expert on the cultural and political impact of Orwell on the world. His latest book, &lt;i&gt;Becoming George Orwell: Life and Letters, Legend and Legacy,&lt;/i&gt; more than justifies that reputation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 17:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/orwell_stansky</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42245742235756/huge/11d23c7d54d935c6a69f75ee2f0c43643e0c2149.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="178413"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Data Workshop: Content Analysis with NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join Esha Chatterjee, qualitative data software consultant for Stanford Libraries, for an intermediate level class on content analysis.&amp;nbsp; Learn how to upload your collection of textual data for content analysis using NVivo software.&amp;nbsp; Esha will cover coding and other tips.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Feb 2023 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_data_workshop_interview_analysis_with_nvivo</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42274114270008/huge/61e20aa9c07b03a264098d5b96f01d901a7f4207.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="405" width="720" isDefault="true" fileSize="31435"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, March 1 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2023 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_7735</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42276290636813/huge/cc37f9dab80213bb241bf110c991f3375e9808d7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Text Analysis</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in analyzing collections of novels or journal articles? Do you want to understand patterns across collections of tweets or other social media data? In this workshop, we&amp;#39;ll learn how to import, clean, and analyze collections of text with R using several standard text mining libraries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080964" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_text_analysis_971</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Photographs of Rod Dresser at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Photographs of Rod Dresser&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view March 3, 2023, through May 7, 2023, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Mar 2023 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_photographs_of_rod_dresser</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42399897509627/huge/a811011388d7c0cc77f68cae6693093fdf271dd9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="211604"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Machine Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a beginner-friendly introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts, quantitative data preprocessing for machine learning, and the SuperLearner R package.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080965" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R"&gt;https://github.com/EastBayEv/Intro_ML_R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_machine_learning_3970</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Text Analysis</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to working with text data using the spaCy and textacy Python libraries. You will learn to effectively streamline text preprocessing, understand word tokenization, sentence segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, and named entity recognition using a single document (a short excerpt from H.G. Wells&amp;#39;s A Short History of the World) and across a corpus of legal documents.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080968" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_text_analysis_2832</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for March&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Mar 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_9290</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228363356/huge/ad3516023ce1e1e5a75f977c9365d3d5f498fb28.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing Sea Routes on Maps: A conversation on the European and Asian contexts with Sara Caputo and Elke Papelitzky</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;Two leading experts will discuss the appearance and function of sea routes on European and East Asian maps, showing the interconnections of the early modern global maritime world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We have all seen tracks marching across the oceans of a map. Have you ever wondered where they came from and why they are there? In this online event, Sara Caputo (Cambridge) and Elke Papelitzky (KU Leuven) will share their ongoing research on route lines on European and East Asian maps, respectively. They will each give a brief presentation, followed by a conversation moderated by Katherine Parker (BLR Antique Maps).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Trailblazers&amp;rsquo; wakes: Ship tracks in Western imperial mapping&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Sara Caputo, University of Cambridge (UK)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the ancient and medieval European world, the seas on maps were trackless. The few extant itinerary maps never seem to extend their lines onto the water. In the sixteenth century, however, European mapmakers began to include route lines on their representations of the oceans. These lines were closely linked to the navigational practice of pricking a course on portolan charts. They may have also drawn inspiration from the routes that had long featured in East Asian maritime mapping. However, in a Western context, tracks became a powerful tool to recount individual journeys and establish imperial claims, in relation to developing notions of &amp;lsquo;discovery&amp;rsquo;. This half of the talk will include some material from Caputo&amp;rsquo;s forthcoming book, Tracks on the Ocean (under contract with Profile Books).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Red lines in the ocean: Sea routes on early modern East Asian maps&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Elke Papelitzky, KU Leuven&lt;br /&gt;
Many early modern Chinese, Japanese, and Korean maps draw lines in ocean areas that represent sea routes. These lines appear on maps of a single country, of a larger region, or on maps of the globe. They serve a range of different functions from providing information about (imagined) travel to visually integrating East Asia into global networks, reflecting a perception of East Asian mapmakers of their countries being integrated in these networks. Setting East Asian maps in conversations with European ones shows that when map images shift context between Western Europe and East Asia, the function of the route-lines changes. In the case of East Asian maps, these changes further promote the mapmakers&amp;rsquo; narrative of early modern East Asia not being isolated but being a part of the global, maritime world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tracing_sea_routes</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42220224768727/huge/30f4aa3b35fc82ab05d2f5edd48ab981f1d4a2fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1789" width="1909" isDefault="true" fileSize="7565547"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Machine Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for classifying text and images using the scikit-learn, lime, and tensorflow Python libraries.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10080983" target="_blank"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Mar 2023 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_machine_learning_240</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41793171351192/huge/f79638acd09cdd3eb46f5563266d54bf52a9d0a6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="60813"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 1 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385304" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/1_How_to_use_this_book.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_1_3560</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403934637389/huge/c98c6cafa4edbc34196682c1112c389737ae3b24.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 2 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385307" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/4_Numeric_data_wrangling.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_2_3817</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403931372745/huge/28ab47031a57fe449c06e722c838298b5fd9d9a9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for April&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_2015</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228556903/huge/0b8000d865e38646ca9cfca163ffacd123b4d682.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 3 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385314" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/6_Core_concepts_vocabularies.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_3_3486</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403929043465/huge/edcc34c4e78af4c417e5ab41bedb3f61e08bdad6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SSDS Text Analysis and Machine Learning Group - Meeting 4 at 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Every Friday in April, 1-4PM in 120F Green Library (Velma Denning Room)&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/10385321" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/spring2023/8_spaCy_textaCy.html" target="_blank"&gt;Click here to open the book and get started.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 7&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 1-3&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Gain confidence&lt;/i&gt; coding with Python to import, wrangle, visualize, and understand data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 14&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 4-5&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Develop strategies&lt;/i&gt; to internalize basic principles for working with text and machine learning&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 21&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 6-7&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Learn best practices&lt;/i&gt; for performing text analysis within and across documents&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px"&gt;&lt;b&gt;April 27&lt;/b&gt;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp;Chapters 8-9&amp;nbsp;&amp;nbsp; &lt;i&gt;Explore new research possibilities&lt;/i&gt; with large language models&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2023 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ssds_text_analysis_and_machine_learning_group_-_meeting_4_4169</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/42403927605041/huge/72494d0d0cfc33baf275ae6e867b1ba9895b4403.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1370" width="1705" isDefault="true" fileSize="507452"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
