<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>BioBlitz 2026</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.inaturalist.org/projects/stanford-love-data-week-2026-bioblitz"&gt;Join us for a BioBlitz!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A bioblitz is a community event to observe and record as many species as possible within a specific location and time period. As part of Love Data Week, we'll be using iNaturalist to gather information on our local biodiversity - around Stanford and the Hopkins Marine Station - to better understand the plants, animals, and critters that share the campus with us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you're not sure where to start, check out some of the &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://community.stanford.edu/explore-campus/campus-walks"&gt;themed walks and trails&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt; on campus. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/love-data-week-2026-bioblitz</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51508127819396/huge/f6850340921b289c6117bab9fbf426b179a2967f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1047" isDefault="true" fileSize="385182"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Doctor Syntax: A Regency Icon at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Regency's most popular character is on display at the Bowes Art and Architecture Library this Winter in a new exhibit curated by Dr. Ben Wiebracht! Reception this Friday, 1/30 from 3:30-4:30.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The writers of the Regency (1811-20) created some of the most enduring characters in English literature – the sparkling Elizabeth Bennet of &lt;i&gt;Pride and Prejudice&lt;/i&gt;, the brooding Conrad of Lord Byron’s &lt;i&gt;Corsair&lt;/i&gt;, and the chivalrous Ivanhoe of Sir Walter Scott’s great historical romance, to name a few. But in their day, they were all eclipsed by Doctor Syntax.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scrawny clergyman astride his rawboned nag, traipsing around the country in search of picturesque sights, delighted readers the country over. The Doctor originally appeared in a long comic poem called &lt;i&gt;The Tour of Doctor Syntax in Search of the Picturesque. &lt;/i&gt;Written by William Combe and illustrated by the great caricaturist Thomas Rowlandson, the poem was such a success that, before long, spinoffs started to appear extending the Doctor’s adventures in one way or another. Fans of the Doc could stock up on Syntax merchandise as well, and Syntax figurines and chinaware remain a common sight in antique stores on both sides of the Atlantic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, the most extensive collection of Doctor Syntax books in the world resides at the Bowes Library. At its core are ten Regency copies of &lt;i&gt;The Tour of Doctor Syntax in Seach of the Picturesque &lt;/i&gt;(including one inscribed by the author) spanning eight editions. The library also holds copies of all three sequels, as well as several rare spinoffs. This exhibit uses these splendid materials to tell the story of Doctor Syntax—his creation, his adventures, and his explosive popularity in Regency England. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These materials also allowed for publication a new critical edition of The Tour of Doctor Syntax in Search of the Picturesque (Pixelia Publishing, 2024). Sixteen students at Stanford Online High School and their instructor created the book together during a course on Jane Austen, using the Bowes Library's copies as their source texts. The book was honored with the 2023-4 Modern Language Association Prize for a Scholarly Edition. It can be downloaded for free at pixeliapublishing.org/doctor-syntax.  &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/doctor-syntax-a-regency-icon</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51783258595192/huge/618cd406c20787804455d9d0a0a6b853859dfa5b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1000" isDefault="true" fileSize="141887"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Amos Gitai Archive at Stanford at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="http://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;The Amos Gitai Archive at Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from November 17, 2025, to February 15, 2026. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Amos Gitai’s strategy for his artistic legacy might be likened to the principle of "scatter in order to endure.” The way he has distributed traces of his films is a means of bringing to life, internationally, the memory of his filmography, the history of his young country, and universal themes about the fragility and degradation of memory. In this era of digital archives, Gitai decided early on to place his work at well-known international institutions, among them Stanford and the National Library of France. The Gitai archive at Stanford is characterized by its historical depth, featuring eight films spanning the years 1980 to 2014, as well as multimedia works from the 2020s. It contains 10.5 terabytes of photographs, screenplays, scripts, letters, and shooting reports. Also included are rushes, early cuts, subtitles, scores, and post-production documents revealing traces of the artistic process. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;i&gt;House&lt;/i&gt; trilogy (1980, 1998, 2005) revolves around a house in West Jerusalem—its successive inhabitants, their descendants, and the people who worked on it. It brings the memory this house bears to the eyes and ears of old and new generations, those who have stayed and those who have scattered, from the new arrivals from Turkey to the descendants of the Palestinian family now settled in Jordan, zooming out from a close-up of the house to encompass the entire geopolitical fate of the region. Whereas the House trilogy has historical depth and spans several generations, the &lt;i&gt;Borders&lt;/i&gt; trilogy—comprising &lt;i&gt;Promised Land&lt;/i&gt; (2004), &lt;i&gt;Free Zone&lt;/i&gt; (2005), and &lt;i&gt;Disengagement&lt;/i&gt; (2007)—was created over a shorter timeframe. These two trilogies, one documentary and one fiction, enter into a type of resonance. &lt;i&gt;News from Home / News from House&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Free Zone&lt;/i&gt; were shot simultaneously in 2004 and share images, cover the same geography and history, and both deal with porous memory and its gradual disintegration. The Gitai archive at Stanford also contains the archives of the films &lt;i&gt;Plus Tard Tu Comprendes&lt;/i&gt; (One Day You’ll Understand) (2008) and &lt;i&gt;Tsili&lt;/i&gt; (2014). Both are adaptations of literary works by contemporary authors. Both raise questions about the transmission of Holocaust memory in a European context, as well as cinematographic and ethical questions about how to film the words of others. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Gitai’s work on the Israeli Prime Minister Yitzhak Rabin, part of his archives at the National Library of France, showcased in a forthcoming book published by Stanford University Libraries, could be described as a series of palimpsests, an endless process of revision and editing to understand precisely what happened and what was lost with Rabin’s assassination. And it is also an aesthetic journey, like &lt;i&gt;House&lt;/i&gt;, a decades-long exploration of broad histories told through focus on a single figure. With this exhibition, we invite you to explore Gitai’s archive at Stanford and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Ayda Melika and Eitan Kensky with texts by Marie-José Sanselme and Marie-Pierre Ulloa; produced by Deardra Fuzzell, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Pasha Tope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/amos-gitai-archive-at-stanford</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51101333905443/huge/db5941e86abbb11d09bf845e9c8b28d8347051dc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2500" width="3750" isDefault="true" fileSize="3919561"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Undergraduate Showcase: The Senior Reflection in Biology at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibit showcases capstone projects from "The Senior Reflection" in the Biology Department, a unique course that asks students to conceive, produce, and exhibit a creative project centering around Biology or the life sciences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Co-founded and taught by Professor Susan McConnell and Lecturer Andrew Todhunter, the course provides a space for students to blend their scientific studies with creative expression, using media as diverse as painting, poetry, needle point, bookmaking, and the performing arts. The projects in this display were created by students in the 2024-2025 cohort. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit will be on display in Hohbach Hall in Green Library for the duration of the Winter 2026 quarter. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/undergraduate-showcase-the-senior-reflection-in-biology</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38511130104994/huge/ea6d123e35d7eb6c603bb8708a57e9e332578cb9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="40804"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Relax with Data Crafts: Love Data Week De-stress! at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Take a moment to relax with snacks, crafts, and games at Branner Earth Sciences Library! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This event is part of &lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. So grab a coffee while you create your own data inspired crafts!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Available activities:&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;AI APIs &amp;amp; Astronomy Imagery &lt;/b&gt;- Compare real astronomical photos from Astronomy Picture of the Day (APoD) with AI images we generate on demand for you from Stanford's AI Playground API. Check out &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/ai-astronomy-imagery/exhibits" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;last year's gallery&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Map Embroidery &lt;/b&gt;- Make a meaningful map in this data physicalization activity! We provide the raw materials for you to embroider a personal mini-map, you bring the creativity. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Textile Data Weaving&lt;/b&gt; - You’re probably used to seeing data represented in charts and graphs, but have you ever seen a data set turned into a textile? With this activity, you can weave a data set into cloth to destress and learn a fun method of displaying data.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Guess the Dataset!&lt;/b&gt; - Try to guess the underlying dataset from an unlabeled graph. This is a fun way to put your knowledge of trends in the world to the test. We'll put it up on a bit screen so you can play with your friends, and maybe make some new friends! &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;All activities are free, no experience necessary (we'll show you how!), and will be available while supplies last!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Help us reduce waste, bring your own covered mug and reusable plate!&lt;br&gt;
Branner Library will also be hosting several data inspired events throughout the day, be sure to check them out!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We will be taking photos at this event for publicity purposes. Your presence at this event constitutes consent to be photographed unless you express otherwise.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-data-destress</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51472103615178/huge/99a1429e7967cc61c0600528851f82d30e88b061.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="788" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="1438610"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Scan Demonstration: Doerr School Geoscience Specimen Collection! at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Libraries' Digital Production Group is partnering again with the Doerr School Geoscience Specimen Collection to promote the use and understanding of 3D scanning of objects for research and teaching. We will demonstrate scanning of 3D objects, in particular a selection of fossils from the Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability Geoscience Specimen Collections and include examples of how this 3D scan data is used in research.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/15946503"&gt;Register here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event is part of &lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;Love Data Week &lt;/a&gt;at Stanford, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;This event will be held in Branner Earth Sciences Library. To access the library, please bring your Stanford ID or valid government-issued ID.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We will be taking photos at this event for publicity purposes. Your presence at this event constitutes consent to be photographed unless you express otherwise.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 10:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ldw2026-3d-scan-demo</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51507288050831/huge/89d9b749c053d77c477441f0f35654af09a92468.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="788" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="1542198"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Above &amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library) </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Above &amp;amp; Below: Cartography Beyond Terrain&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; is an exhibition that&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; explores how cartography depicts the depths of the Earth, the ocean floor, weather systems, the solar system, and even the seemingly intangible internet – anything but the thin boundary that divides land and sky that we tend to associate with maps. The exhibition celebrates the multifaceted nature of mapping, inviting reflection on our interconnected existence and revealing the beauty and complexity of our world. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Above &amp;amp; Below&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, curated by the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/speakers" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;2025 Ruderman Conference presenters&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, opened in conjunction with  the &lt;a href="https://ruderman.stanford.edu/"&gt;Fifth Biennial Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography&lt;/a&gt; and will be on view through &lt;b&gt;Friday, February 27, 2026&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/above-below-cartography-beyond-terrain</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50907645575537/huge/66abcb4b11be9e58c37698de6abc31a76c242b19.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3840" width="4800" isDefault="true" fileSize="5645151"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dask for Geospatial Analysis: Efficient Parallel Workflows for Satellite Imagery in Sherlock at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop will provide an introduction to Dask in Python for satellite image analysis on distributed systems at scale. We will learn workflows for accessing Earth Observation satellite imagery from NASA as we learn to interact efficiently with images that are larger than the onboard memory of a single chip, build and run custom functions targeted at only the pixels needed for our analysis goals, and process targeted, machine learning ready datasets from these images with the help of Dask's parallelization and distributed data capabilities. This workshop is aimed at researchers who have intermediate Python experience or higher, and all levels of experience (beginner-advanced) with HPC computing. Access to Sherlock is required to participate fully in the session. This workshop is offered in partnership with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://sdss-compute.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;the SDSS Center for Computation&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;1:00–2:00PM, Thursday, February 12, 2026&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Branner Earth Sciences Library and Zoom (link provided upon registration)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Instructors: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Ellianna Abrahams (Research Software and Technology Consultant), Maricela Abarca (Data Curator for Interdisciplinary Sustainability)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is part of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;To access Branner Library, please bring your Stanford ID and tap in. The library is on the 2nd floor of Mitchell and is ADA accessible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;We will be taking photos at this event for publicity purposes. Your presence at this event constitutes consent to be photographed unless you express otherwise.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/dask-for-geospatial-analysis</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51454887348125/huge/079655c51380b4016ca34c418b2352f67e6eb408.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="806457"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stanford Data Farm: Datasets For Research at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Data Farm is Stanford University's research data exploration, extraction, and analysis tool for datasets. Stanford contracts with &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://redivis.com/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Redivis&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; for use of their SaaS platform for storing, distributing, and analyzing research data. Redivis offers a modern, high-performance web-based interface that enables researchers to work with a wide variety of datasets. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;What can Data Farm do?&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Data Farm allows highly efficient and fast queries (using either the visual query editor or writing SQL) directly in the browser. After performing a query, such as: filter-aggregate-combine, you can explore descriptive statistics and visualizations right away or move into integrated notebooks for further data manipulation.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Datasets on Data Farm are interoperable with common data analysis tools such as: Python, R, SAS, and Stata and can be easily exported to on-premise computing environments such as Farmshare / Sherlock&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; into cloud compute services like GCP, AWS, Azure, or downloaded for local analysis (usage rights permitting).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 2:00PM–3:00PM, Thursday, February 12, 2026&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Zoom (link provided upon registration) and Velma Denning Room (120F), Bing Wing, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor:  Ian Matthews (CEO, Redivis) &amp;amp; Vijoy Abraham (Assistant University Librarian, Research Data Services, Stanford University Libraries)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This event is part of &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Love Data Week&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/redivis-workshop-a-data-and-computational-environment-for-reproducible-data-science-6460</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51898752178748/huge/6c819865a489d3f7d52eddf726bffef013c5d939.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="753359"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Oceans: The Arctic at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Oceans&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 2025–2026 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will e&lt;span style="background-color:transparent;"&gt;xplore Earth’s oceans’ complex biological and ecological systems that regulate climate and support life.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;February's exhibition explores how ocean structure, sea ice processes, and ecological interactions govern Arctic systems, influence global climate feedbacks, and shape emerging environmental, scientific, and societal challenges in a rapidly changing Arctic Ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Featuring books, e-resources, and maps, the exhibition demonstrates why the Arctic is central to advancing understanding of global climate dynamics, biodiversity, and human–environment interactions in a warming world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit is available for viewing Monday through Friday during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits and subscribe to the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a valid, physical government-issued photo ID to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-exhibit-oceans-arctic</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51948023521872/huge/599b8032d0d3d059365260cd38c52b3438a620f6.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="424741"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2026 Wikidata Edit-a-thon: Performers from the Piano Roll Archive at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In part two of our LDW Wikidata Edit-a-thon series, participants will do a deep dive into one of Stanford’s collections: the Piano Roll Archive, part of the Archive of Recorded Sound. Participants will add metadata about piano roll performers to Wikidata. A brief overview of Wikidata will be provided before learning about this unique Stanford collection, and how it benefits from discovery in Wikidata, an open, multilingual structured knowledge base that can be read and edited by both humans and machines and is made by people like you. We will learn and discuss the collection, review relevant data as a group, and then edit and add to Wikidata in this 2-hour hands-on session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Friday, February 13, 2026, 11am - 1pm&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Join us in-person in the IC Classroom, Green Library or join us over &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/j/99544719128?pwd=zdpfPcmpYkBFhC7basSA9XatBW37Wb.1"&gt;Zoom&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://appointments.library.stanford.edu/event/15884999"&gt;Register to attend the event in person:&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/b&gt;spots are open to current Stanford Affiliates only.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://m.wikidata.org/wiki/Special:CreateAccount"&gt;create an account&lt;/a&gt; in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is part of &lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://lovedataweek.stanford.edu/"&gt;a series of workshops for Love Data Week&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;, an annual festival highlighting topics, opportunities and services relevant to data in research. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;For those attending the in-person workshop, please bring your Stanford ID card/mobile ID to enter the library. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
We will be taking photos at this event for publicity purposes. Your presence at this event constitutes consent to be photographed unless you express otherwise.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2026-wikidata-edit-a-thon-performers-from-the-piano-roll-archive</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51506913522957/huge/42d2083d741ed90bc1745074d1b72d0f0aa50e75.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="788" width="940" isDefault="true" fileSize="1348921"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Year of the Horse Pop-up at Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Gallop into the Year of the Horse! Come see a selection of scrolls, prints and more New Year's and equine-related materials selected from our Locked Stacks collection. Stop in anytime&lt;b&gt; &lt;/b&gt;on &lt;b&gt;Feb. 17 between 1-3 pm.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/year-of-the-horse-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/52055817026099/huge/cb237019eba89a24bbad09e064888a163e89fe47.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1200" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="730316"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Nights @ Green at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Join us for Game Nights every Tuesday in Green Library from 5pm-8pm in the IC Classroom (near the Reference Desk) of Green Library! These Game Nights will be open to all, from those who can only stop by briefly to those who can be there for the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be added to the Game Nights @ Green mailing list, suggest a game, or if you have other feedback, please fill out &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BM1NjYwbukyKgbTy8"&gt;this contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Feb 2026 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/game-nights-green-3104</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39078028170292/huge/4a76916771a71980996b171e1129d6c1e87ec941.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="853" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="362251"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX Office Hours at Jen-Hsun Huang Building (School of Engineering)</title>
      <description>&lt;div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bring whatever LaTeX documents you are working on and get help on your sticking points!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This event will be held Huang 219.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/latex-office-hours-1115</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427784</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.174323</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38511017081751/huge/7b0ef630b5f952971c64fe176deb4cc90b89f01f.jpg" type="image/png" medium="image" isDefault="true"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Google Earth Engine Python API Quickstart at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;Google Earth Engine Python API Quickstart&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Expanding Your Earth Engine Skills with Google Cloud Platform&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Overview&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop introduces the &lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google Earth Engine Python API&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; as the next step for Stanford researchers and instructors who want to move beyond the JavaScript Code Editor and work with Earth Engine in Python, Jupyter notebooks, and cloud-based analysis environments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A central focus of the session is understanding how Earth Engine integrates with &lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;Google Cloud Platform&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt; (GCP), including the use of user-managed cloud projects that enable Python API access, scalable computation, and reproducible workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Workshop Description&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This session walks participants through the full setup and use of the Earth Engine Python API, starting with cloud project configuration and ending with a complete, working analytical example in a Jupyter Notebook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Participants will be guided through:&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Logging into the Earth Engine&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating a Google Cloud Project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registering the project as non-commercial&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enabling the Earth Engine API within the project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Attaching the project to an existing Earth Engine account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once this process is complete, participants will be able to use the Earth Engine Python API, which was previously unavailable to student users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Example Notebook and Workflow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop is built around a hands-on walkthrough of an example Jupyter Notebook that demonstrates an end-to-end Earth Engine Python workflow. The notebook illustrates how to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authenticate Earth Engine within a notebook environment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Query and filter Earth Engine image collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perform server-side analysis from Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Return and visualize results interactively&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Introducing geemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop also introduces &lt;a href="https://geemap.org/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;b&gt;geemap&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, a Python package that simplifies interactive mapping, visualization, and export of Earth Engine data in Jupyter and Colab environments. geemap bridges Earth Engine’s server-side model with familiar Python-based exploratory and presentation workflows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Topics Covered&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth Engine Python API fundamentals&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Earth Engine and Google Cloud project integration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authentication and project selection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client-side vs. server-side execution in Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive mapping and visualization with geemap&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Patterns for reproducible, notebook-based workflows&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with Google Earth Engine concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Working knowledge of Python&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Some exposure to GIS or remote sensing concepts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This workshop is not an introduction to Earth Engine or Python, but it is designed to be accessible to users who are still early in their Python-based geospatial work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;Testing/Getting Access&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To determine whether you currently have access to the Stanford Google Earth Engine Org, as well as the ability to create GCP Projects for Google Earth Engine, you can do the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are a member of the Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability, you may already be a member of the GIS Users Workgroup, which gives you login access to Google Earth Engine, as well as Google Cloud Project creation, when using Earth Engine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can test your access to Google Earth Engine by logging in with your SUNetID Credentials, at the Earth Engine Code Editor: &lt;a href="https://code.earthengine.google.com/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://code.earthengine.google.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You will be guided through a process to create a GCP Project, register your project as a non-commercial project, as well as enabling the Google Earth Engine API, before you can then select the project for use in Google Earth Engine. Once you have gone through the process and attached the project to your Google Earth Engine account, you should be able to access the Earth Engine Python API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use the following to authenticate and see basic usage of the Python API: &lt;a href="https://colab.research.google.com/github/google/earthengine-community/blob/master/guides/linked/ee-api-colab-setup.ipynb" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer" target="_blank"&gt;https://colab.research.google.com/github/google/earthengine-community/blob/master/guides/linked/ee-api-colab-setup.ipynb&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you find that your Stanford credentials do not allow you access to the Earth Engine platform, email Stace &lt;a href="mailto:maples@stanford.edu"&gt;maples@stanford.edu&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/google-earth-engine-101-python_api</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426413</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172471</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51808861724364/huge/f0f2f228be51c1852e9749831fac7a411601c940.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1307" width="1722" isDefault="true" fileSize="2541518"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in R at  Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;1:00PM–3:00PM, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Tuesday, February 24, 2026&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Teaching Corner, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Alma Parada (Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is an introduction to working with data visualization in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but you have never created figures beyond maybe a few base R visualizations (using the plot, hist, barplot functions), then this class is a good fit for you! By the end of this workshop, you will have learned the syntax of ggplot2, how to modify and customize graph aesthetics, how to generate common plots (e.g., scatter , and how to save your figures to your computer. Time permitting, we will explore a few extra features such as faceting, custom colors, and themes!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure R and RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop. You can download both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID to enter the library.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-visualization-in-r-4829</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426413</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172471</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51773389112359/huge/6ca352cf24e71721222cc9d574ce36f6e5cf6e3e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="43142"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing open source air quality datasets for public health policy action (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This month we are joined by Ayako Kawano, a PhD candidate in the Emmett Interdisciplinary Program in Environment and Resources at Stanford. Ayako’s research examines the impact of air pollution on population health and climate change in low- and middle-income countries using remote sensing data and machine learning methods. Ayako recently won the Stanford University Libraries Data Sharing Prize for her work publishing a long-term dataset of fine particulate matter concentrations in India, which has been used to inform public health programs and policy as well as used in further research projects.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:left;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;u&gt;&lt;a href="https://bayareaopensciencegroup.github.io/"&gt;Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; is a growing community for Bay Area academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/air-quality-datasets</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/52004814483392/huge/c4914d1201a29cc778814dd438f3da31f42df68c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="102446"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Nights @ Green at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Join us for Game Nights every Tuesday in Green Library from 5pm-8pm in the IC Classroom (near the Reference Desk) of Green Library! These Game Nights will be open to all, from those who can only stop by briefly to those who can be there for the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be added to the Game Nights @ Green mailing list, suggest a game, or if you have other feedback, please fill out &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BM1NjYwbukyKgbTy8"&gt;this contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/game-nights-green-3724</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39078028170292/huge/4a76916771a71980996b171e1129d6c1e87ec941.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="853" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="362251"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New &amp; Notable Maps at Branner Library at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Drop in to see our February selection of new &amp;amp; notable maps from the Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collections. These include recent acquisitions (donations and purchases) as well as amazing things our staff have found in our map cases lately!&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Wednesday, Feb 25, 2026 from 2-5pm in Branner Library (2nd Floor, Mitchell Earth Sciences Building). Proceed to the mezzanine/map floor via the stairs or request elevator access at the front desk&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Each month we'll be featuring a new selection so follow us on Instagram @&lt;a href="https://www.instagram.com/brannerlibrary/"&gt;brannerlibrary&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-notable-feb2026</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51960941256762/huge/5173ff4c9d5ee5b42a8774c99259cc4351bcb902.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2582" width="2582" isDefault="true" fileSize="2268799"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Introduction to NVivo workshop for social science students.  Please register for this session at the following link below:  &lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current"&gt;https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-2336</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47746634515153/huge/4b7271aa6a1855e0b196ba9e4f4d29d03c880256.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finely Printed Books: Albert Bender and the Birth of Stanford Special Collections at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;Finely Printed Books: Albert Bender and the Birth of Stanford Special Collections&lt;/i&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda of the Cecil H. Green Library from February 26 to May 17, 2026. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Finely Printed Books&lt;/i&gt; tells the incredible story of Albert Bender and his remarkable gifts to Stanford that became the foundation of Stanford University Libraries Special Collections. It has been almost one hundred years since the first beautiful book came to the Green Library. From 1926 to 1941, Albert M. Bender personally donated more than five hundred volumes and encouraged his friends to contribute to the growing collection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“This, my copy of the &lt;i&gt;Laudes Creaturarum of S. Francis&lt;/i&gt;, I now give to the Leland Stanford Junior University through Albert M. Bender, in memory of my husband’s dearly loved sister Frances A. H. Sanderson Stewart.&lt;br&gt;
–Anne Cobden-Sanderson, Stanford, June 27th, 1926.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Sunday, June 27, 1926, Anne Cobden-Sanderson made her way down the peninsula from San Francisco to the Stanford campus. The previous evening, she had attended a meal in her honor at Coppa’s restaurant in San Francisco, a haunt for Bohemians, artists, literati, and book people. The trip to Stanford came at the end of a week of celebration of the “book beautiful,” during which Cobden-Sanderson, was feted by the area’s printers, publishers, and book collectors. It was one of the final stops on a West Coast visit from Santa Barbara to the Bay Area, a tour punctuated by lectures on the suffragette movement, the labor movement in England, the Doves Press, and interviews and research on prison reform – all topics which had played key roles in Cobden-Sanderson’s life – with every event documented by the California newspapers as she worked her way north.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
While we cannot know for certain what was discussed over dinner that Saturday evening nearly a century ago, we do know three things with some certainty: first, that Albert M. Bender was there; second, that he encouraged Cobden-Sanderson to travel from the city to a young campus near Palo Alto, pay a visit to the Stanford University Library in what is now the Green Library building, and inscribe her copy of a book from the Doves Press, founded by her husband T. J. Cobden-Sanderson and financed by Anne herself, to a nascent rare book collection; third, that this gift to the University, from a person who bridged the worlds of William Morris, Jane Stanford, and the burgeoning post-earthquake Bay Area book arts scene, was the first step in the transformation of a haphazard accumulation of old and rare books acquired in the first three decades of the University’s operations into a well-organized Department of Special Collections serving the faculty and students of a major research institution.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Albert M. Bender (1866–1941), the self-effacing catalyst who transformed Bay Area cultural life through his extensive philanthropy and enthusiasm for beauty in art, literature, and the book arts, shaped Stanford’s collections in ways that are still felt today. He encouraged dozens of his friends and acquaintances to give generously to help Stanford grow from a library that struggled to keep up with the demands of building a basic teaching collection to one that could also support access to rare, antiquarian, and unique materials for serious scholarship. By providing us with carefully selected examples of fine printing, illustration, type design, papermaking, and binding, ranging across all periods, he challenged the librarians at the time to rethink how Stanford viewed its role as a repository of research materials. No longer were our rare books defined just by how old they were or which texts they contained, but now there was a need to consider aesthetics, research importance, monetary value, book history, provenance, uniqueness, and, in short, all the myriad attributes that might make a book an object of scholarly inquiry. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This exhibition tells the story of Albert M. Bender’s remarkable gift to Stanford University. An inventory of the gifts that Bender helped bring to Stanford in 1926 and 1927, &lt;i&gt;Finely Printed Books Presented to the Library of Stanford University: A Catalogue&lt;/i&gt;, has allowed us to identify and update the provenance for 179 volumes from that initial gift, recovering information that had been lost from our catalog decades ago in the conversion from card catalogs to online records. On display are highlights from this bountiful donation. The archival traces of Albert M. Bender, his circle of friends who made the initial donations possible, the librarians who helped shepherd in a new era of collecting for Stanford University, and the impact that this gift had on the Stanford community at the time. As we look ahead to a second century of rare book collecting, much has been done, and much remains to be done, to build a world-class resource to support Stanford scholarship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Benjamin Albritton, Rare Books Curator for the Department of Special Collections. Produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach, Kylee Diedrich, and Pasha Tope. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/finely-printed-books-albert-bender-and-the-birth-of-stanford-special-collections</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/52059394480987/huge/f631a6a9d79c01a56f7a88da4b5cccc34d756333.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="960" width="1440" isDefault="true" fileSize="1132884"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Event with Matt Wisnioski:  Beyond the Buzzword, a Critical History of "Innovation" at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The consensus that innovation drives American progress has cracked. For over half a century innovation served as a universal good. While the imperative to innovate for a better future continues to fuel systemic change around the world, critics now assail innovation culture as an engine of inequality or accuse its do-gooders of woke groupthink. What happened? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSeSk4t0h2pdNKo4S2S0M5oWKbpcgpP-0z4Vxz0mO7GWQhUSyQ/viewform"&gt;RSVP at this link&lt;/a&gt; to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book talk, the historian Matt Wisnioski investigates how innovation—a once obscure academic term—became ingrained in our institutions, our education, and our beliefs about ourselves. He reveals the central role of a new class of experts in spreading toolkits and mindsets from the cornfields of 1940s Iowa to Silicon Valley tech giants today. This group posited that “innovators” were society’s most important change agents and remade the nation in their image. The innovation culture they built transcended partisan divisions and made strange bedfellows. Wisnioski will discuss how Kennedy-era policymakers inspired President Nixon’s dream of a Nobel Prize for innovators, how anti-military professors built the first university incubators for entrepreneurs, how radical feminists became millionaire consultants, how demands for a rust belt manufacturing renaissance inspired theories of a global creative class, how philanthropic encouraged girls and minority children to pursue innovative lives, and why the innovation consensus is now in dispute&lt;b&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wisnioski will be joined in conversation by Stanford's Elizabeth Kessler, an advanced lecturer in the American Studies program who frequently offers courses on the history of Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Matthew Wisnioski&lt;/b&gt; is an interdisciplinary historian of innovation, engineering, science education, and the nexus of science, engineering, art, and design (SEAD). He teaches at Virginia Tech University, where he serves as professor and director of graduate studies in Science, Technology, and Society. He also hols affiliated appointments in History and Engineering Education. He is the author of &lt;i&gt;Every American an Innovator: How Innovation Became a Way of Life&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Engineers for Change: Competing Visions of Technology in 1960s America&lt;/i&gt;, and co-editor with Eric S. Hintz and Marie Stettler Kleine of &lt;i&gt;Does America Need More Innovators? &lt;/i&gt;He is writing a new book on The Magic School Bus and the history of science education. His public writing has appeared in The Atlantic, Chronicle of Higher Education, IEEE Spectrum, Medium, Science, and the Washington Post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Elizabeth Kessler&lt;/b&gt; is an Advanced Lecturer in the American Studies program at Stanford. Her research and teaching focus on twentieth and twenty-first century American visual culture. Her diverse interests include: the role of aesthetics, visual culture, and media in modern and contemporary science, especially astronomy; the interchange between technology and ways of seeing and representing; the history of photography; and the representation of fashion in different media. Her first book, &lt;i&gt;Picturing the Cosmos: Hubble Space Telescope Images and the Astronomical Sublime&lt;/i&gt;, on the aesthetics of deep space images, was published in 2012. She’s currently writing on book on extraterrestrial time capsules, as well as developing a new project on fashion photography.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2026 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/wisnioski-innovation-critical-history</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51834454975411/huge/d63631964a0d24ef0fee2800226b9a75bcd7fa13.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1365" width="2048" isDefault="true" fileSize="1767066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Nights @ Green at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Join us for Game Nights every Tuesday in Green Library from 5pm-8pm in the IC Classroom (near the Reference Desk) of Green Library! These Game Nights will be open to all, from those who can only stop by briefly to those who can be there for the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be added to the Game Nights @ Green mailing list, suggest a game, or if you have other feedback, please fill out &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BM1NjYwbukyKgbTy8"&gt;this contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2026 17:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/game-nights-green-9218</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39078028170292/huge/4a76916771a71980996b171e1129d6c1e87ec941.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="853" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="362251"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Intro to Data Analysis and Statistics in R at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 1:00PM–3:00PM, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Wednesday, March 4, 2026&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Teaching Corner, Branner Earth Sciences Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructors: Dr. Alex Threlkeld (Mathematics, Statistics &amp;amp; Computational Sciences Librarian) &amp;amp; Dr. Alma Parada (Head Librarian, Branner Earth Sciences Library)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is a gentle introduction to performing basic data analysis and statistics in R for those who have moderate programming experience in R. If you know how to work with datasets (variables, matrices, dataframes) and functions in R, but want to learn more about summarizing your data, identifying patterns, and potential interactions between variables, this class is for you. We will explore how to perform descriptive statistics, analysis of variance, regression, and identify interactions between variables on example datasets.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please ensure that R and the RStudio are installed on your computer before the workshop (you can get both here: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;https://posit.co/download/rstudio-desktop/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;. If you know how, please install the tidyverse package, otherwise we’ll do it in class. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This workshop is open exclusively to current Stanford affiliates, and registration will be on a first-come, first-served basis. Space is limited, and a waitlist will be available once spots are filled.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID to enter the library.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2026 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro-to-data-analysis-and-statistics-in-r</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426413</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172471</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51773408540827/huge/845f12e7c8c0a2bd549f788a687df6f0f83bd602.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="43142"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Drop-In Samizdat* Workshop (*DIY Unofficial, Unsanctioned, Limited Edition Publication) at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Take a seat at a manual typewriter and create a limited edition, uncensored, unofficial publication to circulate from hand to hand.  Just like Eastern European dissidents used to do in the 1960's and 70's.  (&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/3022617"&gt;Here's an old-school, digitized example from Stanford Libraries' collections.&lt;/a&gt;)  Typewriters, carbon paper, onionskin paper all provided.  Hohbach Hall lobby (Green Library, 1st floor, near the reference desk), 2 - 4PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2026 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/samizdat</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/52003681298381/huge/c9451728c58af4691fdfeb448353502c18271690.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2858" width="2998" isDefault="true" fileSize="1913719"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Mar. 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2026 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-8702</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51763541870866/huge/937d5a2feda2cc3260e46ffc542b6fb1c0adcdcb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Visualization in Python (AI-Assisted Coding) at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Date and Time: 3:00–4:30PM, Thursday, March 5, 2026&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Location: Room TBD, Bing Wing, Green Library&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Lead Instructor: Dr. Jooyeon Hahm (Head of Data Science Training &amp;amp; Consultation)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn to transform your data into clear, effective visualizations by mastering the fundamentals of data visualization and matplotlib syntax, with AI as your coding assistant. This hands-on workshop emphasizes core visualization principles and practical matplotlib skills, teaching you when and why to use different chart types (bar charts, line plots, scatter plots, histograms, and more), how to make design choices that enhance clarity (color, layout, labels, and annotations), and common visualization mistakes to avoid. You'll learn matplotlib's syntax and structure, including its object-oriented approach (figures, axes, subplots), essential plotting commands and customization options. Throughout the workshop, you'll leverage AI tools like Stanford's AI Playground to accelerate your coding by crafting effective prompts for specific visualization needs, iterating and refining AI-generated code, and debugging outputs.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Bring Your Own Data (BYOD)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;! This workshop works best when you apply concepts to your own datasets. Bring a dataset you'd like to visualize, or use provided sample data. Expect hands-on practice creating visualizations with guided AI assistance.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please register to attend. Registration is exclusively open to current Stanford Affiliates and will be offered on a first-come, first-served basis. Given the limited space, a waitlist will be available once all spots are filled. (Please cancel your registration if you can’t make it.)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;For those attending the in-person event, please bring your Stanford ID card or mobile ID to enter the library.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;br style="font-style:normal;text-align:start;"&gt;
 &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2026 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data-visualization-in-python-ai-assisted-coding</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51773094349891/huge/c8ec060940b4efe4136f2d593465af8a8e87dd0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="58514"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Nights @ Green at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Join us for Game Nights every Tuesday in Green Library from 5pm-8pm in the IC Classroom (near the Reference Desk) of Green Library! These Game Nights will be open to all, from those who can only stop by briefly to those who can be there for the entire time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be added to the Game Nights @ Green mailing list, suggest a game, or if you have other feedback, please fill out &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BM1NjYwbukyKgbTy8"&gt;this contact form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2026 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/game-nights-green-5524</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39078028170292/huge/4a76916771a71980996b171e1129d6c1e87ec941.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="853" width="1280" isDefault="true" fileSize="362251"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Taste of Freedom, the Smell of Democracy: Cold War Spontaneous Humanitarian Aid from Finland to Estonia at Encina Commons</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Estonians and Finns are separated by the Baltic Sea but have close linguistic and cultural ties which persevered throughout the Cold War. At the end of the 1980s these blossomed into a wave of Finnish aid which not only alleviated economic woes inherent to the Soviet system, but took on a political dimension by kindling the fire of pro-independence movements in Estonia. Person-to-person informal networks which moved vast amounts of clothing, medicine, technology, toys and food from independent Finland to Soviet Estonia gave recipients a real “taste” of freedom even before the fall of the Iron Curtain. These networks enabled individual families in Estonia not only to survive but to thrive within the precarious economic environment that defined the last years of Soviet rule. Although taste, smell, flavor and their social constructs have traditionally been ignored in political histories, there is no denying that a sort of "sensual turn" has taken place in the 21st century. The echoes of the olfactory as well as material encounters between Estonians and Finns can be still heard in modern day experiences and routines as well as Estonia’s political culture, which sets Estonia apart from many other former Soviet states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSfpPYfeGjYkPLDMruu02xILkb_dwmSDbsE4_jqSf3HxxwwQpA/viewform?usp=header"&gt;Please RSVP here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maarja Merivoo-Parro is dedicated to exploring the history of mentality at the crossroads of culture and politics and has extensive field work experience among Estonian communities from Abkhazia to Australia. She is a Fulbright scholar and currently holds the position of Marie Curie fellow at the University of Jyväskylä in Finland. Maarja has received national recognition for her work as a public intellectual bridging academia and society through documentary films, television and radio programs.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Mar 2026 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-taste-of-freedom-the-smell-of-democracy-cold-war-spontaneous-humanitarian-aid-from-finland-to-estonia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426792</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.164842</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/52066019389129/huge/c41a56a3a246ca8d0fdd6eee157f65149d50966d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="997" width="1246" isDefault="true" fileSize="190628"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Launch with Quinn Slobodian and Ben Tarnoff: "Muskism: A Guide for the Perplexed" at Green Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Elon Musk. A troubled dreamer. A power-hungry, vengeful bungler. A hero who became a villain; a villain who became a hero. What if he isn’t any of these things? What if he was more like an idea? An avatar for a world view, the master code for an operating system. This is the topic of Quinn Slobodian and Ben Tarnoff’s new book, &lt;i&gt;Muskism: A Guide for the Perplexed&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book launch event, the authors will be joined in conversation by Stanford professor Adrian Daub, author of &lt;i&gt;What Tech Calls Thinking&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1OwwSV3PUm-KtgVCItmkGM7MPvCk1xm4loG2S51IXtHk/preview"&gt;RSVP at this link&lt;/a&gt; to attend. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To understand Elon Musk and the world he intends to make, Slobodian and Tarnoff argue, we have to understand the worlds that made him. From his early years in apartheid South Africa come a deep commitment to racial hierarchy, industrial self-reliance, and fortress futurism. From Silicon Valley we get the idea to finance moonshot projects with public money. And online we see Musk use the tools of virality, repetition and provocation to undermine legacy institutions in pursuit of a kind of techno-state. Not dissimilar to the world of his beloved video games.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worlds that made Musk are now making ours. Into a de-globalizing world comes a promise of sovereignty through technology. But not for everyone. The techno-maximalism of the political and business elite sees a cyborg future and signs us all up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To say that Muskism is worth taking seriously is not to say that its success is guaranteed. But the institutional breakdown of our era offers an opening. At some point, society will stabilize on a new basis. Muskism could provide the foundation. In this book launch event, the authors will help us all understand the ground taking shape beneath us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Quinn Slobodian&lt;/b&gt; is professor of international history at Boston University, and the author or editor of seven books translated into ten languages including, &lt;i&gt;Hayek’s Bastards: Race, Gold&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;IQ and the Capitalism of the Far Right&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Crack-Up Capitalism: Market Radicals and the Dream of a World without Democracy&lt;/i&gt;, and &lt;i&gt;Globalists: The End of Empire and the Birth of Neoliberalism&lt;/i&gt;. In 2024, the &lt;i&gt;Prospect Magazine &lt;/i&gt;(UK) named him one of the World’s 25 Top Thinkers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Ben Tarnoff&lt;/b&gt; is a writer and technologist based in Massachusetts and is the author of &lt;i&gt;Internet for the People&lt;/i&gt; and the co-author of &lt;i&gt;Voices from the Valley: Tech Workers Talk About What They Do—And How They Do It&lt;/i&gt;. He is a frequent contributor to the &lt;i&gt;New York Review of Books&lt;/i&gt;, and has also written for the &lt;i&gt;New York Times&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;The New Yorker&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;New Republic&lt;/i&gt;, among other publications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Adrian Daub &lt;/b&gt;is an academic and critic based in San Francisco and Berlin. He is the J.E. Wallace Sterling Professor in the Humanities in the Departments of Comparative Literature and German Studies at Stanford University. Since 2019, he has also served as the Faculty Director of the Michelle R. Clayman Institute for Gender Research. He is the author of six academic books as well as several works of cultural and political criticism. His writing regularly appears in magazines and newspapers across the German-speaking and Anglophone worlds.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2026 19:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book-launch-muskism</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/51783000887501/huge/e341c7d4389adf151c9670d0e09c7e559bc39648.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1000" width="1500" isDefault="true" fileSize="1196379"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
