<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Rise Up for Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders exhibit</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In response to the precipitous increase in Asian American and Pacific Islander (AAPI) hate crimes throughout the United States, the staff of Stanford Libraries created the Rise Up against AAPI exhibit which focuses on the history of systemic racism against the AAPI community. The aim of this exhibit is to help educate our community and provide support and resources so that we can start the process of healing and prevent future incidents. In this exhibit, we discuss past events that have led to these reprehensible acts, including institutionalized policies that have pitted minority groups in our country against each other to weaken the other&amp;#8217;s influence.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;We hope that through education, our community at large can rise to action against racism at all levels of our society. From the nuanced exclusions on the playground and in the workplace, to the blatant disregard for human life demonstrated in the murders of Asian American women in Atlanta and the brutal attacks on elderly AAPI community members in California and New York&amp;#8212;we must all take an active stand against the scourge that racism is to humanity.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibit has both an online and physical presence. You can access the online exhibit at &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;exhibits.stanford.edu/riseup&lt;/a&gt;. The physical exhibit is in the East Asia Library and is a companion to the online exhibit. The physical exhibit highlights material from the Stanford Libraries collection and other sources that illustrate the racial struggle of the Asian American and Pacific Islander community throughout US history. Please note the physical exhibit is only open during the East Asia Library's open hours. Visit &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;library.stanford.edu/hours&lt;/a&gt; to see current hours.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This exhibit is a work in progress and just the beginning of our efforts to combat racism in this country. Look for expanded content covering more ethnic groups and a broader range of issues as this exhibit continues to grow over the fall 2021 quarter.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries stands with the AAPI community and denounces all hate crimes, including the recent surge in hate crimes specifically targeted at the AAPI community. We hope you will join our efforts to learn about the history of violence against the AAPI community so that we can prevent history from repeating itself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rise_up_for_asian_americans_and_pacific_islanders_exhibit_6719</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574964232972/huge/51d7df4d3a242c95b72cfc6a541c16b99c5ff99b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="89766"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Say Their Names - No More Names</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Say Their Names &amp;ndash; No More Names&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is an online and in-person exhibit that highlights Black Americans who have been killed or impacted by police brutality and systemic racism. The exhibit originated in direct response to the global Black Lives Matter movement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The physical exhibition in Green Library includes names affixed to glass panels in the Bing Wing as well as banners throughout the first floor that contain the names and faces of the featured victims.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/saytheirnames" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;online exhibit&lt;/a&gt; displays the images and individual stories of victims, including Emmett Till, Kalief Browder, Salecia Johnson and Bettie Jones; it also calls attention to events like the Tulsa riots, the Tuskegee syphilis experiment and the Chicago Police Department Midnight Crew.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who visit Stanford can also see a large banner featuring the words &amp;#39;Know Justice Know Peace,&amp;#39; which was hung on the front entrance of Green Library commemorating the opening of the exhibit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note the physical exhibit in Green Library is currently limited to authorized Stanford ID cardholders due to COVID-19.&amp;nbsp; However, the online exhibit, which also includes photos of the physical exhibit is available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibit is sponsored by the Stanford Libraries and is a follow up to a &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/node/171904" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;statement of solidarity and support&lt;/a&gt; against systemic racism published by Stanford Libraries over the summer. It offers opportunities for learning, reflection and discussion.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/say_their_names_-_no_more_names_5200</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38574945719380/huge/1338d497cd2a334e576defd1efcaa1e0d3740ede.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="108932"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina: Contemporary Artists' Books from the Codex International Book Fair&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, on view February 24, 2022, through August 28, 2022, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library Bing Wing, 2nd Floor.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;Materialia Lumina&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Robert Trujillo; produced, designed, and installed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and currently restricted to the following current Stanford ID cardholders: students, post-docs, professors (including emeriti), academic staff, fellows, and Stanford visiting scholars. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/materialia_lumina_contemporary_artist_books_from_the_codex_international_book_fair</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118485903850/huge/23c7599baa91e1cd67c67e00d6c403ed88b088a4.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="151056"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under-Mapped Spaces Public Lecture 1: Pancakes &amp; Silver: Historic Map Reading, Data Extraction</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pancakes &amp; Silver, the 2019 ArcGIS StoryMap of the Year, is a demonstration of how to utilize digitized paper maps for interdisciplinary purposes: storytelling, data extraction, and data visualization. Along with telling the cartographic story of the Comstock Lode, a significant lode of silver ore discovered in Virginia City, Nevada in 1859, Pancakes &amp; Silver is also an instructional guide in how to read maps for the purpose of extracting data. It then guides its readers in how to apply these data to create digital visualizations for expanded exploration and understanding. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Andria Olson is the map librarian at Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp; Map Collections at Stanford University and provides instruction on ArcGIS StoryMaps for her community.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event is free but you need to &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_bObnyi9qT5-THHyQPe6ysg" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt; to get your zoom link.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Feb 2022 16:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/under-mapped_spaces_public_lecture_1_pancakes_silver_historic_map_reading_data_extraction</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118487446001/huge/24032b1d985a609c415b0f68daf96cda53eb62bd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="128765"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Introduction to Machine Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This two-part workshop series provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for ensemble machine learning practices and how to classify images using various R packages. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Prerequisites: The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Make sure you have installed R and RStudio prior to the start of the workshop: &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;Download R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;Download RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_introduction_to_machine_learning</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/38569616605548/huge/a3711b2b950e412ee12ce80972657cc2f51bc991.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Humanities and Libraries - What is Next?</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is pleased to welcome &lt;strong&gt;Wolfram Horstmann&lt;/strong&gt;, director, Göttingen State and University Library, who will be speaking on &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humanities and Libraries – What is Next?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;What is next, after Digital Humanities has served its purpose to bring technology and novel research methods on the agenda across various fields of the humanities? And what are new roles of libraries that are massively transforming to become a novel form of research infrastructure? Traditionally, Humanities and libraries have an intensive relationship that is also persisting current transformations. How will the new relationship look like that can be built on both the transformation trajectories in the humanities and the transformation trajectories in libraries? Possible scenarios in contexts of text-technologies, data-intensive applications (AI) or data narratives will be tentatively explored in the talk.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.sub.uni-goettingen.de/en/contact/staff-a-z/staff-details/person/wolfram-horstmann/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Wolfram Horstmann&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; is the director the Göttingen State and University Library, University Librarian at Göttingen University and professor at the Institute for Library and Information Science (IBI) at Humboldt-University Berlin. Prior to his current position he was Associate Director at the Bodleian Libraries of the University of Oxford, UK. In previous positions, he worked as Chief Information Officer for Scholarly Information and managed national and international initiatives for information infrastructure, science publishing and educational resources. He is a biologist by training, having worked in the field of computational neuroscience, did a PhD in the context of Philosophy of Science before he actively turned his attention towards scholarly communication and libraries.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;His current strategic focus is on research engagement of the library. One element is to build research data support on campus through a service center operated together with research computing and a data science institute with researchers across disciplines. He is also representing the university in cooperative research infrastructures such as the National Research Data Infrastructure in Germany and the European Open Science Cloud.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;In 2022, he was appointed to develop the research profile of the university in the humanities together with leading researchers. Central to this humanities research profile are novel forms of publishing and scholarly communication and data-intensive applications on texts, lexical resources, geo-information and imaging.&lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/humanities_and_libraries_-_what_is_next</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39277601543946/huge/316341c69ed7c6993534b27030660ce834825561.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="129672"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under-Mapped Spaces Public Lecture 2: American Imaginaries after Cartography</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"If Englande crie out, this Norumbega offreth the remedie": American Imaginaries after Cartography&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Richard Hakluyt's early modern propagandizing for English colonization in North America depended on the availability of printed matter: maps, narratives, and images. Using the 2018 French historical graphic novel &lt;em&gt;Florida&lt;/em&gt; by Jean Dytar and its depiction of Hakluyt, Sá Pereira considers the imaginary that the novel's geographical history creates. Yet in 2022, after the various spatial turns, can we even speak of an American imaginary outside of the rigid forms of the cartographic ideal?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Moacir P. de Sá Pereira is the Research Data Librarian at Columbia University Libraries.   &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The lecture will take place &lt;strong&gt;Tuesday, March 1, 2022 &lt;/strong&gt;on Zoom and follows the schedule below: &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:45 p.m. PST&lt;/strong&gt;: Zoom opens&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:00 p.m. PST&lt;/strong&gt;: Lecture by Moacir P. de Sá Pereira&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event is free but please &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_TwwthxHxS56zn1-I1t9EeQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt; to get your zoom link.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 16:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/under-mapped_spaces_public_lecture_2_american_imaginaries_after_cartography</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118487645688/huge/0ea1f842e9b697548ef953ccb90b85f1bc19287e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="134875"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under-Mapped Spaces Public Lecture 3: Community ownership and open data: where is the balance? </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Open data is integral to the work of scholarship, but openness can easily turn into an extractive exercise that enforces exploitative dynamics. What considerations do people working with open data have to take into account while working with open spatial data?&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Majd Al-Shihabi is a technologist and urban planner, and a PhD student in the geography department at the University of Toronto. Majd's current research is on the use of agent-based modelling to address the wicked problem of the housing crisis, and is the co-founder of Palestine Open Maps.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The lecture will take place &lt;strong&gt;Wednesday, March 2, 2022 &lt;/strong&gt;on Zoom and follows the schedule below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:45 p.m. PST&lt;/strong&gt;: Zoom opens&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:00 p.m. PST&lt;/strong&gt;: Lecture by Majd al-Shihabi&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event is free but you need to &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_oMXFRxJSSj-3GxJf-zfuKQ" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt; to get your zoom link.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/under-mapped_spaces_public_lecture_3_community_ownership_and_open_data_where_is_the_balance</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118487851520/huge/47fda1f88844f65a064c8a421fa4de3baa029523.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="166259"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The U.S. Census &amp; COVID-19 Interactive Data Hub  Presentation by Lia Bolden</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries Presents the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;2022 Gear Up for Social Science Data&lt;/a&gt; Program&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please join us for a presentation by Lia Bolden of the U.S. Census Bureau for details about the census data and the COVID-19 Interactive Data Hub. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by: James R. Jacobs, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;All about the U.S. Census Bureau &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Census Bureau provides current facts and figures about America's people, places, and economy. While we're best known for the decennial census (or census of population and housing taken every 10 years), we also conduct more than 130 censuses and surveys of households and businesses across the nation each year. Our work provides the data used for decision making by businesses, city planners, non-profit organizations, students and more. The Census Bureau's mission is to serve as the nation's leading provider of quality data about its people and economy and invite you to visit &lt;a href="about:blank" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;www.census.gov&lt;/a&gt; to explore our current and past offerings. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;COVID-19 Interactive Data Hub &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The U.S. Census Bureau, in collaboration with multiple federal agencies, is in a unique position to produce data on the social and economic effects of coronavirus on American households. This session will provide an overview of the Household Pulse Survey, Small Business Pulse Survey, Community Resilience Estimates, and other Census Bureau programs that were stood up during 2020 to help users understand the impacts of the coronavirus pandemic. The session will also include a demo of the &lt;a href="https://covid19.census.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;COVID19 Interactive HUB  &lt;/a&gt; , a platform built to make access to these and other key programs easier for users who are unfamiliar with Census data. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Bio: Lia Bolden&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Lia Bolden has been employed by the Census Bureau for over 19 years. As a Data Dissemination Specialist, Lia promotes the use of census data to anyone with an interest or a need to work with this valuable information including community organizations, municipal officials, chambers of commerce, librarians, students, and businesspersons.  Lia's background includes consulting, marketing, community relations and co-manager of a consulting firm specializing in providing planning, training, facilitating, coaching and project management services to local communities and organizations engaged in community/ economic development.   &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Lia holds a Bachelor of Science in Business Administration from California State University, Chico and has completed graduate coursework at the University of San Francisco.  Lia brings a wealth of experience to her work and is an engaging trainer illuminating the value of data on community transformation.  &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_us_census_covid-19_interactive_data_hub_presentation_by_lia_bolden</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259949586814/huge/d1bb69c0f68ee3a45d1de8379e8730567a65864a.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="303" width="303" isDefault="true" fileSize="38910"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Institutional Review Board (IRB) at Stanford, overview by Kateri Noble</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford University Libraries &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022&lt;/a&gt; Program is hosting this informational talk covering the basics of the Institutional Review Board (IRB) at Stanford.  If you are planning on doing reseach that may need IRB oversight, this session is for you. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by: Regina Roberts, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;IRB Overview&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Institutional Review Board (IRB) is an administrative body established to protect the rights and welfare of human research subjects recruited to participate in research activities conducted under the auspices of the institution with which it is affiliated.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The IRB is charged with the responsibility of reviewing, prior to initiation, all research (whether funded or not) involving human participants. The IRB is concerned with protecting the welfare, rights, and privacy of human subjects. Kateri Noble's presentation will provide researchers basic information on the IRB process for social science research at Stanford University for non-medical research related to human subjects. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Bio: Kateri Noble&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Kateri Noble is the non-medical IRB (Institutional Review Board) manager at Stanford University.  Nobel coordinates the reviews of all human subjects research proposals that are submitted across the university (outside the School of Medicine).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_institutional_review_board_irb_at_stanford_overview_by_kateri_noble</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259949916571/huge/c1a1517aa190c1a06c01c45fa49df11f1923ad0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="350" width="350" isDefault="true" fileSize="45066"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to EPS China Data, Presentation by Lei Lei of EPS China Data</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Invited speaker Lei Lei of EPS China Data will give a presentation at the Stanford Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022 &lt;/a&gt; Program.  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by Zhaohui Xue, East Asia Library, Stanford Libraries. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This talk is an introduction to the EPS China Data Platform and content coverage which includes: Data resources, Data Search, Data Display, and Data Processing.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/11997333" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;EPS China Data&lt;/a&gt; presents a collection of China statistical data and census data which could be the largest and most comprehensive on the market. One platform (i.e. EPS Data Platform) provides access to 41 China statistical databases (and more sub-databases) in a wider range of subjects and fields. EPS China Data contains over 1.2 million time series of basic and combined statistical indicators with a yearly increment of more than 55 million numeric data.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Join us to find out more about how to use this data provided by Stanford University Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction_to_eps_china_data_presentation_by_lei_lei_of_eps_china_data</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259950213557/huge/3d886f9fa421d45ef784fd321b17a296813be6b8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="300" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="35692"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Research Workshop with Special Guest  Professor Johnny Saldaña</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stanford Libraries is pleased to announce this qualitative data workshop taught by Johnny Saldaña. This is a featured event of the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;2022 Gear Up for Social Science Data&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/form/SV_6DxHxzqRaWVn4Ls" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Register&lt;/a&gt; in advance to recieve workshop handouts.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Workshop organizer &amp; moderator: Alesia Montgomery, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The purpose of this three-hour workshop is to survey how narrative data can be inductively analyzed through different methods from the canon of qualitative inquiry heuristics. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Approaches to the analysis of social media and interview data will be demonstrated, and participants will explore each of these methods with authentic data sets. The first is coding and categorizing the story of a senior adult woman's health conditions through dramaturgical coding. The second is thematic analysis of a high school teacher's narrative about her relationship with students. Additional workshop topics include analytic memos, constructing diagrams and matrices, found poetry, and analytic writing.  &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Workshop content and participatory exercises are designed to provide participants with a sampling of analytic approaches to non-numeric data. These methods can be utilized with written and oral empirical materials for research, practice, and professional development. The workshop is targeted to graduate students and novices to qualitative research. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Selected Publications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Longitudinal Qualitative Research: Analyzing Change through Time (AltaMira Press, 2003) &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14056090" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14056090&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;The Coding Manual for Qualitative Researchers (4th ed., Sage Publishing, 2021; previous editions translated into Korean, Turkish, and Chinese-Simplified) &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13874055" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13874055&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Fundamentals of Qualitative Research (Oxford University Press, 2011) &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13071918" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13071918&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Ethnotheatre: Research from Page to Stage (Left Coast Press, 2011) &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13032431" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13032431&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Johnny Saldaña&lt;/strong&gt; is Professor Emeritus from Arizona State University's School of Film, Dance, and Theatre in the Herberger Institute for Design and the Arts. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;His methods titles have been cited and referenced in more than 24,000 research studies conducted in over 135 countries in disciplines such as education, medicine and health care, technology and social media, business and economics, government and social services, the fine arts, engineering, and the social sciences. Saldaña's research has received awards from the American Alliance for Theatre &amp; Education, the National Communication Association – Ethnography Division, the American Educational Research Association's Qualitative Research Special Interest Group, New York University's Program in Educational Theatre, the Children's Theatre Foundation of America, and the ASU Herberger Institute for Design and the Arts.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_research_workshop_with_special_guest_professor_johnny_saldana</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259950779879/huge/dd5e9c360950b23bb34c560983d6ebd02c75f1c5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="231184"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Redivis Quantitative Data Research Platform Presentation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Stanford University Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022&lt;/a&gt; Program, Ian Mathews, Co-founder and CEO of Redivis will give a presentation and demo highlighting the use of Redivis on the Stanford Campus. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by: Vijoy Abraham, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Redivis is a data platform for academic research. Redivis enables organizations to securely distribute rich datasets, and empowers scientists to undertake groundbreaking research. Our goal is to reduce complexity in data science and make it accessible to everyone. Ian Mathews is the Co-founder and CEO of Redivis and will give a brief overview of Redivis and the use of Redivis at Stanford Libraries. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/redivis_quantitative_data_research_platform_presentation</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259950464461/huge/310fc04e3442b133037ed03496042d90fa73f12c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="300" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="24660"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Under-Mapped Spaces Public Lecture 4: Mapping the Gap: Intersections, Counter-Surveillance...</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mapping the Gap: Intersections, Counter-Surveillance and the Mapping Divide &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Be it due to lack of training, censorship or differences in infrastructure, not everyone in the world has access to mapping, despite the accessibility of off-the-shelf tools online. At the same time, the possibilities and challenges for mapping grow as we become increasingly aware of the gaps in the historical and cultural record, and the question of mapping absence takes center stage in mapping and scholarly communities. In this lecture, Alex Gil will thread through a selection of web visualizations and maps in order to shed light on the conditions for cartographic creativity in an uneven, broken world. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Alex is the Digital Scholarship Librarian at Columbia University, where he collaborates with faculty, students and library colleagues in humanities research, pedagogy and knowledge production that involves the use of advanced computation, digital media design, and network technologies. He is the lead coordinator for the &lt;a href="https://studio.cul.columbia.edu/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://studio.cul.columbia.edu/" rel="noopener"&gt;Butler Library Studio&lt;/a&gt; at Columbia University Libraries, a tech-light library space focused on digital scholarship and pedagogy, and now a broadcast, &lt;a href="https://www.twitch.tv/culstudio" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.twitch.tv/culstudio" rel="noopener"&gt;Studio Remote&lt;/a&gt;. He is also co-founder and moderator of &lt;a href="http://xpmethod.plaintext.in/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://xpmethod.plaintext.in/" rel="noopener"&gt;Columbia's Group for Experimental Methods in the Humanities&lt;/a&gt;, a trans-disciplinary research cluster focused on experimental humanities; one of the creators and main editors of &lt;a href="http://archipelagosjournal.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://archipelagosjournal.org/" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;archipelagos journal: a journal of Caribbean digital praxis&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and co-wrangler of its sister conference series, &lt;a href="http://caribbeandigitalnyc.net/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="http://caribbeandigitalnyc.net/" rel="noopener"&gt;The Caribbean Digital&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The lecture will take place &lt;strong&gt;Thursday, March 3, 2022&lt;/strong&gt; on Zoom and follows the schedule below:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4:45 p.m. PST:&lt;/strong&gt; Zoom opens&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5:00 p.m. PST:&lt;/strong&gt; Lecture by Alexander Gil Fuentes&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The event is free but please &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_tbi6FSumSv2OHiwgv4rWSw" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;register here&lt;/a&gt; to get your zoom link.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Mar 2022 16:45:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/under-mapped_spaces_public_lecture_4_mapping_the_gap_intersections_counter-surveillance</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39118488045064/huge/5a750014b4c310cf11c13e129a997d0f9c19788b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="106985"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CoreLogic: Powering the U.S. Residential Real Estate Market</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This invited presentation by CoreLogic representative, Tyler Waaler, is part of Stanford Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022&lt;/a&gt; Program.  Join us for an overview of the CoreLogic Data provided by Stanford Libraries. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderator: Kris Kasianovitz, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Tyler Waaler, Data Strategy Consultant at CoreLogic.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Tyler Waaler is a consultant for CoreLogic, the nation's leading real estate and business intelligence firm. As a consultant, Tyler connects CoreLogic's data assets and clients to develop comprehensive custom solutions and build leading models to describe the state of the United States' housing market.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/14127292" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;CoreLogic&lt;/a&gt; is proud to partner with Stanford to provide more than 1 billion historical real estate transactions for over 3,000 County Clerk/Recorder offices. Property tax records include more than 150 million residential and commercial property records collected from 3,100+ U.S. County Tax Assessor, Collector and Treasurer offices. The company will be walking through how CoreLogic collects this information and ensures data quality, and how our clients use it to unlock new groundbreaking insights about the housing market, ensure affordable homeownership, and disrupt the mortgage loan industry.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;CoreLogic offers best-in-class intelligence in the real estate industry, with an unmatched network of trusted relationships and capacity for technical and digital innovation that comes with deep experience and collaboration. CoreLogic data provides a seamless and superior homeownership journey powered by accurate, comprehensive, and current data for the banks, insurers, researchers, and government clients that power the United States housing market.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 10:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/corelogic_powering_the_us_residential_real_estate_market</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259951091197/huge/f95f4dd3b7d2ec9cb31ba16e5047522f6ad4c82d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="579" width="579" isDefault="true" fileSize="156414"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gallup Polling Data Presentation</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stanford Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022 &lt;/a&gt;, is pleased to invite you to attend a presentation by Jerry Hansen from Galllup World Poll. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderator: Ron Nakao, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn &lt;/strong&gt;how the data from the Gallup US Daily Tracking and World Polls can uniquely enrich your research.  A variety of time series plots and cross-tabs from these two polls can be viewed via Stanford's subscription to &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10320533" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gallup Analytics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Gallup US Daily Tracking Poll, begun in 2008, and running until the end of 2016, is a nationally representative poll of about 7000 adults per week. Questions provide unique and detailed insights into Americans' opinions and perceptions of important political and economic issues, as well as the current events that affect the world, the U.S., and their lives.  With almost 1900 variables and large sample sizes that accumulate over time, the US Daily Tracking Poll will allow you to slice and dice the microdata to fairly detailed breakdowns by demographic categories or geography.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The Gallup World Poll, begun in 2005, is an annual poll of more than 20000 variables from over 167 countries that represent 99% of the world's adult population.  The World Poll tracks the opinions and perceptions of the adult population of these countries on the most important issues worldwide, such as safety, food access, governance, employment, and subjective well-being.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bio: Jerry Hansen&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Jerry Hansen joined Gallup in 1996 and works with the Gallup Analytics team to provide tools that allow access to unique data sets from their 100 year longitudinal poll of the world, and their daily studies of public opinion from the United States.  Jerry's long tenure with Gallup began as an interviewing manager specializing in challenging methodology, complicated call designs, and overseeing foreign language interviewing. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/gallup_polling_data_presentation</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259951362576/huge/912ac8fd38b5bcde2001c870fd6fcfe9d2d76565.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="349" width="349" isDefault="true" fileSize="35352"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wharton Research Data Services (WRDS) Presentation on SEC Analytics</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn about SEC Analytics at Stanford Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022 &lt;/a&gt;Program&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is an invited presesntation by Eunji Oh, Research Support Director, WRDS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by: Alice Kalinowski, GSB Research HUB.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; SEC filings are one of the fundamental data sources for finance/accounting research. However, dealing with millions of SEC filings requires intensive time and effort, even to curate the filings for your research. WRDS jumped in and has provided convenience for researchers who use SEC filings by providing SEC Analytics Suite composed of ready-to-use data queries and structured datasets from the raw filings. In the talk, several key distinctive features of the SEC Analytics Suite will be introduced including massive filings search &amp; download, sectionalized 8-K filings, and itemized filings. The features can help researchers broaden their research topics and improve research productivity.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speaker Bio: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Eunji Oh&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Eunji joined Wharton Research Data Services (WRDS) as a Research Support Director in 2019. Her primary research focus is on asset pricing, innovation, and intangible assets. Before joining WRDS, she received her Ph.D. in Finance from the University of Illinois, Urbana-Champaign, and her M.S. degree in Business Administrations and B.S. in Civil, Urban, and Geosystem engineering from Seoul National University in South Korea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/wharton_research_data_services_wrds_presentation_on_sec_analytics</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259951753777/huge/8ad5db52da2de4cd642b8795c8272655944629f1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="64468"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Software &amp; Services for Data Science (SSDS) Overview</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join Stanford Libraries' Evan Muzzall and Kate Barron for an overview of the consultation services available through the Software &amp; Services for Data Science (SSDS), within the Stanford Libraries. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by: Regina Roberts, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;This talk will provide an overview of SSDS services to support your computational research needs. We help you get onboarded to research data collections and essential tools such as R and Python in the context of basic research workflows. We also offer one-to-one consultation support for when you get stuck. We will also discuss the Text Analysis and Machine Learning group, which is an informal space for you to familiarize yourself with these topics. Learn more at &lt;a href="https://ssds.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://ssds.stanford.edu/&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Evan Muzzall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Evan is a social data scientist and digital humanist with experience in pedagogy and curriculum development, instruction, instructor coaching, consultation, mentoring and professional development, and collaborative interdisciplinary research projects. He supports the computational research pursuits of students, librarians, faculty, and staff using a variety of pedagogical and methodological resources that emphasize critical thinking and data skills.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;His formal training is in forensic anthropology and bioarchaeology. His research interests span functional biomechanics, mortuary archeology, microbiology, teaching computational text analysis in digital humanities contexts, machine learning applications to bioarchaeology and international conflict, the science of science, deep learning, and natural language processing and computational text analysis.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;He earned his PhD from Southern Illinois University Carbondale Department of Anthropology in 2015. Before joining Stanford, he was the Instructional Services Lead at the UC Berkeley D-Lab.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kate Barron&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;As a research data curator in the Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research (CIDR), Kate helps preserve and document data that the library has acquired. Her goal is to ensure that the library's data collections are discoverable and reusable by the university community. Kate also advises faculty, staff and students about data management best practices. Kate earned her Master of Science in Information from the University of Michigan. Before joining Stanford, she was the Data Services Librarian at San José State University.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This talk is part of the Stanford Libraries events for &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022. &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 13:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/software_services_for_data_science_ssds_overview</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259952043597/huge/48af9f5bbbeca935a725d417dc65a1b887447b27.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="319" width="319" isDefault="true" fileSize="40747"/>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Health &amp; Wellbeing Panel Qualitative Methods with Dr. Patricia Rodriguez Espinosa &amp; Charles Varner.</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured event: &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022 &lt;/a&gt;Program.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Join &lt;/strong&gt;Stanford's Qualitative Data Librarian, Alesia Montgomery as she leads a discussion on methods and collaboration with Stanford researchers about their recent projects on Health &amp; Wellbeing: reflections &amp; lessons for qualitative research collaborations across language and culture with Dr. Espinosa (Stanford Medicine) and The American Voices Project with Charles Varner (Stanford Center on Poverty and Inequality). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Patricia Rodriguez Espinosa &lt;/strong&gt;will reflect on lessons for qualitative research collaborations across language and culture, noting that qualitative scholars are increasingly engaged in global research where members of the research team are from different countries and cultures and have different primary languages. However, in-depth descriptions of how to rigorously work as a transnational team are scarce. Using a collaboration between Stanford and Chulalongkorn University in Thailand as a case example, the following presentation will showcase nuances and challenges experienced in this research collaboration, and the strategies employed to optimize the validity and reliability of the study findings. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Varner o&lt;/strong&gt;f the Stanford Center on Poverty and Inequality will speak about the use of qualitative methods in the research by the American Voices Project. The American Voices Project (AVP) relies on immersive interviews to deliver a comprehensive portrait of life across the country. The interview protocol blends qualitative, survey, administrative, and experimental approaches to collecting data on such topics as family, living situations, community, health, emotional well-being, living costs, and income.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Panelist &amp; Moderator Bios:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dr. Patricia Rodriguez Espinosa&lt;/strong&gt; is an instructor in the Department of Epidemiology and Population Health and the Associate Director of Research for the Office of Community Engagement at Stanford University School of Medicine. The ultimate goal of her research is to decrease health inequities among racial/ethnic minority populations through transdisciplinary and community-engaged scholarship. Her research aims to understand factors that create and maintain health inequities and use these insights to develop novel multi-level interventions and health promotion programs to address the inequity gap and that include multi-sectoral collaborations. Dr. Rodriguez Espinosa's research has also centered around developing the science of community-based participatory research, citizen science, and other participatory research approaches.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Charles Varner&lt;/strong&gt;, Associate Director of the Center on Poverty and Inequality, leads the CPI's research, training, and administrative data programs and is senior editor of Pathways Magazine. Author of influential tax-return studies of "millionaire migration," he is a scholar of the demographic, social, and political sources of poverty and inequality.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alesia Montgomery &lt;/strong&gt;is the liaison for the Sociology and Psychology Departments. She consults and collaborates with qualitative researchers campus-wide (see her topic guide on &lt;a href="https://guides.library.stanford.edu/qualitative_research" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;qualitative research&lt;/a&gt;). Montgomery is also an urban ethnographer, and teaches in Stanford's Urban Studies Program. Her recent book is &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13571958" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Greening the Black Urban Regime: The Culture and Commerce of Sustainability in Detroit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/health_wellbeing_panel_qualitative_methods_with_dr_patricia_rodriguez_espinosa_charles_varner</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259952314983/huge/09580f7dd75b65166edbb064c79a3b91a04019fe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="317" width="317" isDefault="true" fileSize="58621"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research (CIDR) Panel Discussion</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stanford Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/gear-research/winter-2022" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Gear Up for Social Science Data 2022&lt;/a&gt; Program is pleased to present the team of researchers from the Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research (CIDR) in a panel discussion.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Moderated by Vijoy Abraham, Stanford Libraries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Abstract of panel discussion: &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Join the team from the Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research (CIDR) and engage in a wide-ranging discussion and question and answer session around topics related to digital projects and computational work in the social sciences and humanities.  We've gathered frequently asked questions for discussions and invite participants to bring their questions and research challenges to us.  Come and learn about our services, instructional and training events, as well as opportunities to get involved with supporting fellow students by sharing your own expertise!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;About CIDR:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Center for Interdisciplinary Digital Research (CIDR) enables digital research and teaching to encourage and inspire innovative scholarship throughout the University. We are a team of humanists and social scientists within the Stanford University Libraries who design and develop new tools and methods, and integrate technology and information resources, to promote scholarship. Our expertise in data discovery, data creation, data management and analytical tools supports the generation and dissemination of new knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;People bios and photos:&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/department/cidr/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://library.stanford.edu/department/cidr/about&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/center_for_interdisciplinary_digital_research_cidr_panel_discussion</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39259952618118/huge/006c8c1712ff5e9d719d106cb38c918fc7003243.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45256"/>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accessing &amp; Analyzing Large Corpora in the HathiTrust Research Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The HathiTrust Research Center has millions of documents scanned by Google and universities, including books, articles, and reference material. This workshop will cover how to identify documents you want to work with, pull them into an HTRC "workset", and perform computational analysis on that workset via pre-programmed algorithms or your own code in the HTRC data capsule.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2022 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/accessing_analyzing_large_corpora_in_the_hathitrust_research_center</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39127348943848/huge/8806727d6ac948ffa39622e4044c9801eabbd4aa.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Thursday, March 10 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Please note that masks will be required and we will be asking that hands be sanitized before and after petting. Hand sanitizer will be provided. Please join us!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_3702</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39145118553259/huge/315d6eef48593d7f1c73efdb2ee62d2872108489.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
