<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every archival collection that Stanford Libraries acquires must be processed before it can be made available for research. The expertise, thought, and care that goes into processing archival collections often occurs behind-the-scenes. Using the John Perry Barlow papers as a throughline, this exhibit explores the art of processing archival collections. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/paper_trails_the_art_of_processing_archival_collections</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40861265484890/huge/796758a62e11f9aaae17dc593730c2e172be4fbe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="425" width="425" isDefault="true" fileSize="109634"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoze Xie: Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie's new exhibition, &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt;, opening on September 15, 2022, in the main second-floor exhibit space at the Stanford East Asia Library, reminds us that, if "knowledge is power," as the quotation goes, then books can become battlegrounds. For over ten years, Xie has been engaged in an ongoing project titled &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Memories&lt;/em&gt; that focuses on the history of banned books in China. &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; features new works from this project. In addition to books from the artist's own collection, the exhibition will also feature several of Xie's sculptures. Working with photographs of books in public and private collections, Xie has created life-size, hand-sculpted and hand-painted porcelain reproductions of banned books both ancient and modern, some of which will be displayed publicly for the first time in this exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; will be on view from September 15, 2022, through the end of Fall Quarter. An opening reception will be held on October 12, 2022, in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie, the Paul L. &amp; Phyllis Wattis Professor of Art at Stanford University, is an internationally recognized artist who has exhibited extensively in the US and abroad. His work is in the permanent collection of such institutions as the Denver Art Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts Houston, San Jose Museum of Art, the Scottsdale Museum of Contemporary Art, and Oakland Museum of California. Xie received the Asia Game Changer West Award from the Asia Society (2022), the Painter and Sculptor's Grant from the Joan Mitchell Foundation (2013), the Pollock-Krasner Foundation Grant (2003) and artist awards from Phoenix Art Museum (1999) and Dallas Museum of Art (1996).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/xiaoze_xie_flammable_ideas_fragile_objects</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41074045488313/huge/df720f80197b036bed4df7bb0508525112431604.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="195807"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Book at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 6, 2022, through February 5, 2023 in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Elaine Treharne and Benjamin Albritton, produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_handmade_book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127511947685/huge/fa816f484827df107b7a256d92f54535a019c421.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="581" width="581" isDefault="true" fileSize="232881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Imagining Maritime Spaces Exhibition at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Imagining Maritime Spaces&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;draws together maps of the world&amp;rsquo;s oceans and seas to explore how cartographers, navigators, and others have historically come to know and to represent these dynamic spaces. Charts, tools, and other visualizations illustrate elements of navigation by stars, winds, and waves, exploration of unknown waters and depths, and shifting coasts. This exhibit coincides with the Computational Archaeology &amp;amp; Seafaring Theory Workshop being sponsored by the Archaeology Center and collaborating centers and institutions both on and beyond campus. The exhibition was curated by Justin Leidwanger, Beth Minney and Nicole Constantine; it was coordinated and mounted by Kristina Larsen.&amp;nbsp; The exhibition opens at the same time as the&amp;nbsp;&lt;i&gt;Micronesian&amp;nbsp;Seafaring System&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;talk and can be viewed during the Center&amp;#39;s open hours until Feb 10, 2023.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Dec 2022 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/ImaginingMaritimeSpacesExhibition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426818</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.16714</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41768402192589/huge/c260d776d652a9531faad55d7e816255851dad66.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="866" width="1200" isDefault="true" fileSize="321602"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for January&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays &lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt; is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jan 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286227988551/huge/cfbfaf020cbc3de75f000e5c7ff884e8ef279aef.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2023-01-30 Intro To Arduino at Terman Engineering Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;Rapid prototyping and design requires some ready-made solutions, while some projects can be solved using simple computational technologies. Arduino microprocessors are one possible solution, being affordable, easy-to-learn, and relatively powerful with a little bit of knowledge. In this hands-on workshop, you will explore how to leverage these microprocessors for your research projects. No experience is required. If you have a computer with administrative privileges to install software, it is encouraged to bring it to the session.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2023 11:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2023-01-30_intro_to_arduino</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41742486537603/huge/deb52e71643607c06f7552e637ff90ba0804f657.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="320" width="320" isDefault="true" fileSize="17930"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays at Green Library, East Wing, SVA Seminar Room (Hohbach 126)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Save the date for February&amp;#39;s &lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&amp;nbsp;&lt;/i&gt;(theme and featured games TBD).&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays&lt;/i&gt;&amp;nbsp;is a new event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we&amp;#39;ll feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL&amp;#39;s holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month&amp;#39;s featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Feb 2023 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop_tuesdays_1402</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41286228185169/huge/557bc68859b3e0e31bd70178ca7542ad20827027.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="97366"/>
      <category>Other</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
