<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Highlights from the Apple Inc. Collections in the Silicon Valley Archives  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Apple Inc. (formerly: Apple Computer, Inc.), located in Cupertino, California, has long been one of Silicon Valley's iconic technology companies. It was founded in 1976 by Steve Jobs, Steve Wozniak, and Ron Wayne (who shortly thereafter sold his share in the company) to develop computers for personal use. Their first product was the Apple I computer. Apple products such as the Apple I and Il and Macintosh personal computers, the iPod music player, the iPod, the iPhone, and the iTunes Music Store have been successful in the marketplace, defined new product categories, and influenced design generally. Apple has during the last decade generally been among the world's largest companies by market capitalization.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The Stanford University Libraries have acquired approximately forty archival collections, as well as print and media resources, on the history of Apple. The foundation for building this set of collections was the acquisition of the Apple Computer, Inc. Records in 1997, shortly after Steve Jobs returned to the company as its CEO. This collection alone consists of roughly 600 linear feet of documentation and other materials assembled by Apple staff over a period of more than a decade. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit runs from August 29 to October 15, 2025. This exhibit is free and open to the public. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/about-stanford-libraries/visit-us" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on the Libraries’ website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/highlights-from-the-apple-inc-collections-from-the-silicon-valley-archives</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50605570132695/huge/1d3ffaed07523e9d80553eee6ce8abb06be88cbe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2041" width="2722" isDefault="true" fileSize="354813"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spotlight on Special Collections at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/a&gt;, on view in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda from May 15 to October 26, 2025.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/"&gt;Spotlight Exhibits&lt;/a&gt; is an open-source digital exhibit platform developed and maintained by Stanford’s Digital Library Systems and Services department (DLSS). Eleven years since its inception, the site hosts 164 online exhibits that span the range of Stanford’s general and special collections and cover such diverse topics as &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/mss"&gt;Ancient, Medieval, and Early Modern Manuscripts&lt;/a&gt;, Philip Zimbardo’s &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/spe"&gt;Stanford Prison Experiment&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/sunset"&gt;Sunset Magazine&lt;/a&gt;, the &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/gardiner-sfba"&gt;Gardiner Transit Collection&lt;/a&gt;, and the photography archives of &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/fitch"&gt;Bob Fitch&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/bacon"&gt;David Bacon&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href="https://exhibits.stanford.edu/menuez"&gt;Douglas Menuez&lt;/a&gt;.  Created by Stanford librarians, faculty, and students, and arranged and described in narrative format, the site’s digital content is accessed thousands of times a day. It helps make the libraries’ collections accessible to a vast audience of researchers at Stanford and beyond.  DLSS continues to add functionality, including the display of streaming media. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition, &lt;i&gt;Spotlight on Special Collections&lt;/i&gt;, invites viewers into the deep collections that underlie or form the basis for the digital exhibits by presenting original artifacts, books, and manuscripts represented on the platform. Library curators selected from the approximately 100 Spotlight exhibits that feature Special Collections and University Archives content to show in the galleries. Original objects on display include historical photographs, books, illuminated manuscripts, early printed documents, musical scores, objects related to Stanford’s history, and ephemera representing movements for social change. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No single exhibition could capture the full range and diversity of the content available on the Spotlight platform. However, with this exhibition, we have endeavored to represent the depth and breadth of this rich resource as it pertains to our Special Collections and University Archives holdings. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This exhibition is curated by Benjamin Lee Stone with Rebecca Wingfield and Franz Kunst, Benjamin Albritton, Ray Heigemeir, Josh Schneider, with Connor Yankowitz, Kathleen Smith, Charlotte Kwok-Glasser, and Natalie Marine-Street; produced by Deardra Fuzzell with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach and Connor Yankowitz. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spotlight-on-special-collections</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49517102456786/huge/ef13e9ac8bc8849ce49f9fa880f7850953f4ff53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="123903"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Acquisitions exhibition, Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library, Summer 2025 at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stop by to visit a selection of new artists' books acquired for the Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library Locked Stacks collection. Works range from Chinese takeout menus to a photobook about a team measuring ice cores in Antarctica. Curated by Lorna Corbetta and Katie Keller. Opening June 9th.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/new-acquisitions-exhibition-summer-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49854519808297/huge/56ab3bf03905c7e4495658677692b27b2c03a073.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3360" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="2379979"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibition is only available to view during the &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/Rumsey"&gt;David Rumsey Map Center's public drop-in hours&lt;/a&gt;. Please check our website for our most updated information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/83a42ebc28b44fe7b355532da798b938"&gt;view digitally&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Colonial Gulf: How Empires Documented a Region at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span&gt;How have colonial and imperial regimes imagined and represented the Persian Gulf? &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibit explores how the British, Ottoman and American empires documented the human and non-human geography, resources, and landscapes of the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It features historical maps and artifacts from the collections of the Branner Earth Sciences Library and the David Rumsey Map Center alongside cartographic visualizations created by the &lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/"&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt; research collective.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Featured materials include maps derived from a dataset collected from the &lt;i&gt;British Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabia, and Oman&lt;/i&gt; created using QGIS, including the map of mentions of date palms displayed here.  By placing these historical materials and contemporary analyses in conversation, we uncover a genealogy of geographical thinking alongside the power structures embedded in imperial and colonial record-keeping.  This exhibit aims to illustrate and critically engage the breadth, depth, and nature of colonial and imperial knowledge production regarding the Persian Gulf and Arabian Peninsula, highlighting its varied expressions in texts, maps, and charts.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/b90cd597a47f46d39567b4c9824ca6ee"&gt;&lt;span&gt;view digitally&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Sponsored by: &lt;a href="https://history.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Dept. of History&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt;, &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://cesta.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;CESTA&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;b&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford Libraries&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;&lt;span&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11.0pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/colonial-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49820497130375/huge/021478f5ef78e5ba12d6141026a426a42130fff1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="667372"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Oceans: Pacific Ocean at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Oceans&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From the complexity of deep trenches to the shifting dynamics of sea ice, Earth’s oceans are vital to understanding our planet’s past, present, and future. In the 2025–2026 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature ocean geology, biology, physics, chemistry, and mapping, highlighting their roles in regulating the climate, sustaining biodiversity, and connecting global systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;September - October: Explore the unique geology of the Pacific Ocean with its deep trenches, fast-spreading ridges, and volcanic island chains through books, electronic resources, and maps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a valid, physical government-issued photo ID to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-exhibit-pacific-ocean</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50659519179157/huge/676fa101f5b2a2b416cc19e1be4c115d8bd765ec.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="379149"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Library Treasure Hunt 2025</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Embark on a quest across campus and discover the amazing resources our libraries and research centers have to offer!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;b style="font-style:normal;"&gt; &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The treasure hunt opens on &lt;b&gt;Monday September 15th and ends on Friday October 3rd at 5pm.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://guides.library.stanford.edu/LibTreasureHunt25"&gt;Participate in the Library Treasure Hunt 2025&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/library-treasure-hunt-2025</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50641285814605/huge/bee389148b6b02c255963ddd52ad36ad26a4b60b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="309627"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>East Asia Library Open House at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come visit the East Asia Library for our annual Open House event!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy some snacks outside the library entrance and socialize with fellow new and returning students.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet the East Asia Library curators and view items from the library's collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explore the East Asia Library, learn more about our services, and play games to win prizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The East Asia Library is located on the second floor of the Lathrop Library building.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/east-asia-library-open-house-9294</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50667885042250/huge/7d327620b021bb7ae33c10c16f5187ed88302594.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1308" width="1962" isDefault="true" fileSize="714626"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library Open House at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Welcome&lt;/b&gt; to all new and returning students, faculty, and staff! Visit our beautiful library and explore the study spaces. On view in the seminar room, a special selection of artists' books from our Locked Stacks collection. We're located on the 2nd floor of the McMurtry Building on Roth Way. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/bowes-art-architecture-library-open-house-3019</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50597799114178/huge/5fcec1d7f5347ffda6b2986d7ed1985fff0bca31.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2000" width="1545" isDefault="true" fileSize="364835"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science Library Open House at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome in! Come explore your Robin Li &amp;amp; Melissa Ma Science Library:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Join a guided tour.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discover answers to &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/library-treasure-hunt-2025"&gt;Library Treasure Hunt &lt;/a&gt;questions to win prizes.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try your hand at tabletop puzzles and games.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take a selfie with Einstein.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Meet your subject librarians and fellow new grad students over light refreshments.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Li &amp;amp; Ma Science Library is located on the 3rd and 4th floors of the Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning. The Science Library entrance is on the 3rd floor.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/sciencelibrary_openhouse_2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50640932848334/huge/a47e7fdd70a7a9a80661e065b9862f31621ea8f2.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="272380"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Library Welcome Table at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Green Library's Access Services team is excited to welcome you to the 2025-2026 Academic Year! Join us at our Welcome Table on September 15 and 16, 3-5pm for an introduction to all the fantastic services and resources we have to offer!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;New book displays&lt;/b&gt; featuring the latest additions to our collections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Popular fiction&lt;/b&gt; recommendations to jumpstart your reading list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Course reserves information&lt;/b&gt; to help you access required materials quickly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Swag and pomotional items &lt;/b&gt;to take with you&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Live demonstrations&lt;/b&gt; of our Interlibrary Loan (ILL) quick request system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Information about our services&lt;/b&gt;, including after-hours access and alumni services&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;"Guess how many candies are in the jar,"&lt;/b&gt; drawing to win the jar of candy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Small crocheted creatures drawing&lt;/b&gt; - enter to win adorable crocheted creatures!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Expert staff &lt;/b&gt;ready to answer questions about accessing materials from other libraries&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our knowledgeable Access Services staff will be on hand both days to help you discover everything the library has to offer and get you set up for academic success!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is your chance to learn about services you might not know existed and connect with the team that's here to support your research and study needs throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please note:&lt;/b&gt; Please bring your Stanford ID card to enter the library, or present your government-issued ID card at the front-desk to sign-in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop by anytime during our hours - we can't wait to meet you and help make this your best academic year yet!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Sep 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/green-library-welcome-table</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50659780583282/huge/c565e4485857ae25f5693855fc178051aa7a3bb0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="776969"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Terman Engineering Library Open House at Jen-Hsun Huang Building (School of Engineering)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Welcome to our new and returning engineering students, faculty, and staff! Join the Terman Library staff for a range of activities including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Collaborative art projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Board games and puzzles&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;A retro gaming tournament (including prizes for three winners)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li class="desc_normal"&gt;Free food and drink&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Terman staff will also offer tours of the space and answer any questions you may have about library services!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/terman-engineering-library-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427784</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.174323</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50517884480279/huge/2929b204d53bbbc588451aefd0fab6e89fd2a91c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="581527"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rock, Paper, Maps: Tour the Earth Science library, map, GIS, &amp; SDSS specimen collections at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Branner Earth Science Library &amp;amp; Map Collections will be hosting an open house!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;On Wednesday, September 17th, 10am - 12pm, we will have snacks and on-going guided tours of the library and map collections. We will also have historic books and maps related to National Hispanic Heritage Month on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tours of the Stanford Doerr School of Sustainability specimen collections and introductory demos to spatial data resources (ArcGIS, Planet.com, Google Earth Engine) will occur &lt;b&gt;every 30 minutes, starting at 10am. Tours will start at the library front desk.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The library is located on the 2nd floor of the Mitchell Earth Sciences Building.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please bring your Stanford ID card to enter the library, visitors must present their government issued ID card at the front-desk to sign-in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50649772340384/huge/88100d324db6a9e497acd33beb59fbc6b1cc7663.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="1228662"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Media Center Open House  at Green Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Media &amp;amp; Microtext Center is ready to kick off the 2025-2026 Academic Year! Join the Media &amp;amp; Access Services staff for an (re)-introduction to our space and our collections!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We will have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A media format "petting zoo." Never seen microfilm before? Prepare to encounter reels in their natural habitat!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Video game consoles ready for drop in play&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Film viewing stations playing some of your favorites for drop in viewing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Media &amp;amp; Microtext Center equipment demos&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;TO-GO Snacks!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Special &lt;i&gt;behind the scences &lt;/i&gt;tours of our Media Cage Stacks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staff can't wait to welcome you in &amp;amp; get you excited for the year ahead!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please note: Please bring your Stanford ID card to enter the library, or present your government issued ID card at the front-desk to sign-in.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/media-center-open-house</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426903</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167571</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50597582179101/huge/43634bf080b4a7ec0f1f5bfd88e169bb5ce5ed34.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="682057"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rescuing Federal Research Data (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;This month Yea-Hung Chen and Ariel Deardorff from UCSF will present on efforts to safeguard disappearing government data. Since early 2025 several federal research datasets have been altered or deleted in response to executive orders from the White House. These actions have raised significant concerns about the accessibility and integrity of government data. For example, in February, several datasets from the US Census Bureau suddenly became unavailable, and others from the CDC were removed and then later restored. In this presentation, we will explore the latest developments in data censorship and the current efforts to rescue and preserve government datasets. You’ll learn about the organizations that have worked to preserve data, alternative sources of government data, and how you can get involved to protect valuable public information.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;a href="https://bayareaopensciencegroup.github.io/" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is a growing community for Bay Area academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Sep 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rescuing-federal-research-data</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50570231024589/huge/8c5ce33cf0980d250cc52255f5b27b4daffd904d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="500" width="500" isDefault="true" fileSize="102446"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an Introduction to NVivo workshop for social science students.  Please register for this session at the following link below:  &lt;a href="https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current"&gt;https://stanforduniversity.qualtrics.com/jfe/preview/previewId/518d849d-41b9-4b33-bba2-2085b86c30fa/SV_cFOCU1m0qSzru7Q?Q_CHL=preview&amp;amp;Q_SurveyVersionID=current&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-2336</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47746634515153/huge/4b7271aa6a1855e0b196ba9e4f4d29d03c880256.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="76653"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to QGIS (Sept 26th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis and Map Construction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Sep 2025 09:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/intro_qgis_sept26</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50650021264656/huge/d58382f83b81d5b7ce8c35567e33ae822072a104.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="422" width="597" isDefault="true" fileSize="284421"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Oct. 1 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-1579</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693383361026/huge/838ff72604f0e90be0f1b695121646316b0c9411.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to QGIS (Oct 2nd) at Branner Earth Sciences Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop will focus on the fundamental concepts and skills needed to begin using Geographic Information Systems software for the exploration and analysis of spatial data using the open source GIS package QGIS. Topics covered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a GIS?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spatial Data Models and Formats&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Projections and Coordinate Systems&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Data Management&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The QGIS User Interface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic Analysis and Map Construction&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. This workshop or prior GIS experience are required for most other SGC workshops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Oct 2025 09:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-introduction-to-qgis-sept-26th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50650057515314/huge/bfdeac92f762f8486dcecdbe2d10206b9c2a14cb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="422" width="597" isDefault="true" fileSize="284421"/>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits: The Making of a Children's Book at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This exhibition showcases &lt;i&gt;Lavinia's Wondrous Portraits&lt;/i&gt;, a children’s book by Stanford art historian Emanuele Lugli that explores why portraits matter through the life and work of Lavinia Fontana, Europe’s first professional woman painter. Illustrated by Chiara Palillo, the book is more than a study of portraiture and early modern women—it is an artist’s book in itself, a hybrid creation where collage, acrylic, cyanotype, and digital color converge in playful, unexpected ways.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/lavinias-wondrous-portraits-the-making-of-a-childrens-book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50569364017038/huge/5bb505839ed649401c32d60e7c1b38b22b8da0c8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="900" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="77463"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (Oct 7th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the More Info link for registration and workshop landing page URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-georeferencing-in-qgis-april-18th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50650072100898/huge/3a8e0a610720c0afb9e01f53439a3ab12d8985bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Please join us for the fifth biennial Ruderman Conference on Cartography, to be held &lt;b&gt;October 8-10, 2025&lt;/b&gt; at the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Speakers from a variety of disciplinary backgrounds and specializations will share their expertise about cartography of anything but the earth's surface, from the ocean's depths to the stars. Keynote speakers include &lt;b&gt;Betsy Mason&lt;/b&gt; (freelance science journalist) and &lt;b&gt;Peter Bellerby&lt;/b&gt; (Bellerby and Co. Globemakers).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conference speaker info can be found on the &lt;a href="https://ruderman.sites.stanford.edu/" rel="nofollow noopener noreferrer ugc" target="_blank"&gt;Barry Lawrence Ruderman Conference on Cartography website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/barry-lawrence-ruderman-conference-on-cartography</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50162629646370/huge/4c9881418fd324cfb22f8e4eb2bd13c195a6e2c7.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1562" width="3374" isDefault="true" fileSize="2814865"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>"Essential Engagement: The Works of Joseph DeLappe" Exhibit Opening and Artist Talk at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Join us for the opening of &lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Essential Engagement: The Works of Joseph DeLappe&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;, a retrospective exhibit of the works of Joseph DeLappe (b. 1963) in the Silicon Valley Archives exhibition space, Hohbach Hall, Cecil H. Green Library, on the Stanford campus. This event will feature an artist’s talk by Joseph DeLappe, followed by an engaging conversation with Joel Slayton, founding director of the CADRE Lab at San Jose State University, to celebrate the opening of this exhibit.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;The prolific work of Joseph DeLappe, spanning a wide range of physical and digital mediums, provides an opportunity for critical reflection and thoughtful discussions about our relationship to technology and the post-9/11 political landscape. As the most comprehensive repository of materials related to the history and development of the Silicon Valley region, the Silicon Valley Archives is honored to exhibit a selection of this work and bring the history of recent technology into conversation with our present through this pioneering artist’s work.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Growing out of a prior project and conference at San Jose State in 1984, the CADRE Lab was founded as an academic program for exploring the emerging interactions between computation and the arts. It was arguably the first such lab, and the first student to pass through the program was Joseph DeLappe. Joel Slayton, the founding director of the Lab, will join us for a conversation about CADRE’s impact on digital and media arts, particularly in the Bay Area. This conversation will be moderated by Henry Lowood, the Harold C. Hohbach Curator and head of the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;A guided tour of the exhibit will follow the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/1Jel1ombwQA7e6lQi2YfvsBmMFzJ5V0SziokK1L67oVw/preview" style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;Registration is requested&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joseph DeLappe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:inherit;"&gt;, born San Francisco 1963, is an artist, activist and educator, he relocated to Scotland from the USA in 2017 where he is the Professor of Games and Tactical Media at Abertay University, Dundee. Working with electronic and digital media since 1983, projects in online gaming performance, sculpture and electromechanical installation have been shown throughout the world. He has developed works for venues such as Eyebeam Art and Technology in New York, The Guangdong Museum of Art, China, the Southern Utah Museum of Art and Transitio MX, Mexico City, among many others. Creative works and actions have been featured widely in scholarly journals, books and in the popular media, including the &lt;i&gt;New York Times, The Australian Morning Herald, Art in America, The Guardian &lt;/i&gt;and the BBC.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="descnormal" style="text-align:start;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:medium;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:inherit;"&gt;Joel Slayton&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt; &lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;is a pioneering artist, researcher, and curator with over 35 years of experience involving art and technology. His work engages a wide range of practice including media, installation and performance and has been featured in over 100 exhibitions around the world. Joel is Professor Emeritus at San Jose State University where he was Founding Director of the CADRE Laboratory for New Media. Joel Slayton was 2018-2019 Stanford University Sterling Visiting Scholar in Department of Chemical Sysems and Biology in the School of Medicine. Joel was curator for the 5th LAST Festival Exhibition at the SLAC National Accelerator at Stanford University in 2018. From 2008-2016 Joel was Executive Director of ZERO1, a Silicon Valley based arts organization where he was responsible for the ZERO1 Biennial, an international exhibition program celebrating creativity and innovation in the arts. Joel serves on the Board of Directors of LEONARDO/ISAST (International Society for Arts, Science, and Technology) where he founded the Leonardo-MIT Press Book Series in 1999 and is a Senior Fellow of the Silicon Valley American Leadership Forum.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/essential-engagement</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50694747221575/huge/aa065cfa7a962ff74b283e17c41502a5185ded95.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3779" width="3785" isDefault="true" fileSize="10358048"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Nov. 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-2026</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693397424570/huge/41bca654587cde9ea86a68b313125093dc8f8074.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jeannette Estruth in Conversation with Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew on women libertarians in Silicon Valley at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming the historian Jeannette Estruth as she discusses her new research on the history of women libertarians in Silicon Valley. Jeannette will be joined in conversation by the Stanford historians Jennifer Burns and Jenni Depew.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Silicon Valley today represents not only a specific location in California but also a larger imaginative vision that shapes economic and social realities. In this powerful conceptual landscape, the libertarian political fantasy emerges as a critical factor of cultural reproduction. In this talk and the conversation that follows, Jeannette Estruth will reveal how the Libertarian Party in Silicon Valley of the 1990s built durable and significant connections between technology firms, media, and the voting public in ways that were deeply rooted in the specific geographies and histories of Santa Clara and San Mateo Counties. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This political moment in Silicon Valley rehearsed a powerful political script that combined technology, the free market, sexuality, gender, anti-statism, and electoral politics. Estruth argues that Santa Clara and San Mateo counties’ local Libertarian Parties were crucial to Silicon Valley’s libertarianism, and to its political development as a technology hub, a financial center, and a site of production for a powerful vision of the future. By turning back to the 1990s, we can learn much about the world we live in today. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jeannette Estruth&lt;/b&gt; is an assistant professor of history at Santa Clara University. Her writing has appeared in venues ranging from the Washington Post to the Business History Review. She is completing her book manuscript, &lt;i&gt;Think Different: Silicon Valley Activism and the Making of Modern American Politics&lt;/i&gt;, which explores the history of social movements, the technology industry, and economic culture in the United States.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jennifer Burns&lt;/b&gt; is a professor of history at Stanford University. She is a historian of the twentieth century United States working at the intersection of intellectual, political, and cultural history, with a particular interest in ideas about the state, markets, and capitalism and how these play out in policy and politics. Her most recent book, &lt;i&gt;Milton Friedman: The Last Conservative,&lt;/i&gt; is the first full biography of the influential economist and political figure. It was awarded the 2025 Reagan Book Prize and was a finalist for the 2024 Hayek Prize. She has published articles about the history of conservatism, libertarianism, and liberalism in a number of academic and popular journals, including &lt;i&gt;Reviews in American History, Modern Intellectual History, Journal of Cultural Economy, The New York Times, The New Republic, &lt;/i&gt;and&lt;i&gt; Dissent&lt;/i&gt;.   &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jenni Depew&lt;/b&gt; is a PhD student in history at Stanford University. She studies the history of American political thought and development from the 18th to 21st centuries. She has previously published work on the role of the U.S. Presidency in regards to civil rights, third parties in the 19th century, and Indigenous food sovereignty in her home state of Wisconsin. Her most recent work focuses on the history of libertarianism. Jennifer is also a Knight-Hennessy Scholar, JD student at Stanford Law School, and former graduate research assistant at the Stanford Internet Observatory (SIO).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2025 16:30:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/jeannette-estruth-in-conversation-with-jennifer-burns-and-jenni-depew-on-women-libertarians-in-silicon-valley</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50703481059715/huge/870f537346dcff60bfe8880798ff989b9ec4fdab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1572" width="1500" isDefault="true" fileSize="1594716"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Dec. 3 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7123</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/50693405343948/huge/daea989242dbe63d8d8d26df0ddd96a0e16e347b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
