<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Every archival collection that Stanford Libraries acquires must be processed before it can be made available for research. The expertise, thought, and care that goes into processing archival collections often occurs behind-the-scenes. Using the John Perry Barlow papers as a throughline, this exhibit explores the art of processing archival collections. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/paper_trails_the_art_of_processing_archival_collections</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40861265484890/huge/796758a62e11f9aaae17dc593730c2e172be4fbe.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="425" width="425" isDefault="true" fileSize="109634"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Xiaoze Xie: Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie's new exhibition, &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt;, opening on September 15, 2022, in the main second-floor exhibit space at the Stanford East Asia Library, reminds us that, if "knowledge is power," as the quotation goes, then books can become battlegrounds. For over ten years, Xie has been engaged in an ongoing project titled &lt;em&gt;Forbidden Memories&lt;/em&gt; that focuses on the history of banned books in China. &lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; features new works from this project. In addition to books from the artist's own collection, the exhibition will also feature several of Xie's sculptures. Working with photographs of books in public and private collections, Xie has created life-size, hand-sculpted and hand-painted porcelain reproductions of banned books both ancient and modern, some of which will be displayed publicly for the first time in this exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Flammable Ideas, Fragile Objects&lt;/em&gt; will be on view from September 15, 2022, through the end of Fall Quarter. An opening reception will be held on October 12, 2022, in the East Asia Library, room 224.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Xiaoze Xie, the Paul L. &amp; Phyllis Wattis Professor of Art at Stanford University, is an internationally recognized artist who has exhibited extensively in the US and abroad. His work is in the permanent collection of such institutions as the Denver Art Museum, the Museum of Fine Arts Houston, San Jose Museum of Art, the Scottsdale Museum of Contemporary Art, and Oakland Museum of California. Xie received the Asia Game Changer West Award from the Asia Society (2022), the Painter and Sculptor's Grant from the Joan Mitchell Foundation (2013), the Pollock-Krasner Foundation Grant (2003) and artist awards from Phoenix Art Museum (1999) and Dallas Museum of Art (1996).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/xiaoze_xie_flammable_ideas_fragile_objects</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41074045488313/huge/df720f80197b036bed4df7bb0508525112431604.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="195807"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Intro to R at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This introductory workshop is geared towards those who would like to get started with R or need to brush up on their skills. You will learn how to use R, RStudio, how to create objects in R, how to work with different data types, how to read tabular data into R and how to subset tables.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-intro" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cengel.github.io/R-intro" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-intro&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_intro_to_r</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932249899056/huge/8dc9c8ea8806e245a8b8412105c15224fb9f6546.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tag der Deutschen Einheit/Day of German Unity celebrating German graphic designer Otl Aicher at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the German national holiday Tag der Deutschen Einheit (Day of German Unity) on Monday, October 3rd, 2022, there will be a showcase of rare materials and works to celebrate the 100th anniversary of the birth of German graphic designer Otl Aicher (1922-1991).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The influential co-founder of the Ulm School of Design, Aicher designed numerous logos for companies such as Lufthansa, but his most famous legacy is as the head of the design team for the 1972 Summer Olympics in Munich, Germany. These Olympics were intended to present a cheerful and optimistic atmosphere and to represent West Germany to the world in a welcoming light, to contrast with last time the Olympics were held under Hitler in Berlin, Germany, in 1936. Tragically, the 1972 Olympics saw a horrific incident in which 12 people (11 Israeli athletes and coaches and 1 West German policeman) were taken hostage and then killed by the Palestinian terrorist group Black September. 2022 marks the 50th anniversary of these Olympics, and on October 19th, there will be an event at Stanford (&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/munich_an_evening_with_tony_kushner" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;MUNICH: An Evening with Tony Kushner&lt;/a&gt;) discussing the 2005 film &lt;em&gt;Munich&lt;/em&gt; based on this event, and how it is remembered in Germany, Israel, and the United States.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The 1972 Olympics were also remarkable for their comprehensive graphic design, covering not just print and the sports and informational pictograms, but souvenirs, stadium decoration, signable, and the first official Olympic mascot, Waldi the dachshund. On display will be &lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/13566293" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;original posters from the 1972 Olympics&lt;/a&gt; by artists such as David Hockney, Friedensreich Hundertwasser, Serge Poliakoff, Jan Lenica, Jacob Lawrence, Josef Albers, Tom Wesselmann, Max Bill and others.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The Day of German Unity celebrates the anniversary of German reunification in 1990, when East and West Germany were re-united after decades of separation following WWII. In 1990, Stanford University Libraries began actively acquiring primary source collections related to culture and cultural politics in East Germany, both in response to changing research interests and because more GDR items became available for acquisition.  &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image of David Hockney's poster for the 1972 Olympic Games from the collection "Olympische Spiele München posters" (in process), Dept. of Special Collections. &lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tag_der_deutschen_einheitday_of_german_unity_celebrating_german_graphic_designer_otl_aicher</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41171670683947/huge/d4a6923c380ec638a14a633dbbaf51e1c202cc62.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="356044"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS at Branner Earth Sciences Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the More Info link for registration and workshop landing page URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note:&amp;nbsp;&lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates&amp;nbsp;&lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;.&amp;nbsp;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing_in_qgis_2716</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39519065549929/huge/36ecf7eef696ef2fc4be5cd1cafb4c93c8ea2a25.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: SPORTS at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Special, Unique, and Rare! Don&amp;#39;t miss Green Library&amp;#39;s monthly pop-up exhibits, every first Tuesday, featuring extraordinary finds from Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; vast and diverse collections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us Tuesday, October 4, from 1:00-3:00 for our inaugural exhibit of rare, unique, and fun items from Stanford Libraries&amp;#39; collections that have something to say about SPORTS. Come with your curiosity and 15 minutes to wander and wonder, and leave inspired and engaged with the depth and breadth of resources the Libraries have to offer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford Libraries, Humanities and Area Studies Resource Group.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special_unique_and_rare_sports</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41171670959413/huge/e3e700be8ea795a7e3a4c114691a002bd20891f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="400" width="400" isDefault="true" fileSize="120290"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Intro to Python at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides an introduction to the Python programming language: basic syntax, variable assignment, functions, data import, and how to understand error messages and find help. You will learn enough Python to perform common tasks and explore the rich environment of Python packages available. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;None&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html" rel="noopener"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/intro.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_intro_to_python</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250061881/huge/d2e4e32e406efe067aecf7455d7ce3488d57c513.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, October 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_6004</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136263613740/huge/b7e1f5a033470e8d0298e41df564803421b6fd02.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Handmade Book at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/spc/current-exhibits" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;, on view October 6, 2022, through February 5, 2023 in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition &lt;em&gt;The Handmade Book&lt;/em&gt; is curated by Elaine Treharne and Benjamin Albritton, produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The exhibition is free and open to the public. Learn about the Libraries' &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/status" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;entry requirements and available services&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_handmade_book</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127511947685/huge/fa816f484827df107b7a256d92f54535a019c421.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="581" width="581" isDefault="true" fileSize="232881"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remembering Partition: 75 Years of Independence-Partition at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Come join us as we commemorate 75 years since the Partition of the Indian subcontinent with a panel discussion and presentation about the collaboration between The 1947 Partition Archive and Stanford Libraries to make almost 10,000 oral histories of Partition witnesses available online for streaming. The panel will feature local Partition witnesses; Founder of The 1947 Partition Archive, Guneeta Singh Bhalla; Fisher Family Director of Stanford Global Studies and Associate Professor in Theater and Performance Studies, Jisha Menon; and South Asian Studies Curator at Stanford Libraries, C. Ryan Perkins.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Oct 2022 17:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/remembering_partition_75_years_of_independence-partition</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40861269704928/huge/d6bcbdb386ad9de266796a4eccd3c9724bdedef8.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="400" width="400" isDefault="true" fileSize="61485"/>
      <category>Meeting</category>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Data Wrangling at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop is for those who know the basics of R and would like to get started working with their research data. We will look into the tools that R provides to manipulate and explore tabular data, including reshaping, summarizing, and plotting. You will learn how to use the tidyverse package, in particular dplyr, tidyr, and ggplot.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or equivalent knowledge).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-data-wrangling&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_data_wrangling_7852</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250218562/huge/bfb9ae4a2c8fd887c172b87e1b3356406acae374.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teaching the aspiring researcher: an educational workshop [Gear-Up] at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since 2020, every summer term the Libraries have partnered with several different undergraduate research programs on the Stanford campus. These programs are designed to help underrepresented students achieve their goals of entering into graduate school. With the shift towards more and more computational based research, helping these students learn about basic coding and programming is a critical skill. In this workshop you will hear from some of the students from these programs talk about their experiences in the program, how they used the information they learned to complete their projects, and how you can apply these teaching practices in your own work. This event will have live, hands-on teaching demonstrations, and will also cover content inspired by the computational program known as The Carpentries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructor: &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/zwp" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Zac Painter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a hybrid workshop. Upon registering you can select to attend in-person at the Li &amp; Ma Science Library in the SAPP Center or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/teaching_the_aspiring_researcher_an_educational_workshop_gear-up</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40994206451089/huge/240716b0315b871b74c99d864a1f7d7c7e9d5e16.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data Science in Practice [Gear-Up]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Quantitative Sciences Unit brings you a multi-part workshop!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Workshop Outline:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Intro to the QSU&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Presentation: "Data Visualization: Making great graphs for your next manuscript"&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Panel of Data Science Experts: "Ask Us Anything"&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Here is a brief description of the Presentation:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kate Miller, PhD MPH, Senior Biostatistician, Quantitative Sciences Unit, BMIR, Dept of Medicine, Stanford University&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Have you ever made a graph of your research results and wondered how to improve it? Communicating data effectively with graphs is essential to clinical research, and it is a far deeper skill than just applying the default settings in a data viz program. Every design decision in a graph should be informed by the specifics of your research as well as an understanding of how we humans process information and perceive data. In this highly interactive session, we will revise a graph step by step, applying two basic design principles. The concepts that participants will take away are simple yet powerful, and can be used with any type of quantitative data, any format for presentation (paper, poster, slide deck, interactive), and any graphics program (R, Python, D3, Tableau, Excel, etc.) The goal is for participants to walk out of the session with clear, practical tools for improving their next graph. &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/maples" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a virtual workshop. You will receive a Zoom link after registration. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/data_science_in_practice_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41109675035968/huge/c2a0f39f90456ca3d08a4d74cf04776fd3982c95.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Data Wrangling at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop teaches basic data manipulation with Python using the Pandas library, and will cover topics such as loading data into and out of a Pandas DataFrame, performing basic data cleaning, preparation, and analysis, and visualizing relevant aspects of a dataset.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python (or similar knowledge). (If you need a refresher, check out A Byte of Python (&lt;a href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://python.swaroopch.com/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://python.swaroopch.com/&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Data_Manipulation_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_data_wrangling_8825</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250516570/huge/4d275d9c657eed9acee248c0b43a6ffecfc8dbca.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Photovoice: A method to amplify communities' voice through participatory action research [Gear-Up] at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Participatory Action Research (PAR) is a study method that allows researchers and participants to look into specific topics or problems through an iterative cycle of research, dialogue, action, and reflection, using a range of qualitative and quantitative techniques. At the core of PAR resides the recognition of the value of local and traditional knowledge through direct involvement of community members in the research process.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Photovoice is a participatory photography methodology that uses participatory photography to empower participants to reflect on their personal experiences around a research question and share their perspectives through storytelling and focus groups. In this sense, participants act as co-researchers by interpreting the meaning behind their stories for the researchers. providing a participatory framework for the elicitation and representation of social and cultural knowledge.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In this workshop, participants will learn about how to design and prepare a photovoice project, as well as to analyze related qualitative and quantitative data related using a mixed-methods software, using environmental justice data.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructor: &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/maria-carrera-zamanillo" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Isabel Carrera Zamanillo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a hybrid workshop. Upon registering you can select to attend in-person at the Li &amp; Ma Science Library in the SAPP Center or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2022 15:15:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/photovoice_a_method_to_amplify_communities_voice_through_participatory_action_research_gear-up</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40994206729634/huge/618b0a8ff7850732e97b687d2474b873577b9c0d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Qualitative Research Software: NVivo Basics [Gear-Up]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a basic demonstration of how to use NVivo for Qualitative research projects. We will undertake a brief description of the basic features and some advanced aspects of the software. We will show how you can import, code and analyze data. The basic demonstration will be followed by a Q&amp;A. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructor: &lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/esha-chatterjee?tab=bio" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Esha Chatterjee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a virtual workshop. You will receive a Zoom link after registration. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/qualitative_research_software_nvivo_basics_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41109675372884/huge/dfbb21617b9f24668a6b07c7c3c0971ccd8c37cb.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>An Introduction to the Stanford Geospatial Center &amp; ArcGIS Online [Gear-Up]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Stanford Geospatial Center will present an orientation to their resources, as well as an hands-on Introduction to ArcGIS Online, for Beginners. The first part of this event will orient users to the resources and services of the SGC, including software provisioning and support as well as access to data sources like Planetscope Monitoring, a daily, global, 3 meter resolution, multispectral image. The second part of the event is designed to introduce new spatial data users to ArcGIS Online, part of an ecosystem of software and data that Stanford Libraries' provide to researchers for creating, managing analyzing and presenting their spatial data. No previous experience with spatial data is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructor: &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/maples" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Stace Maples&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a virtual workshop. You will receive a Zoom link after registration. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/an_introduction_to_the_stanford_geospatial_center_arcgis_online_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40994206997939/huge/0c5cfdb3b87477802eb45e86ffc33776a42cd73f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries is hosting its 2nd annual Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion (JEDI) Fair to highlight social justice projects, collections, and efforts happening within the Libraries and at other departments across the Stanford campus.   &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Hear featured speakers, see live demonstrations of the Know Systemic Racism (KSR) website and highlights from the Libraries existing social justice collections, attend a new book release and signing by co-authors Stephen Shames and Ericka Huggins, and pick up lots of great giveaways. &lt;em&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Following the Fair, starting at 4:30 pm in Green Library's Bender Room (5th floor), join co-authors Stephen Shames and Ericka Huggins of the newly released book, &lt;a href="https://www.marcusbooks.com/book/9781788841757" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comrade Sisters: Women of the Black Panther Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, and former Black Panther Party members &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1BI0HssRL8tk5BksnLJKDRHNcL-nB88V-/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;M. Gayle Asali Dickson&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1q23W1rBSEDu3lOjoOMvlAS-wCah1Iunl/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Rosita Thomas&lt;/a&gt; for a &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/panel_disussion_new_book_release_comrade_sisters_women_of_the_black_panther_party" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;panel discussion&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event will also be livestreamed. Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/XqMme5sL3GAzdGaXA" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="3" rel="noopener"&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; for the panel discussion and indicate if you will be attending in person or virtually. &lt;/strong&gt;Book sales and signing will follow.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Come expecting to leave empowered!&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Check back for updates.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice_equity_diversity_and_inclusion_jedi_fair_8413</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40621750570646/huge/c2b7a9495971b7d8f110b5dab27e32fc73fa9c8e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="181353"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panel Discussion: New book release, "Comrade Sisters: Women of the Black Panther Party" at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of us have heard these three words: Black Panther Party.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Some know the Party's history as a movement for the social, political, economic, and spiritual upliftment of Black and indigenous people of color – but to this day, few know the story of the backbone of the Party: the women... While these remarkable women of all ages and diverse backgrounds were regularly making headlines agitating, protesting, and organizing, these same women were building communities and enacting social justice&lt;em&gt;... &lt;a href="https://www.marcusbooks.com/book/9781788841757" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Comrade Sisters&lt;/a&gt; &lt;/em&gt;is their story.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Please join Stanford Libraries as we host what is sure to be an exciting discussion featuring co-authors Stephen Shames and Ericka Huggins of the newly released book, &lt;a href="https://www.marcusbooks.com/book/9781788841757" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Comrade Sisters: Women of the Black Panther Party&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. Mr. Shames and Ms. Huggins will be joined by two other former Black Panther Party members, M. Gayle Asali Dickson and Rosita Thomas for the discussion.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;The panel discussion will begin at 4:30 pm following the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/justice_equity_diversity_and_inclusion_jedi_fair_8413" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;JEDI (Justice, Equity, Diversity, and Inclusion) Fair&lt;/a&gt;, (2–4 pm).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The event will also be livestreamed. Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/XqMme5sL3GAzdGaXA" target="_blank" data-auth="NotApplicable" data-safelink="true" data-linkindex="3" rel="noopener"&gt;RSVP&lt;/a&gt; for the panel discussion and indicate if you will be attending in person or virtually.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Book sales and signing will follow.&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ericka Huggins&lt;/strong&gt; is an activist, former political prisoner, and leader in the Black Panther Party. She has devoted her life to the equitable treatment of all human beings, beyond the boundaries of race, age, culture, class, gender, sexual orientation, ability, and status associated with citizenship. For the past 40 years, she has lectured across the country and internationally. She spent 14 years in the Black Panther Party, and eight years as Director of the renowned Oakland Community School (1973-1981).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stephen Shames &lt;/strong&gt;has authored 15 monographs, and his images are in the permanent collections of 40 museums and foundations. His work is dedicated to promoting social change and sharing the stories of those who are frequently overlooked by society. His two previous Panther books are Power to the People: The World of the Black Panthers by Stephen Shames and Bobby Seale (Abrams,2016) and The Black Panthers (Aperture, 2006).&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. Gayle Asali Dickson&lt;/strong&gt; is an ordained minister and served as Pastor of the South Berkeley Congregational Church (SBCC), United Church of Christ, in Berkeley, CA from 1998 - 2006. Prior to serving as pastor of SBCC, Gayle Asali was a graphic artist for the Black Panther Party (BPP) Newspaper and drew for its back pages under the name Asali. She also served as a preschool teacher at its Oakland Community School... &lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1BI0HssRL8tk5BksnLJKDRHNcL-nB88V-/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Read more&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;In the early 1970s, at age 20, &lt;strong&gt;Rosita Holland Thomas&lt;/strong&gt; joined the Seattle Chapter of the Black Panther Party to work with the organization's community Survival Programs. She played a central role administratively and organizationally in establishing the Free Medical Clinic while also working side by side with fellow Party and community members to implement the free breakfast for schoolchildren programs, the free busing to prisons program...&lt;em&gt; &lt;/em&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1q23W1rBSEDu3lOjoOMvlAS-wCah1Iunl/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;em&gt;Read more&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Oct 2022 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/panel_disussion_new_book_release_comrade_sisters_women_of_the_black_panther_party</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40870123249674/huge/6dbd0e8a2f54a55a85774b30aa6beb6975af01ab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="250070"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The business data resources most popular with science researchers [Gear-Up]</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Todd Hines and Rashelle Pragar, GSB Library business librarians, will give summary overviews of several of the business data resources most heavily used by science researchers, including how to access Wall Street analyst reports and recommended sources for researching science-related industries.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructors: Todd Hines and Rashelle Pragar&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a virtual presentation. You will receive a Zoom link after registration. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the_business_data_resources_most_popular_with_science_researchers_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41047357212047/huge/2567c54e7f4f2448025ecad164352ec0b95c24ea.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Messy Time Series Data [Gear-Up] at Sapp Center for Science Teaching and Learning</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop introduces you to working with messy time series data. We will teach you about common pitfalls for data sourcing and continuity through use of Gross Domestic Product (GDP) as a rough measure of global societal well-being. The first hour will introduce GDP to discuss these issues when different reporting agencies, incentives, and approaches are considered. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The second hour will dive into code that compares results of different models based on endogenous and exogenous data filling methods, along with useful guidance on tools for vectorized approaches to your data. Basic Python proficiency is assumed if you want to run the examples, but all are welcome to attend and learn about data robustness issues and how the concepts might be useful to apply to your own data and research. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;If you want to learn basic Python, visit us at &lt;a href="https://ssds.stanford.edu/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;https://ssds.stanford.edu &lt;/a&gt;to register for the upcoming Text Analysis and Machine Learning (TAML) Bootcamp (September 19, 21, and 23) or Introduction to Python workshop (October 5). &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Instructors: &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/research/software-and-services-data-science/people" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Anthony Weng&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/muzzall" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Evan Muzzall&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a hybrid workshop. Upon registering you can select to attend in-person at the Li &amp; Ma Science Library in the SAPP Center or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Oct 2022 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/understanding_messy_time_series_data_gear-up</link>
      <geo:lat>37.430651</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171413</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40994207358413/huge/174c1eb8cee1cfcdfb1b422fa9b75147921740d5.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gear-Up for Science Data Symposium  [Gear-Up] at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Real data is not always perfect. Sometimes, it is messy. Sometimes, it is not nice to work with. The Fall 2022 Gear-Up for Science Data Symposium will conclude a series of workshops, talks and demos (Oct. 10-12) exploring the techniques used by experts to find, prepare, manage and analyze non-idealized data for research and analytics. This in person event will provide a forum to present and discuss the obstacles scientists face when collecting and analyzing data, as well as showcasing the variety of library services available for researchers to help in the acquisition and analysis of research data.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Schedule:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:00p Introduction&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:05p Student and Postdoc Lightning Talks&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;2:30p Keynote Speakers&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;3:45p Panel Discussion&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;4:05p Social Hour &amp; Library Resource Fair  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;At Koret Park (courtyard adjacent to Green Library East Wing Exit &amp; Coupa Cafe)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keynote Speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/elliott-white-jr-" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Elliott White Jr.&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;  &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;em&gt;From Sauntering Through Swamps to Scanning Satellite Scenes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;Coastal forested wetlands are critical components of the coastal ecosystem mosaic; however, climate change threatens their existence. Remote sensing offers a powerful tool to examine this ecosystem at a broad scale, but there are challenges to using these data.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/maria-monzani" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Maria Elena Monzani&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;Data-Intensive searches for Dark Matter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract:&lt;/strong&gt; The nature and origin of dark matter are among the most compelling mysteries of contemporary science. There is strong evidence for dark matter from its role in shaping the galaxies and galaxy clusters that we observe in the universe. Still, for over three decades, physicists have been trying to detect the dark matter particles themselves with little success. Given the extremely elusive nature of the hypothetical dark matter particle, the experiments trying to discover it have collected increasingly massive datasets, which pose tremendous "needle in a haystack" challenges. In my talk, I will describe two of the experiments currently looking to detect dark matter, together with their associated datasets, and some of the data handling tools employed for their analysis.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/dominique-bergmann" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Dominique Bergmann&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Presentation Title:&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Following biology (and data) across spatial scales in a changing world&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Abstract: &lt;/strong&gt;When considering how plants adapt their development to prevailing climates, data vary in type and completeness. One on end of the scale, detailed microscopy-based imaging may capture how cells divide in a single growing leaf, or the genes expressed in each in of those cells in the leaf. On the other end, characterizing the genetic variation of in genomes of plant populations growing across the world, or preserved in the last 300 years in herbaria involves a massive collaborative effort to obtain, compare and standardize samples. In my talk, I will highlight how we evaluate data from diverse sources, and some challenges we've encountered when data originate from disciplines with different norms and expectations. I will also answer questions about the changing publishing landscape from the perspective of an author and of an editorial board member for general audience and specialty journals.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/gear-up_for_science_data_symposium_gear-up</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41047357469095/huge/9d95e34a77ed256b03d1046eb415f94ebbd1c69f.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="498" width="498" isDefault="true" fileSize="93125"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>HOWLoween 2022: Celebrating Wolf Awareness Week at Stanford Libraries on Oct. 17-22 at Green Library, East Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/blogs/stanford-libraries-blog/2021/10/howloween-2021-celebrating-wolf-awareness-week-stanford#:~:text=We%20love%20Halloween%20at%20Stanford,October%2018%2D22%2C%202021." target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;2021 celebration of HOWLoween: Wolf Awareness Week&lt;/a&gt; was such a success that we're holding it again this year! Join us at Green Library for National Wolf Awareness Week on October 16-22, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;SCHEDULE OF EVENTS&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;TBD on Monday, October 17&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tabletop Tuesday: Our Werewolves, Ourselves &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;In this session of Tabletop Tuesday, we will begin with an exploration of werewolves and their depictions in a wide variety of popular media. What does the long historical tradition of werewolf mythology and literature reveal about humans and our relationship with wolves? After this discussion, we will play the game Werewolf to discover who among us has the talent and drive to survive the game using our all-too-human skills of deception and treachery.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;SVA Seminar Room&lt;br /&gt;2-4:00PM on Tuesday, Oct. 18&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;"The Return of the Wolf"&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/amaroq-weiss-64806932" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Amaroq Weiss&lt;/a&gt;, Senior Wolf Advocate with the Center for Biological Diversity, will discuss the return of wolves to California and other limited parts of the lower 48 United States. Her talk will cover legal and policy issues around wolf recovery, wolf biology/behavior/ecology, and challenges wolves continue to face which require ongoing public involvement to protect and recover this magnificent representative of the wild.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;SVA Presentation Room 122&lt;br /&gt;7-8:00PM on Wednesday, Oct. 19&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Howling Lesson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://profiles.stanford.edu/stephanie-hunt" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Stephanie Hunt&lt;/a&gt; (Theater and Performance Studies) will teach us how to properly and safely howl using correct vocal techniques while thinking about the biological adaptations that make wolves such good howlers. The lesson will be followed by a "Group Howl." Although wolves are pack animals, physical distancing will be observed, esp. for the loudest howls. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Koret Park, outside Green Library&lt;br /&gt;5:00PM on Thursday, Oct. 20&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Wolf&lt;/em&gt; (1994), a Mike Nichols film&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/people/kensky" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Eitan Kensky&lt;/a&gt; (Judaica &amp; Hebraica curator) will introduce this 1994 "romantic horror office comedy" starring Jack Nicholson, Michelle Pfeiffer, James Spader, Christopher Plummer, etc., in which mild-mannered editor Jack Nicholson is bitten by a wolf and then discovers how well-suited his new werewolf abilities are for the cut-throat world of office politics. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;Green Library, IC Classroom&lt;br /&gt;4:00PM on Friday, Oct. 21&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Image credit to Gary Kramer. This is a public domain image from https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Front_view_of_a_resting_Canis_lupus_ssp.jpg&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/howloween_2022_celebrating_wolf_awareness_week_at_stanford_libraries_on_oct_17-22</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41197888250497/huge/5bcac789674848322adeb8a6d64bd018c8ce7a71.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="300" width="300" isDefault="true" fileSize="72838"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Visualization at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will review three base plots in R (histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot) before introducing you to the ggplot2 package. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/data-visualization-ggplot2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_visualization_4198</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250671203/huge/8466ae85e8a11a7e9b960861425e96bcc3352b3c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Visualization at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data visualizations are essential to effectively communicate research. This workshop will introduce you to three basic visualizations using the Python matplotlib and seaborn libraries: histogram, boxplot, and scatterplot. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html" rel="noopener"&gt;https://eastbayev.github.io/SSDS-TAML/fall2022/5_Data_visualization_essentials.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_visualization_2716</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250833004/huge/7f2578af5e30ac5ea3aceed9f6cbe8ae89e73601.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Book Madness by Denise Gigante at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Book Launch! Celebrating the publication of:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;a href="https://yalebooks.yale.edu/book/9780300248487/book-madness/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Book Madness: A Story of Book Collectors in America&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;(Yale University Press, 2022)&lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;by Denise Gigante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Sadie Dernham Patek Professor of Humanities&lt;br /&gt;Department of English, Stanford University&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Featured speakers:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Gavin Jones, Frederick P. Rehmus Family Professor of Humanities&lt;br /&gt;Peter Stansky, Frances and Charles Field Professor of History, Emeritus &lt;br /&gt;John Windle, Antiquarian Bookseller, San Francisco&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Book signing to follow. Learn more about &lt;em&gt;Book Madness&lt;/em&gt; by viewing &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1J18vKTXFNyrA5iYaLr5jFLDpkCdN2aRf/view?usp=sharing" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://drive.google.com/file/d/1J18vKTXFNyrA5iYaLr5jFLDpkCdN2aRf/view?usp=sharing" rel="noopener"&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The event will also be livestreamed. Please &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/6SmcvneAWJnCfpEPA" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;register&lt;/a&gt; for the event and indicate if you will be attending in person or virtually.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Oct 2022 17:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/book_madness_by_denise_gigante</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41127520396854/huge/b4900454615cd38819192c5b7b7a78c2f99d1a52.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="508" width="508" isDefault="true" fileSize="145548"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Text Analysis at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop will introduce you to working with text data using the spaCy and textacy Python libraries. You will learn to effectively streamline text preprocessing, understand word tokenization, sentence segmentation, part-of-speech tagging, and named entity recognition using a single document (a short excerpt from H.G. Wells's A Short History of the World) and across a corpus of legal documents. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Text_Analysis_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_text_analysis</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932250984565/huge/82224d6b0b7e89960e809345e84f0eabb5679551.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Text Analysis at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Are you interested in analyzing collections of novels or journal articles? Do you want to understand patterns across collections of tweets or other social media data? In this workshop, we'll learn how to import, clean, and analyze collections of text with R using several standard text mining libraries. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;The Introduction to R CIDR workshop or equivalent experience.&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;strong&gt; &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R:&lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt; https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cengel.github.io/R-text-analysis/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_text_analysis</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251165822/huge/372a5a9c3001e8a2ff66d0837b6be7a5386ecf09.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Python Machine Learning at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a gentle introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts. You will learn the basics for classifying text and images using the scikit-learn, lime, and tensorflow Python libraries. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to Python workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_to_ML_with_Python&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_python_machine_learning</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251322503/huge/4e467a322bbe91a3a909617185decb2273c1ed77.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR R Machine Learning at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop provides a beginner-friendly introduction to machine learning vocabulary and concepts, quantitative data preprocessing for machine learning, and the SuperLearner R package.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Introduction to R workshop (or similar experience).&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop, be sure to download and install:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;R: &lt;a href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://cloud.r-project.org/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://cloud.r-project.org/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li aria-level="1"&gt;RStudio Desktop Free: &lt;a href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/" rel="noopener"&gt;https://www.rstudio.com/products/rstudio/download/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/Workshops/tree/master/Intro_ML_R&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Oct 2022 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_r_machine_learning</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251469968/huge/51f6a2e7e1fcbaa0a3d6d5ed9d0d7aa5582da0ac.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, October 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;    &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Nov 2022 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_5863</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136264145214/huge/5ee944b777d1875b9aef6589a53800ffffa7793d.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR Bash and GitHub at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the first half of this workshop you will learn how to use the Bash programming language to interface with your computer's operating system and perform basic actions to navigate your file system and create and edit files and directories. In the second half you will apply these principles to use the collaborative version tracking platform GitHub to store your coding projects.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Basic familiarity with computers&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop - Mac users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you have the Xcode developer toolset installed. Open a Terminal and type&lt;br /&gt;xcode-select --install&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;When asked if you want to install the command line developer tools, click "yes/install"&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Before the workshop - Windows users&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Install git/gitbash by clicking here: &lt;a href="https://git-scm.com/downloads" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://git-scm.com/downloads" rel="noopener"&gt;https://git-scm.com/downloads&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;li&gt;Download the file and double-click it to run the installer&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/strong&gt; coming soon&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Nov 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_bash_and_github</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251619481/huge/23472b806847b1b93e55fe970a9c1640ab9a0de9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CIDR GitHub Pages at Hybrid</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this workshop you will build on the skills you learn in CIDR Intro to Bash and GitHub to create free static webpages for your CV, projects, and other activities.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This is a Hybrid workshop! Upon registering you can select to attend in-person (Velma Denning Room, 120F Green Library) or via Zoom. &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Prerequisites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;CIDR Bash and GitHub (or equivalent knowledge)&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Workshop materials:&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;ul&gt;  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021" target="_blank" data-cke-saved-href="https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021" rel="noopener"&gt;https://github.com/sul-cidr/gh-pages-2021&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;  &lt;/ul&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/cidr_github_pages</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/40932251771042/huge/d6401eae129ace21d99e2c11ead4f4364066f364.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="45357"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grand Opening of Hohbach Hall at Green Library, East Wing, 1st floor</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Join us for the Grand Opening of Hohbach Hall!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Experience Silicon Valley like never before during a self-paced Open House celebrating the opening of Hohbach Hall, the home of the Silicon Valley Archives in Green Library. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;During the open house you will have the opportunity to engage with:&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;"I Never Knew I Could Study That"&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Join Professor of History Thomas Mullaney as he discusses how archival research is key to inclusion, engagement and belonging in the classroom. Using items from the Libraries' collection that illustrate the global history of computing, he will demonstrate how he continues to upstream, scale-up, and diversify the hands-on research experience within the Humanities and Social Sciences. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Digital Storytelling&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Meet digital storyteller and documentary film-maker Kathy Cotton who produced &lt;em&gt;A Place at the Table: The Story of African American Pioneers of Silicon Valley&lt;/em&gt;. Kathy is also the host of the Cottontails podcast that presents interviews with African Americans who have contributed to the on-going story of their communities' successes and the contributions that are made every day to African American history.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Collection Processing&lt;/em&gt; |&lt;/strong&gt; Enjoy a sneak peek into the papers of John Perry Barlow, Electronic Frontier Foundation founder and Grateful Dead lyricist in the exhibition &lt;em&gt;Paper Trails: The Art of Processing Archival Collections&lt;/em&gt;. This exhibit not only presents selections from his papers, but carefully explores the work that occurs behind-the-scenes in the library to organize, preserve and make archival collections accessible for research and teaching.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;a href="https://forms.gle/7ihUzrTfxtLoMN9M6" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please register if you would like to attend&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;-------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;About Hohbach Hall&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;The renovated first floor of Green Library's East Wing reopened Monday, January 3, 2022, as the newly named Hohbach Hall. The makeover was made possible by the &lt;strong&gt;Harold and Marilyn Hohbach Foundation&lt;/strong&gt; and has created a modern and inspiring space for research, collaboration, and study. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Anchored within Hohbach Hall is the &lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/projects/silicon-valley-archives" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Silicon Valley Archives&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;, which now has a physical space for students and scholars to engage with archival material focused on the history of Silicon Valley. Library patrons will be welcomed by a combined service desk that includes circulation and privileges staff, as well as reference librarians. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Designed by CAW Architects, the space offers myriad ways for patrons to engage with the space. Down the central corridor of Hohbach Hall is a promenade of exhibition cases with a walnut ceiling overhead mimicking a sine wave, a subtle nod to the audio oscillator developed in the region. A large presentation space is at the center of the Hall and outfitted for events and seminars. Sprinkled around the presentation space are group and individual study desks, several with views looking out to the Red Fountain or green spaces. Librarians will also be able to welcome students, faculty, and library guests into a new secure Special Collections room to examine rare objects and treasures. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;With the opening of Hohbach Hall, students and scholars have additional study and collaboration spaces, and visitors can discover a variety of objects, ephemera, and archives from the Stanford Libraries collection. &lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is much more to explore in the space! We look forward to welcoming you to Hohbach Hall.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 18:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/grand_opening_of_hohbach_hall</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41118625206593/huge/d3e23650ec58d2989f8af42e7cb75f603174bf79.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="255467"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
      <category>Film/Screening</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, October 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;  &lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/take_a_break_pet_a_dog_222</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/41136264572243/huge/1246dc2c65e22d7be1ceaf15d0f29974bdc97991.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="418" width="418" isDefault="true" fileSize="94748"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
