<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>ART/WORK at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;ART/WORK | Creative Pursuits of Stanford Libraries Staff&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; on view February 20, 2024, through April 27, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this exhibition, we sought to create a space where staff could share their artistic, creative side that may not otherwise be a part of their work at Stanford. In the Summer of 2024, Special Collections invited current Stanford Libraries staff to enter creative work in any medium to be considered for a Winter 2025 exhibit in Green Library’s Peterson Gallery and Rotunda. Response to the call for entries was hearty. In addition to traditional fine art techniques of drawing, painting, printmaking, and photography, submissions included mixed media sculpture, ceramics, collage, textiles, and poetry. An anonymous selection committee of library staff blind-reviewed over a hundred entries and chose the fifty works displayed in the galleries. We asked the people whose pieces were selected to write a brief statement to accompany their work in the exhibit and posed several questions for their consideration: Why do creative work? What medium do you work in and why? How did you get started? What does it mean to you to be an artist (if you define yourself as one)? Does art need an audience? Who is your audience? What influences your work, and whose work do you admire? As you will see, Stanford library staff are talented and thoughtful, pursuing many forms of creative work after hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo, Associate University Librarian, Director of Special Collections and Frances and Charles Field Curator of Special Collections; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their careful consideration of all staff art submissions, we thank the staff members who served on the jury; For their assessment of materials, Aisha Wahab and Beth Ryan in Conservation Services; For their assistance with logistics Ranelle Sharma and Jacob Cohn in Library Facilities, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/artwork</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48687359684680/huge/603b1fb303d73747de62963ba10e4c95a4135903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="78990"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Panoply of Pop-Ups exhibition, Bowes Library, Winter quarter at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spoiler alert: Come see flying playing cards in &lt;i&gt;Alice in Wonderland&lt;/i&gt; to Dada-inspired happenings in &lt;i&gt;Cabaret Voltaire. &lt;/i&gt;Featuring books from the Bowes Locked Stacks collection. Curated by Lorna Corbetta and Katie Keller. On view Winter quarter. M-Th 9-7, F 9-5, Sun 12-6. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 09:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/panoply-of-pop-ups-exhibition-bowes-library-winter-quarter</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48536008940945/huge/8a9499777f165c14ff6964627b2ef65d13591452.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="3264" width="3744" isDefault="true" fileSize="9109456"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Epicenters: Navigating Recovery and Renewal from Disasters at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;In the wake of disaster, maps play many roles, shaping understanding of the event in the immediate aftermath, serving as visceral portrayals for those who were not there, and communicating both scale and extent of the tragedy. They gavanize support for rebuilding by showing new possible futures and can be used to memorialize the event, inscribing the memory over the landscape. Drawing upon sources from historical representations to contemporary satellite imagery, the maps in this exhibition explore various ways communities use maps to make sense of calamity and move forward from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;The exhibition was curated by Stanford student Muhammad Dhafer, winner of the 2024 California Map Society student exhibition competition. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;This exhibition is ongoing and will be available until Friday, March 7th, 2025. To view the exhibit, visit the David Rumsey Map Center during its public drop-in hours.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 13:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/epicenters-navigating-recovery-and-renewal-from-disasters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426635</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167076</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47684547090877/huge/3760917787646284b7c17d5db40811eb358972fd.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1229" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="562133"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, Mar. 5 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 15:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-983</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Archiving the History of Modern Iranian Women at In person at Stanford (RSVP for location)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From Houri Moghadam to Homa Sarshar: Iranian Women Archives at Stanford &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a half-day conference celebrating important archival collections at Stanford University created by or about Iranian women. Scholars will explore the intricacies of archival creation, the vital role these collections play in preserving the modern history of Iranian women, and the pressing need for continued archival research and scholarship in this area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sponsored by Stanford's Green Library and the Hamid and Christina Moghadam Program in Iranian Studies&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;Conference is in English.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;AGENDA&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Welcome Remarks: 2:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panel One: 2:15-3:45 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coffee/Tea Break: 3:45-4:00 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Panel Two: 4:00-5:45 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Light Reception: 5:45-6:30 PM&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;PANELISTS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Kioumars Ghereghlou&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Kioumars Ghereghlou" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/ghereghlou_web.jpg" style="height:300px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kioumars Ghereghlou is the Curator for Middle East Collections at the Stanford University Libraries. His most recent book is a critical edition of Hayati Tabrizi’s (d. after 1554) newly-found chronicle of the early Safavids and the opening years of the reign of Shah Isma’il I (New Haven, Conn.: American Oriental Society, 2018).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sepideh Mohammadian&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Sepideh Mohammadian" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/mohammadian_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sepideh Mohammadian was born in 1986 in Tehran, Iran. She is an author, screenwriter and researcher. She earned her BA in Law and MA in sociology and is fluent in Farsi, English, French and Turkish. Mohammadian has been writing for 20 years now, working with Roshangaran Publication since the beginning of her career as a writer. She has worked with several literary magazines in Iran having published short stories and also is a member of Pen America. Mohammadian’s research works focus on semiotics in films and the difficulties social, racial and sexual minorities face in society. She has written eight books some of which are banned in Iran. Her latest book, &lt;i&gt;The Assembly of the Forgotten&lt;/i&gt;, which was banned in Iran, was recently published by Mehri Publication in London. Since she has been advocating for the freedom to write, particularly for marginalized voices, she actively promotes and highlights banned books by fellow writers on her social media platforms, aiming to raise awareness of their work and the unjust censorship they face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Negar Mottahedeh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Negar Mottahedeh" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/mottahedeh_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Negar Mottahedeh is a Professor of Literature at Duke University. Her research on film, social media, and social movements in the Middle East has been published with Stanford University Press, Syracuse University Press, Duke University Press. This includes her monographs &lt;i&gt;Whisper Tapes: Kate Millet in Iran&lt;/i&gt; which was published with Stanford UP in 2019, &lt;i&gt;Displaced Allegories: Iranian Cinema 1980-2000&lt;/i&gt; published with DUP in 2008 and&lt;i&gt; #iranelection: hashtag solidarity and the transformation of online life&lt;/i&gt;. She has written for WIRED magazine, The Hill, Salon.com, The Observer and The Wall Street Journal. She holds a PhD in Comparative Studies in Discourse and Society from the University of Minnesota and a BA in International Relations from Mount Holyoke College.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Abbas Milani&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Abbas Milani" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/abbas-milani_sm.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Abbas Milani is the Director of the Hamid and Christina Moghadam Program in Iranian Studies at Stanford University, an Adjunct Professor, and co-director of the Iran Democracy Project and a research fellow at the Hoover Institution. His expertise is U.S.-Iran relations as well as Iranian cultural, political, and security issues. Milani is the author of numerous books in Persian and English. Most recently, he published &lt;i&gt;30 Portraits&lt;/i&gt; (Persian Circle). Milani has also translated numerous books and articles into Persian and English. He has published more than 250 essays and book reviews in journals and papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Farzaneh Milani&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Farzaneh Milani" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/events/91716-1.jpg" style="height:300px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Farzaneh Milani is Raymond J. Nelson Professor Emerita of Iranian literature and Gender Studies at the University of Virginia. She has published several articles and books, most recently, &lt;i&gt;The Literary Biography of Forugh Farrokhzad and Unpublished Letters&lt;/i&gt;. Milani is currently working on a book project tentatively titled, “Iranian Women Writers at the Threshold of the Local and the Global.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Nahid Pirnazar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Nahid Pirnazar" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/pirnazar_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nahid Pirnazar is a lecturer of Iranian Studies at UCLA where she received her Ph.D. in 2004 in Iranian Studies with an emphasis on Judeo-Persian literature and Iranian Jewish History. She has been teaching the Habib Levy Visiting Professorship of Judeo-Persian Literature at UCLA since 2000, and the History of Iranian Jews at UCLA since 2007. Pirnazar is the founder and president of The House of Judeo-Persian Manuscripts, an academic organization, which collects, preserves, transliterates and publishes Judeo-Persian manuscripts. She presents her research internationally, which focuses on varied aspects of Judeo-Persian writings and Iranian literature as well as the history, culture and national identity of Iranian Jews. Among her many publications in both English and Persian, the most recent ones are: &lt;i&gt;Judeo-Persian Writings, A Manifestation of Intellectual and Literary Life&lt;/i&gt; (Routhledge, 2020); &lt;i&gt;Ketab-e Anusi, Poetic Narratives of the Life of Iranian Jews in the Safavid Era&lt;/i&gt;, which is the latest volume in the series  of “Ketab-e Iran Namag”, published jointly by University of Toronto, Elahe Omidyar Mir-Djalali Institute of Iranian Studies &amp;amp; Houses of Judeo-Persian Manuscripts, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Homa Sarshar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Homa Sarshar" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/sarshar_sq_0.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Homa Sarshar is a published author, award-winning journalist, writer, and media personality. She is the author of five books and the editor of nine volumes. From 1964 to 1978, she worked as a correspondent, reporter, and columnist for Zan-e Ruz weekly magazine and Kayhan daily newspaper in Iran. From 1972 to 1978 she worked as a television producer, director, and talk-show host for National Iranian Radio &amp;amp; Television. In 1978, Sarshar moved to Los Angeles where she resumed her career as a freelance journalist, radio and television producer, and on-air host. In 1982 as the co-producer, writer, and talk-show host of Omid Radio she co-founded a daily AM radio broadcast. In 1996, Sarshar founded the Center for Iranian Jewish Oral History (CIJOH) in Los Angeles. In 2006, she founded Honar Foundation in Los Angeles. From 2006 until March 2021 Sarshar has been producing, writing, and hosting a two hour weekly radio show at 670AM KIRN. She earned a BA in French literature from Tehran University; a MA in journalism from the Annenberg School of Communications, USC; and a Ph.D. (HC) in Journalism from College of Letters and Science at the American World University – LA, CA. She has received numerous awards for her work, including the Medal for Special Achievement in Women's Rights, given by The Iranian Women's Organization of Tehran, Iran; Journalism Award: Distinguished Iranian Women by the Encyclopaedia Iranica; Commendation for Community Affairs Services by the County of Los Angeles; 2013 Ellis Island Medal of Honor; 2016 American Heritage Award by American Immigration Council; and in 2023 the 13th Bita Prize for Persian Arts - Stanford University, Iranian Studies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mona Tajali&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;img alt="Mona Tajali" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/tajali_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mona Tajali is a scholar of gender and politics, specializing in women's political participation and representation in Muslim countries, with a comparative focus on Iran, Afghanistan, and Turkey. Her research includes analysis of feminist mobilization against patriarchal structures as well as the experiences of institutionalization of women's rights in semi-democratic and non-democratic contexts. She is the author of &lt;i&gt;Women’s Political Representation in Iran and Turkey: Demanding a Seat at the Table&lt;/i&gt; (2022) and co-author of &lt;i&gt;Electoral Politics: Making Quotas Work for Women&lt;/i&gt; (2011), both published as open access. She is also the co-editor of &lt;i&gt;Women and Constitutions in Muslim Contexts&lt;/i&gt; (2024), the first compilation analyzing several national constitutions of the Muslim world through a gender lens. A firm believer in engaging across the academic-practitioner divide, Tajali has been a long-term collaborator with transnational solidarity network and Women Living Under Muslim Laws (WLUML), and, since 2019, has served as a member of its executive board. She is published in both academic and popular outlets, among them the Middle East Journal, Politics &amp;amp; Gender, The Conversation, and The Washington Post. Tajali is a former associate professor of international relations and women’s, gender, and sexuality studies at Agnes Scott College in Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Mandana Zandian&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Mandana Zandian" src="https://iranian-studies.stanford.edu/sites/iranianstudies/files/media/image/zandian_sq.jpg" style="height:306px;width:300px;"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mandana Zandian graduated from Shahid Beheshti Medical School in 1997. She worked as a researcher at Cedars-Sinai Hospital in Los Angeles for 20 years, specializing in research on aggressive forms of advanced cancers.  Dr. Zandian is also a published poet, author, and journalist, actively collaborating with "Rahavard" quarterly journal. Her books include: &lt;i&gt;Omid o Azadi&lt;/i&gt; (Hope and Liberty, Los Angeles, 2012) on the life and works of Iraj Gorgin; &lt;i&gt;Baz-khani-e Dah Shab&lt;/i&gt; (The Ten-Nights Revisited, Los Angeles, 2014); &lt;i&gt;Ehsan Yarshater in Conversation with Mandana Zandian&lt;/i&gt; (Los Angeles, 2016); She also edited &lt;i&gt;Yaddashtha&lt;/i&gt; (Diaries, Washington DC, 2021), a collection of notes written between 1986-2012 for the journals "Irannameh" and "Iranshenasi" by Dr. Ehsan Yarshater. Zandian's most recent collection of poems is titled &lt;i&gt;Seda-ye Saye-haye Ham Boodim&lt;/i&gt; (Our Voice Echoed the Shadows of All, Los Angeles, 2019).  Dr. Zandian is also the host and producer of a podcast on Persian Literature titled "A Window of Freedom." She collaborated on a section of Homa Sarshar's weekly radio program, introducing Persian contemporary poets, for 10 years. Zandian's latest book is titled &lt;i&gt;Persian Cypress and the Booms of Modernity, in Conversation with Abbas Milani&lt;/i&gt; (Los Angeles, 2023).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Stanford is committed to ensuring its facilities, programs and services are accessible to everyone. To request access information and/or accommodations for this event, please complete&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://tinyurl.com/AccessStanford"&gt;https://tinyurl.com/AccessStanford&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt; &lt;/span&gt;at the latest one week before the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/archiving-the-history-of-modern-iranian-women</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48775571599842/huge/da820662f31878a6ae8794708d915c9d42f646f0.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2500" width="4446" isDefault="true" fileSize="3566195"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to NVivo</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 11:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/introduction-to-nvivo-1029</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48614558710645/huge/db2640587d11bfcf27b116ed03820fb4bab9b488.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="600" isDefault="true" fileSize="77711"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploration Pop-up! Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library, March 12, 2-4pm at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In our latest pop-up exhibition,&lt;b&gt; explore &lt;/b&gt;Mount Kilimanjaro, Antarctica, ancient Egypt, and &lt;b&gt;more&lt;/b&gt; with books from our Locked Stacks collection. Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, Wed., March. 12, 2-4 pm.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/exploration-popup-bowes-art-architecture-library-mar-12-2-4pm</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48985588012078/huge/c1f95c3d7ddf6cb2c49829216a17726c8cf945e1.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="932" width="699" isDefault="true" fileSize="1142134"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: March 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Mar 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-march-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Right to Privacy: Lowry Pressly in Conversation with Alexander Nemerov at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Lowry Pressly for a conversation with Alexander Nemerov. The two will discuss Pressly's newly published book, &lt;i&gt;The Right to Oblivion: Privacy and the Good Life&lt;/i&gt;, on April 1, 2025. This event is co-sponsored by the &lt;a href="https://ethicsinsociety.stanford.edu/"&gt;McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;a href="https://www.hup.harvard.edu/books/9780674260528"&gt;A copy can be purchased here&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The parts of our lives that are not being surveilled and turned into data diminish each day. We are able to configure privacy settings on our devices and social media platforms, but we know our efforts pale in comparison to the scale of surveillance capitalism and algorithmic manipulation. In our hyperconnected era, many have begun to wonder whether it is still possible to live a private life, or whether it is no longer worth fighting for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Right to Oblivion&lt;/i&gt; argues incisively and persuasively that we still can and should strive for privacy, though for different reasons than we might think. Recent years have seen heated debate in the realm of law and technology about why privacy matters, often focusing on how personal data breaches amount to violations of individual freedom. Yet as Lowry Pressly shows, the very terms of this debate have undermined our understanding of privacy’s real value. In a novel philosophical account, Pressly insists that privacy isn’t simply a right to be protected but a tool for making life meaningful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Privacy deepens our relationships with others as well as ourselves, reinforcing our capacities for agency, trust, play, self-discovery, and growth. Without privacy, the world would grow shallow, lonely, and inhospitable. Drawing inspiration from the likes of Hannah Arendt, Jorge Luis Borges, and a range of contemporary artists, Pressly shows why we all need a refuge from the world: not a place to hide, but a psychic space beyond the confines of a digital world in which the individual is treated as mere data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Lowry Pressly&lt;/b&gt; is a lecturer in the Department of Political Science, the McCoy Family Center for Ethics in Society, and the Stanford Civics Initiative. His philosophical work, criticism, fiction, and translations appear in a wide variety of publications, both academic and popular, including most recently &lt;i&gt;Ethics&lt;/i&gt;, &lt;i&gt;Asymptote&lt;/i&gt;, and the &lt;i&gt;Los Angeles Review of Books&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Alexander Nemerov&lt;/b&gt; is the author of many books on American art, most recently &lt;i&gt;The Forest: A Fable of America in the 1830s&lt;/i&gt;, praised by the novelist Annie Proulx as “one of the richest books ever to come my way—deeply beautiful, achingly painful and astonishingly tender”; and &lt;i&gt;Fierce Poise: Helen Frankenthaler and 1950s New York&lt;/i&gt;, named by &lt;i&gt;Vogue&lt;/i&gt; one of its best books of 2021 and a finalist for the National Book Critics Circle Award in Biography. Nemerov is the Carl and Marilynn Thoma Provostial Professor in the Arts and Humanities.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-right-to-privacy-lowry-pressly-in-conversation-with-alexander-nemerov</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48906044806136/huge/e36dee4ba12a99217e43e27fa8598bc15e8632f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="480" width="480" isDefault="true" fileSize="39134"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exhibit Opening: Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto &lt;/b&gt;(CISAC) to celebrate the opening of the temporary exhibit in Green Library:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;"Why Estonia? The 30-Year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit opening features a talk, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;“What America and DOGE can learn from 30 years of digital government success in Estonia?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; by former Estonian Government CIO &lt;b&gt;Luukas Ilves&lt;/b&gt;, kicking off a series of three talks on e-Estonia hosted by Stanford Libraries in April-May. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Luukas Ilves &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;is an advisor to the Deputy Prime Minister of Ukraine on questions of AI and digital transformation and a non-resident fellow at the International Center for Defence Studies (Tallinn, Estonia). &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From 2022–2024, Luukas was Government CIO and Undersecretary for Digital Transformation of Estonia. He previously held various roles with the Government of Estonia and the European Commission, has worked for the cryptography deep tech Guardtime, and as deputy director and senior fellow at the Lisbon Council (a Brussels-based thinktank).&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Luukas is a recipient of the Estonian Order of the White Star and President Zelensky’s Ukraine Peace Prize. He is a graduate of Stanford University.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Opening remarks will be delivered by &lt;b&gt;Michael Keller&lt;/b&gt; (Stanford Libraries) and &lt;b&gt;Ivo Lille&lt;/b&gt; (Vabamu), with &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt; (CISAC) moderating the discussion. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;A guided tour of the exhibit will follow the event.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:16px;"&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/ivBxjGKUBXHxjvt19"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783405896477/huge/51c9ed5ab4294eec599fce1abe366bfc4c9c07ff.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="866" width="870" isDefault="true" fileSize="1387240"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Persuasive Data Graphics Practicum with RJ Andrews at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data graphics are magical. Come learn how pictures can help us discover and discuss otherwise invisible phenomena. We will dissect the elements that make charts spectacular, ranging from choosing effective visual metaphors to picturing uncertainty and the subtle art of color-encoding. Our emphasis will be on the hard human decisions necessary to create effective data graphics. Our learning will be anchored by masterpieces of information design, including the study of rare works on display.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdKbOHdW-so9qbcQvDkTy2s1QnXgom9jH-RKHozcfNj5AAddg/viewform?usp=dialog"&gt;submit a brief application&lt;/a&gt; to apply to take part in the practicum. Applications are due at 11:59pm PST on &lt;b&gt;Friday, March 21&lt;/b&gt; to be considered. Please note that the practicum is only open to Stanford affiliates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About RJ Andrews&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ Andrews is a San Francisco data storyteller. By day, he tackles high-stakes problems for clients like The White House and Google. By night, he studies the history of charts, maps, and diagrams. The overlap between Andrews’ hands-on real-world practice and deep historical research gave rise to his latest book, &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/persuasive-data-graphics-practicum-with-rj-andrews</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48871376554133/huge/044bb7d98fcd9be252f9b2100efa95db6ca15d9b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1370" width="2189" isDefault="true" fileSize="2141757"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
      <category>Workshop</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Info We Trust Book Launch at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for the launch of &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; (Visionary Press, 2025), an illuminating journey through the world of data storytelling. Author RJ Andrews weaves a rich tapestry of insights, combining text and imagery to trace the evolution of data graphics from simple products of civilization to potent instruments of persuasion. With a storyteller’s flair, Andrews navigates narrative artistry and scientific inquiry to get at the heart of information design: creating meaning from space, time, and beyond. Featuring hundreds of hand-drawn illustrations and dotted with fascinating marginalia, &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; is a visual feast that captures the essence and excitement of data storytelling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdS-7qGn9WK7AeICkYNge2698Ax7H9t-AgpcFYHBYOT7aRKZA/viewform?usp=preview"&gt;register in advance&lt;/a&gt; to attend. Copies of &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt; will be available to purchase at the talk. This is an in-person-only event. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interested in learning about data graphics? Consider attending the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/persuasive-data-graphics-practicum-with-rj-andrews"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Persuasive Data Graphics Practicum&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; with RJ Andrews the same day as the book talk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About RJ Andrews&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;RJ Andrews is a San Francisco data storyteller. By day, he tackles high-stakes problems for clients like The White House and Google. By night, he studies the history of charts, maps, and diagrams. The overlap between Andrews’ hands-on real-world practice and deep historical research gave rise to &lt;i&gt;Info We Trust&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/info-we-trust-book-launch</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48810483174129/huge/c952d9edc3be71785e4517ca86bcf5f9053ad9ce.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="4630325"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: April 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-april-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Information Revolution:  How Soviet Cyberneticists Built the Liberal Information Age at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by &lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet &lt;/b&gt;(University of Southern California) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Information Revolution:  How Soviet Cyberneticists Built the Liberal Information Age&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia is often portrayed as the world’s most advanced "digital state," where citizens can vote, do their taxes, and renew their driver’s license, all online. According to this story, after fifty years of Soviet occupation, Estonia understood the dangers of monopolizing information and chose to break with the Soviet legacy by building a state where information was transparent, available, and online. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk offers a different perspective. It explores the role of Soviet cybernetics and late socialist reform movements in the construction of the first iterations of the digital state. Why did Soviet thinkers imagine information technology as the solution to political and economic stagnation? And what can the long history of the information processing state tell us about late modern politics?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet&lt;/b&gt; is an associate professor of history at the University of Southern California. He is a visiting researcher at the Davis Center at Princeton University and a visiting researcher at the Institute of Social Studies at the University of Tartu. He writes about technological utopias and the history of science in a variety of imperial and post-imperial contexts. His first book, Pasteur’s Empire (Oxford University Press, 2020), looked at how bacteriologists reimagined imperial governance in early twentieth century France. His current project, The Information Revolution, looks at how computer engineers reimagined imperial governance in late twentieth century Soviet Union.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session and screening of the film, &lt;b&gt;"Disco and Atomic War" &lt;/b&gt;(2009). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The film tells the story of a strange kind of information war, where a totalitarian regime stands face to face with the heroes of popular culture. And loses. It was a time when it was possible for erotic film star Emmanuelle to bring down the Red Army and MacGyver to outdo an entire school administration. It is a film about our generation, who were unknowingly brought to the front line of the Cold War. Western popular culture had an incomparable role shaping Soviet children's world views in those days. Finnish television was a window to a world of dreams that the authorities could not block in any way. Though Finnish channels were banned, many households found some way to access the forbidden fruit." – Warsaw Film Festival&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/XqSgxs4Y1R5UGfsj9"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783490397155/huge/20687f99a4a0c0a96409655cc6b6787f9e085f1e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="722" width="692" isDefault="true" fileSize="941498"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Time, Space and Habitat: a talk by Dr. Ben Gitai at David Rumsey Map Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have always shaped and been shaped by the landscapes they inhabit. "Chronomapping" is an innovative methodology developed by Dr. Gitai that investigates landscape transformations through time by integrating data and insights from disciplines such as architecture, landscape architecture, hydrology, urban planning, climatology, ecology, sociology, anthropology, political geography, history, and even the psychology of aesthetics. The methodology is a means to produce visual representations and new conceptual frameworks of territories and habitats across time. It can also cast power dynamics and territorial transformations in new lights by examining the interplay between terrain, territory, and cartography across historical periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is designed to serve as a counterbalance to the short-sightedness that has characterized much development in the Western world. The methodology is explicitly designed to account for the palimpsestic nature of development. It has both scholarly and practical applications with potential utility in fields of governance, urban and spatial planning, and industrial development. Dr. Gitai's lecture will reference two of his forthcoming publications: &lt;i&gt;Mapping Power: History of Landscape in the Jordan Valley&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Landscapes Atlas of Paris&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the speaker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Gitai is the founder of Gitai Architects, based in Paris and Haifa, which specializes in urban development and architectural typologies for housing and offices in conflict territories. He is also a lecturer at ETH Zurich and EPFL Lausanne, where he has developed a research and teaching method titled &lt;i&gt;Mapping Power&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScZfdPIJvqU2suflntJ37WPy2l5DzHRt2LS9IeCbNB-MDnfhw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register to attend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is an in-person-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mapping-time-space-and-habitat-a-talk-by-dr-ben-gitai</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48986076260218/huge/574da834c9fe7204b040f8ea7caab42d6ca0da0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="302" width="454" isDefault="true" fileSize="144870"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for an engaging conversation with Author &lt;b&gt;Joel Burke &lt;/b&gt;and &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto &lt;/b&gt;(CISAC) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three decades after gaining independence from the Soviet Union, Estonia is a nation transformed. Today, the country is known around the world as a startup hub, with numerous local billion-dollar companies including Wise, Veriff, and Bolt. More impressive are Estonia’s pioneering efforts in e-government. With 100% of government services digitalized and accessible online, citizens can vote via computer and file their taxes online in minutes, and the use of artificial intelligence (AI) to enhance and automate government services long predates ChatGPT. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this book talk, the author of &lt;a href="https://global.oup.com/academic/product/rebooting-a-nation-9781805263012?cc=us&amp;amp;lang=en&amp;amp;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt; Joel Burke offers unique insight into Estonia’s rapid rise as a tech and e-government powerhouse since the turn of the century. From the founding of Skype to the future of the e-state, he unveils the tactics and stories behind Estonia’s spectacular journey—after years of Soviet occupation and mismanagement to global tech leadership. For those hoping to learn from Estonia’s incredible journey, Burke offers insights into the government’s use of AI, its creation of a digital society, and its cultivation of a culture driving public-sector creativity and innovation. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Joel Burke&lt;/b&gt; is a research fellow at fp21. A former AI Fellow for Senator Mike Rounds, Joel advised the office on AI, technology, and security issues. Previously, he worked in various roles and geographies including in Tallinn as Head of Business Development for e-Residency, the Republic of Estonia’s flagship digital initiative. Other experiences include working as a fellow in Cameroon staffed to a local startup via Venture for Africa; serving as a NYCx Fellow; working as a Partner at Tribe.AI, a managed marketplace for top AI talent; and leading a venture for a Rocket Internet AG subsidiary in Berlin. He started his career at a YC and Andreessen Horowitz-backed startup. &lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk is moderated by &lt;b&gt;Andrew Grotto&lt;/b&gt;, Research Scholar, Center for International Security and Cooperation (FSI). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/HHxM6uEJxEa8unCQA"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783921187599/huge/ba7c5becb4781871efc08f684638d2ea994bc6da.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="586" width="722" isDefault="true" fileSize="730084"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: May 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-may-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
