<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#">
  <channel>
    <title>Stanford University Calendar</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://events.stanford.edu/</link>
    <item>
      <title>Translating Three Japanese Masters, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura, and Kazuko Shiraishi: Selections from the Yumiko Tsumura Collection at Lathrop Library</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On display at the East Asia Library from 3/6/25-5/13/25, selections from a recent donation from Yumiko Tsumura, a local poet and translator, related to three major modern Japanese authors, Yumiko Kurahashi, Ryuichi Tamura and Kazuko Shiraishi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yumiko Kurahashi’s meteoric career began with &lt;i&gt;Parutai&lt;/i&gt; (&lt;i&gt;The Party&lt;/i&gt;), a brilliant satire of the Japanese leftist students movement that she wrote while still a student. As part of a first generation of women writers who had benefited from equal opportunity for education in the post-war period, her innovative writing style, influenced by Satre, Kafka, and Camus, rocked the literary world of the 1960s, exposing structural inequities in Japanese society. Perhaps the most renowned post-WWII Japanese poet, Ryuichi Tamura’s poetry searingly reveals the agony of war and the disorientation induced by rapid modernization. Kazuko Shiraishi, known for performing her provocative poetry to jazz accompaniment, has been called the “Allen Ginsberg of Japan.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to introduce this donation in an exhibit in our main exhibit space. Please visit the East Asia Library to learn more about these three authors, who each left a powerful critique of the modern world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/news/east-asia-library-exhibits-selections-yumiko-tsumura-collection-japanese-poetry"&gt;Read an interview with the donor, Yumiko Tsumura, to learn more about her and each of these authors.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/translating-three-japanese-masters</link>
      <geo:lat>37.429468</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167272</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49021026270886/huge/0a889191391152cee3133e7261ae17eb90597460.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="469" width="512" isDefault="true" fileSize="80335"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why Estonia? The 30-year Journey from the USSR to e-Estonia at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Despite a population of fewer than 1.5 million, Estonia has emerged as a global leader in e-governance. From ID cards and digital voting to online tax declarations and thriving tech startups, Estonia’s remarkable digital evolution is a testament to visionary decisions and strategic leadership.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This transformation wasn’t inevitable. After regaining independence in the early 1990s, Estonia faced the challenges of rebuilding after 50 years of Soviet occupation. The exhibit, a collaboration between the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://vabamu.ee/en/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;Vabamu Museum of Occupations and Freedom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; and Stanford Libraries, explores Estonia’s journey from its historical roots to its digital success, highlighting achievements and challenges along the way.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The exhibit runs from April 2 to August &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;22&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;, 2025, in Green Library’s Hohbach Hall. This exhibit is free and open to the public.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/visitor-access" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Learn more about visiting Stanford Libraries on our website&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks exploring e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:12pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48784006670593/huge/fcc0e4782c3b22ef835cd5a2bc04a6752a27d369.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="858" width="862" isDefault="true" fileSize="1286480"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ART/WORK at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Stanford Libraries presents &lt;i&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/special-collections-exhibits"&gt;ART/WORK | Creative Pursuits of Stanford Libraries Staff&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;/i&gt; on view February 20, 2024, through April 27, 2025, in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda, Cecil H. Green Library, Bing Wing. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this exhibition, we sought to create a space where staff could share their artistic, creative side that may not otherwise be a part of their work at Stanford. In the Summer of 2024, Special Collections invited current Stanford Libraries staff to enter creative work in any medium to be considered for a Winter 2025 exhibit in Green Library’s Peterson Gallery and Rotunda. Response to the call for entries was hearty. In addition to traditional fine art techniques of drawing, painting, printmaking, and photography, submissions included mixed media sculpture, ceramics, collage, textiles, and poetry. An anonymous selection committee of library staff blind-reviewed over a hundred entries and chose the fifty works displayed in the galleries. We asked the people whose pieces were selected to write a brief statement to accompany their work in the exhibit and posed several questions for their consideration: Why do creative work? What medium do you work in and why? How did you get started? What does it mean to you to be an artist (if you define yourself as one)? Does art need an audience? Who is your audience? What influences your work, and whose work do you admire? As you will see, Stanford library staff are talented and thoughtful, pursuing many forms of creative work after hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exhibition is curated by Roberto Trujillo, Associate University Librarian, Director of Special Collections and Frances and Charles Field Curator of Special Collections; produced and designed by Deardra Fuzzell, Manager and Designer of Exhibitions, with assistance from Elizabeth Fischbach.  Special thanks to the many colleagues in the Stanford Libraries who helped to make the exhibition possible: For their careful consideration of all staff art submissions, we thank the staff members who served on the jury; For their assessment of materials, Aisha Wahab and Beth Ryan in Conservation Services; For their assistance with logistics Ranelle Sharma and Jacob Cohn in Library Facilities, and Tim Noakes, Leif Anderson, and Kylee Diedrich in Public Services. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NOTE: Exhibit cases in the Peterson Gallery and Munger Rotunda are illuminated from 9 a.m. to 5 p.m. The exhibition is free and open to the public. Visitors are encouraged to call 650-723-0931 or visit the &lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/libraries_collections/hours_locations.html" rel="noopener" target="_blank"&gt;Library Hours page &lt;/a&gt;to confirm hours and access.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Apr 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/artwork</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48687359684680/huge/603b1fb303d73747de62963ba10e4c95a4135903.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1076" isDefault="true" fileSize="78990"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Art of the Ad: Fashion for a New Century  at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pochoir fashion plates and advertisements are part of the allure of early 20th-century Parisian fashion magazines. Art history major, Sita Antel, '26 investigates the role of fashion in her Spring exhibition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On view in Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 1 - June 20th. M-Th 9-7, Fri 9-5, Sun. 12-6.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Apr 2025 12:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/art-of-the-ad-fashion-for-a-new-century</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49092294783840/huge/f89ef044fd107f813a0005d6667e49c04115261e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="626799"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Branner Library Monthly Book &amp; Map Exhibit - Naturally Hazardous: Wildfires at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_biggest"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collection exhibit series: Naturally Hazardous&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
From the cosmically unavoidable to the anthropogenically-induced, Earth can be naturally hazardous to humans. In the 2024-25 academic year, Branner Library’s exhibit series will feature the science and impact of volcanoes, wildfires, drought, and more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_bigger"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
April 1 - April 24:  Extreme wildfires have become more frequent. Learn more about their effects on the environment, public health, infrastructure, and efforts to monitor and remediate those effects through books, maps, and data in our monthly exhibit!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Books and a selection of maps are displayed on the library's main floor. Additional maps are displayed on the library mezzanine exhibit wall (access from within the library). The exhibit is available for viewing during &lt;a href="https://library-hours.stanford.edu/libraries/branner"&gt;regular library open hours&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Check out past exhibits featured in the &lt;a href="https://us20.campaign-archive.com/home/?u=6a552426d5d24e9958bbd78fe&amp;amp;id=2e6cf2db76" target="_blank"&gt;Branner Library Newsletter&lt;/a&gt;.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the library, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2025 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/branner-library-monthly-book-map-exhibit-naturally-hazardous-wildfires</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49243078500398/huge/2e04d7f86b57cf45a111ede44d125340be99d063.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1080" width="1080" isDefault="true" fileSize="317898"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Special, Unique, and Rare: Food at Green Library, Bing Wing</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Growing, providing, preparing, sharing, and consuming food are all essential for human life.  At the most fundamental, biological level, food sustains life by delivering nutrients and staving off hunger. But the ways people eat and the ways they think about food, as well as what people eat -- and don’t eat -- are strongly influenced by culture, ritual, ethics, climate, geography, technology, and economics. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Drop by Hohbach 123 (Silicon Valley Archive classroom, Green Library) any time between 2-4 PM on Tuesday, April 8th to partake in a curated tasting menu of Special, Unique and Rare delicacies from the Libraries’ collections that have something to say about FOOD.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-food</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426984</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167998</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49217733501357/huge/ab7c67d7c72e72730b1651ea89c8ce0fec92fdda.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3139" width="2271" isDefault="true" fileSize="3502198"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spheres of Influence: Projecting Power and Fear Onto the Globe at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;i&gt;"Americans can learn geography and be saved; they can forsake it and forever be lost."&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;—Richard Edes Harrison&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Global view maps show the Earth’s curved surface as if seen from space. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Spheres of Influence, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;an exhibition curated by California Map Society Student Exhibition Contest winner Champ Turner, traces the evolving uses of this unique type of map.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;The global view map emerged in the 1930s and rose to prominence during the turbulent events of the mid-20th century. Widely published in magazines and newspapers, these maps use persuasive visual language to interpret complex international conflicts for the general public. Their emergence coincided with the rise of long-distance air travel and a changing perception of global security. Introduced to a mass audience by cartographer Richard Edes Harrison and rapidly adopted by his contemporaries, the global view countered the prevailing sense of American isolation and challenged audiences to reconsider the relative proximity of international allies and adversaries.  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Using the global view map has allowed cartographers to wield significant influence over the narrative of global conflicts throughout the twentieth century.  In this exhibition, we invite you to examine how cartographers, publications, and governments used the global view to inform, persuade and subtly shape our sense of place in the world.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;This exhibition is also available to &lt;a href="https://storymaps.arcgis.com/stories/83a42ebc28b44fe7b355532da798b938"&gt;view digitally&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/spheres-of-influence-projecting-power-and-fear-onto-the-globe</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49048646899058/huge/2216673d0cf6e17ea236e4a915c0307c8685ad53.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1194" width="1536" isDefault="true" fileSize="1094237"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Pop-up! Bowes Art &amp; Architecture Library, April 9th, 2-4 PM at McMurtry Building</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From scallop shells to Chinese menus, stop by to see a variety of artists' books about food selected from our Locked Stacks collection. On view in the Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library, April 9, 2-4 PM.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-april-9th-2-4-pm</link>
      <geo:lat>37.432546</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.171856</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49234627043743/huge/6c3259c851e2ee5bb0d6cfa56041f95862a56f6b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="2381" width="3024" isDefault="true" fileSize="2179208"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Talk &amp; Panel on the Work of Visiting Artist Sohei Nishino at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by visiting artist &lt;a href="https://soheinishino.net/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Sohei Nishino&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt; followed by remarks and reflections on the artist’s work by a distinguished group of panelists including cultural historian Abby Smith Rumsey; poet and Stanford lecturer in creative writing, Sara Michas-Martin; and associate professor of the history of the built environment at the University of California, Santa Cruz, Albert Narath. The program will conclude with a panel discussion and Q&amp;amp;A facilitated by art historian and Stanford ITALIC Associate Director Kim Beil and David Rumsey Map Center staff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScURuI9ZRQtdyWABC4zvyvj89HLdi5v0Z8sUaWfk_O756Dziw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;register to attend&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 14:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/talk-panel-on-visiting-artist-sohei-nishinos-work</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49082204927615/huge/9310b57b1135015f4b941582f3f6981bf4fceb81.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1000" width="1000" isDefault="true" fileSize="508439"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Food Pop-up Exhibit @ Branner Earth Sciences Library at Mitchell Earth Sciences</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of the Stanford Libraries pop-up exhibits on &lt;b&gt;FOOD&lt;/b&gt;, Branner Earth Sciences Library &amp;amp; Map Collections will feature a selection of maps, atlases, and books that feature different perspectives on how we manage agriculture and access to food.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thursday, April 10, 2025 from 2-4pm in Branner Library (2nd Floor, Mitchell Earth Sciences Building). &lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On display will be several items including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/in00000298208"&gt;Feed the planet: a photographic journey to the world's food&lt;/a&gt; (George Steinmetz, 2024)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10110785"&gt;Food: an atlas &lt;/a&gt;(Guerrilla Cartography, 2023)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/10406279"&gt;Reedley, California: "the world's fruit basket" &lt;/a&gt;(Barkclay Maps, 1969)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/view/12093152"&gt;Great Britain, her natural &amp;amp; industrial resources&lt;/a&gt; (British Information Services, c.1944)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href="https://searchworks.stanford.edu/?search_field=search&amp;amp;q=%22An+atlas+of+Stanford+counter-maps%22"&gt;Several counter-maps created by Stanford students&lt;/a&gt; depicting their food experiences at Stanford.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;Before heading to Branner on Thursday, check out two other Food Pop-up Exhibits happening Tuesday (4/08) and Wednesday (4/09)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;April 8, Tues, 2- 4pm, &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/special-unique-and-rare-food"&gt;Special, Unique and Rare: Food @ Green Library&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;April 9, Wed, 2-4pm, &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-pop-up-bowes-art-architecture-library-april-9th-2-4-pm"&gt;Food Pop-Up! @ Bowes Art &amp;amp; Architecture Library&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt; &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;A current Stanford ID is needed to enter the libraries, visitors must present a government issued ID card to sign-in at the front desk.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/food-pop-up-exhibit-branner-earth-sciences-library</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49303906824369/huge/9c3207ae6ec27f2c8a77a63769290a87c7533593.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3024" width="4032" isDefault="true" fileSize="4386288"/>
      <category>Exhibition</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: April 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-april-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join us for a talk by &lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet &lt;/b&gt;(University of Southern California) on:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Estonia is often portrayed as the world’s most advanced „digital state, “ where citizens can vote, do their taxes, and renew their driver’s license, all online. But before the „digital state,“ there was the „National Automated Control System." From the 1960s, cyberneticians, sociologists, and management scientists in Ukraine, Estonia, Novosibirsk, and elsewhere imagined constructing a network of data centers – the NACS – that would revitalize the Soviet empire. They failed in building this network, but their expertise catalyzed large social movements that ultimately contributed to the empire’s collapse. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This talk provides a history of the information age in the Soviet Union. This history is relevant not only because expertise from this period led to some of the most innovative work in digital public infrastructure in 1990s Estonia but also because visionaries then were grappling with questions that remain relevant today: What is the relationship between digital technology and the state? What are the risks and rewards of collecting and processing data about the public? And can technology aid or disrupt the functioning of an authoritarian state?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;i&gt;&lt;b&gt;Aro Velmet&lt;/b&gt; is an Associate Professor of History at the University of Southern California. He is a visiting researcher at the Davis Center at Princeton University and a visiting researcher at the Institute of Social Studies at the University of Tartu. He writes about technological utopias and the history of science in a variety of imperial and post-imperial contexts. His first book, Pasteur’s Empire (Oxford University Press, 2020), looked at how bacteriologists reimagined imperial governance in early twentieth century France. His current project, The Information Revolution, looks at how computer engineers reimagined imperial governance in late twentieth century Soviet Union.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The talk will be followed by a Q&amp;amp;A session and screening of the film, &lt;b&gt;"Disco and Atomic War" &lt;/b&gt;(2009). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"The film tells the story of a strange kind of information war, where a totalitarian regime stands face to face with the heroes of popular culture. And loses. It was a time when it was possible for erotic film star Emmanuelle to bring down the Red Army and MacGyver to outdo an entire school administration. It is a film about our generation, who were unknowingly brought to the front line of the Cold War. Western popular culture had an incomparable role shaping Soviet children's world views in those days. Finnish television was a window to a world of dreams that the authorities could not block in any way. Though Finnish channels were banned, many households found some way to access the forbidden fruit." – Warsaw Film Festival&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Free and open to the public. &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/XqSgxs4Y1R5UGfsj9"&gt;Registration is requested.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From April to May, Stanford Libraries hosts three public talks that are related to the &lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/why-estonia-exhibit"&gt;"Why Estonia?" exhibit in Green Library &lt;/a&gt;and that explore e-Estonia’s history, achievements, challenges, and the potential applicability of its e-governance model in the U.S.: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/exhibit-opening-why-estonia"&gt;April 2, 2025: Exhibit Opening Featuring a Talk by Luukas Ilves, “What the world’s most digital country can teach us about government efficiency and effectiveness?”&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution"&gt;April 15, 2025: Talk by Aro Velmet, "The Information Revolution: How Estonian Cyberneticians Invented the Information Age in the Soviet Empire"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://events.stanford.edu/event/rebooting-a-nation"&gt;May 7, 2025: Book Talk with Joel Burke, "Rebooting a Nation: The Incredible Rise of Estonia, E-Government and the Startup Revolution"&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/the-information-revolution</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48783490397155/huge/20687f99a4a0c0a96409655cc6b6787f9e085f1e.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="722" width="692" isDefault="true" fileSize="941498"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matteo Maggiori: Geoeconomics and the US-China Great Power Competition at GSB Knight Management Center</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://library.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford University Libraries&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href="https://sccei.fsi.stanford.edu/"&gt;Stanford Center on China's Economy and Institutions&lt;/a&gt; are pleased to present the &lt;b&gt;2025 Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture&lt;/b&gt; featuring &lt;b&gt;Professor Matteo Maggiori &lt;/b&gt;who will be speaking on &lt;i&gt;Geoeconomics and the US-China Great Power Competition.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;To attend in person, please register &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/2rDmd8jGWSbXBioXA" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;b&gt;To attend online, please register &lt;a href="https://stanford.zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_5XWbHcREQW-7ib6JqIMlRw" target="_blank"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Professor Maggiori&lt;/b&gt; will discuss how the U.S. and China apply economic pressure to achieve their political and economic goals, and the economic costs and benefits that this competition is imposing on the world. A discussion of economic security policies that other countries are implementing to shield their economies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.matteomaggiori.com/" target="_blank"&gt;Professor Maggiori&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt; is the Moghadam Family Professor of Finance at the Stanford Graduate School of Business. His research focuses on international macroeconomics and finance. He is a co-founder and director of the Global Capital Allocation Project. His research topics have included the analysis of exchange rates under imperfect capital markets, capital flows, the international monetary system, reserve currencies, geoeconomics, tax havens, very long-run discount rates and climate change, and expectations and portfolio investment. His research combines theory and data with the aim of improving international economic policy. He is a faculty research fellow at the National Bureau of Economic Research and a research affiliate at the Center for Economic Policy Research. He received his PhD from the University of California at Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among a number of honors, he is the recipient of the Fischer Black Prize awarded to an outstanding financial economist under the age of 40, the Carnegie and Guggenheim fellowships, and the Bernacer Prize for outstanding contributions in macroeconomics and finance by a European economist under age 40.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;---------------------------------------------------------------------------&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The family of &lt;b&gt;Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh&lt;/b&gt; donated his personal archive to the Stanford University Libraries' Special Collections and endowed the Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh Memorial Lecture series to honor his legacy and to inspire future generations. Dr. Sam-Chung Hsieh (1919-2004) was former Governor of the Central Bank in Taiwan. During his tenure, he was responsible for the world's largest foreign exchange reserves, and was widely recognized for achieving stability and economic growth. In his long and distinguished career as economist and development specialist, he held key positions in multilateral institutions including the Asian Development Bank, where as founding Director, he was instrumental in advancing the green revolution and in the transformation of rural Asia. &lt;a href="https://hsiehlecture.sites.stanford.edu/"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Read more about Dr. Hsieh&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/2025hsiehlecture</link>
      <geo:lat>37.427663</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.162043</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49038974016477/huge/b9018054c15077f158e533c0b97ff90e03f35e75.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="600" width="1067" isDefault="true" fileSize="622482"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Georeferencing in QGIS (April 18th) at Branner Earth Sciences Library </title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This workshop covers the basics of georeferencing static images in a GIS using the open source GIS package QGIS. Georeferenced images or maps can be used as contextual layers in a GIS project, or as part of a data extraction process to convert static map data into digital vector data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Setting up for best results&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing from a set of known map coordinates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Georeferencing by linking to a basemap&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Digitizing new GIS features from a georeferenced maps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See the More Info link for registration and workshop landing page URL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Note: &lt;/b&gt;Open to current Stanford affiliates &lt;b&gt;ONLY&lt;/b&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Plese use the Event Website to register. Registration page has link to online resouerces for workshop.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 13:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/georeferencing-in-qgis-april-18th</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426402</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.172635</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/39519065549929/huge/36ecf7eef696ef2fc4be5cd1cafb4c93c8ea2a25.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="450" width="900" isDefault="true" fileSize="221696"/>
      <category>Class/Seminar</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Survive a Robot Apocalypse  at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming filmmaker Andrea Gatopoulos for a talk on their latest film, "The Eggregores Theory," on April 22, 2025. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reconstructing the culture, philosophies, and economic structures that gave rise to artificial intelligences, Andrea will try to deconstruct the apocalyptic fear that is associated with this technology.  The goal is a better understanding of AI’s limits as well as the potential it has to power up our creative energy and upscale the output of our world-building imagination. After the introduction, we will watch and delve into the making of my film, "The Eggregores' Theory", the first AI film to be screened at Venice Film Festival. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Andrea Gatopoulos&lt;/b&gt; is an Italian and Greek director, producer and distributor. Member of EFA, Berlinale Talents, Locarno Spring Academy and TFL, he founded his company Il Varco, the short film distribution Gargantua and the avant-garde cinema residency Nouvelle Bug. He graduated in Literature and studied in workshops with W. Herzog, Radu Jude and A. Weerasethakul. His films deal with virtual realities, uncanny valleys, disillusion, anti-capitalism and critiques of progressivism. "Happy New Year, Jim" (2022) was the first machinima in Cannes, at the 54. Quinzaine des Réalisateurs. In 2023 he presented in Locarno "Eschaton Ad", a film about the apocalyptic advent of AI. Later that year he presented "A stranger quest" (2023), his first documentary feature about maps at Torino Film Festival. In 2024 his short film "The Eggregores' Theory" opened the 39. Venice Film Critics' Week as the first AI film in Venice and was nominated for EFA by ZINEBI.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 12:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/how-to-survive-a-robot-apocalypse</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49287680748846/huge/fac3ed2042b3def43b0d1bb7fbf3d703434decdc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1489" width="2560" isDefault="true" fileSize="709524"/>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Science and Health Policy: Forward Progress or Complete Chaos? (Bay Area Open Science Group Meeting)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This month, the Bay Area Open Science Group will feature Kathryn Phillips, PhD, Professor of Health Economics and Health Services Research at UCSF, in a conversation on open science and health policy. Although the move towards open science – including data sharing and open access publication – continues, these efforts must now consider the changing policy environment. Kathryn will lead a discussion on open science and health policy with topics to include evolving trends in open science, particularly open access publication, and how these trends might be impacted by the changing policy environment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kathryn will bring her perspectives as both a researcher and Editor-in-Chief of an open access journal. Her thoughts will be informed by her 2024 publication on open access, her upcoming participation in the National Academy of Sciences Journal Summit, and an upcoming one-month residency at the Brocher Foundation (Geneva) to focus on open access publication globally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the Bay Area Open Science Group&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bay Area Open Science Group is a growing community for Bay Area (and more!) academics and researchers interested in incorporating open science into their research, teaching, and learning. Targeting students, faculty, and staff at UCSF, Berkeley, and Stanford, the goal of the community is to increase awareness of and engagement with all things open science, including open access articles, open research data, open source software, and open educational resources. Through this work the group hopes to connect researchers with tools they can use to make the products and process of science more equitable and reproducible. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/open-science-and-health-policy</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49268398667096/huge/a924a2d39baf14fe7ae607d131d5dc425b6b551c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="557" width="990" isDefault="true" fileSize="942056"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
      <category>Meeting</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mapping Time, Space and Habitat: a talk by Dr. Ben Gitai at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Humans have always shaped and been shaped by the landscapes they inhabit. "Chronomapping" is an innovative methodology developed by Dr. Gitai that investigates landscape transformations through time by integrating data and insights from disciplines such as architecture, landscape architecture, hydrology, urban planning, climatology, ecology, sociology, anthropology, political geography, history, and even the psychology of aesthetics. The methodology is a means to produce visual representations and new conceptual frameworks of territories and habitats across time. It can also cast power dynamics and territorial transformations in new lights by examining the interplay between terrain, territory, and cartography across historical periods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This model is designed to serve as a counterbalance to the short-sightedness that has characterized much development in the Western world. The methodology is explicitly designed to account for the palimpsestic nature of development. It has both scholarly and practical applications with potential utility in fields of governance, urban and spatial planning, and industrial development. Dr. Gitai's lecture will reference two of his forthcoming publications: &lt;i&gt;Mapping Power: History of Landscape in the Jordan Valley&lt;/i&gt; and &lt;i&gt;Landscapes Atlas of Paris&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;About the speaker&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Ben Gitai integrates geography, architecture, and related disciplines in his research and practice. He has taught at various institutions in Switzerland (ETHZ, EPFL) and France. His cross-disciplinary approach combines tools and perspectives from landscape architecture, urban planning, political geography, and history, exploring the evolution of geo-spatial configurations over historical periods and how these transformations reflect broader socio-political and economic processes. His work recontextualizes mapping practices as instruments for understanding the complex relationships between human and natural systems, offering innovative perspectives on the forces that shape our environments. Today, he is the head coordinator of the Habitat Research Center and the Paris Atlas of Landscapes at EPFL. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScZfdPIJvqU2suflntJ37WPy2l5DzHRt2LS9IeCbNB-MDnfhw/viewform?usp=header"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Please register to attend&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This is an in-person-only event.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 May 2025 15:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/mapping-time-space-and-habitat-a-talk-by-dr-ben-gitai</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48986076260218/huge/574da834c9fe7204b040f8ea7caab42d6ca0da0b.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="302" width="454" isDefault="true" fileSize="144870"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, May 7 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 May 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-4083</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>David Rumsey Map Center Guided Tour at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Explore the World of Maps at the David Rumsey Map Center&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Join us for a &lt;b&gt;guided tour&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center at Stanford Libraries. Upon arrival, you'll be greeted by one of our knowledgeable staff members for an immersive experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;30-Minute Overview&lt;/b&gt;: Dive deep into the &lt;b&gt;history, collections, and special exhibitions&lt;/b&gt; of the David Rumsey Map Center, enriched with insights and stories from our passionate team.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Interactive Experience&lt;/b&gt;: After the guided portion, we invite you to explore the &lt;b&gt;digital collections&lt;/b&gt; on our state-of-the-art large touch screen monitors. Feel the past come alive at your fingertips!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Exhibition Exploration&lt;/b&gt;: Take your time to &lt;b&gt;peruse our rotating exhibition&lt;/b&gt;, showcasing rare and fascinating maps from various eras and regions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Connect with Experts&lt;/b&gt;: Our friendly staff will be around for a chat, ready to share their knowledge and answer any questions you might have.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;✍️ &lt;b&gt;Registration Details&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🔗 &lt;a href="https://forms.gle/BDoTttbKFf72cmjr6"&gt;&lt;b&gt;Register for the tour here&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;b&gt;Deadline&lt;/b&gt;: Registration closes at 4:00pm on the Thursday before the tour.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Note&lt;/b&gt;: Tours without registrants by the deadline will be canceled.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Drop-in Visitors&lt;/b&gt;: Not registered? No problem! We welcome and encourage visitors to explore the David Rumsey Map Center, its exhibitions, and technology at their own pace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;🚫 &lt;b&gt;Please Note&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;No food, drink, or pen/ink&lt;/b&gt; is allowed inside the Center to protect our collections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;b&gt;Photography&lt;/b&gt;: Feel free to capture your memories! Personal photography without flash is permitted.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Discover the stories maps can tell at the David Rumsey Map Center. &lt;b&gt;See you there!&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/david-rumsey-map-center-tour</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/45864850942816/huge/4cc594315a3137bbea4f148c26a5cbc31631a6f9.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1281" width="1920" isDefault="true" fileSize="883046"/>
      <category>Tour</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: May 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 May 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-may-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenGulf: Creating Open Historical Data about the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at David Rumsey Map Center (Green Library)</title>
      <description>&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;How can we critically examine, interpret, and repurpose colonial knowledge through creating structured data? Can colonial texts serve as meaningful data sources to explore the histories of understudied regions like the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf? How can historical sources be transformed into datasets, and what insights can such data offer? This symposium addresses these questions and marks the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="http://opengulf.github.io" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;OpenGulf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; research collective’s completion and publication of a comprehensive dataset of geocoded place names derived from a seminal early-twentieth-century British colonial Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Arabian Peninsula, and Oman. This open-access, historical-geographical dataset is the culmination of seven years of collaborative annotation, geolocation, and disambiguation carried out by faculty, students, and OpenGulf community members across several institutions. During the sessions, we will discuss OpenGulf’s collaborative workflows and methods, introduce potential uses among scholars and practitioners, and emphasize the pedagogical potential of historical dataset creation by celebrating the work of student researchers. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;In addition to morning sessions at the David Rumsey Map Center, the event will feature an exhibition of historical materials related to the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf at Branner Library and a student-led poster session including lightning talks on undergraduate research.  The afternoon event will include cartographic visualizations created using the OpenGulf dataset such as the one pictured here, a &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://opengulf.github.io/camels/" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt; of mentions of over 66,000 camels in the &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;i style="font-style:italic;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Gazetteer of the Persian Gulf, Oman and Central Arabia.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Scholars, students, and members of the public with an interest in advancing and broadening their knowledge of both the history of the Arabian Peninsula and the Persian Gulf and digital humanities debates and methodologies will especially benefit from this event. &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Detailed program coming soon.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class="desc_normal"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;Please &lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLSdlExG8oCxQA7mwF9gL3IdeWS6QRquumozO-DMWwEcHxA4GSA/viewform?usp=sharing" style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;u style="text-decoration:underline;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;register to attend&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;span style="font-size:11pt;"&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;span style="font-style:normal;"&gt;&lt;span style="text-decoration:none;"&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 May 2025 09:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/opengulf-creating-open-historical-data-about-the-arabian-peninsula-and-the-persian-gulf</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/49172453653870/huge/1df3b2294274ccef609cb54e75ec894d1f5d85ab.jpg" medium="image" type="image/png" height="1322" width="1999" isDefault="true" fileSize="2215084"/>
      <category>Conference/Symposium</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title> From Ecotopia to NIMBYland:  Environment, Ideology, and the Antigrowth Style in California Politics at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Join the Silicon Valley Archives in welcoming Jacob Anbinder and Michael Kahan on May 29, 2025, as they discuss Jacbob Anbinder's upcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation: The War on Growth That Created Our Housing Crisis and Remade American Politics&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1975, a tiny Berkeley press published &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt;. Set in 1999, the novel told the story of a fledgling nation which had declared its independence from the U.S. out of disdain for America’s obsession with growth. &lt;i&gt;Ecotopia&lt;/i&gt; ended up selling more than four hundred thousand copies and won author Ernest Callenbach praise in progressive circles for his visionary environmentalism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For Callenbach and others, California was ground zero for the disasters wrought by unfettered urbanization. Yet it was also the place where an alternative politics focused on ecological protection and quality of life seemed most likely to emerge. In the seventies and eighties, California liberals embarked on an intensive effort to remake their political agenda in the Ecotopian mold. Whether expressing dismay about freeway traffic, forest fires, water use, overcrowded parks and beaches, the loss of scenic views, or the unsightliness of high-rises, environmental protection became the shared language through which they voiced their objection to growth. This “mood of revulsion,” as one journalist called it, permeated every level of politics and ultimately reshaped the state’s patterns of urban development and land use. Soon, however, the imbalance between people’s demand to live in California and California’s new inability to accommodate them produced one of the most severe housing shortages in American history. No longer the poster child of unchecked sprawl, the state instead found itself at the center of a new epidemic: NIMBYism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Drawing on his forthcoming book &lt;i&gt;NIMBY Nation&lt;/i&gt;, Anbinder tells a new history of California’s cost-of-living crisis that moves beyond simplistic caricatures of NIMBYs and their motives. Instead, he instead traces the origins of the housing shortage to a more fundamental shift in liberals’ ideas about whether urban growth could help effect social progress at all. This influential but largely overlooked political movement ultimately dismantled much of the “growth machine” that had built modern California. In doing so, however, antigrowth liberals created the conditions for the paradoxical problem that defines the Golden State today: namely, that America’s most ostensibly progressive place is too expensive for most Americans to live in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Jacob Anbinder&lt;/b&gt; is a historian of the modern United States with a particular focus on the politics of cities and suburbs in the twentieth century. His research interests include the political economy of major infrastructure projects, movements for and against change to the built environment, and the ways in which sprawl and spatial segregation create social inequities. His writing has been published in &lt;i&gt;The Atlantic&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Wall Street Journal&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; U.S. News &amp;amp; World Report&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Business History Review&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; The Week&lt;/i&gt;,&lt;i&gt; Democracy: A Journal of Ideas&lt;/i&gt;, and other outlets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Michael Kahan &lt;/b&gt;is the Co-Director of the Program on Urban Studies at Stanford University and a senior lecturer in Sociology at Stanford University. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 16:30:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/silicon-valley-talks-jacob-anbinder-nimby-nation-the-war-on-growth-that-created-our-housing-crisis-and-remade-american-politics</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/48914944947267/huge/6006580a3a1941c248b79331b8954649e74a4a0c.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="515" width="450" isDefault="true" fileSize="29742"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Take a break, pet a dog at Science and Engineering Quad, Y2E2 Courtyard</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Terman Engineering Library is pleased to have therapy dogs again this quarter. Please join us in the Y2E2 Courtyard on Wednesday, June 4 from 3-4pm. Dog and owner teams from Pet Partners will be providing relaxation and stress relief. In the event of rain, look for us under the covered walkway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Image Credit: Michael Spencer&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2025 15:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/copy-of-take-a-break-pet-a-dog-7053</link>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/44413091992153/huge/3b9b9706613f371cbdb56151f9dcc5610c7e83bc.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="3333" width="5000" isDefault="true" fileSize="2062913"/>
      <category>Social Event/Reception</category>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tabletop Tuesdays: June 2025 at Hohbach Hall</title>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tabletop Tuesdays is an event series held on the third Tuesday of each month. At these events, we feature a selection of board games and collection items from across SUL's holdings around a specific theme. Drop in to learn about the month's featured game(s) and/or try some of the board games we have for open play at the Silicon Valley Archives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The month's theme and featured games will be shared closer to the event date. &lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 14:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <link>https://events.stanford.edu/event/tabletop-tuesdays-june-2025</link>
      <geo:lat>37.426631</geo:lat>
      <geo:long>-122.167086</geo:long>
      <media:content url="https://localist-images.azureedge.net/photos/47252269537831/huge/89cac97242ed25bbf32332051801aac313160880.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg" height="1512" width="2016" isDefault="true" fileSize="581277"/>
      <category>Lecture/Presentation/Talk</category>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
